## way it's not speciesism because i'm not doing
## it because of the species i'm doing it because
## of the severity of the situation we've never
## even said the term animals first human second
## like that's come from other people we've
## never said that before right right what we've
## never said is animals deserve to have a cause
## dedicated solely to them and so av will be that
## sure i actually i i don't know if i've ever heard
## you say that i don't think i don't think i have
## and something but some people have messaged
## that so if anyone's watching right now and you
## you feel like you have some evidence of that then
## you're more than welcome to send it and we'll
## discuss it and you know but i i yeah it's it's
## something that does keep coming up and that goes
## for other things by the way if you're watching
## now and we we go through something and and you
## know but we discuss our poorness i've never said
## that or this has not happened and you think it has
## you just send me a message with what you think has
## happened or within with evidence of it and we'll
## we'll talk about it right now we're not we're not
## here to hide away from things and you know paul
## and us how you agreed to come on here to actually
## directly face some of these things you know so if
## anyone does have something that they feel should
## be directly faced just send it me on instagram or
## a messenger or email or you know tag tag me in
## the comments and tell me you're gonna send it on
## messenger or whatever and i'll and i'll pick it
## up and we'll bring it up on the screen and we'll
## talk about it like we're not we're not hiding
## anything but i've got a sneaky suspicion that
## that's not gonna happen because most of the stuff
## we're talking about is just rumor and you know
## it's i don't think there's a lot
## of evidence behind it to be honest
## um yeah but um let's let's i think we're still on
## intersectionality and i think i feel like we maybe
## want to delve into that just a little bit further
## um i guess what i guess your guys stance on it i
## mean somebody asked the question here saying what
## are you doing to make your activism intersectional
## somebody asked that uh of you guys and and i was
## thinking like how can i really ask that because i
## don't i don't know if it's something that you
## actually are trying to do um i don't i know
## that there was a i know there was a change of
## direction recently as to i don't know not be so
## i don't know what the word is to be more sensitive
## i think with your own words um because maybe in
## the past there was a little bit of insensitivity
## but i guess yeah what would you say to someone
## who's asking you that how what are you doing
## to make your activism more intersectional
## we're not trying to do that like you said but
## that's not the goal there's no need for us to
## try to do that and let's just cut the [ __ ] here
## people who say this are not actually asking us
## to adopt anti-oppression values within
## our organization because we already have
## those what they're asking us to do is become
## activists for human related issues and we are
## dedicated to non-human animals sorry not sorry
## so you draw you draw a line i guess uh between
## not contributing to other oppressions
## are they drawing a line sorry between
## not contributing to other oppressions and being
## active for other oppressions and they feel that
## because you are on the not contributing side
## of the line that therefore means that you are
## wrong and that you should be actually active
## for those oppressions too correct they want us
## to be on the streets showing footage of
## what's happening in the blm movement or
## with regards to homelessness or feminism or
## i guess whatever the mainstream issue is of
## the times but going back to what you were
## saying earlier about like the definition of
## intersectionality it actually doesn't apply here
## because sure you can be an animal rights activist
## you can also be a human rights activist in what
## that whatever area you want to work in but um
## what's the relationship between like any of those
## things that you mentioned and animals suffering
## you know what i mean there is no relationship
## so i i don't think it actually makes sense
## to ask that of us so how are we gonna make it
## work with that even if that was something we
## were looking at doing how are you gonna connect
## homelessness to animal suffering in the meat
## dairy and egg industry i mean we get asked to
## speak up about various issues and it is really
## only about what is popular at that time what is
## being spoken about at that time and it's not about
## these issues that cause a vast number of deaths
## around the world for example in the middle east
## that never gets spoken about that we're aware
## of because we have heritage in the middle east
## we know about these things these people for
## example who were outraged about what was going on