## in america during the protests in minnesota
## and throughout other states said really
## nothing about what happened in lebanon
## for example yeah they are very selective
## the causes that they choose to speak up about and
## that's the thing because when people ask us to do
## the same thing they're asking us to to speak up
## for those specific issues um because you know how
## many different things are out there that you could
## be speaking about when it comes to human rights
## there are so many different things and i don't
## know anyone who claims to be an intersectional
## and they actually cover all of those issues
## there's literally thousands of different
## things that you could talk about and i i only see
## these people focusing on two or three different
## categories and they want us to do the same and
## that points out that you do have to choose your
## cause yeah because if they're claiming you
## have to speak up for all of them well there's
## literally thousands of injustices occurring
## right now around the world all the time so
## it's not only impractical it's impossible
## for you to physically pull that off to
## actually speak up for all of them yeah and to
## fight to end all of them all at once i mean
## think about how insane that is so these people are
## being hypocrites because these people are choosing
## their causes which is guess what we have you have
## our support you have our full support to do that
## because we chose a cause yeah and that's how it is
## you guys are doing the same thing that we're doing
## how about we i'm actually taking this moment
## to see where we have something in common
## and maybe you should do the same thing instead of
## looking at where we have a difference or where you
## think you're more holier than that or something
## to that effect have you considered this before
## there's a concept that actually if i i'll tell
## you who who introduced me to it but um this was
## actually back in the day when things were a little
## bit nicer but it was actually anita who introduced
## me to this concept um years like maybe a year and
## a half ago two years ago when i i brought up the i
## brought up some comments about insectionality and
## i kind of warned anita that it looked like this
## was going to start to take a turn for the worse
## people were starting to attack me for not you know
## saying certain things or for saying certain things
## and i felt like it was starting to seep into
## organizations and i mentioned this and she told me
## we won't do this because we are all about positive
## intersectionality and she had this concept and
## this mindset and it really inspired me actually
## because she said we can fight for the animals
## 100 always but when there are situations where
## it also benefits humans we can also note it for
## example look these vegans went out and gave free
## food that are homeless because they're suffering
## they're doing animal rights activism by teaching
## the homeless about veganism and they're helping
## the homeless for example that would be a positive
## intersectional message right it's not no one
## loses out here the animals are focused and
## the the homeless people have a focus in lebanon
## for example with the blast the the vegans the
## local vegans were doing incredible work they were
## getting like food out to everyone they were like
## you know um helping the vegan businesses in
## the area they were helping the animals in the
## area it was it was amazing but you're also raising
## awareness of that corrupt government and how this
## even happened in the first place it's it's two in
## one it's easy right um and this was great when she
## said this i was really inspired but obviously we
## know how that went and it didn't end up staying
## um staying that way unfortunately but for you guys
## like what do you think about av in that sense do
## you think this is something av could do like with
## social media i mean not with the cubes but like
## with how you represent yourselves on social
## media is that something that you've thought about
## or would ever consider or you do you have do
## you disagree with that that kind of way of doing
## things what way of doing things specifically
## what is being suggested so so like for example
## when there are some um when there is there are
## issues that potentially could be both benefited by
## raising awareness of it for example you obviously
## av is 100 focused on the animals but let's imagine
## there is uh some of your av organizers or
## your av team goes out and gives food to the
## homeless raising putting that on av social
## media and saying like look look look at what
## our awesome activists are doing they're fighting
## for the animals and they're helping the homeless
## do you see some pro a problem with doing something
## like that or do you think that that you agree with
## that as a as an idea that specific suggestion just
## sounds like we would be i don't see how that helps
## a human cause of any kind
## by making a post like that
## i don't see that as activism to help a human
## cause i mean at best it's congratulatory and