## is the actual interaction so this is the
## individual
## saying the information requested is
## pretty standard for an audit so this is
## correct this is what she said
## no lies there okay that's in line with
## the message i received
## so here's paul being extremely
## aggressive apparently
## i don't know now requests bank login
## details to be handled
## handed over to a non-accountant and a
## former gang member how is that stuck
## that's how stock standard audit is
## carried out is it so
## that's the aggressive response
## apparently um this person responds
## saying
## you know she's upset because the it's
## calling joey a former gang member
## um and saying that screenshots could be
## manipulated and then
## paul goes to justify himself saying well
## joey calls himself
## an ex-gang member um okay so not not
## nothing really going on there no [ __ ]
## off nothing like that so far
## and it goes on you're thinking okay so
## where is the [ __ ] off coming where's the
## [ __ ] off and leave
## part coming right because that's the
## main part here that sounds horrible the
## aggressive [ __ ] off and leave
## um all we've got here is paul saying get
## out of here
## you said get out of here so let's not
## [ __ ] off and leave and then
## this person who was an organizer gets
## out of there she decides to leave
## and that's it that's it that's the whole
## interaction
## yeah can i just pause you there yeah go
## ahead
## uh so at this point i didn't even know
## that she was an organizer that's why she
## says in the next comment oh no paul
## bless you i am one of your organizers so
## she's now informed me of this
## after you said get out of here yeah so
## after
## the uh fact but yeah
## just that's it's okay yeah and that
## that's exactly it's even
## this is my point basically when i was
## talking about the whole nickelback thing
## and
## how these rumors get spread and it's
## cool to hate av it's because of things
## like this
## don't get me wrong i know there are
## examples out there of me
## being an [ __ ] to people and i'm sure
## there are examples out there of you guys
## being an [ __ ] to people
## but to go and actually take something
## that didn't happen
## and get it into your head that it
## happened a certain way where you know
## you were told to [ __ ] off and leave as
## an organizer and
## you know people believe this and this
## goes and goes and goes and i guess my
## question for you is
## how does this happen how do we get to
## the point now where we have people that
## believe that they have been wronged by
## you they believe it so much
## that they go and tell other people they
## were wronged by you that they were told
## to [ __ ] off
## when there is literal evidence that you
## have obviously and it's online
## to show that this is not how it went why
## does it happen
## and why do people believe it instantly
## without even
## checking or questioning it like how did
## we get to this point in your opinion
## it's for the same reason that you get
## hate when
## people choose to run
## hate campaign small or large against you
## and their baseless claims it's the same
## reason that
## anyone of any amount of influence in
## this day and age in this
## age of outrage you know in this council
## council culture this is the way that it
## works right people don't
## work off people don't
## have standards for information anymore
## then
## they don't hear something and then
## screen it they hear something and they
## say well he said it with conviction or
## she said it with conviction
## or they said it with conviction and
## therefore it must be true and if they
## said it in the comments section of a
## post with emotion
## it's true it doesn't you don't need to
## do any more homework than that so
## i guess that question is a bit more
## deeper it's
## it's it's more of a question about why
## humans are the way
## humans are yeah
## yeah and and yeah i can see so you think
## you you're putting it down to the
## the more the popularity aspect of it in
## that like the more
## the more well-known an individual or a
## group is the more of this that's going
## to come
## is that is that am i right and
## understanding this is kind of the point
## yeah and you know a lot of our
## organizers have had
## challenges in dealing with hate that
## they get when they come on to
## become an organizer and represent
## av in their cities because they're seen
## as like
## working for hitler you know right
## and yeah you know we we tell organizers
## one of the things you learn
## about being a human rights activist when
## you
## work with us is dealing with that [ __ ]
## right and that's part of it if you want
## to
## do something of influence within this
## world and make an impact
## i i i agree
## so um let's yeah i think i think that's
## a that's going to be a recurring topic
## to be honest with you so