## it was there were certain criterias that you
## you need to meet as an organizer or as a chapter
## you need to be active you need to be doing a
## minimum number of cubes and you need to be you
## know operating for a certain amount of time and
## then even with that because the money was limited
## we had to pick chapters so sometimes it
## was just you know picking this chapter
## over the other chapter and then next month they
## would have a higher chance of getting it but
## um yeah there will be many organizers that would
## actually be able to come forward and say yeah we
## received that and this is what we spent it on but
## i mean our conditions for our criteria for being
## accepted in in getting the funding was nothing
## crazy like you had to be on board for six months
## you know just six months and do one a month
## i think that's what yeah one cube a month so
## you had to do a total amount of six cubes before
## we would we would look at giving you money yeah
## and yeah you know that's nothing that's nothing
## too strenuous i think what's happened is
## a lot of organizers don't really pay attention
## to what we do they they come on and they just do
## their own thing in their own cities and they want
## to be a king or a queen in their own on their own
## mountains and and literally we've seen so many
## people come and go who carry this attitude with
## the navy they just do their own thing in their own
## city and they aren't a part of what we're doing
## as a global movement and uh and these
## people don't really pay attention to
## the things that we have going on yeah and they
## don't really know about these uh things to any
## 20 details so they don't apply and then they
## complain that they never got the money right um
## how do you how do you think we can handle that i
## mean this is uh not even an av specific thing but
## we can we can talk about it for a second that it's
## something i've also experienced not only in av but
## in save and also in um in even you know grassroots
## like none like local grassroots organizations
## local grassroots groups is that there seems to
## always be some kind of power struggle going on
## in these groups i don't know if it's only within
## animal rights or if it's also within i don't know
## women's rights if it's in black lives matter i
## don't know if it's in all these groups i i've not
## been in those groups for enough time to know but
## in animal rights it seems to be that in every
## single group there is a power struggle of somebody
## trying to take over and somebody else who's trying
## to take over that person and you know somebody
## who's trying to reject the leader they have or
## whatever you want to call them leader whatever
## it is it's it's it seems to be very common like
## what do you think what's causing that and uh would
## you have a suggestion on on how to how to fix that
## well you know one of the things
## i'm really proud of with av
## is that we really took into account like
## how we're taken by the public and the fact
## that we want to be taken seriously and like we
## want to address that within the public eye and
## we don't necessarily expect people to trust our
## leadership to like trust our decision making
## but i think it's safe to say we've earned a
## certain level of trust because you know we
## stick to our ship pretty well and
## we do what we do pretty well and
## and uh those who choose to trust our leadership
## aren't forced to choose that they choose it
## on their own accord and i guess if you want
## that entitlement that asylum i have earned to
## run an organization the way that we choose
## then you should start your own organization
## sure if you come on to some come on board with
## someone else you know you choose to volunteer
## or you choose to work for an organization and
## you're on boarding their ethos and representing
## what their movement is about you really have no
## right to say you shouldn't make the decisions
## sure sure so the idea is kind of do you think
## the baby should be some kind of i don't know
## um let's say a self-reflection with people who
## who join groups or who start to work with not
## just av but with any group really that if
## you are going to volunteer with a group um
## i guess you need to learn that maybe your ideas
## won't always be accepted by the current i don't