## humans have been through so it's not something
## that should be accepted um just because it's big
## and because it's being pushed but at the same time
## for good or for bad there are people out there who
## uh yeah like specifically it is it is very much
## intertwined with trends with the trans issues
## which is why it keeps coming up and this you
## didn't you said earlier i don't understand why
## people keep saying it's about trans it's because
## i feel i feel personally i don't tell me if i'm
## wrong i feel like that that um i wouldn't say
## popularity but the the more exposure let's say
## the more awareness of trends and what it means
## to be trans has also come tied in with gender
## and and gender identity yeah because yeah confuse
## the issue though i think deliberately they have to
## use the two now it's like all mixed in but
## it doesn't need to be because when we're
## talking about gender pronouns and gender
## we're talking about gender roles and like
## you can you can be a female like you can be
## born a female in a female body but you may
## not necessarily feel like you are fitting into
## that you know that i don't know mindset or that
## gender role and that's totally fine but that's
## not what we're talking about when we're talking
## about like someone transitioning you're talking
## about them changing their their body and that's
## the sex it's like when you go to the doctor they
## they care about knowing your birth sex because
## you know the doctor needs about your body and your
## biology so that's why sex and gender are different
## and if anyone wants to confuse the two that's
## just not gonna you know that's fine but that's
## that's just not the reality of it they're they're
## completely separate uh and my trans um supporters
## tell me this and and i agree with them convoluting
## conflating gender politics uh the gender pronoun
## issue in society that's been brought up uh with
## the trans movement and struggle of trans people
## is actually diminishing them as victims of their
## struggle so it takes away from what they're really
## dealing with and uh they're not struggling
## with gender pronouns necessarily like the
## the struggles are different
## they're they're struggling
## with uh with just being accepted as a trans
## person and that's a different discussion
## completely to what we're discussing here this is
## what they tell me and i agree with them and uh
## it's disrespectful to the trans movement to just
## attach all these other things to it and say that's
## a trans issue too yeah if you care about the trans
## movement then you wouldn't do that i understand so
## yeah there's a distinction between just wanting
## to identify as one of the limitless genders and
## actually suffering from gender dysphoria and and
## changing your sex and wanting to be referred to
## as a different pronoun because it it validates who
## you are and it's something that you have struggled
## through yes you're drawing there's a distinction
## between the two basically is what you're saying
## right there absolutely is and trans people
## around the world feel diminished because of this
## this incessant um obsessive need to link it to
## everything else and they've already finished on
## top okay but it's but although although you hold
## this belief and obviously av operates on this um
## not belief i wouldn't say but let's say opinion
## and the av operates also on this opinion like that
## av will not accept um people bringing
## in ideologies um without let's say
## like obviously trans trend the trans movement
## isn't an ideology um not for them not for the
## people who are actually uh you know suffering from
## gender dysphoria anyway although there are people
## who are calling themselves trans who are actually
## not don't have gender dysphoria then that's an
## ideology i would say that's different that's a
## political um ideology or or some i don't know
## ideology of some sort um but unfortunately i would
## say it is it is difficult to actually determine
## who is who right and and who is for real and who
## is doing this because they genuinely you know are
## a trans person and who is doing this because they
## have they want to get on board with an ideology
## and and kind of i don't know be different um i
## guess how does av how does it how is av going
## to operate with that because i know that you like
## you've just said you'll you accept people who have
## uh and you accept and will respect people
## who are genuinely you know are trans or or
## whatever if they have whatever condition the av
## will respect them and people will be booted if
## they don't respect them but then also in the same
## breath you're saying that the political ideology
## is not actually welcome and so if somebody isn't
## actually trans and they are just identifying as
## someone else because it's something they want
## to do so how is av going to actually how would