## mission is to tell the truth on behalf of the
## victims because it's the least that we can do so
## that's what i said and that was that was uh what
## people have called me racist over so that was like
## i mean it's let's let's let's be like that's not [
## __ ] here it's definitely something that would be
## considered to be like insensitive but but that's
## not your the goal isn't to be sensitive um a lot
## you know it's i don't think being insensitive is
## necessarily something negative i think sometimes
## it needs to be um like that but but how is that
## translating to racism like if somebody said paul
## you're [ __ ] insensitive i i wouldn't i don't
## think i'd even bring that up because it's like
## well yeah that's obvious like you you
## know your outreach videos tend to be
## towards the side of insensitivity and more towards
## the side of like straight direct like you're going
## to get the message whether it pisses you off or
## not right if you're being sensitive you would
## dress it up and be nice but you're not being and
## that's not something to criticize in my opinion
## or it is whatever but that's not the point here
## the point is racism so how does that translate to
## racism how do you think someone gets it from
## that video that that's you somehow you know
## disrespecting somebody because of their ethnicity
## just because of her skin color right well no no
## again no it's not just well it's not just that you
## are speaking to a white woman would would you get
## no of course not but it's not just that it's
## also the fact what people are overlooking here
## is if if we are going to entertain the notion
## that there is insensitivity at play here
## people are overlooking the fact that she
## was being incredibly insensitive to the
## animal victims that she is an oppressor of
## directly responsible for victimizing herself
## and so that's where it started that's where the
## context of all of this began i was responding
## to her not by saying [ __ ] black people and [ __
## ] black rights but by saying animals are the most
## oppressed group of beings on the planet if me
## pointing out a fact is insensitive while she's
## literally saying [ __ ] the animals and [ __ ]
## their rights well i guess you need to ask yourself
## which like what does it take for you to see
## injustice for what it is especially when it's
## to the degree that it is he in this case with the
## animals when they're subjected to the most brutal
## violence that has ever been carried out on any
## group of beings ever what does it take for people
## to to to just literally just acknowledge them and
## to acknowledge the fact that they are subjected
## to oppression to the extent that they
## are subjected to that oppression and for
## simply just simply for people to simply say
## that for people to simply speak about that
## if that's offensive we have no hope as a species
## evolving and developing into better ways of
## of living on this planet and uh with truly
## addressing injustice and oppression on this
## planet it's never going to happen unless we
## change the way we think around things like this
## yeah i i i think honestly my opinion on
## this is like to to label that as racism
## is is offensive um to it's offensive because
## it's not even offensive it's it's harmful
## because it confuses what actual racism is right
## how how can you call like and this is this
## when you really lay it out like this
## right you've got two people of color
## you're not white so two people of color
## having a conversation about the animals
## and one of the people says that you know the
## reality about the animals and somehow that
## person is racist it's just such a strange thing to
## call racism over and it completely takes away the
## meaning of the word and i've said this before
## people get really upset about it that the more
## you use the word racist sexist transphobe the more
## difficult it becomes to actually identify racists
## sexists and transphobes and and i think nowadays
## we're in a position where it's like you said who
## hasn't been called a racist um or a transphobe or
## a sexist in 2020 practically anyone who has dared
## to even question the narrative has been called
## one of those things it's either you you do what
## you're told and you say what you're supposed
## to say or that's what you get branded with
## do you know how harmful that is to the people who
## actually suffer from sexism racism and transphobia
## the fact that you know that label is so used so
## flippantly if you could you could say that for
## every every other label that is thrown around
## um to to to to try and cancel others when uh
## when faceless whether it's the term fascist
## or or sexist or racist or or whatever it is