## saying they won't they won't go to av
## events because of this um so yeah
## this is the topic we're going to get
## into i'll ask you a question someone
## just asked this question earlier
## uh why do intersectionals
## intersectionals not like you
## that's what someone said so that's an
## easy question to start with why do these
## people hate you why are they coming for
## you
## why are they trying to cancel you why
## are they trying to ruin um your
## organization
## you want to go only um
## yeah i i guess yeah like you you already
## explained that
## it's not that we're anti-intersectional
## um we just made a decision that
## av is going to be 100 dedicated to the
## animals non-human animals
## and there are many reasons why we
## decided on that
## but that doesn't mean that we don't
## think or anyone within the organization
## not just
## us too doesn't believe that other groups
## of beings need
## um voices to speak up for them or we
## shouldn't be doing activism in different
## areas so it's again it's just the way
## that people
## decide to interpret this like someone
## decided that because
## av is 100 dedicated to non-human animals
## that means that
## we have hatred towards humans or
## we there's discrimination when it comes
## to certain groups of humans
## and they're just running with that idea
## i think it's
## easy to paint that image of us
## given that we are aware of the fact
## that we dedicate av 100 to animal rights
## in light of a temp
## the temperament currently in society is
## that
## anyone who does such a thing must also
## pander
## to human rights otherwise it's totally
## out of place so we're completely aware
## of this
## and we still won't pander so
## it's easy to paint us like that but we
## don't care because
## we want for this to exist in the world
## we want a movement who is still willing
## to just
## do the right thing in the face of what
## is popular in
## the moment and you've been also
## a popular thing that comes up when
## discussing these things is the the idea
## of a hierarchy of oppression
## of which it it appears that you that you
## guys
## do um have a hierarchy as in you i've
## heard at least
## you paul especially i've heard this but
## i don't know if i'm sure you've said it
## as well
## and this is not an attack it's just you
## know just quoting
## um that the animals are by far the most
## oppressed beings
## on the planet right and some people get
## upset about that because they say that
## you're creating a hierarchy of
## oppression and apparently this
## is this is uh this is wrong um how do
## you respond to that
## um that's disrespectful and it's a spit
## in the face of every animal that
## that is subjected to that injustice
## you know you can you can act like
## you're offended by these semantics all
## you want
## but just remember that while your
## charade is going on
## you're spitting in the face of the
## victims who are involved in the
## injustice that you're carrying on about
## and that's my response to that it's just
## simple that
## we shouldn't have to explain that we're
## not saying that humans aren't oppressed
## what you said doesn't sound like
## something
## that resonates with me the hierarchy of
## oppression
## but it is a fact that the animals
## well okay so in terms of the number of
## individual animals
## who have been tortured and abused and
## murdered
## compared to any other injustice that's
## literally what we're talking about so
## i don't think it's i don't think it
## means like if anyone takes that as
## so you're saying there is a hierarchy of
## oppression meaning
## this group is more oppressed or we
## should speak up for them first that's
## not what we're saying you can't take
## that from
## from saying you know animals are the
## most suppressed meaning they have been
## um they have been oppressed for the
## longest
## and the number of individual victims is
## higher than any other injustice that's
## just the fact that's the reality of it
## and
## you're right if somebody gets upset
## because of that
## then i think they need to just reflect
## on why that is because
## i know that there are people out there
## that were more oppressed than me
## as as a woman of color
## and so therefore anyone else in any