## that 100 takes away from what we're doing because
## it's not necessary and it's irrelevant so to put
## time aside 15 20 minutes for everyone to go around
## and say my name is blah blah blah and this is my
## preferred pronoun which is unnecessary because in
## case we need to refer to you you let us know then
## if we got it wrong you correct us that's fine we
## can get on with our day um i know that that was
## something that was brought up and i just wanted to
## clarify that there are many other things that are
## human-centric that we don't allocate our activism
## our time to at the cubes to engaging in and so you
## could use this same logic if you're claiming that
## we are discriminatory towards those who have uh
## again we've never even spoken about trans
## people so i reject the notion of even
## commenting on trans people people with gender
## pronouns uh the same argument could be used
## for uh not um honoring the custodians of the
## land and saying something about like the original
## custodians the land the aboriginals or or the
## native americans depending on the of the region
## that we're talking about here we don't do that at
## the cubes either does that mean that we are also
## racist or we're also colonial colonialists
## or whatever the word is that's being tossed
## around regarding that discrimination no of
## course not because we're there for non-humans
## and non-humans deserve a cause dedicated
## to them that's what this comes down to
## is if you think that we're being discriminatory
## under that logic then you really just don't think
## that animals deserve a cause solely dedicated to
## them that's what we're disagreeing about yeah yeah
## i guess i guess my my what i'm what i was trying
## to get out of it here is try to get to clarify
## what for 100 this which i think you have clarified
## now is that like the the you know what you don't
## want people you don't want to bring up um like
## let's say identity politics into into cubing
## you don't want it to become part of av you don't
## want it to become part of an action or an event
## um however if somebody has personal a personal
## thing where they want to be referred to as
## a certain pronoun or they've recently transitioned
## that av is part of av policies to respect that
## because not respecting that would be considered
## bullying that's what i'm trying to clarify here
## so this is you're making a distinction between the
## two i also need to make the distinction here that
## we're referring to sex if anything whenever the
## word gender is being used in this conversation
## we are not referring to anything other than
## sex we are not referring our repeat to anything
## other than sex and the conversation keeps getting
## skewed by others to be referring to gender but uh
## regarding trans issues or regarding this
## whole thing uh with my comments on being
## skeptical of gender pronouns it was regarding
## sex that i was skeptical of this there aren't
## more than two sexes in my opinion and i think
## that people are entitled to have that opinion
## trans people are transitioning between those
## two sexes i think they have the right to do that
## so i support the trans movement if that's what it
## is right i have trans people that follow me that
## support me that like me in the face of my comments
## and the hate i receive getting called a transfer
## does not waver these people i'm not trying to use
## them as a token i'm just giving people context
## because context is lost in our in our culture
## and yeah that's all i have to say okay um
## yeah yes i'm trying to wrap my head around it
## and also i just sorry i was just taking care of
## a troll as well i'm just asking annie to get rid
## of a troll in the chat as i was also trying to get
## that sword it seems like they're bothering people
## so you obviously you make a separation between um
## sex and gender which i think most well i mean
## that's just that's that's scientific um there
## is there is actually i think um some people would
## argue including myself that there are three sexes
## because there's intersex which is very rare but
## it exists right it's it's when someone's born with
## both or like like you know both um genetics or
## whatever i don't know too much about it but i
## know that it exists um and then yeah and then and
## then you're drawing the line because because um
## yeah because genders it's a new it is an ideology
## the ideology gender ideology is new it is new
## if anyone's upset about this then i'm not sorry
## because you need to do some research on this and
## how realize how gender ideology is a very recent
## thing and it hasn't been put through the rigorous
## testing that most other psychological and science
## scientific you know concepts have you know about