## said you know shut the [ __ ] up like stfu in
## a comment i personally saw that myself at one
## point and i was like who the [ __ ] said that you
## know that was quite a surprise for me to see um
## you know is this something that you guys stand
## behind are you are you okay with like you know
## going out and telling people like if they're being
## you know if they're acting silly or if they're
## being silly is that is that with your social media
## team are they like you know go and do that or was
## this some bad actors in the team that are now
## not doing that you know how has that changed i
## haven't seen it since you know it seems like when
## the whole thing happened with george um it seemed
## after that that social media has been direct and
## but there's not been any of this like shut up and
## you know and the rude comments seem to have almost
## stopped so it was am i right in assuming that
## that was linked or or is this something you've
## changed inside internally and now it's different
## well it's not good it's not it's it's not
## the george it's not that george was just
## cursing people out using our account um i think we
## need to see like specific examples of where this
## has happened for us to comment more specifically
## about those things but generally we don't just
## curse people out no we don't but we do speak
## in a real way and so sometimes you might see
## us calling someone a dick because they're acting
## like a dick and it's and it won't be without us
## communicating effectively you know we're not
## just calling them a dick and if you if you just
## don't be a dick yourself and just conclude it that
## way when you know there's more context involved
## here if you read the entire comment usually you
## can see us responding with an educated a response
## that educates the viewer that the reader and
## we're not just telling them to [ __ ] off or
## to shut the [ __ ] up or whatever it is you know
## that's not that's not what we do we're we're out
## to edify people hold them accountable when you
## hold people accountable sometimes you have to
## be real with them and you have to pull them out
## and say you're being a dick when they're being do
## sure and and um this links in with the the
## the vegetarian drama let's let's call it
## so this is something that av does focus on quite
## a lot and nasal i know you actually made a posted
## a video on this relatively recently about
## about uh vegetarians um that's a that's a
## another big criticism that the criticism
## being that av is av attacks vegetarians
## that's the criticism like that that's come up a
## lot actually and i've seen that not only in my own
## you know me asking people for questions
## but also when you're just scrolling and
## if you're in reddit or something like that one
## of the common things that comes up is like av
## is counterproductive because they attack
## vegetarians um i think i already know how
## you're gonna answer this but um maybe it's a
## bit of an easier one to deal with what do you
## respond to these people who get upset about
## that and say you're attacking vegetarians
## which vegetarian we've never
## targeted a specific vegetarian
## we attack vegetarianism and i think
## that vegetarianism is the single
## greatest cancer in the animal rights
## movement other than vegans themselves
## being number one actually vegans vegans are number
## one the number one threat to the animal rights
## movement uh vegetarians are operating in society
## under this idea this image of being on the side
## of the animals to be there they're portraying
## themselves as animal people quote unquote right
## and whenever they speak to vegans generally
## speaking of course majority of these individuals
## are pompous and they tell you that you don't
## need to talk to them because they're already
## vegetarian is the way that they would frame
## it i'm already vegetarian so these people
## on paper in terms of the facts are
## doing exactly as much as someone whose
## paleo is doing for the animals because they
## don't consume dairy vegetarians don't consume
## flesh dairy is considered more cruel to cows than
## eating their flesh is the dairy industry we as
## animal rights activists tend to say this stuff so
## it's not just me saying that so if that's the case
## paleo people are more in alignment with us than
## vegetarians are but that logic is flawed so
## it's insane that they would get a pass for being
## portrayed as animal people and as long as they
## continue to parade and act like they are animal
## people the longer it will take to get vegetarians
## to become vegan and the more we make a mockery of
## the real animal rights message for everybody else
## and the longer the vegans cuddle vegetarians
## and again i'm not talking about any specific
## vegetarian talking about vegetarianism
## the longer we cuddle vegetarianism