## has never done yeah no i know that's yeah i think
## we're on the same page with that that's why i
## just i think we can just kind of go on because
## i don't i don't like that i see others doing it
## i'm like okay cool but it doesn't sit right for
## me to promote these massive monster companies uh
## it doesn't feel right um but but if people do it
## that's their call right it's not for me my point
## i was going to make though with this is that so
## for example quorn is a massive company in the uk
## i don't know if they're in australia too but they
## uh they're one of the oh cool so like the og like
## um fake meat mock meat companies and they they
## have this thing called microprotein and that was
## tested on animals when they first released it but
## the pushback was so intense and from vegetarians
## that they had to like reconvene and they released
## a statement where basically the uh i think it was
## the ceo i can't remember it's on their website
## right now um he basically says that he he regrets
## it that he wishes that he did it differently
## or she i can't remember if it's a guy or a girl
## and they said they will never test on animals ever
## again this company will never do it ever again
## and we totally listen to your feedback and it's
## done um versus unfortunately the impossible burger
## impossible foods and i think beyond
## foods as well i think beyond me also
## say this they're saying the opposite like
## they're saying they're going to continue to test
## for me and for many i think that's where they
## draw the line and say wait a minute okay testing
## once is one thing testing once and saying yeah we
## see you're pissed off and we know it's wrong but
## we're going to do it again if we if we want to
## they they draw a distinction between these two
## companies and one being like okay we'll support
## this one and the other one they say no we're not
## going to support them because they're pro with
## a section you know where do you stand on on that
## comparison that logic doesn't work that logic does
## not work because corn is still selling products
## with cheese and egg in it um or at least egg yeah
## they have a vegetarian range and a vegan brain
## so yeah okay they're against animal testing
## they're still not a vegan company however yeah in
## exactly the same way that impossible foods is not
## a vegan company so sure but comparison then yeah
## yeah well no it's just people are getting
## angry about what they choose to be angry about
## yeah i think it's about being consistent
## that's a great point because they're not
## a vegan company and the whole range is not
## vegan so why are we only taking issue with
## animal testing and not what happens to
## the animals in the dairy egg industry
## sure sure it's about that's my bad that's a
## bad comparison with corn um i guess what i
## was trying to get at is is uh we've supported
## a company that is going to say that they're
## going to continue to test on animals but is
## producing um plant-based burgers like is is
## there no is is there no ethical consideration to
## be hard here i guess is what i'm trying to say
## of course come on man of course there it is of
## course of course we need to ask impossible foods
## to cut the [ __ ] and stop testing on animals and
## to be vegan but the point here is that expecting
## them to be vegan before you buy their product
## which is vegan stand alone in and of itself is
## just a ridiculous uh standard to apply if you're
## going to do it you have to be consistent and that
## would make it impractical to be impractical to
## be negan it would make it impossible to be vegan
## and i don't mean to use that pun
## but we're in an impossible situation
## sure okay okay um yeah i think that's all i
## wanted to ask about that i don't think there's
## anything else i can go through do you have
## anything to close on that with it being mainly
## the questions targeted at you is there anything
## else you'd like to say to people who are still
## like dubious about this or unsure about this i
## think that's it just the last point that you said
## about um you know how they've they've basically
## said they will test in the future and then coin
## saying they will never do it again i just think i
## personally on a personal level i don't take that
## seriously anyway just because the ceo came out and
## said something i don't take it either way i don't
## take it as seriously as others actually forget
## because i just think okay i'll just wait and see
## in future if impossible keeps doing it
## then i will not be supporting it anymore or
## um at the same time i don't trust that
## company that says we will never do it again
## i just don't trust people like that because they
## might do it and at the same time they are abusing
## other animals anyway so that's why like somebody
## just making a statement on their website is not
## i don't take it that seriously no one no one
## is protesting magnums the vegan magnums the
## company whether they put out a statement or not
## uh are saying in their actions that they do not
## reject animal abuse that they will continue to
## condone it and sell products and make money off
## the backs of animals because just look at the
## rest of their range same could be said about