## video there's no way to determine this we i i'm
## only uh making an educated guess here okay so
## even after hours and hours of research being put
## into that video that was her conclusion but how
## are these individuals coming to this conclusion
## when is this where is this data even being logged
## how all those marine animals that are slaughtered
## in the fish industry are they being logged
## who's who's noting how many animals are being
## murdered like it's all an assumption and um i
## wouldn't trust any any piece of information
## coming from animal agriculture of course or
## any study that's funded by animal agriculture of
## course if it says something to the effect that
## their products are on the rise and they're doing
## really well and all this i wouldn't trust that
## and especially since we know actually that the
## dairy industry is on its way out there's many
## indicators of that so it depends on what you're
## looking at and i need more data and more evidence
## to even entertain the notion that uh that it's
## going in the opposite direction in terms of the
## numbers however in terms of public perception and
## the way that animal rights is perceived publicly
## now animal rights has been pushed even further
## back than it was last year i do agree with that
## yeah no totally i agree all right that brings us
## to the end of my topics um and now if you've if
## you've i guess it's late for you guys actually
## but if you do have another like let's say let's
## limit it to maybe like i don't know would you
## agree for another 20 minutes is that okay 30
## minutes or is that too much for you guys right
## now 20 minutes sounds good all right i can see
## yeah i'm waking up and you're and you're going
## to bed so this is kind of like yeah yeah how
## late is it sorry what time 40. all right okay
## cool yeah we can start to wrap up then so
## um guys you got to put some questions in um i
## didn't see you putting any questions in so far
## i'm not going to go back through all the way back
## to the beginning because i know some of you aren't
## even here anymore so if you've got questions
## now's the time and if you really really want your
## question to be asked like right now and you want
## it to make sure you fit it in 20 minutes in the
## next 20 minutes then you can uh do a super chat
## and that will 100 be asked as long as it's not
## something shitty um to be to put it bluntly uh but
## yeah we're open to questions now for the next like
## 20 minutes or so but after that
## i'm gonna let them go to bed so
## i'm gonna run to the toilet sure man go go
## no worries no worries and whilst whilst i'm
## waiting for that yeah i just want to say i do
## really appreciate you both coming on here i know
## it's it's mentally exhausting to go through these
## things um especially considering that some of them
## are really ugly accusations right um i've i've
## the reason one of the main reasons i wanted to do
## it as well is because i feel like i can empathize
## with this because i've also been on the receiving
## end of equally ugly accusations so i know i know
## how it feels when you read that like we all we all
## pretend like yeah well whatever you know whatever
## but like really it does it does get you right when
## you read something so horrible and someone's
## saying it about you i know how it feels so i'm
## happy we could get through this and and you know
## i hope a few people have had uh i hope it's given
## a few people something to think about at least so
## they don't go and repeat this nonsense uh over and
## over again because it doesn't it doesn't feel good
## to read it does it you know yeah i just hope that
## what people can take from this maybe is that they
## start thinking a bit more critically and if they
## hear something they ask for evidence they ask for
## proof you know they look into it before deciding
## that somebody is a racist sexist etc because
## these are horrible things that you can say and
## yeah i just it's sad that people can just use this
## term so loosely now and they don't realize how
## insulting and destructive that is and how much it
## actually takes away from the real victims of these
## um depression so yeah no for sure um yeah i'm
## gonna be honest with you it doesn't look like
## there's any questions coming in i guess i guess
## we kind of answered so much i guess they don't
## have any anything else that's not being answered
## to be honest i thought about this earlier in that
## we've gone through so many topics that
## maybe there aren't going to be questions
## because there's like 60 people watching right
## now and so far there's no questions so if that's
## the case we can we can wrap up there's a lot
## of statements though i can put some of those
## on the screen you know just like for the
## last like maybe like 10 minutes or so just
## being king saying here they don't have evidence
## for their claims and when they do it's hilarious
## i i mean this is how it seems to be right that
## they there's no evidence or there is evidence but
## it's not evidence like it's something they have
## made a i don't know they've made it some kind of
## assumption from or they've twisted right yeah this
## seems to be happening most of the time really yeah