## you operate with these two individuals let's say
## being around how are you going to determine who
## who should be respected and and you know should
## be dealt with in a very in a respectful way
## and who should actually be told no don't
## bring your ideologies here leave it at home
## well everyone everyone everyone needs to be
## respected okay everyone including yeah that's
## the answer everyone needs to be respected so i
## mean uh everyone is entitled to their opinions
## but no one is entitled to use their to weaponize
## their opinions against others and that's my
## most accurate answer to that okay sure everyone
## is respected for their opinions and their right to
## have an opinion no one has a right to weaponize
## their opinion against others in any way and so
## that's it i mean you know where do we draw
## the line with human stuff as well because
## we allow people who are disabled to come
## to our cubes and rock a wheelchair in the
## cube we've had so many people in wheelchairs
## in our cubes around the world we don't say
## we don't you know we welcome these people i don't
## know why i'm using that as a point i guess it's
## just of course we welcome different uh struggles
## and we accommodate different struggles within nav
## but only as far as getting the job done is
## required because we're there for the animals and
## that just needs to be respected
## also everyone needs to be respected
## for the mission when we're at the cube but
## i think we should move on now to the next
## subject all right all right okay can
## i close off of the bottom line and
## bottom line yes or no question and then
## we'll move on is that all right with you
## but it's bottom line yes or no then so what
## i'm understanding is that someone comes to the
## cube they request to be called a certain thing
## and people in the cubes people the organizers
## are requested to respect that and if they get it
## wrong by accident no worries don't do it again
## if you get it wrong on purpose you're being
## disrespectful and you'll be you'll be if it
## comes up you will be told either told off or or i
## don't know warned and saying that that's bullying
## am i right is that correct is that if i understood
## this correctly or is there something i've missed
## um sorry i sorry i just kind of zoned out for a
## bit so you said right somebody got it wrong by
## accident no worries obviously what are we gonna
## do um and then if they did it on purpose they're
## gonna get kicked out is that always not kicked
## out whatever it may be they'd be either warned
## or if it's been multiple times let's say you
## would you you would take a further action if
## it's if it's becoming a habit you know if it's
## something they've done more than once for example
## yeah um yeah basically but like what i was saying
## earlier if somebody feels that strongly about
## it that they're not willing to because they
## feel like they're accepting that ideology
## by referring to um say you showed up at a
## cube and you want to be referred to as she
## and like i just can't accept that then in that
## case they could refer to you with your name
## and if they're not willing to do that then yes
## that would be an issue because then that person
## buying this thing on not wanting to refer to
## you as whatever then that that person is taking
## away from the event in the queue because they're
## good yeah they're making good about anything else
## yeah they make yeah okay but i think that yeah
## that seems reasonable to me but i'm i'm i guess
## it's not good enough for everyone for a lot of
## people but i i feel like it's reasonable i just
## wanted to clarify it before we moved on though
## yeah when we move on i just want to say one more
## time like this has literally never happened in
## our personal experience has never happened and i
## haven't heard of a specific um event where this
## was the issue and this this was brought up and
## somebody you know had an issue with referring to
## someone else with their preferred name or pronouns
## i just want to say how uncommon this is but yeah
## i guess it's just about future proofing because
## this is the world we're in um now you know uh
## it's it's i don't think it's a bad world that
## we're in i think it's good i think uh that's why
## i wanted to really get into it because i i am 100
## certain that as as we go into the future this
## is going to become more and more and more common
## and not just in av in other organizations
## like you know jobs like people working in
## offices and stuff like that this is going to
## start becoming more and more common because
## people you know in general people don't like
## change um in general uh so you're gonna have to i
## think we i feel we hope we all have to expect that
## we're gonna be some people out there who are gonna