## other beings you know that are more oppressed than
## themselves and that doesn't take away from their
## pain or their suffering that's how i see it i
## mean how more audacious could you possibly be
## as a human being any human being to say
## you're more oppressed than a group of beings
## enslaved tortured and murdered by the trillion
## with a t every year when was the last genocide
## of one billion with a b humans oh wait crickets
## a billion i'm talking three trillion with a t
## are subjected to this injustice every single year
## it's happening every second of every day doesn't
## need to be explained to vegans of course but hello
## don't get mad at us for being a medium of truth
## yeah i think um just to add to that i think this
## is this is a point that i i agree on i mean i'm i
## guess i'm not supposed to be sharing my personal
## views here i am interviewing you but i have to
## say i agree with you because um i don't believe
## that it's down to emotions this point i believe
## it's down to the facts and it's objectively
## true it's it's it's not something that can
## even be argued against and anyone who's tried to
## argue against even with me the arguments it just
## falls to pieces because you can't possibly claim
## that any other animal on the planet is abused
## or any any human animal on the planet is abused or
## or exploited or objectified more than a non-human
## the non-humans don't even have political rights or
## voices like it's it's not even about how much they
## say even if we forget how many of them are abused
## in the severity the fact that they literally have
## no say at all in their own lives um like none
## none whatsoever no legal almost no legal rights
## you know um it's it's enough you know it's enough
## to just even go from that even if it wasn't three
## trillion that alone is enough of a point you know
## but at that and the fact there's three trillion
## of them being you know horrifically murdered
## it's it's it's yeah it's a crazy point to try to
## to try to argue against that in my opinion and i'm
## always surprised when vegans try to argue against
## it it's i mean i mean nothing really surprises
## me anymore actually but but yeah it's slightly
## more surprised with that um i've got a question
## uh do you think this is this came from a a uh
## instagramer i think uh do you think it's
## speciesist to ignore human oppression while
## fighting for non-human animals that was that was
## a question that somebody wanted to ask you guys
## you know i know that people aren't
## attuned to nuance and context but
## it is required for us to answer this
## question uh as a general statement yeah like
## the way you ask that of course not like yeah
## sorry the question was is it is it speciesist
## do you think it yeah do you think it is personally
## do you find it to be is that is that an example
## of speciesism basically yes when i hear that
## question as a blanket statement like that yes
## because it sounds like otherwise you're going to
## say otherwise you're denying that group of things
## like their existence and their suffering and
## their oppression so yeah of course it is but
## yeah like we need an example or an explanation
## of why because is that because again because
## av is 100 focused on non-human animals or is this
## question directed at us personally and people are
## wondering if we do other forms of activism or we
## care about other poison forms of injustice every
## every day we make a post on social media about
## non-human animals every day we set up cube of
## truth action on the streets those energies are
## spent on fighting for non-human animals while
## human injustices are occurring within human human
## to human injustices are occurring around the world
## at that time so if at a general level you
## want to say because of our answer we're
## technically ignoring all of these other
## injustices while we're doing that well
## there's no such there's no point of even
## trying to like there's no nuance at all
## in a way that someone would think if
## that's the conclusion they're trying
## yeah yeah i think i would add to that and i
## don't think it's speciesism because you're not uh
## you're not not fighting for humans i'm not i'm not
## not fighting for humans because i think humans are
## somehow inferior i'm choosing to fight for
## non-humans because i believe that well not
## i believe they are um in more need simple as that
## so that's my how i answer that question is is that