## it's not just an opinion that we had this was
## really happening and uh that was the issue that
## you're pointing out david sure and and george and
## another individual they were removed from the team
## was was that because of this specific example or
## was there another reason that these individuals
## were removed there was another question somebody
## asked that was one of the comments but there were
## other comments left um by george but also it was
## the conversations we had in private with them
## about the issue i believe the comments were
## about um denying that systemic oppression exists
## and how that comment was left by our social media
## members without them running it by us and that's
## not something that um just didn't align with us
## or av or other team members so that's why we had
## to have private conversations to clarify this and
## that and during those conversations we realized
## that we're just not aligned and it was just not
## possible at that point to have them on the team
## yeah just to clarify yeah because it might be
## confused by people in what we're saying here uh
## that like gemma and george were like fired on
## the same premise they weren't removed from ab
## on the same premise there was a different uh
## scenario for those both individuals like we
## a different decision process for both
## those individuals there were different
## things that occurred with george as well it
## wasn't just one thing it wasn't one comment
## or one point multiple comments and then
## multiple conversations that we were having that
## made it clear that yeah but it was different
## and it wasn't just this no i was like another
## example was about how because the comment that
## you just read out i didn't remember that one
## but i know there was another one going around
## what our team said systemic oppression doesn't
## exist in the west or something like that which
## we were getting lots of messages about and so i
## do remember that very clearly right there
## were i think there were multiple things
## otherwise we wouldn't just ask someone to leave
## the team over one comment especially someone who
## was an asset to the organization george was
## a prized member of the team whom i really
## liked working with and i thought that he was a
## great member so it's ridiculous that we would
## um yeah it's tough to be in this position
## um you know that's the thing also like
## it sucks to have to fire someone like george
## yeah i just want to add because it's okay to have
## your own political views your religious
## views but if you are commenting as a v
## as a part of the team and then those views are
## coming through your comments and your messages
## then that's not okay because within the team
## like i said we have over 20 people or something
## and we all have different views and then we have
## our own political views or our own views on god
## or religion or whatever but you never see us
## commenting about it when we're commenting as a
## v because av is supposed to represent something
## that is just about the animal so regardless of
## your views you can be a part of that and that
## was the issue that it was just not possible to
## to have that with those individuals and people
## don't seem to be wanting to work with us to create
## the most conducive organization
## that is dedicated to the animals
## people don't seem to be working with us to
## achieve this we seem to be dedicated to it and
## everyone seems to be pushing back and pushing
## back and pushing back we are open to ideas we
## want to see how we can help other like other
## things here but we have like assa was saying
## we have other people in the organization who have
## even stronger political views than george do than
## george does even stronger political views than
## than george does think i mean think about that
## you know yeah sure and they don't they don't ever
## they never let their advices come through their
## work so that's but again when it's not to focus on
## just one point here because it wasn't just one a
## one-dimensional decision it was multi-dimensional
## and that that's also kind of entwined with the uh
## intertwined the with another kind of criticism i
## had about the comments like uh there were i don't
## know if there still are i haven't seen any since
## this but there were quite a lot of let's say rude
## comments um on on the av social media let's say
## like sometimes i think i even saw one someone