## that's that's me as well you know that's kind of
## i faced that personally uh we do have a question
## though now from um i'm not even going to try and
## pronounce your name i'm sorry i should oh should
## knights disrespectful mr jackal let's say um do
## you think donating money to animal sanctuaries
## is worth the money oftentimes the same people who
## say outreach doesn't work advocate for donating
## to sanctuaries or fundraise themselves well of
## course it's worth the money i think we need we
## need people to donate to animal sanctuaries and
## also donate to organizations like av so that we
## can keep doing what we're doing i think it's all
## needed so once we have these animals who are being
## rescued obviously they're gonna need a home so
## that's where the animal center is coming and
## they can't just operate without the money so yeah
## i think that's obvious that it's worth the money
## yeah i think maybe they're also alluding to
## the idea that a lot of these same individuals
## will say don't donate to ed or james or av
## or or whatever donate to a sanctuary because
## it's better and you kind of give the impression
## that it's one or the other you know that there's
## people that that's it you can only choose one
## and you know one should get all the money um
## which which is nonsense obviously yeah um
## all right this is from michael paul and assal
## you're still young do you think we'll be living
## in a majority vegan world in your lifetime
## i want to say yes so badly
## i just really don't know
## doesn't feel like in the next 50 years
## or so we're going to achieve that
## to be realistic standing sure i
## think for my side of this i think um
## i agree but i also see it as positive that we i
## feel like we lay the foundations for the future
## generations that will achieve this so although
## we won't see it be realistic we're not going
## to see it but we can do a lot of good
## work to help the future people to see it
## yeah it's like two-pack said you know we may not
## be the ones to see that but we will be the ones to
## spark the minds of those who will create that
## world and if we don't create it ourselves but
## um i think it's more important to just
## be focused on spending our lifetime
## on fighting for a vegan world rather than being
## attached to it coming to fruition in our lifetime
## not that this question suggests that it's just
## wondering whether we think it will happen or not
## i guess i just stopped thinking about it and
## caring i guess i just i'm focused on what
## i can do day to day and uh in our lifetime that's
## all that we can focus on cool agreed um a super
## question this is a super chat by the way if anyone
## was wondering what that looks like it looks like
## this so you can put a price on it and it means
## that will uh you'll pay for it it means you'll
## get your question answered so any updates on
## future campaigns for next year once covid is gone
## we're gonna get back to our world tour that
## we were doing i just um just started that tour
## did two cities ended it as a result covered
## so that tour will continue and then we will
## pardon me we will do two weeks of truth
## which we're really looking forward to doing
## we're going to do one damn week and
## we're going to do what was the other one
## uh we're going to do the av academy
## it's going to be a boot camp um and
## yeah that's it yeah we will do those things
## once this whole thing's over awesome cool
## um i've got another question here
## but i'll just give you a heads up
## it's a it's a it's a one of those another kind
## of accusational question all right so just gotta
## give you a heads up on it it's one that i
## forgot to cover with you actually i didn't
## have time to cover it with you but i think i
## was gonna cover it i guess we can cover it now
## it's the about the rumor that uh about the
## whole creation of av um this rumor has been
## around for a long time as far as i know i think
## i've seen you deal with it once before on another
## live or something but uh yeah if you could
## respond to this is it true that another activist
## from melbourne created the idea i've never
## this is actually new i've never had this one
## okay okay ask paul to be a violent volunteer
## for them yeah one have you well there's a
## second half of it by the way this is this as
## well this is the second half of that question