## so there you go what's that yeah this is
## a completely new thing i've never heard
## of what a wise imagination
## um yeah that's it's interesting because
## uh nah this is i've never heard this one
## before i'm wondering where this has come
## from
## and i'm wondering
## yeah i don't what's the what's the
## correct political what's the political
## correct term for chinese whispers these
## days
## oh god i don't even know i i would just
## say that but yeah you're right i think
## people would get would get upset about
## that actually no
## um i don't know okay well
## that's what this is i'm trying to use
## the correct term but uh
## trying not to crucify me guys uh yeah so
## you know i don't really know you know i
## don't really know
## what this is but we know about the
## original accusation that came
## from individuals plural in melbourne
## and uh and
## that's all documented actually it came
## out with the whole liberation is
## inclusive truth of cube
## uh video that was made about us
## um they jumped on that bandwagon
## and contribute contributed to the
## document that was
## linked in the caption of that video
## wherever it's shared you'll see the link
## and wherever you see that link you'll
## see the document and in that document
## you'll see these individuals who came
## out initially
## and made this accusation that they
## created av with us
## and that we stole it from them now this
## story
## that we're being asked of here is
## is is is claiming that it was uh
## we were volunteering
## according to this person just to close
## this off they say it's they're saying
## this is a direct claim
## from the person who claims to have had
## this conversation with you
## so it's it's uh it seems like it's um i
## don't know if you don't if you don't
## know this and it's
## it's you know it seems made up i guess
## yeah
## if it's like when someone becomes famous
## many people start coming out and
## claiming that that person is their
## cousin
## right uh and yet that's what
## it's kind of like the same thing here
## people are claiming that they created a
## v but there's no basis for any of this
## we've heard
## i've heard a couple of different uh
## people trying to claim this
## over the years but um
## these people aren't doing much
## yeah so that's what they claim to to
## activism is
## but i uh i i feel for these people if
## they really want to tear
## like they want to try to steal that from
## us
## all the hard work we've put in and all
## the
## commitment we've given to this
## organization if they want to try to
## steal that from us
## it says something about what they're
## suffering from internally
## like i'm sorry that they thought they
## need to take from us
## in that scenario because it means that
## they must be hurting
## somewhere somewhere else and not feeling
## adequate for themselves
## and i i really mean it that i feel bad
## for these people
## fair enough um funny question okay it's
## kind of funny
## um are you friends with joey carver
## strong again nope
## no yeah i thought that might be the case
## i genuinely like i didn't say this in my
## video actually but um when i made the
## video about this but i on a personal
## note you don't have to respond to this
## but
## i do hope i do hold some hope that that
## can be
## fixed between you guys that you can come
## to some kind of i don't know
## i hope that you can be friends again
## because it was you know you had a good
## thing going
## you were supporting each other it was
## good it's a shame to see it all go to
## [ __ ]
## but he did what he did and what happened
## happened you know
## yeah look i forgive him for making a
## stupid mistake he's human
## humans make stupid mistakes but for as
## long as he
## won't acknowledge his mistake there's no
## room for
## i don't i can't be friends with people
## who lack accountability it's just not a
## part of
## my quality that i hold myself to and
## what i expect from friends
## yeah that's understandable it's
## understandable but i can't yeah as many
## most people i can't help hoping that it
## can be worked out
## but it's this is kind of in his court
## isn't it the balls in his court on this
## um someone's asking a question that it's
## it's an obvious question
## uh but i'm gonna put it up anyway
## because it's a yeah you can easily just
## answer it um
## it's on the transgender topic again
## they're saying you said everyone should
## be respected we all agreed everyone
## should be respected does this mean that
## if someone hates transgender people
## should they be respected
## this is what i mean this is what i mean