## we barely need your name at the cube and
## uh and
## that's what we said regarding this whole
## thing
## yeah so if if like putting this into
## real life like if someone actually
## did uh come to a cube and uh
## let's say it was it was one of your
## organizers or you whichever
## and they said okay i when you refer to
## me
## as like you know if if they are like
## doing something and that you're talking
## about them
## like they can't hear you or whatever or
## maybe they're in the conversation
## whatever they want to be referred to as
## a she
## um because now they're a trans woman and
## and is that something that you would
## respect
## or you would tell your organizers to
## respect or would you tell them no
## only refer to them by their name like
## that's his name but if if by respect
## you mean are we going to then call them
## a man in their face in order to make a
## point
## that we reject the notion that they
## identify as a woman
## well of course we're not going to do
## that that that would be impolite
## and counterproductive for our mission on
## the streets to begin with
## which is to get on with non-human animal
## rights activism
## not get caught up in issues between
## humans human centric
## issues and the reason why i'm pointing
## out
## that i initially started with pointing
## out that
## this is clearly ideological is that we
## don't allow any other
## political ideologies to be carried out
## or political agendas to be carried out
## at the cubes
## of any kind so when we've never
## specifically targeted this
## in any way you know it's just across the
## board not welcome
## sure and what what what about in the
## case that someone doesn't actually
## believe or doesn't really agree with you
## that it's political because a lot
## of people who are become become a trans
## woman or a trans man
## they don't do it out of some political
## ideology they do it because they have
## gender dysphoria right it's a medical
## condition
## and them being referred to as a he or
## she
## um it's nothing to do with their
## politics is to do with them being
## like validated as a person right so it's
## actually really important
## i know i know there are a lot of trans
## activists out there who are making this
## very very political i understand that
## they exist
## and there are people who are not even
## trans who make it political by
## forcing others to call them a he or she
## when they've they don't have gender
## dysphoria you know what i mean i
## understand this is happening
## and i understand standing up to that but
## in the case where these people are
## genuine
## um and you know they are asking as a
## as like a you know as a courtesy to help
## them adapt to
## this new life for example would that be
## a policy of av
## to to tell people right you refer to
## them as they want to be referred to or
## is that not a policy navy and it's no
## you just you call them by name and
## that's it
## so just to clarify here because i think
## there's some things being communicated
## that
## in this interaction that might lead
## people to think that we've commented on
## trans people when we haven't even
## commented on trans people
## at all ever ever
## uh my comments were only about gender
## pronouns
## and uh gender pronouns are a completely
## different discussion
## to trans issues gender pronouns are
## used by people who don't even identify
## as trans
## so i'm not talking about trans people
## i've never talked i've never said
## anything about trans people and neither
## is a cell
## and that needs to be clarified 100 i
## think because
## i don't appreciate getting tossed into
## that category of someone who has spoken
## about trans people when i haven't said a
## single word about trans people
## uh my comments are about my skepticism
## towards gender pronouns and the use of
## gender pronouns and then being
## 50 plus gender pronouns that was my
## comment
## and uh this like i said at the cube
## there's no real need for even
## even for someone's name so if if
## this is happening this interaction is
## happening at a cube
## where someone is offended because you
## haven't used their correct gender
## pronoun
## that's what i mean by becoming political
## and someone bringing a political agenda
## into
## that space when we don't even really
## require
## your name so if that discussion is
## occurring at the cube it's likely
## because someone is choosing
## to make a rise out of it and you know to
## uh to you know
## obviously if someone is like i said
## already
## going out of their way to disrespect
## somebody like this yes we would take
## issue with that 100
## we would see that as bullying it would
## be implied and it would be
## bullying to say no i don't
## not only do i not believe what you
## believe but your belief is stupid
## that's bullying right so of course we
## don't condone that