## just i guess what i'm trying to say is
## like assume
## good intentions stop assuming bad
## intentions of people
## um whoever you're talking to really like
## give them a chance to prove themselves
## to be
## you know good don't don't look for bad
## look for good and assume they want
## the best i think is it's really
## important we'll have one more question
## and then we'll close off it's it's a
## it's a nice question i think um do the
## where's the money go people have any
## idea how much
## unpaid work that you guys have put into
## animal rights
## do you think thank you generally
## that's a refreshing perspective
## to hear and not just for our case
## and uh it's not just refreshing for
## for us to hear for you know when i think
## about us and that and the criticisms
## that we get
## it's also refreshing to hear that any
## other
## activist on behalf of any other activist
## that gets similar criticisms like this
## you know i don't think that animal
## rights activists
## are um getting
## the opportunity given to them all the
## respects given to them that they deserve
## in terms of acquiring financial security
## whilst
## being an animal rights activist
## full-time
## if there's any question about motives
## then you just have to look at
## you know like this person has graciously
## pointed out and i think i think it's
## refreshing because it's
## it's the kind of perspective that really
## people should have
## is looking more deeply at the work that
## people do
## and that doesn't lie and if it is a
## question about motives
## then yeah look at all the work we've
## done when we had no money towards any of
## this and we put all of our own personal
## money towards everything
## it's when we went broke
## putting all of our money into a b from
## the beginning and we will continue to do
## that
## to the very end for the for the simple
## fact
## that it's about the mission it's about
## what
## the organization is intended for and uh
## well you know that's the thing i yeah i
## don't know
## what else to say about this i guess you
## want to answer that
## yes i just want animal rights activists
## to feel
## that it's a very viable option for them
## to come into animal rights as an
## activist to be an activist full-time
## part-time and to have financial security
## and not to
## expect that they're going to
## be walking on on hot coal
## just because they they do want financial
## security while being
## by you know while being an animal rights
## activists i know that we
## probably entertain on this stream and
## probably entertain
## the accusations maybe too much i don't
## know i'll walk
## back and i'll judge later but uh
## that's why i think it's important to
## just know that you know
## we need to hold a certain priesthood and
## set a certain tone for animal rights
## activists
## in this movement who may be wanting to
## come into this movie maybe they want to
## come into this movement and become an
## activist
## or maybe they're maybe you're already an
## activist and
## you know i want them to understand that
## there's nothing wrong
## with fighting for the animals whilst
## also acquiring financial security as
## long as your motive is not financial
## to begin with yeah
## absolutely and we'll wrap it up there
## i'll just say that um
## i hope that you said we gave too much
## attention to some of these topics and i
## would be you know likely to agree but um
## tended to agree but i think what i was
## trying to achieve here is to have this
## be
## in my opinion like the last the last
## time i'm gonna talk about any of this
## anyway and i hope the last time you also
## talk about it
## because this is going to go up on my
## channel now and it's going to have
## sectors
## marked for every single topic so that
## any time anything does come up about
## this
## and and you know someone's saying asking
## you hey what do i say to this
## you can literally say to them go and
## find you know the topic that they're
## talking about
## copy paste and if they don't want to
## watch the video well [ __ ] them then
## you know like they they want to keep
## making their quesations fine but if they
## want to know the truth well we've
## answered it it's right here
## that was the goal for this so you're
## right we did give it too much attention
## but that's because this was the goal
## i don't think most of these accusations
## deserved even
## five seconds of time but i i do
## i do i do think it's important to have
## it somewhere so that it's dealt with
## for good you know in my opinion and
## that's kind of what i wanted to achieve
## today and i hope we've achieved that
## um thank you both for coming here and
## doing this you didn't have to do it and
## i think people overlook that as well you
## you you don't owe anyone anything
## and you did not have to sit here and
## answer these questions and they weren't
## nice questions they were shitty
## questions
## um i know what it feels like to be
## attacked i know what it feels like to be
## called these things
## and i know how horrible it feels when