## said they will test again if they feel
## that they
## they say need to but let's be honest we
## don't need that burger right
## um so they say they would do it again
## and some people are saying because of
## that the av
## is not abolitionist and that's why they
## don't want to work with av anymore
## how do you what do you think of that
## well i just think that
## to be consistent um
## exactly what you said if we are
## consuming products that at one time
## in the past they were tested or an
## ingredient was tested
## we also use many products that um
## again were either tested or they are
## produced by a company that is not vegan
## and you know like we can just keep going
## down this rabbit hole but
## ultimately to be consistent with the
## values that we have
## i think it's okay to say that if you're
## vegan and you eat the impossible burger
## you're not suddenly not vegan that's
## literally what i was saying i wasn't
## promoting it necessarily but i was
## saying
## um the impossible burger is as vegan
## as the beyond burger because one of the
## things that i don't think i mentioned in
## that video
## and i think it's something that i
## actually learned after doing that video
## was that
## when they were working on the beyond
## burger
## they were buying burgers made of cow
## flesh
## and they were testing them or they were
## maybe
## just having a tasting session or
## whatever to get the texture or the
## flavors right so
## i don't see any difference between the
## two um in one scenario cows are being
## murdered for the burgers and in the
## other scenario mice are being murdered
## because they're being tested on so
## i just see them exactly the same they're
## just different animals that are being
## used in the process but
## i just think to be consistent you either
## have to say
## i don't use anything that was ever
## tested or
## is ever coming from a company that uses
## animals or uses animal testing
## or you're just going to have to accept
## that we do live in a non-vegan world and
## as much as possible yes sure you can
## avoid it but
## i just don't see the difference between
## like i said that
## product and other products that we're
## using um like to beyond virgo which
## nobody has ever taken an issue with i
## haven't seen it
## and if i can just add to this argument
## that we as an organization have made
## essentially
## regarding this topic uh
## the only arguments i've ever heard from
## those who are
## trying to damn us
## by uh saying that we're not like we're
## not we're not abolitionists because we
## hold this position
## the only argument i see coming from
## these people
## is an argument for how impossible foods
## as a company is not vegan
## to which we totally agree with the
## company is not vegan
## the product itself however is vegan
## and that's why sales made the
## distinction
## between this and any other company that
## sells a vegan product
## a non-vegan company selling a vegan
## product has always
## been a product that vegans
## consume and are still considered to be
## vegan when they consume it
## uh and we don't you know when you said
## we don't we don't need the impossible
## burger that the same could be said for
## every other product
## that exists on the shelf so where do you
## draw the line
## and how do we make veganism practical
## for people
## by saying you can only support vegan
## companies
## if you're only supporting vegan
## companies in this
## modern world we live in i don't think
## veganism is possible
## that's it's actually i think an
## irresponsible message
## if we care about animal liberation
## yeah so there's two points i'd like to
## push on a little bit further with this
## um
## one of them being that what do you think
## about
## this is this these are this is internal
## okay i'm with you and i think that i
## just want to put this point away
## actually
## that this will not in my opinion what we
## are discussing here is the message we
## put out to the public
## because i don't believe that that's it's
## it's going to be in any way
## uh beneficial for us to slam the
## impossible burger
## to the non-vegan public right that
## doesn't make any sense um
## whatever they tested it on animals yeah
## it's [ __ ]
## but um it's making tracks with
## non-vegans and it's it's
## i don't know it's it's i feel like it's
## more of an internal thing that
## that we discuss in this like as part of
## the animal rights movement
## should this be an accepted thing like
## into the movement or into veganism
## should this burger be accepted should
## these products be accepted i feel like
## that's what we're discussing more than
## a public statement um and that being
## said
## so a company like i mean that's where i
## stand on it anyway that's why i don't
## really
## i don't want to get into like should we
## talk about it you know pushing it to the
## public or not i don't really think
## advertising vegan consumerism is i don't
## really agree with that anyway i'm not
## posting about subways vegan option or
## mcdonald's vegan options