## know manager leader organizer of that group and
## if you don't like it then that's absolutely fine
## you either continue volunteering or you create
## your own thing and do it your way it's basically
## is that am i is that what you're saying basically
## what yeah because like of course we always welcome
## feedback but welcoming feedback doesn't mean we're
## going to take it on board we're going to discuss
## it between us too and then the team that we have
## and then we might take it on board or we may not
## but to expect that every single feedback is just
## going to be accepted and we're going to implement
## that idea whatever it might be i think that's very
## unrealistic yeah it will be very chaotic so yes if
## somebody doesn't like the fact that you know their
## feedback wasn't accepted then i think if they feel
## like they're not aligned with the organization
## then they should just do their own thing i mean
## that just makes sense to me it's just very common
## yeah and you know i think you clarified but just
## to make sure just to make sure that no one is
## confused by what we're saying here we're not
## saying you know if you if you have any input you
## know you have any feedback you have any criticism
## as a represent as a representative of
## ab whether you're an organizer volunteer
## we're not saying that we're just going to
## say [ __ ] you and go do your own thing
## that's not how we operate we and like to think
## that we've only ever enacted ideas that have come
## from either my brain or a cell's brain is insane
## we've always taken on feedback from others
## and taken it into account and i think the
## last thing i want people to consider here is
## where would av be today like really think
## about where a baby would be today if we
## weren't operating the way that we are if we
## ran a system where we had like a board of um
## you know board of directors
## where we only had a vote
## into what was and we only had two votes of many
## into what was being decided on i mean i think it's
## i i think it's clear that av wouldn't be clear
## about the message and i don't think that we would
## be where we are today that leads on to another
## point quite nicely actually because i think what
## i feel like you're hinting at here is that that
## if you didn't maintain control you feel
## that av would go down the same road as
## pretty much every other ar organization
## has gone down where they are bringing in
## uh human issues um human rights issues and
## basically kind of i guess i guess if you could put
## in a way that they're moving with the times rather
## than staying true to what they started for if
## that makes sense um and some people would say that
## that is a positive thing you know to move with the
## times because let's be honest the you know the the
## times are very much changing and you know a lot of
## human rights issues have very much been thrown to
## the front and that's not necessarily a bad thing
## um but you could argue that ar organizations
## also taking those fights on board is some
## some and i guess you would argue that is a bad
## thing and that brings me to another question that
## has been asked or let's say a topic that has been
## brought up uh the topic of anti-intersectionality
## and uh and you know what this means with with av
## what intersect or not intersectionality i don't
## think that's even the correct thing to talk to
## to say because i don't intersectionality itself
## i'm sure we all if there's anybody in this in
## this chat or even you guys that say disagrees
## with the concept of it i would just say you're
## disagreeing with facts right if the fact is that
## intersexuality as it was originally coined
## it's it's factual it's like you know someone
## who's female or black will experience the world
## differently to someone who's male and white or
## someone who's female and white or someone who's
## you know transgender and black or transgender
## everyone experiences the world differently and has
## different challenges right that's what it means
## that's literally what it means not what vegans
## have made it that's [ __ ] so we all will agree
## that that's what it means i'm sure and i you
## know i guess no one really would would say it
## would argue against that it's just logic it's just
## factual but let's say uh the they call themselves
## consistent anti-oppression crowd let's say and and
## this is something that you have get like more than
## once you've stood out stood up against and you've
## said said some things about you know the animals
## first um approach non-humans first approach um
## and this has been widely criticized and a lot
## of people have even you know people make videos
## about this they are constantly attacking you guys
## for this they are people um saying they won't they
## won't go to av events because of this um so yeah