## clarify yeah no no maybe that
## was framed like i was like being
## defensive
## but i'm asking a genuine question
## because my next thing i was going to say
## because i say that to say this
## like that's how much more
## urgent it is for us to maintain a focus
## on using those platforms for that reason
## so it's not you know okay
## yeah totally i i don't i don't see
## it as a a negative the reason i got into
## this this discussion now is because i
## i personally i i see some benefit in
## that for myself personally that's why i
## make some of the videos i make where i
## talk about
## vegans doing good work also for people i
## see some benefit in it and and that's my
## choice
## but that doesn't by default mean that
## your choice is wrong
## and i think this is um it's very
## important for anyone that watched this
## section and thinks
## oh but you know but some people are
## going to agree with you and they'll be
## like no keep keep the people off
## right i just just keep keep it really
## really focused and some people are going
## to agree with me and say well
## there's no harm in doing this and maybe
## it will help and that's totally fine to
## have different opinions
## um it doesn't mean one of us is wrong
## and deserves to be cancelled and the
## others
## are you know deserve to be celebrated
## it's just you align with who you align
## with and if you're aligned with paul and
## asylum this then you
## great keep you do that for your page and
## if you align with me then great you do
## what i said and if you don't align with
## either of us then i don't know alive
## with someone else and do
## do that then it's it's not um this isn't
## a case of being right or wrong i just
## wanted to see what you thought about it
## on this specific example the specific
## topic
## okay cool um let's let's uh
## all right let's go to a more direct
## thing then because i've got a few like
## let's say more direct accusations direct
## uh rumors
## and um we talked about humans quite a
## lot now
## and actually um it's kind of shitty that
## i bring the co-founders of anonymous for
## the voiceless on and we just talk about
## people
## but um that's what we came here for uh
## maybe we can do another live stream
## where we actually get into the
## you know into animal rights and activism
## and really you know go for that i think
## that would be nice to do
## um to kind of balance having to talk
## about this
## for such a long time but um
## these uh main accusations we've had and
## this also comes in with the
## intersectionality and also comes in with
## the things you just discussed about your
## uh your policies
## um the number one that came up multiple
## times was
## accusations of transphobia and pronouns
## and
## you've dealt with this uh obviously paul
## you've dealt with this personally and
## you've
## spoken about this in other places but we
## are going to talk about it a bit here
## and some specific
## questions um somebody's asked the
## question
## uh well i'll go for like the longer one
## actually there's a few questions but
## this one's actually quite a well
## written one so they said and they left
## av this individual because
## um because apparently av was focusing on
## they said focusing on the animals
## instead of encouraging respect between
## activists
## uh they said that there was a situation
## where you guys decided to call people by
## birth names
## rather than calling people by their
## preferred pronouns and for them
## this was extremely offensive and wrong
## um and the discussion around the pronoun
## politics or what you called uh
## i think you call it something like uh
## identity politics
## um they found this to be a lot of people
## i guess found this to be
## controversial or controversial enough
## for them to leave av
## or at least not go to cubes anymore so
## i guess the question is um why
## why why is that why is this decision
## been made to
## not use people's pronouns and use their
## first names instead
## even if they want to be referred to by a
## pronoun
## i guess i'll answer because there's our
## main interaction yeah
## uh gender pronouns are clearly
## ideological
## and uh we don't
## so you're just specifically asking about
## the cubes
## like in nab i guess yeah let's keep it
## focused on like cubes av
## yeah yeah so
## i've never like
## personally being asked to refer to
## someone as
## a particular like
## name and uh
## where where i've refused to call them
## that name that's never happened
## you know it's obviously the polite thing
## to do
## to use the requested name of someone
## but at cubes we don't even really need
## your name
## so it makes no sense for us to apply a
## protocol
## regarding one's gender
## so we don't even have a protocol
## regarding gender at all
## because it's not required it's