## but at the same time forcing others to believe
## what you believe at the cube is not welcome
## that's not what we're there for right everybody
## has a different belief system when it comes
## to this topic and people are entitled
## to have different opinions about this
## and that's it's not a time and a space at a cube
## of truth to be fighting each other to be engaging
## in this kind of discord when it's human-centric
## and we are supposed to be there for non-human
## animals we should be respecting each other
## to have the right to have a different opinion
## and to just get on with the one thing we're
## supposed to be on the same page about which is
## non-human animal rights deserve to have this three
## or four hours dedicated to them on the streets
## yeah i guess i guess to kind of close this
## off or i hope we can close it off as if
## so if if uh we have i mean obviously there
## are there are obviously trans activists right
## i'm focusing on trans here because i understand
## what you're saying about gender pronouns in that
## if somebody has chosen a pronoun because it's
## whatever it's something they want to identify as
## i understand why there's some some skepticism here
## because it's kind of like all right that's fine
## you'll go ahead and do that and people can
## respect that but if if they forget or if they
## i don't know if they don't want to and there's
## no real logic behind the reason that the view
## identifying is that i can understand why
## someone you know not being into that but
## where i'm specifically focusing on here and
## and i'm focusing on it because it is it is
## medical it is it is it is a psychological
## thing it is not something that's like
## opinion is that you know gender dysphoria
## exists like trans people exist we have to
## time but now it's becoming more acceptable to
## discuss it right so you see a lot more people
## who are coming out this way whereas in the past
## they wouldn't have done they would have hidden
## it because they were embarrassed or ashamed and
## they just go through their whole life with this
## situation you know with this this problem nowadays
## uh people are being encouraged to speak up about
## it and you know go public and get the operation
## and and re-identify themselves so that they're
## more they are who they are right what i'm trying
## to get here is that does does av have like uh
## something in place that is also accommodating that
## so that so that if somebody does come to a cube as
## a trans person um and they want to be identified
## as a he um or she or they if they're not sure um
## and somebody is is you know if they get it wrong
## by accident okay i get that that's something that
## you know it shouldn't if it's a complaint you
## just say okay hey please you know don't don't
## get it wrong by accident in the future like do us
## a favor but if if they're choosing to get it wrong
## if they're like actually saying no i don't accept
## that are you saying that yeah bullying yeah that
## could that could be bullying yeah um but also i
## kind of i'm kind of trying to understand where
## the line's drawn between well that's your
## ideology so tough [ __ ] versus well okay no
## this is something that this is you this is who
## you are and look this person needs to respect
## that or or they're the one that'll be kicked
## out like where are you where are you drawing
## the line between the ideology versus the bullying
## if you understand what i'm saying because maybe
## an organizer says well i don't need to respect
## that because i don't agree where's the line drawn
## the line is simply drawn at if the interaction
## at the cube requires your gender then okay we'll
## use whatever gender you choose us to use however
## whatever name because in that case they can also
## use the name if the organizer or the volunteer
## feels uncomfortable or they don't align with the
## same ideologies they don't have to use the pronoun
## they can just refer to them with their chosen name
## yeah that's what i was going to say is that the
## interactions that you don't actually require
## don't actually require the gender so that's what i
## was saying is that if i'm trying to be charitable
## and open-minded here by saying if there is
## a circumstance of the cube that requires the
## gender and the interaction to be successful in
## the communication sure no not using that would
## be rude it would be bullying and when there's
## no case at a cube of truth never within ab
## where this has happened where we've bullied
## people and said [ __ ] your beliefs that's
## never happened it's just ridiculous to even
## suggest that that has happened but you know
## but it's not required that's what we're saying
## it's not required it's it's yeah this this notion
## that it is required is a new notion that's being
## brought into a b it's never been required and um i
## i think i know something that was brought up a
## while ago was um people are suggesting that at the
## start of the cube because we do a briefing right
## when everyone's there getting ready to do the cube
## somebody or maybe a few people suggested that
## we do this like we go around and get people to
## introduce themselves and choose their preferred
## like announce their preferred pronoun and this
## is something that brought was brought up to us
## and that was our response because something like