## uh like if hitler shows up to the cube should
## he be respected like if he just is resurrected
## from from the earth uh comes back to life
## and shows up to keep will he be respected
## uh uh do i have to answer that oh we said everyone
## should be respected we said we meant the person
## who chooses a different pronoun or name as well as
## the person who might disagree with that ideology
## oppressed that's what we meant we didn't say
## the bully or the oppressor so oppression is
## not respected i thought that yeah like because we
## led into that point with saying that actually and
## so yeah no totally totally i i understand this is
## i think i watched a uh this thing with uh bilbao
## you know the comedian bilbao he he he was talking
## about new ones as well do you know the ginger guy
## and speaks really quickly i don't know if you know
## what i'm talking about yeah cool so he he talked
## about nuance as well he was saying that like
## everything i say is twisted and he said something
## like he said he was talking about consent right
## and i'm i'm gonna by the way for anyone that's
## looking for something to get me on here this is
## bill burr's words not my words all right don't
## [ __ ] start here um but basically he said like
## today's world like how how do you even work right
## so he said like it's all about consent and there's
## you're at risk all the way always and he said how
## do you have it rough now like if a girl wants it
## rough how do you do that because you know how does
## it work right and this guy in the crowd shouted
## you need to get consent first and he was like
## this is why you can't make jokes anymore he was
## like this [ __ ] [ __ ] thinks that i'm saying
## that i was not going to get consent i never said
## that he was like when did i say that why would you
## assume that that's what i meant right and he was
## like it's [ __ ] ridiculous you assumed the worst
## of me and he called this guy an idiot and a [
## __ ] and like really slammed him for shouting
## that because it's like i'm not a monster dude
## like i'm making a joke about rough sex i'm not
## making a joke about not getting consent are
## you insane there's a very big difference and
## this is i'm saying it because he commented on it
## and it's kind of what's just happened here it's
## like you guys said respect everyone and someone
## understood that as respect transphobic people
## it's like no that's not what i said no one said
## that jesus do you think i would have let that fly
## in the conversation do you really think i am that
## morally corrupt that i would just let someone say
## that on my channel and just not question wait
## a minute you've just said you want to respect
## transphobes it's like no i would never let that
## go even if i had someone like some monster on
## the channel i would never i wouldn't let
## that go but that's not the case you know
## anyway i'm just i've just got off the handle a
## bit there but we're at the end anyway it's fine
## it's just as silly as having to say oh with the
## exception of intersex when you're saying there's
## two sexes like why should we even have to say that
## it's an anomaly of course that's an exception to
## the rule and like you know you don't need to
## say certain things i guess if you are reading
## between the lines and you are attuned to nuance
## and you don't just see things through this uh
## cancel culture lens where you know is it what what
## billboard said is these days you say something and
## what you say goes into someone's brain and then
## it gets cut with all of the things that they're
## conditioned with and you know and then it comes
## out of their brain they spit it out after that
## you know according to what they perceive it to be
## and it's usually completely different to what you
## said and uh it's the same thing here it shouldn't
## that shouldn't that's something that shouldn't in
## my opinion shouldn't need to be clarified you
## should assume the best in people not the worst
## i i don't understand what you what you have done
## or even what i have done because i'm involved
## in this that question was for all of us right
## because i they're assuming that you have said
## that and i have i have been like yeah great cool
## like what did i do to deserve that what did you
## do to deserve that assumption like i i don't think
## any of us has done anything particularly you know
## that horrible to think that any of us would like
## believe that or let it go it's such a strange
## and i think the person's saying it innocently
## enough i don't think they're trying to attack
## but at the same time it's like dude be reasonable
## here come on it's a fair enough question um but i
## mean i i don't know is it fair enough actually am
## i trying to be nice i don't think it's fair enough
## at all in my opinion i think it's something that
## if you watched the whole conversation and listened
## without assuming the worst in all three of us you
## would come to the conclusion that that that's not
## what was being said like that you're not going
## to respect a bigger you're not going to respect
## someone who hates trans people like what the [
## __ ] like what kind of rational person would ever
## have irrational hatred or acceptance of irrational
## hatred like it's not it's not rational to accept
## that and we've i don't believe we've been acting
## irrationally in this conversation so i just i