## supportive of individuals within
## our network who are doing that uh
## i don't see that as activism though i don't see
## that as like fighting a human rights cause of
## some kind no i guess not but i guess it would be
## raising awareness that homeless people need food
## i know people know that or maybe inspiring other
## vegans to go out and outreach homeless people and
## give them food i don't know it's an idea it's
## just it's just an idea as is what i mean it's
## it's something that uh like i don't know if it
## even would count as intersectionality in that
## case but for example the lebanon example would
## because they they have the corrupt government
## they are they're oppressing their people um making
## someone making a post or making a video on that
## where you're saying hey look at what these
## awesome vegans are doing they're fighting a
## corrupt government and they're also saving animals
## and they're getting people food that that would be
## a better example of of how to raise awareness of
## two oppressions um in one without either of them
## losing anything if that makes sense because
## it's not like we're just talking about
## you know lebanon we're talking about vegan and
## activists in lebanon so like then it becomes
## something that encompasses all of it you
## know but i mean i i'm a bit confused because
## i don't see how it was like an animal rights
## uh thing that they did they're just vegans
## people who don't abuse and torture animals
## animal rights activists who went and did
## a deed for humans and that deed was a human rights
## good that they did and when they were doing that
## that act that deed had nothing to do with the
## animals really it was just about i think david was
## saying that they were kind of outreaching people
## when they were giving them the food were they
## yeah i believe they were i don't know
## this for sure but i believe they were
## sending out like leaflets and stuff with the
## with the bags and also they were rescuing animals
## too they were actually rescuing animals
## off the street and getting them treated
## they were raising money for that too so they
## were doing a few yeah it was like uh it was
## yeah they were doing a few a few different things
## to try and help the animals and also the people
## yeah i didn't know the full extent of the campaign
## that they carried out over there uh i all i know
## is at the time i reached out and you know i
## checked in with them and i was just wanting to
## know if they were okay during the whole blast but
## i forgive my ignorance to those who were carrying
## out that awesome campaign because it looked very
## helpful i was just confused on how it was tied
## into animal rights i just thought they were doing
## a deed a good deed for humans at in that moment
## i didn't see how maybe they were maybe they were
## maybe they were maybe maybe they were only doing
## that some of them um but i know for sure some
## of them were also rescuing the animals i guess
## i mean with a more concrete example if let's
## imagine there is a concrete example of this
## where they're actually doing that they're actually
## advocating for animal rights whilst simultaneously
## helping humans um i guess the question is like
## would would that be something av would consider to
## post about if it came up or or is is there some a
## reason not to that's what i'm trying to understand
## like hosting this you're asking specifically
## about posting about it on social media
## our platforms are for animal rights for non-human
## animal rights so that's our general response to
## that but we do carry out what you're saying we
## do take the opportunity to how did you want it
## to benefit humans while benefiting the
## animals you know in those moments when we see
## any form of oppression or discrimination
## occurring within our organization
## we stamp it out with the quickness and we have
## a process that we go through to rid it from the
## organization in those moments we're taking
## action that benefits humans and the animals
## we're just not posting about it i guess because
## our platforms and network is for non-human animals
## okay i understand i understand so it's kind of
## like um yeah so your base your base kind of um
## i don't know what to put it here your
## let's say default your your focus your
## baseline i keep using that word is is that you
## know the the account is for non-humans and that
## that's kind of the be that's it basically that
## that's how it's going to be like social media
## and also the cubes it that that's where it's
## going to stay and that that's your core kind
## of value basically that's what you're saying here
## right yeah like again going back to the numbers
## thing you know three trillion animals every year
## if you think about the amount of victims that are
## involved in this injustice you know how many more
## times uh more urgent would you say in terms of the
## numbers this injustice is than other injustices
## on the planet how many more times more urgent
## would you say totally it's like it's not a it's
## not a criticism for me i'm actually just trying
## to uh you know clarify yeah no no maybe that was
## framed like i was like being defensive but i'm