## talking about vegetarianism the longer
## we cuddle vegetarianism
## the longer it will take for animal
## rights to be taken seriously in the
## public eye
## i think i can't remember which one of
## you said it or if it actually was one of
## you but
## um there was a quote that vegetarians
## are contributing to one less form of
## animal abuse than a meat-eater
## uh they contribute to every other form
## of animal abuse it's just not
## just not meat just not flesh and that
## that was quite for me that was very
## powerful and i feel like that
## that was that was a quote that was a
## sentence that really brought it home to
## me that actually yeah
## we we we should be targeting
## vegetarianism
## as you know just the same as we would
## target anyone else you know who's a
## non-vegan because it's just it's just
## there's only one
## between them even more yeah even more
## because
## non-vegans don't say you don't need to
## talk to me unknown
## they know that they need that's the
## correct conversation to have with them
## they know that they're culpable
## right it's the same as someone who's
## non-vegan who doesn't support animal
## testing they never buy cosmetics
## that are tested on on animals i mean
## they don't support one form of animal
## injustice yeah there are many non-vegans
## they don't claim that claim to be exempt
## from the message regarding meat dairy
## and eggs
## vegetarians do claim to be exempt from
## hearing that
## yeah it's just very counterproductive to
## separate
## like vegetarians and the rest of
## non-vegans
## because i see that a lot from vegans and
## animal rights activists they think that
## they should get a different treatment
## but really vegetarians are just
## non-vegan so let's not separate them
## the reason why we focus on it is because
## we want to change their mentality it's
## not because there is any difference you
## know we're not
## like singling them out it's the same
## it's just non-vegans
## it's just clarifying the message yeah on
## behalf of the animals
## okay perfect yeah i yeah this for me was
## an easy topic because i'm
## i also uh focus on vegetarians for the
## same reasons
## um i think i think it's something our
## movement really needs to
## needs to shape people need to shake
## their head on this and just realize that
## these vegetarians they're not helping us
## they're not our allies
## um understanding veganism doesn't help
## anyone like oh i understand you or i'm
## supportive of you i'm a vegetarian
## it doesn't mean [ __ ] and i think the
## more we start to
## realize that the better and the easier
## things are going to be in the long term
## um so a style actually i have a specific
## topic for you and this was this was
## actually only brought up yesterday
## um so that's why i don't know if you got
## chance to
## um yeah i'll i'll i'll explain it now so
## basically the impossible burger
## all right uh you did your video when
## when was it earlier this year i don't
## know if you've thought about it since
## then
## but um i think it's been like two years
## now
## is it two years wow okay i don't know i
## watched it only recently anyway so i
## don't know if you've had chance to
## catch up on on that and or if you still
## think the same
## but um somebody brought this up and
## they're very passionate about it and
## they wanted to
## uh discuss this um apparently according
## to them again don't know if this is true
## or not
## a lot of people left or at least stopped
## going to cubes or
## even some chapters maybe even closed
## over
## a disagreement about the impossible
## burger and the video that you made
## i watched the video obviously i watched
## the video i i only watched it yesterday
## so it's fresh in my mind
## um and your position's on the impossible
## burger and i you know
## went through it um what what how do you
## respond to people who who have this
## like they don't believe that av is
## abolitionist because of
## you being the founder holding the view
## that you hold that
## uh an impossible burger um is
## it's it's vegan because they tested on
## animals um
## i'll i'll explain the video if you want
## really quickly for anyone that's
## watching real quick i watched it
## yesterday so it's really
## fresh in the video asal basically makes
## the position makes the claim i don't
## know takes the position that
## practically every single e number and
## additive has been tested on animals at
## one point
## so pretty much every vegan product you
## would buy has
## has something in it that has been tested
## on animals but not by the company that
## you're buying it from
## uh the impossible burger and possible
## foods did the testing themselves
## and but the product now that's in the
## store technically hasn't been tested on
## it's the product that the one thing that
## was in it was previously tested
## so therefore it's in the same category
## as another item that you would buy
## um they're both been tested at some
## point
## um and if you take issue with the
## impossible burger
## then how long does it have to be before
## we don't take issue with it anymore and
## it becomes in the same category as the
## other products
## that have were once tested on animals
## that's the position that a cell takes
## so if anyone's got a question about that
## either super chat it or save it for
## later
## but yeah how do you how would you
## respond to someone now who says right
## that that makes av non-abolitionist
## because av
## is supporting a product that was tested
## on animals and they take the position
## that because impossible foods did the
## testing
## and they have not actually said they
## wouldn't test the gain so impossible