## been communicated better um and that's why before
## we removed it we actually went in and edited the
## post a little bit so we changed the wording
## in certain parts um so that there was more
## empathy or you know it didn't come across as
## insensitive like you said but absolutely no
## it wasn't yes so i think i think that's that's a
## a wider issue really isn't it insensitivity versus
## uh versus racism or or whatever ism you want to
## attach it's uh it's not bigoted to be insensitive
## um it's some people are i don't know harsher than
## others and i think um on a personal level i think
## i think that's where a lot of the criticisms and
## accusations come from with av i don't think it's
## uh i think it is that our movement is quite a
## sensitive movement with very sensitive people and
## av isn't isn't very sensitive and that's that's
## not i don't mean that as a criticism at all i mean
## that as in some people don't like that and that's
## that's you know that's where we get a lot of
## a lot of people who come up and speak up about
## it whereas if you look at an organization like
## save for example they're the complete opposite
## side they're extremely sensitive and so they
## attract a lot of people who are uh you know also
## extremely sensitive which happens to be the vast
## majority of of the animal rights movement and the
## vegan movement people tend to be very sensitive
## in these groups so you know i can see i can see
## where the accusations come flying in from but um
## i think if they were accusing you of insensitivity
## and and being too mean i think that would
## probably be not as nowhere near as harmful as
## throwing the word racist at every turn you know
## that's my observation anyway that's
## what i'm observing from the outside
## and this kind of track this this continues
## really with the social media people have
## been upset by your social media quite a lot and i
## know some of these examples are going to be very
## easy to discuss but we'll start off with the most
## difficult one just to uh kick it off with this um
## i want to discuss the whole uh the whole hitler
## thing and george because a few people asked me
## about this they asked me about george they asked
## me about this post this this uh which obviously
## i know you removed it um but they kind of
## want to know how it got to the point where
## someone in the organization would think about
## making a post a comment like that and kind of
## what you guys think about it so if again for those
## who don't know there was the um there was a post
## made i believe it was it was avs page as well
## wasn't it on facebook it was a comment um where
## the comment was talking about hitler and it was
## comparing hitler and the it was saying basically
## out of context here by the way completely out
## of context and i've not got the screenshot so
## i'm not going to put it up but out of context
## it was making a comparison and saying that the
## holocaust that hitler did had more justification
## than the holocaust of the animals i'm paraphrasing
## here it was put into a better context than
## that but that's that was the takeaway message
## that it was it had more justification because a
## book was written about it practically or have i
## missed a big point there but either way that
## seemed to be the takeaway point from it um
## out of context and that was obviously posted by i
## believe george in the in the organization on as av
## so like what happened with this have i got
## that wrong have people got that wrong and yeah
## he's not saying that he wasn't saying
## like legitimate justifications were
## were afoot in those cases he was saying that more
## reasons were provided by hitler and his regime
## to the public then then the re then then what
## non-vegans offer to the public regarding the
## injustice that they're involved in that's what he
## was saying but the way that he said it lacked eq
## you got to have iq george is a smart guy but you
## got to have eq2 you got to read the room and not
## be an idiot about how you communicate emotionally
## uh so that's the thing it wasn't clear enough
## the communication we identified as something
## that needs to be improved and that's why we
## addressed the whole blm post to begin with uh the
## way that we did it was about the communication
## and we still feel justified in
## addressing what we addressed
## and we will continue to do so but um i think
## you know sometimes yeah the issue there was um
## sometimes there is bias that's brought into
## the work that people are doing within ab
## they bring their own biases whether they're
## political or otherwise in the way they communicate
## and people need to remember if they're working
## with av they're representing ap just like
## with any other org or group that they're
## working with and when you're representing us
## we don't want that and you know he also
## did admit to doing this himself um so