## like the major donations coming in um so the
## biggest part of it would obviously be the payments
## to the team members so including myself paul
## and um at some point we had just over 30 people
## working with av so you can imagine how much that
## would cost roughly and then now we've got i think
## i don't know actually how many people we've got
## like around 20 people working with us including
## us too so the the bulk of it is going towards
## payments so that those people can continue to
## work for av and then the second biggest um thing
## has always been the av fund which is something
## that we started um and we would dedicate a certain
## amount of money to go towards chapters that were
## um you know active chapters that needed some help
## getting their equipment so that was always like
## the second um biggest expense for us and then yeah
## the rest of it is just you know if if people look
## into what costs are involved in terms of you know
## all the admin stuff all the programs that you need
## the software's the subscriptions and then all
## the big campaigns that we were doing as well so
## okay and with the staff they were 30 were they
## all full-time 30 staff um no we had so we um
## we have people that work with us as
## contractors so av doesn't have like staff
## necessarily but um everyone's like an independent
## contractor that comes in and they can do
## um part-time or full-time and um i think i would
## say maybe it's half-half half of the people that
## work with us are full-time half are part-time
## um or just come in as volunteers even sometimes
## they they do some work casually yeah cool okay
## cause i'm just trying to like put a number on it
## i think for anyone who maybe is not following um
## it's like 30 staff if you had 30 staff that were
## only working let's say like not full-time hours
## late so they're working part-time hours right
## so let's imagine it's 30 staff working 20
## hours a week so we'll go like we'll go low
## right we'll pitch low here 30 staff working
## 20 hours a week and let's imagine that the
## i'm going to work in yearly salaries here
## like base yearly salary in euros for example
## the absolute minimum you could earn a year to
## survive in a place like i don't know let's pick
## a cheap let's baseline everything low let's go low
## on everything the minimum you could earn in a year
## in somewhere like spain for example
## would be like because that's where i know
## it's like 16 000 euros a year it's the absolute
## minimum and that's really pushing it like it's
## really difficult and that would be a full-time
## salary so that's like that's half that 8 000
## a year and let's imagine that's 30 staff that's
## 240 000 euros a year that's a that's pitching low
## that's if you have no full-time staff that's
## if all of your staff are only working like
## like half-time hours let's imagine right so
## just to put that into perspective for anyone
## who's wondering how much that would be so like it
## could it could be anywhere upwards from 240 000
## euros a year which would be like i don't know 300
## 000 us dollars maybe something like that so that
## is that is a huge chunk yeah and i think uh when
## i when i first watched the video and i heard that
## and i worked it out myself at that time and i
## was like yeah that's actually a chunk of money
## that i don't think many people understand right
## um it doesn't it doesn't sound like a lot but
## when you actually calculated it is quite a lot so
## um the next thing then you talked about the the av
## uh fund the for the for the chapters
## where has it come from then that that
## does this apparently this is a rumor okay there's
## no i don't have evidence of this and i'm sure
## there isn't evidence of this uh maybe there's one
## or two organizers who have caused this problem
## but where is it coming from that the chapters are
## not getting the funding where has that started do
## you know where that came from or do you know
## what's going what what is actually behind it
## like are they getting the funding i'm sorry to ask
## the question but it came it came up a lot again
## no i think it's the same thing as everything
## else like somebody just started this rumor
## that av keeps the money or specifically paul and
## assad keep the money to themselves and they don't
## send any money to the chapters i think it's just
## again we don't even know where this came from but
## if people were really interested this is one
## thing that can be easily tracked we have a
## full list of everyone who ever received the fund
## how much they received it what they spent it on
## and um because everyone who receives the fund they
## were supposed to send us the invoices so it's like
## we have all the records and um i guess the only
## thing is that we weren't um doing it in a way
## that just as as soon as you become an organizer
## you can receive two thousand dollars or something