## it takes these people are supposed to care about
## these injustices when they're literally spinning
## in the faces of the victims that are subjected
## by those injustices when they do that definitely
## and move it on to the av racism claim the blm
## post that was the uh the center of apparent
## uh racism you know this is the uh apparently that
## post was in itself racist and and those it's gone
## now obviously but for those who didn't see it it
## was the image the famous image that went around
## of a blm activist a black man holding a pig's
## head by the ears a severed pig's head by the ears
## to protest against police brutality a navy av put
## out a an image with the caption and that was it
## ended up causing so much controversy and claims
## of racism and all these things and it and it was
## removed in the end right so like tell us the i
## know you've done it before again i'm sorry you
## have to keep repeating yourself but you know we
## are we're aiming to get through everything today
## but tell us the story behind that then and and you
## know if you think that was racist as well and the
## reasons you removed it so it wasn't removed um
## it wasn't removed you know as a result of like
## so just to clarify it's still up on our instagram
## it's only been removed on facebook because
## we stupidly took i want to say take the bet we
## took the bait i don't know if that's the proper
## term to use here but whatever with regards to
## what the donor was demanding of us at the time
## throughout the whole debacle that we went through
## with the donor and uh so we made a decision
## to remove that post only because this
## donor was learning to remove our funding um
## and it was it was the only thing that
## we were willing to consider doing
## uh out of all the demands that they gave
## us we completely rejected the notion of
## a board of directors and the other things we we
## really push back on and we we try to be as as
## charitable and open to these demands as possible
## which is why we deleted that post as a decision
## we made and at this point we had deleted it
## probably a month and a half or two months
## after the post was made so at that point it had
## it had seen most of its traction you know so
## uh i just want to clarify it wasn't removed
## after getting heat from people in the comments
## section or anything like that it was uh it
## was a post that we believe needs to happen
## it's just the way that we communicated in
## that post that we felt we could improve
## on and we have already addressed this within
## the organization because recently we saw the
## same thing happening at another protest
## in spain and we made a post about that uh
## it didn't you know it didn't get as much traction
## but um you know so there's something to be said
## about being direct about these things but
## it's unpopular we share a lot of unpopular
## opinions that's what we do because the
## truth is unpopular at the best of times
## uh and yeah and uh we are committed to speak up
## against animal oppression wherever we see it so
## if it's been if it's being paraded on the
## on the main stage on in the mainstream on
## the news every around the world as a appropriate
## and acceptable way of addressing human um centric
## injustices you know to hold decapitated heads
## up to to say [ __ ] the police uh then we have
## a responsibility to say something about that
## um no oppression is acceptable ever no one
## has the right to oppress anyone else ever in any
## situation ever and uh and that's supposed to be
## the ethos behind these protests that were
## occurring this year and that's our ethos so
## we should be seeing eye to eye but uh yeah that's
## really our responsibility to do that but yeah we
## remove that post um as a result of the donor and
## we we regret that decision i don't know how else
## to say it but it's i mean we we still have it on
## instagram it's not being removed from instagram so
## from that what you will sure sure so that's yeah
## it clarifies a lot and and just to clarify here
## like you don't you don't believe that post was
## racist right no like what we said it could have