## or was it just a we request that you
## do this well it seemed like it was
## out of the uh concern for joey's image
## or his uh reputation yeah so so far to
## get it straight there the requirements so the
## requirements for the donor to continue funding av
## are that you delete those videos um give
## them uh of some i don't know financial
## organization access to all of your records
## um is the board of directors things still
## going they still want you to do that as well is
## that still on the cards or did they pull that
## like well here's the thing you know there were
## things mentioned in the email that we got from
## the donor but we don't even know what exactly are
## the expectations on on their side and so that's
## why we wanted to have a conversation with them
## but at this point at this point we're not getting
## we're not getting that do you think it's possible
## that they did that to save a face as in they
## that joey was involved and gave that response
## to try to kind of yeah save face basically would
## that be that's fair to say or do you think that
## that he actually or she i don't know the donor
## didn't they actually want to rectify things or
## is it just to try to repair some of the damage
## to the reputation of joey and the donor i mean
## even in my most charitable of moods towards this
## i can't see it any other way
## yeah it feels like that i mean
## from an outside perspective unfortunately it
## does feel like it was just an attempt to maybe uh
## i don't know get the upper hand take the high road
## you know or appear to be taking the high road but
## it's it's really sad to hear that actually
## it's you you actually took the decision to
## take the high road with them and then they just
## didn't respond which um yeah it's disappointing
## when we heard that there was this interest to
## continue funding us and have another conversation
## then we're like great let's have a conversation
## but then you know we're not going to be bored
## and bossed around and that's not what we designed
## a v for it's in fact the opposite of that
## and that's part of the reason
## why we're at this point
## that we're at and the reason why we
## have an organic following and you know
## it's i think there's just a misunderstanding
## of what we do from the donor's perspective
## and i think that they don't really understand
## that work and they don't really understand us
## and what our mission is and and they they perhaps
## got involved without doing their homework and
## we wanted to have a conversation so that we
## could get on the same page about things and
## we're not able to do that at this point so that's
## where everything is left at this point yeah
## i understand i understand and it's it's it's
## something that it's not a surprise that that
## the donor or anyone basically is having some
## kind of uh you know let's say strong opinion
## towards being like kind of anti-av this seems
## to be quite a common thing right now and i was
## just thinking about it earlier about what kind
## of an example could i give you know to uh like
## i don't know an analogy to give and um it's kind
## of funny i don't know if you'll agree with me but
## i feel like av has become kind of like
## the nickelback of animal rights it's like
## i'm sorry i'm sorry but nickelback
## are extremely successful
## awards end this stream
## nickelback has won loads of awards they play loads
## of gigs they're very successful they've got loads
## of fans but it's also very in to hate them it's
## almost like a trend to hate them right and that's
## what i'm kind of getting at here is that it's not
## a surprise to me that someone is holding really
## negative opinions without even considering what
## you're doing because that's the in thing to do
## that's the kind of point i was making it seems
## cool like when i put out some messages asking
## people hey you know give me some questions for
## av i had a few people just replying just just
## with some you know real virtue signaling stuff
## like just really like just explaining why they
## won't go for av anymore and i'm like that's great
## but like give me a question like give me something
## you know it just seems like it's cool to say i
## don't work with av i it seems cool to be like that
## like it's cool to say i hate nickelback i'm sorry
## to put you in that bracket but it really feels
## like that you know uh i've got to say and and that
## brings me on to go on go on sorry i think it's a
## lot cooler though yeah i mean come on chad kroger
## is not that that much of a loser is he come on
## no i used to listen to them when i was younger
## i have to admit i i i know it seems like it's uh