## because just look at the rest of their
## range same could be said
## about cliff bars same could be said
## about
## literally every other product that we as
## vegans consume
## and these companies that they come from
## are not vegan companies
## so it's just asinine to expect this uh
## from impossible like just because you
## eat their burger
## it doesn't mean you condone them as a
## company if that's the case you're
## condoning every company you ever
## purchase anything from but you're really
## just condoning that product
## you're really just buying a product yeah
## and then to people that take that
## position and some people do take that
## position that by buying the product
## you're
## in the company um and um and it's like
## you said i think it's
## practically impossible uh to do that but
## then they would argue that okay but
## it's not it's practically impossible but
## then surely that that's that's the same
## as saying it's practically impossible to
## be vegan
## but we're just doing the best we can and
## we're going to make extra efforts to not
## buy from companies that we know
## are are really bad though what do you
## think that would be
## an incorrect statement because that
## would suggest a different definition of
## veganism
## veganism is literally defined by
## avoiding animal abuse as much as
## practically possible it's not practical
## to carry out veganism in the way that
## it's being suggested in in all this
## stuff
## it's just that's not practical we're not
## even talking about a scenario where you
## have
## two options in front of you one from a
## vegan company and one
## is an impossible burger and you have no
## other food options because you're on a
## desert
## uh you're on a deserted island or
## something that's not
## the scenario we're in here uh because in
## that scenario obviously the better thing
## to do
## would be to choose the product from the
## vegan company
## um but it's not as black and white as
## this
## okay cool all right we'll close that
## chapter we've got
## just two more topics left and then we'll
## we'll go to a q a
## so um i don't know how many people are
## left from the beginning but there were a
## lot of questions coming in earlier and
## i'm not prepared to go through the chat
## to find them so
## if you have questions uh you're gonna
## have to save them and type them again
## when we do a quick
## q a um and as i said if you if you're
## planning on asking questions keep it
## sensible or we just won't answer it
## it's a waste of your time typing it if
## you're gonna be stupid so
## just keep that in mind um all right the
## last last two points then just
## the first one i want to talk about this
## it's linked to something we discussed
## earlier actually about the the people
## complaining or claiming they weren't
## getting funded you know like they
## weren't getting the
## av fund or whatever and it links into an
## overall problem of
## organizers in av getting somehow feeling
## that they
## haven't been supported or they feel like
## they haven't been supported by you or
## they feel like they've been actually had
## the opposite like some
## some ex-organizers go out there and
## claim that they were actually
## um i don't know what you would say you
## guys were rude to them or they were
## treated badly by av
## and that's why they left or or um they
## were booted out or something
## you know and i'm being generic here in
## general because every time i've pushed
## for more information on these
## claims i've had i've had nothing right
## so i'm bringing it up as a general topic
## and you don't need to
## answer it as if it's like oh this one
## individual or something because they
## never provided me any screenshots or
## anything so i've got nothing to show you
## um but what why are they doing this why
## do you think this this is coming up from
## ex organizers where they're saying
## i wasn't supported or i was treated
## badly um
## where where is that coming from do you
## think there's any truth to it you know
## what are your thoughts on it
## no there's no truth to this because
## we um
## we provide support for every chapter for
## every organizer equally
## right we've got all these different
## things and procedures and
## systems in place that provide support
## from us um to the regional organizers we
## have a manager
## that manages the regional organizers and
## then
## so all of the organizers have the
## ability to reach out to
## us personally in their chat at any
## moment if they need support if they need
## advice if they need any kind of help
## and we always help them and
## we provide support where we can so to
## just leave and say that they felt
## um like they were not supported or they
## were treated badly it's just
## yeah we need to see the evidence because
## it's easy to just make these statements
## but where is it coming from
## again it's just because people think
## okay i'm going to leave av
## because all these people said paul is
## racist and this and that and so
## now i'm going to just jump on the
## bandwagon and say abe treated me badly
## that's the only thing i can think of
## there's no evidence
## right
## i don't think it's much of a help to
## anybody for us to comment on
## this any further than that because
## there's no specific