## when people ask me more questions about it so i do
## understand what you've just been through and i do
## understand that this was a shitty thing to do and
## i really do appreciate you coming and doing it and
## i'm sure i'm sure there are other people who have
## people have already been saying in the chat you
## can check later that they also really appreciate
## you coming doing this and and they support you
## and um one person even said they originally didn't
## support you but after seeing some of your videos
## they were like okay no i actually really hope
## that they can work this out so you know this
## is people i feel like people want to support and
## i hope this can bring some of that support back
## for people who have maybe got lost or confused
## along the way because of all this [ __ ] um
## so yeah thank you so much is there anything you
## want to say clutton closing any points you want to
## add just thank you also david thanks for uh taking
## the time because it's important i think as a
## member of the animal rights movement to want
## to clarify these things it's not really about
## us again it's about the tone it's about the
## precedent we set for others in this movement
## absolutely saw any any final words
## just thank you and um thank you to anyone who sent
## their questions or you know anyone who joined this
## live and they were commenting and watching this
## live so yeah that's it thanks for having us david
## awesome and a little bit more housekeeping just
## before we go um there is another live stream today
## and it will be at 8 pm my time so i don't know
## what that is your time this is just completely
## separate this is just to discuss uh all of the
## different topics that i went through in the five
## minute friday so people watching if you're if
## you want to come to that and do come to that
## and it'll be the usual style of live
## stream where we just go through topics and
## uh and also laugh at some anti-vegan kind of
## standard stuff uh so come on come along for that
## and um don't forget to share this video with
## anyone who's giving you [ __ ] if they are
## giving you [ __ ] and also of course don't
## expect that this video will make a difference
## some people don't want to understand some
## people aren't interested in av anymore and
## they just they're just done that's totally fine
## don't get upset if it happens just just you
## do you and let them do them and and that's
## it you know don't don't take it personally
## yeah i would say it's the same with non-vegans who
## many non-vegans aren't reachable aren't willing
## and there's no point in continuing to outreach
## those individuals either it's the same thing
## with vegans yep sure all right cool we'll
## end it there thanks so much bye everyone