## it's uh it's
## a bandwagon for us to disagree with you
## on using that comparison but
## but it's uh
## that's just a taste in music which i
## guess is
## i guess it's a taste in activism
## i guess you could that's the comparison
## you're making
## kind of yeah kind of but i think with
## nickelback
## um well anyway i don't want to get into
## the comparison
## maybe it's for the best yeah um but i'm
## gonna give an example actually because i
## did have a plan set up for this stream
## but you know what i feel like this is
## relevant right now
## so i want to tell the viewers a quick
## story here about something that happened
## um
## i put these messages out didn't i put
## these posts out on my instagram asking
## people give me some
## give me some questions give me some
## topics i put it on facebook and by the
## way one of those posts has blown up with
## a load of
## nonsense but anyway that's another topic
## but some people responded to me saying
## you know certain things and i want to
## just bring up one of these responses
## that i had
## um from somebody on my instagram who
## who had a story to tell and i want to
## just kind of link it in with what we
## just said about it's cool to hate av
## it's cool to kind of just you know find
## something wrong and just
## almost even sometimes uh [ __ ] as
## well so i'm going to show you something
## that happened
## and this is real by the way i'm not this
## is not designed this wasn't planned this
## is something that genuinely happened and
## i've got the evidence because i can show
## you my um
## i can show you this the literal inbox
## from my
## instagram and you'll see why this is
## relevant in a moment so
## i'm going to share the screen so you can
## see it all right
## so here's my stories right i don't know
## if you can can you see that right now no
## how do i change this hold up i need to
## um
## add the different screen i've never
## added like a
## like uh this kind of screen i'm trying
## to get the uh preview screen up
## okay hold second all right open up
## um where are we
## all right here we go so here's a story
## that uh i put my story out that night
## saying like tell me any topics you think
## should be discussed somebody responded
## saying this
## why do you treat your organizers like
## disposable garbage right
## now like on the surface you're thinking
## wow okay that's
## that's pretty intense right what's going
## on here so i responded to this person
## how do i have to switch this every time
## yeah i do so i responded to this person
## very simply saying
## basically i responded saying okay give
## us give me some information i need to
## ask this question properly so this is
## the response i got
## when the allegations of fraud came up i
## commented on one of paul's comments
## stating something along the lines of it
## being standard practice to ask for
## financial information
## paul was very aggressive in his
## responses even abusive i told him i was
## one of the organizers and he told me to
## [ __ ] off and leave so i stood down
## these are not isolated incidents
## unfortunately his temper gets in the way
## and he burns his people
## his own people good luck so
## i i'm not saying that i don't believe
## that person and at the time i said you
## know okay i believe you
## but i need some evidence right i need
## something to show here do you have a
## screenshot do you have something to show
## me
## that i can show to them and uh you know
## i'm happy to discuss it and this is the
## answer that i got
## i don't he cleans up his message
## straight away i know you believe me but
## understand
## you need for proof you could perhaps
## pose the question more broadly is this
## is behavior as a pattern of his
## and so will be hard to deny sorry i
## can't help you any further david so
## it's pretty damning right this is pretty
## damning and at the time i gotta admit
## that i was a little bit like
## swayed because look i know paul and i
## know you both paul and the style and i
## know that sometimes you know
## i lose my [ __ ] too i say things that i
## later come to regret i told people to
## [ __ ] off i've told i told someone to
## [ __ ] off live
## in a live stream by by accident i
## thought they were saying something that
## they weren't i told them to [ __ ] off and
## then they were like why
## what's wrong i only said this i got
## completely mixed up so it's not it's not
## like you know
## we're infallible we make mistakes but
## anyway i brought this up with you guys
## right
## and um luckily paul actually had the
## screenshots of this interaction
## now i'm going to show you what the
## actual interaction was
## actually hold up i just realized there's
## one little thing i need to blur out
## but you're not going to believe you're
## not going to believe what the actual
## interaction went like um
## on the surface of this it looks it
## obviously looks like it's a done deal
## right
## and i'm going to explain why this is
## relevant after i've shown you if you're
## wondering
## watching this if you're wondering what
## how is this relevant you'll see in a
## moment
## and i'd just like to add that this is
## how people commonly talk
## about they be when they say negative
## things about us
## yeah definitely definitely this is this
## is this is why i'm bringing it up it's
## it is
## absolutely like this and i want to get
## into this as a topic as well it's not
## just
## a thing but hey look so here we go this