## that you know you see conversations with someone
## like you know hudson for example he was a great
## activist and some of his conversations just you
## blow someone's mind you know and do they sign up
## for vegan 22 maybe not but but their mind has been
## blown like you know you can't undo that like maybe
## they don't do vegan 22 but the idea that they
## could potentially go vegan is still is still there
## you know they've definitely made some connections
## so i think engaging the success based on that is
## is a little bit well not a little bit it's very
## short-sighted and it does it does bring up the
## question though of of how can we gauge success
## right because currently this leads on to the
## next question that we can gauge our failure by the
## amount of animals being killed on the rise right
## so that that's something i feel that we all have
## to take as a bit of a slap in the face like okay
## we're trying but you know clearly something isn't
## working as effectively as we'd like it to be or
## we've got a long way to go right um so how can we
## gauge success how can we know that we're working
## towards you know the right place when it looks
## like we're not if you look at the global statistic
## hey look i would agree that animals and the
## animal rights movement has been pushed back
## even further this year than it was
## last year i would agree with that
## all right yeah but to say that we shouldn't
## fight for animals in the way that we're doing it
## is ridiculous uh i i would judge incremental wins
## by saying that you know in our network i'm seeing
## more and more people than ever before speaking
## correctly about this and that's beautiful okay
## we're ending human supremacy we're holding
## people accountable and we're spreading a clear
## vegan message on behalf of the animals so for
## me that's what that's one win that i would use
## as an indicator for us moving in the right
## direction and i think more and more vegans are
## taking on board this this need to to be serious
## about how we're being perceived by others and like
## taking that seriously and being wanting wanting
## to be taken seriously when it comes to this
## uh i don't even think that many others are really
## even taking that into account but i think more
## and more people are actually on boarding this
## attitude which i think is another great indicator
## uh i think there are other great indicators we
## could point at but i guess it depends on the
## way you see it and i guess also whether you're
## an optimist or you're a pessimist and um and
## we don't think that you should just do
## one thing anyway like people should do
## what they think is effective and they should be
## as effective as they can possibly be doing it
## and uh we need people fighting in politics we
## need people fighting in government we need people
## fighting in corporate we need people fighting on
## the streets we need people fighting in hollywood
## it doesn't stop this fight is is multi-faceted
## and it needs to continue at every level
## yeah absolutely i think also something that's not
## being considered is that although some countries
## uh there may be reductions in how much how much
## animal products are being produced right or how
## many people are consuming them or using them
## um whereas other countries are on the rise like
## for example unfortunately india is one of those
## countries uh where i know we have a few indians
## here in the chat who can you can also you know
## vouch for this that the amount of animal products
## specifically meat uh being consumed in india is
## actually increasing and there are other countries
## uh especially in the east who are having the same
## situation previously they had very low consumption
## and now because of the western influence they are
## consuming more whereas it seems like some western
## countries are on the flip side of that they're
## consuming less so this is you know without without
## the hard data to really show and really dive into
## everything that's happening we can't just make
## a general statement that we're losing you know
## we need to actually look at which countries are
## having an impact and which aren't and why and dig
## deep into each situation right um and i agree with
## everything you said also about um you know getting
## the message right and it's reassuring to know that
## the more people are starting to be more
## unapologetic i think the word would be
## about defending the animals yeah yeah and i also
## want to say that we don't have definitive numbers
## either way on this on the amount of animals being
## oppressed so i am skeptical of whatever data
## people are using to make these assumptions or to
## make these declarations about where things are in
## terms of the numbers so i i question that because
## i remember when a bite-sized vegan did a video
## and she was trying to in that video give people
## the kill count and even she concluded in that