## know i i agree with you i don't like bringing
## this up because there's no i've got nothing to
## show you know what i mean and i feel like i've had
## multiple conversations i've had conversations i'll
## be honest with you i've had conversations with
## people that i would consider to be good friends
## and i've had to be quite harsh and say look
## either give me something here or you're full of
## [ __ ] like i'm sorry and we've kind of like got
## into an argument and just agreed to disagree on it
## because they wouldn't give it to me because they
## didn't have it and um so i've got to say i hold
## i hold a bit of a bias on this because i've
## experienced the [ __ ] first hand and it's it's
## really disappointing to see and it kind of happens
## to me as well obviously people say things about me
## and i say okay great give me some evidence tell
## me where i've said that and they disappear you
## know um so i it's it's it's a it's a symptom
## of a larger problem i think yeah um yeah yeah
## for sure yeah and then the final the final
## thing we'll go into then is actually about
## the effectiveness of av so this is a good thing
## or not just av but of animal rights activism but
## the activism that we're doing so somebody
## did message me and they told me um ask them
## they started off with a shitty message they said
## ask them why why the cube of truth doesn't work
## so i was like okay what are you talking about they
## said right look the number of animals being killed
## is on the rise and um the challenge 22 sign ups
## for last year i think it was last year was only 2
## 000 in the entire world so clearly it's not
## working so i broke that down into two sections
## and this is two things i want to go through like
## one side of this is that obviously if the number
## of animals being killed is increasing it's not
## just av that's not working it's every single
## activism group that's not working because clearly
## you know save isn't working dxe isn't working
## direct action isn't working hunt's tabs aren't
## working nothing's working because the amount of
## animals being killed is on the increase right
## so that's that's a topic why is that happening
## um you know what can we do about it as one topic
## and the other topic is um why the um challenge the
## vegan 22 av signups um they seem to be a lot
## lower than what would be expected of a of you
## know considering how much work goes in into the
## cubes right so i think let's maybe start with the
## challenge 22 one because that might be an easier
## quicker one to go into and then we'll close on the
## on the set on the other one so what with
## the challenge 22 reporting um firstly is
## that accurate like what's going on with that or
## how is it only at 2 000 for like the whole year
## nah first of all it's not accurate because many
## people wouldn't use it also at some point we
## stopped promoting it and using it anyway because
## we realized that challenge 22 is now really
## aligned with av in terms of how they promote
## veganism and so we stopped promoting it and maybe
## some organizers some volunteers are still using
## that link when they arrest someone at a cube but
## it's not being done the same way anyway i think
## when did we start doing this when we when did we
## stop using the link last year at least a year and
## a half yeah wait it's it could even be up to two
## years now but it's at least a year yeah i think it
## was last year at some point we realized that we're
## just not aligned we stopped using it and um even
## when we were promoting it and it was on the card i
## can average someone and i can say you know you can
## go and sign up and use this link but that person
## is not necessarily going to do it even if they
## do decide that they want to be vegan so that's
## why it's not a good measurement and we all the
## way that we communicate animal rights to people
## is so simple and easy to digest and with so much
## personal individual accountability attached to it
## that the why factor is is something we focus so
## heavily on hammering into people that the how
## factor is something we empower generally we
## empower other the the bystander to take on within
## their accountability it's their responsibility
## to be to be to you know properly plan how they're
## going to be vegan by simply using google and we
## we sometimes say exactly that you know google is
## all you really need to be to be vegan uh we want
## it to be simple for people we don't want to make
## it sound like you need to be in a 22-day program
## when that's not even true you don't the fact is
## you do not need that is it helpful for some people
## but not for everyone and that's not the message
## that we believe is important we need to clarify
## it further by saying all that's needed is the
## why factor the how you will figure out if there
## were vegans 50 years ago you can be vegan now
## absolutely okay i think i think that's i'll give
## you my personal opinion on that as well because
## i think that's fair um and i think i don't know
## to gauge the success or or failure by how many
## challenge 22 sign-ups seems a little bit there
## are seems a bit short-sighted uh considering