## cause problems on both sides of this you know not
## only on the people rejecting the idea side but
## also the people demanding they be referred to as
## a certain thing it's gonna oh it's only going to
## become more prevalent i guess that's why i feel
## like it's an important topic to get into well
## again like you know yeah just cap this off with a
## black and white answer and then sure you know it's
## it works the other way as well like no bullying
## will be allowed but also if you're bullying others
## to believe what you believe at the cube that's not
## a lot either if you're not required to hand it to
## to give us your gender in that interaction and
## you're forcing it anyways that's an issue yeah
## that's a problem because that's not that's not
## productive communication and uh and teamwork
## when the goal is supposed to be non-human
## animal rights yeah it goes both ways yeah
## sure just but basically just just respect each
## other it's the bottom line earlier the answer to
## it is everyone will be respected
## that's the rule all right got it
## all right cool cool let's uh we're going from
## one to another i guess uh in terms of this i
## think these might be a little bit easier to
## get into though because there's just some
## there's a few more like more direct accusations
## that came through however they didn't really come
## through with any kind of backing but i wanted
## to put them to you as like a topic of like why
## do you think people are saying this right and you
## can tell me why you think people are saying this
## so there's been accusations of of of racism
## as well against av as an organization and also
## i'm sorry paul but it tends to be coming at
## you most of the time um with these things the
## sal seems to get off the hook um but um this
## racism apparently av is racist and apparently
## paul is racist and i think some of this did
## come from the the blm post um but that was
## an av thing that wasn't necessarily a poll
## thing why why do you think people are coming
## at you and and making accusations that you
## are a racist individually paul or not av
## we'll deal with av in a second but why do you
## think it's coming for you that people say this
## who isn't called a racist in 2020
## i'm suss on anyone not being
## called a racist in 2020
## uh why is i mean i'm answering quantum physics in
## that question i don't know the answer it's like
## uh yeah i don't know why why humans
## the way they are i i just i really
## i don't know it's uh i i actually haven't ever
## heard anyone directly call me a racist because
## of the blm poet like me personally yeah no no
## that's that's like an av thing i think it's
## a general thing yeah i mean we have been called
## a racist both of us not over that post though but
## yeah i don't know why i'm not sure why actually
## i'd like to see evidence your honor the evidence
## please yeah i think there was there was there was
## a post i'm just remembering now i think that it
## could have i don't know contributed to it i
## think where you would you were talking to a
## you were outreaching a black guy and you said some
## things about you know you defended the animals
## um and i think some people found it to be
## somehow racist because of the words you used
## and do you remember that at all like yes black
## guy was a black girl so you misgendered her
## you should really be ashamed of
## yourself let's cancel david immediately
## trust me trust me out of this video this is not
## going to be the thing that gets taken there's
## things we've said already that
## i've as they came out of my mouth
## i was like yeah that's going to be that's
## going to be screenshotted that's going to
## be all over the place soon so no don't worry
## we're already that boat was sailed we're done
## um so if you watch the video guys she was
## making a point to me that she doesn't need
## to take animal rights seriously especially
## even if she is the oppressor in this scenario
## as a non-vegan because black people are oppressed
## that was her argument that she put to me
## and she even said something to the effect that
## speciesism doesn't apply to me and my people and
## i said it applies to anybody who oppresses animals
## who isn't vegan uh she carried on and i felt it
## was only right to make the point that animals are
## the most oppressed group of beings on the planet
## it felt to me the most appropriate thing to say at
## that time because i speak on behalf of the animals
## if i was in their position that's
## exactly what i would want to be
## said in that moment so that that
## person had the correct perspective
## uh whether they accept the truth is not my uh i
## don't i don't have any uh skin in that game my