## all right we are
## live welcome all
## to this very special david rams live
## stream where we're going to be joined by
## paul and nassau from anonymous for the
## voiceless
## to discuss a load of different rumors
## accusations
## i laugh because some of them are pretty
## funny but now some of them are very
## serious rumors accusations and
## a whole load of questions that you've
## been sending to me um
## that you want to ask paula nassal the
## co-founders of anonymous for the
## voiceless we're going to go through all
## of these things but first of all i just
## want to do a bit of housekeeping with
## you so
## if you are watching this later as in
## you're not watching it live
## if you check across the bottom the
## progress bar you will see it's been
## split up into sections
## so if you want to find the specific
## question rumor accusation or whatever
## that you're looking for
## you can find it right there if you have
## questions yourself
## right now and you are watching this live
## right now you have questions
## uh we're gonna do a q a at the end so
## save them for that
## but if you have a topic or a question
## that you really really want to be asked
## right now or or sooner you can use the
## super chat if you use a super chat
## i will pause and we'll answer your
## question right away but
## but there is a caveat there is a
## disclaimer here if you are spamming
## trolling or abusing anyone in any way
## including if you send a super chat and
## you pay for a super chat and it's a spam
## or abuse
## it won't be discussed so you'll be
## wasting your money i just want to make
## that very clear for you
## and that also goes for the live chat and
## it goes for the q a at the end
## we won't be tolerating any spam or any
## trolling or any abuse so the moderator
## will be handling that
## i hope it doesn't come to that but i
## know a lot of the topics that we're
## going to discuss are a little bit
## controversial so
## i expect that there will be at least one
## or two
## um so all that being said yeah just keep
## it sensible keep it polite
## and we'll have a a productive
## live stream that's pretty much it so
## with that being said let's bring in
## paul nasal welcome paul welcome missile
## hey what's up how you doing
## good how are you oh good all good
## all good i'm excited to get through this
## and i think a lot of people
## in the comments have been pretty pumped
## as well to uh
## you know get through this um i know for
## you too this is basically like you're
## repeating yourself
## a lot of these things because over the
## years i think i think we've been through
## this a few times or
## your own channels and in your own um
## social medias but there are a few people
## at least a few people here that have
## been asking a few of the the questions
## already and a lot of people have been
## sending me questions so i'm happy we can
## we can do this and you know hopefully
## once and for all get everything
## discussed in one place so i really
## appreciate you coming on and doing this
## i know
## it's not the easiest thing to do um
## so we can kick off i suppose let's just
## kick straight in right i mean let's not
## waste any time we're here for a reason
## let's kick off with the recent there's
## the most recent stuff that's been going
## on
## right now i think most people watching
## are going to be here probably off the
## back of that i think i don't think we
## need to really introduce what av
## is and who you are i think anybody
## watching this is going to know that
## already
## so let's just jump in with the recent
## stuff and
## what's been going on with av with
## the the whole situation with joey the
## situation with animal safe movement
## anita the donor um where are we up to
## with this now
## could you give us an update on that just
## to kick things off
## so we reached out to the donor to
## find out if this was a genuine
## um thing you know to
## legitimately continue donating to av
## and they
## replied with more demands
## on top of everything that was discussed
## in the videos we put out and everything
## that
## joey had mentioned so even more demands
## on top of that
## that we had to respond to but we of
## course
## ourselves had things that we needed to
## communicate to the donor
## i mean there's obviously a break in
## trust at this point and we need to have
## a conversation and
## re-establish that trust and things like
## this and we haven't heard back
## since we've replied so that was over
## almost a month ago now
## and we haven't heard back what were the
## extra
## requirements they were they were giving
## you like what did they add
## one of them was for us to delete these
## videos that we put up
## about joey and that that
## was pretty telling of what this was
## really about
## right right and what did they give her