## supportive of individuals within our
## network who are doing that
## uh
## i don't see that as activism though i
## didn't see that as like fighting a human
## rights cause of some kind
## no i guess not but i guess it would be
## raising awareness that
## homeless people need food i know people
## know that or maybe inspiring other
## vegans to go out and outreach
## homeless people and give them food i
## don't know it's an idea it's just it's
## just an idea is what i mean it's it's
## something that uh
## um like i don't know if it even would
## count as intersectionality in that case
## but for example the
## lebanon example would because they they
## have the corrupt government they are
## they're oppressing their people
## um making someone making a post or
## making a video on that where you're
## saying hey look at what these awesome
## vegans are doing
## they're fighting a corrupt government
## and they're also saving animals and
## they're getting people food
## that that would be a better example of
## of how to raise awareness of
## two oppressions um in one without either
## of them
## losing anything if that makes sense
## because it's not like we're just talking
## about
## you know lebanon we're talking about
## vegan and activists in lebanon so like
## then it becomes
## something that encompasses all of it you
## know but i mean i
## i'm a bit confused because
## i don't see how it was like an animal
## rights
## uh thing that they did
## they're just vegans people who don't
## abuse and torture animals
## animal rights activists who went and did
## a deed for humans and that deed
## was a human rights good
## that they did and when they were doing
## that
## that act that deed had nothing to do
## with the animals really
## it was just about i think david was
## saying that they were kind of
## outreaching
## people when they were giving them the
## food were they
## yeah i believe they were i don't know
## this for sure but i believe they were
## sending out like leaflets and stuff with
## the with the bags and also they were
## rescuing animals too they were actually
## rescuing animals off the street and
## getting them treated
## they were raising money for that too so
## they were doing a few yeah it was like
## uh
## it was yeah they were doing a few little
## a few different things to try and help
## the animals and also the people
## yeah i didn't know the full extent of
## the campaign that they carried out over
## there
## uh i all i know is at the time i reached
## out and you know i checked in with them
## and i
## was just wanting to know if they were
## okay during the whole blast
## but i forgive my ignorance to
## those who were carrying out that awesome
## campaign because it looked very
## helpful i was just confused on how it
## was tied into animal rights i just
## thought they were
## doing a deed a good deed for humans in
## that moment
## i didn't see how maybe they were maybe
## they were maybe they were maybe maybe
## they were only doing that some of them
## um but i know for sure some of them were
## also rescuing the animals i guess
## i mean with a more concrete example if
## let's imagine there is a concrete
## example of this where they're actually
## doing that
## they're actually advocating for animal
## rights whilst simultaneously helping
## humans
## um i guess the question is like would
## would
## that be something av would consider to
## post about if
## it came up or or is is there some a
## reason not to that's what i'm trying to
## understand
## like hosting so you're asking
## specifically about posting about it on
## social media
## our platforms are for animal rights for
## non-human animal rights
## so that's our general response to that
## but we do
## carry out what you're saying we do
## take the opportunity to how did you want
## it
## to benefit humans while benefiting the
## animals you know in those moments when
## we see
## any form of oppression or discrimination
## occurring within our organization
## we stamp it out with the quickness and
## we have a process that we go through
## to rid it from the organization
## in those moments we're taking action
## that benefits humans and the animals
## we're just not posting about it i guess
## because our platforms
## and network is for non-human animals
## okay i understand i understand so it's
## kind of like um
## yeah so your base your base kind of um i
## don't know what to put it here
## your let's say default your your focus
## your
## baseline i keep using that word is is
## that you know the
## the account is for non-humans and that
## that's kind of the be
## that's it basically that that's how it's
## going to be like social media
## and also the cubes it that that's where
## it's going to stay
## and that that's your core kind of value
## basically that's what you're saying here
## right
## yeah like again going back to the
## numbers thing you know three trillion
## animals every year if you think about
## the amount
## of victims that are involved in this
## injustice you know how many more times
## uh more urgent would you say in terms of
## the numbers
## this injustice is than other injustices
## on
## the planet how many more times more
## urgent would you say
## totally it's like it's not a it's not a
## criticism for me i'm actually just
## trying to uh you know