## not sales tools they're communication tools but
## where these communication tools are applicable
## from the sales world into activism but again i
## need to reiterate this i said this in the video
## sales is not activism just because you
## have x number of sales years of sales
## experience doesn't mean you have x number of years
## experience in activism that's not how this works
## at all it just means that you've learned a
## few things about communication that might
## might be applicable here in activism i found
## in fact when i go over all of the sales
## things i've ever learned that most of it is
## actually unapplicable unequivocally unapplicable
## and that's because the the goal in sales is
## usually to get someone to sign on the dotted
## line and there's usually a financial incentive
## here where and i named it the value-based sales
## approach from the very beginning in 2016
## when we started av for the purpose of
## setting it apart from sales in general the common
## view of sales this is a new i was trying to create
## something new here where we can carry over what
## is applicable and what i've found the deeper i've
## gone into this is that a very minimal amount is
## actually applicable from the sales world over here
## so with that added commentary on this bit
## i will now continue for you guys to get
## somebody convicted in what it is that
## you're trying to convince them of
## we have all of the lodge process up to sales one
## of the traditional things that occurs in sales is
## the three-step process for any sale so i'll talk
## you through that right now the three-step process
## is really simple the first step is to get
## somebody convicted in what it is that you're
## trying to convince them of we have all the logic
## all of the reason on our side and it's important
## to use logic and reason i'm not saying don't use
## that but if you don't get somebody emotionally
## convicted in this issue because it's a justice
## issue then don't expect a shift from anybody
## that's why i don't like these philosophical
## discussions that we have with people about
## veganism we have these what seems to be like a bar
## discussion just food for thought and that's a real
## issue because that's not what this is supposed to
## be about this is an accountability conversation
## and that first step is best achieved when you
## connect them to the sense of injustice and you
## hold them accountable to that injustice
## the second step is to make sure that they
## understand that they as an individual are
## responsible that they're in the hot seat
## this isn't something they can just palm off to
## the government or palm off to these industries and
## say we need to focus on petitioning against these
## industries this is about them as an individual and
## you can't let them get out of that that's your job
## meat doesn't just harm yourself it harms someone
## else someone or something do you think an animal
## is a thing oh okay i'll see where you're going
## but like let's but that's the problem that's
## going to be your that's going to be the club
## the lack of compassion for non-human um you know
## that's going to be your problem but what about
## you because i'm talking to you right now do you
## have a lack of compassion for non-human animals
## so are you against animal exploitation yes i am
## okay so what do you think you can do about it
## yeah we're talking yeah i will share
## this conversation with my family
## what do you think you will do
## though yeah i will start more
## the third step once you have achieved that
## second step through dealing with their objections
## anchoring it back to accountability once they
## concede you move on to the third step which is
## tying in the benefits everybody loves to know
## what's in it for them right because humans are
## selfish right okay so the number one benefit
## for you going vegan obviously for the animals
## it's that they no longer have to be tortured
## and abused by you but the benefit for you
## is that you no longer have to abuse them
## and therefore you're no longer a hypocrite
## because you say that you're against animal
## abuse in fact in that very conversation
## they said that that they're against animal
## abuse right that's the only reason we're
## vegan today why you guys are sitting here right
## now trying to learn about outreach is because
## you hate the hypocrisy don't you you would never
## want to live with that hypocrisy again would you
## more importantly would never want to abuse animals
## anymore would you i used to say if you do this
## correctly you eat a whole foods plant-based diet