## oh yeah looks like it's working okay i love you
## what was that that came through all right we're
## live i think all right looks like it's friday
## yo these kids outside crazy
## what was that that came through yo there's
## a double up all right we're live i think
## some doubling up on the audio
## but we are now live i think
## uh what's up everybody let me know in the comments
## if the audio and the visual is okay with you
## i've got a chat section on youtube that i'll
## be maintaining and managing as best as i can
## i'll just wait for people to join and for this
## live to establish itself properly
## and here people are joining the chat on youtube
## what's up everybody what's up isaac sylvia
## all right to be named good morning ariane laura
## now i see you laura says yeah let me know how
## the visual is and the audio i want to make sure
## that the technology is on point for this one
## um i also need you to tell me please
## video and audio is clear thank you i am doing well
## laura thank you i also need to tell i need you to
## tell me if this microphone i'm about to plug
## it in is going to make my audio better or not
## now so i'm now plugged in with this mic
## can you tell me if you can hear me okay
## if it's better or worse than what it just was
## we can't do icd because the uk went back into
## lockdown we're in the same position here i feel
## you we hello sylvia and hello tiff thank you
## tiff appreciate that the audio is good great
## great i'm going to keep this mic in
## then it's better good thank you ariane
## thank you guys appreciate the feedback
## all right so now i'm going to move on
## to the next thing great all right so yeah we're
## in lockdown here in australia and currently uh
## we can only assemble 10 people max in a
## public area and so given that restriction
## it's going to be really difficult for
## any cubes to happen i'm going to be doing
## a limited attendance cube in melbourne
## tomorrow we'll see how we go with that but
## yeah because of the restrictions around
## the world we only have um 170 odd
## uh almost up to 200 i think i haven't even checked
## the figures over the last couple of days but
## yeah i uh i had a look at the figures last
## and was impressed that we have almost 200
## events scheduled given the
## restrictions that we have so
## yeah last year we had 500 cubes scheduled
## around the world and as you may or may not
## know international cube day is the biggest day of
## the year for us because it's our biggest campaign
## and the essence of it in case you don't know is
## to do as many cubes around the world as possible
## so it's a fantastic time of the year for us
## but given the restrictions it's a limited
## campaign
## all right what's up vegan king all right so
## let's get into this we're gonna start off oh i
## need to send out a quick story to everybody on
## instagram telling them that we are now live so
## just bear with me i've got no one moderating
## this stream i'm going to be doing it myself