## let's let's go on to the
## like more let's go into a solid topic
## something we can really like get into
## and kind of debunk so
## one of the more common things that came
## up with my questions that came up
## questions that came up sorry topics that
## came up was
## about money now we talked about the
## donor obviously
## but we didn't talk about the general
## things that people
## seem to be obsessing over when it comes
## to av
## so these general money concerns as i've
## called on my general money concerns they
## include things like people are upset
## because
## you guys didn't want to release
## financial records they're upset because
## apparently
## that they don't know or you have not
## released where donations go
## um they're upset because they
## the the chapters are claiming they
## receive no money
## um so so i know you've dealt with some
## of this on your own channel and i'm
## on your own videos and i guess you're
## sick of talking about it but
## again my aim today is to get into it and
## and to ask
## maybe more questions that maybe people
## haven't you guys maybe haven't had
## before and to get
## really some solid facts and detail out
## here so that people can't
## continue to discuss this randomly like
## you said i feel like we need to vet
## these things rather than just taking
## people's words um
## so what what is that situation then so
## let's let's be more specific with the
## question
## there's money coming in and obviously
## there's money going out
## um people are claiming that there's a
## problem that they
## don't know what's coming in and where
## it's going
## so how would you respond to that like
## what what do you think
## uh how can you reassure these people
## that it's going where it should be
## or you know what the situation is what
## the financial situation is
## i think going back to what you were
## saying before about like
## how it's the cool thing now to hate on
## av
## it's also the cool thing to just ask
## these questions because you don't
## you don't see other organizations or
## other activists being asked the same
## questions
## and the people that are asking these
## questions and making the same claims
## don't have any kind of evidence to back
## up their claim
## so it's just because somebody brought it
## up in the comment section and they saw
## it they're just going to repeat it
## and then the next person is going to say
## the same thing so
## um like the fact that we have never done
## any financial reports is actually
## [ __ ] because it's not that we're not
## willing to do it as that we haven't been
## required to do it yet
## and if anyone is actually interested
## all of this information is public so
## they can just go and look it up
## and they will have access to and they
## can see that
## um we're required to do our first
## financial
## um what is it called like reporting
## this year end of the year or it's
## probably going to be delayed
## next year actually because of coverage
## but
## because we registered av as a non-for
## profit
## i think it was in 2018 the way it works
## here you don't you're not
## asked to do a reporting for like the
## first year or the first couple of years
## so it's not that we because otherwise we
## wouldn't be able to run
## av if we hadn't done our
## um legal requirements
## whatever it is that you know the
## government is asking you to do as a
## not-for-profit
## it's not like you can just say no i'm
## not going to do my reporting and then
## you can continue to run av
## as a not-for-profit so um
## yeah like i said these claims are just
## faceless there's no evidence and also
## people have no reason
## to think that the money is not going
## where we say it's going
## if somebody has proof that the money is
## going elsewhere then
## they need to come forward and show us
## where the money is going um
## we have explained this like you said
## multiple times we have told people where
## the money is going like with all these
## different categories
## so we can just repeat that but i feel
## like these people are committed
## to think a certain way and no matter
## what you say they're just not gonna
## believe you
## so yeah i i just don't know if there's
## anything else that we can say
## to clarify this for people yeah i
## i guess for the sake of for the sake of
## this um
## for the sake of this stream i don't want
## i i don't i'm not interested in going
## through literally
## like i wouldn't expect you to do this to
## go through like okay we spend this much
## here and this much
## i don't want to do that that's just it's
## not you don't owe that to people
## watching this i think
## what i'm more interested in is like
## maybe you could just list off
## like the things that i don't know the
## biggest spending from av
## and like where it goes to give people an
## idea because uh maybe some people
## genuinely have no idea
## where an organization like av would
## spend money let's assume they're asking
## it
## out of you know interest rather than out
## of accusation
## like if somebody asked you hey i'm just
## curious like where would it go like
## where do you spend the most money
## how would you answer that question like
## just just to appease them let's say or
## just
## you know