## to us and that was our response because
## something like that 100 takes away from
## what we're doing because it's
## not necessary and it's irrelevant so to
## put time aside
## 15 20 minutes for everyone to go around
## and say my name is blah blah blah and
## this is my preferred pronoun
## which is unnecessary because in case we
## need to refer to you
## you let us know then if we got it wrong
## you correct us that's fine we can get on
## with our day
## um i know that that was something that
## was brought up and i just wanted to
## clarify that
## there are many other things that are
## human-centric
## that we don't allocate
## our activism our time to at the cubes
## to engaging in and so you could use this
## same logic if you're claiming
## that we are discriminatory towards
## those who have uh
## again we've never even spoken about
## trans people so i reject
## the notion of even commenting on trans
## people
## people with gender pronouns uh the same
## argument could be used
## for uh not um honoring the custodians of
## the land and saying something about like
## the original custodians the land the
## aboriginals or
## or the native americans depending on the
## of the region that we're talking about
## here
## we don't do that at the cubes either
## does that mean that we are also
## racist or we're also colo colon
## colonialists
## or whatever the word is that's being
## tossed around regarding that
## discrimination
## no of course not because we're there for
## non-humans and non-humans deserve a
## cause dedicated to them that's what this
## comes down to
## is if you think that we're being
## discriminatory
## under that logic then you really just
## don't think that animals deserve a cause
## solely dedicated to them
## that's what we're disagreeing about yeah
## yeah i guess i guess my my what i'm what
## i was trying to get out of it here is
## try to get to clarify what for 100 this
## which i think you have clarified now
## is that like the the you know what you
## don't want people you don't want to
## bring up
## um like let's say
## identity politics into into cubing you
## don't want it to become part of
## av you don't want it to become part of
## an action or an event
## um however if somebody has personal
## a personal thing where they want to be
## referred to as
## a certain pronoun or they've recently
## transitioned
## that av is part of av policies to
## respect that because not respecting that
## would be considered bullying
## that's what i'm trying to clarify here
## so this is you're making a distinction
## between the two
## i also need to make the distinction here
## that
## we're referring to sex if anything
## whenever the word gender is being used
## in this conversation
## we are not referring to anything other
## than sex
## we are not referring our repeat to
## anything other than sex
## and the conversation keeps getting
## skewed by others
## to be referring to gender but uh
## regarding trans issues or regarding this
## whole thing
## uh with my comments on being skeptical
## of gender pronouns
## it was regarding sex that i was
## skeptical of this
## there aren't more than two sexes in my
## opinion and i think that people are
## entitled to have that opinion
## trans people are transitioning between
## those two sexes i think they have the
## right to do that
## so i support the trans movement if
## that's what it is right
## i have trans people that follow me that
## support me that like me
## in the face of my comments and the hate
## i receive
## getting called a transfer does not waver
## these people
## i'm not trying to use them as a token
## i'm just giving people context
## because context is lost in our in our
## culture
## and yeah that's all i have to say
## okay um
## yeah yes i'm trying to wrap my head
## around it and also i just sorry i was
## just taking care of a troll
## as well i'm just asking annie to get rid
## of a troll in the chat as i was also
## trying to get that sword it
## seems like they're bothering people so
## you
## obviously you make a separation between
## um
## sex and gender which i think most well i
## mean that's just
## that's that's scientific um there is
## there is actually i think
## um some people would argue including
## myself that there are three sexes
## because there's intersex
## which is very rare but it exists right
## it's it's when someone's born with
## both or like like you know both um
## genetics or whatever i don't know too
## much about it but i know that it exists
## um
## and then yeah and then and then you're
## drawing the line because because um
## yeah because genders it's a new it is an
## ideology the ideology gender ideology is
## new it is new
## if anyone's upset about this then i'm
## not sorry because you need to do some
## research on this and how
## realize how gender ideology is a very
## recent thing and it hasn't been put
## through
## uh the rigorous testing that most other
## psychological
## and scientific you know concepts have