## like any kind of justification for
## wanting that done
## or was it just a we request that you do
## this
## well it seemed like it was
## out of the uh concern for joey's
## image or his uh reputation yeah
## so so far to get it straight there the
## requirements so
## the requirements for the donor to
## continue funding av
## are that you delete those videos
## um give them uh of some i don't know
## financial
## organization access to all of your
## records um
## is the board of directors things still
## going they still want you to do that as
## well is that still on the cards or did
## they pull that
## like well here's the thing you know
## there were
## things mentioned in the email that we
## got from the donor but we don't even
## know what
## exactly are the expectations on on their
## side
## and so that's why we wanted to have a
## conversation with them but at this point
## at this point we're not getting
## we're not getting that do you think it's
## possible that they did that
## to save a face as in they
## that joey was involved and gave that
## response to try to kind of
## yeah save face basically would that be
## that's fair to say or do you think that
## that he actually
## or she i don't know the donor didn't
## they actually want to rectify things or
## is it just to try to repair some of the
## damage to the reputation of joey and
## the donor i mean even in my most
## charitable of moods towards this
## i can't see it any other way
## yeah it feels like that i mean
## from an outside perspective
## unfortunately it does feel like it was
## just an attempt to maybe uh
## i don't know get the upper hand take the
## high road you know or appear to be
## taking the high road but it's
## it's really sad to hear that actually
## you you actually took the decision to
## take the high road with them and then
## they just didn't respond which um yeah
## it's disappointing when we heard that
## there was this interest to continue
## funding us and have another conversation
## then we're like great
## let's have a conversation but then you
## know we're not going to be bored
## and bossed around and
## that's not what we designed a v for it's
## in fact the opposite of that
## and that's part of the reason why we're
## at this point
## that we're at and the reason why we have
## an organic following
## and you know
## it's i think there's just a
## misunderstanding of what we do from the
## donor's perspective
## and i think that they don't really
## understand that work and they don't
## really understand us and what our
## mission is and
## and they they perhaps got involved
## without doing their homework and
## we wanted to have a conversation so that
## we could
## get on the same page about things and
## we're not able to do that at this point
## so that's where everything is left
## at this point yeah i understand i
## understand
## and it's it's it's something that it's
## not a surprise that
## that the donor or anyone basically is
## having
## some kind of uh you know let's say
## strong opinion
## towards being like kind of anti-av this
## seems to be quite a common thing right
## now and i was just thinking about it
## earlier about what kind of an example
## could i give
## you know to uh like i don't know an
## analogy to give
## and um it's kind of funny i don't know
## if you'll agree with me but
## i feel like av has become kind of like
## the nickelback
## of animal rights it's like
## i'm sorry i'm sorry but nickelback are
## extremely successful all right
## we've won so many awards end this stream
## nickelback has won loads of awards they
## play loads of gigs
## they were successful they got loads of
## fans but it's also very
## in to hate them it's almost like a trend
## to hate them
## right and that's what i'm kind of
## getting at here is that it's not a
## surprise to me that
## someone is holding really negative
## opinions without even
## considering what you're doing because
## that's the in thing to do that's the
## kind of point i was making it seems cool
## like when i put out some messages asking
## people hey you know give me some
## questions for av
## i had a few people just replying just
## just with some you know
## real virtue signaling stuff like just
## really like just explaining why they
## won't go for av anymore and i'm like
## that's great but like give me a question
## like give me something you know it just
## seems like it's cool to say
## i don't work with av i it seems cool to
## be like that like it's cool to say i
## hate nickelback
## i'm sorry to put you in that bracket but
## it really feels like that
## you know uh i've got to say and and that
## brings me on to the
## go on go on sorry everything is a lot
## cooler though
## yeah i mean come on chad kroger
## that much of a loser is he come on no i
## used to listen to them when i was
## younger
## i have to admit i i i know it seems like