## i just want to make sure that i
## cover everything for you guys and
## i appreciate you guys being a part of
## this live stream all right moving on
## this approach is pure honesty telling someone the
## truth is the most respectful thing you can do for
## them when you agree with every statement said by
## the bystander they will often lose respect for you
## and you will lose respect so you will lose control
## of the conversation they see that your desire to
## be validated by them is stronger than your desire
## to end animal cruelty thereby making a mockery of
## animal rights this one needs to be repeated
## they see that your desire to be validated by
## them is stronger than your desire to end animal
## cruelty thereby making a mockery of animal rights
## you imagine if the primary goal of human rights
## activists was to be liked by the oppressors
## 30 seconds
## all right that's 30 seconds i'm liking
## the 30 seconds it feels like the right
## amount of time here moving on
## whenever you are afraid to speak up for animals
## directly or if bystanders call you too extreme
## place yourself in the victim's position and
## analyze your approach from their perspective would
## you consider a respectful yet direct conversation
## too extreme if you were locked in a slaughterhouse
## and that's the thing you know we are being
## respectful here it's the most respect you'll
## ever show someone because you're telling
## the truth and giving them a true opportunity
## to end their hypocrisy and to stop
## abusing innocent beings like a psychopath
## like a cold-blooded monster
## that's what these people
## are especially once they know about what is
## going on and they continue to do it right
## um i forgot to press start on the 30 seconds
## so let's just say we're up to 15 seconds now
## yes honesty is the highest form of intimacy this
## might be irritating to some but it may not stop us
## from telling the truth that's beautiful
## yeah that's so true honesty is the
## highest form of intimacy word all right
## moving on guys all right so next slide
## don't talk about health and environment
## why do we think people care about either
## most people in the streets do not care
## about their health nor the environment
## so rooting your outreach in these topics will
## marginalize the animals even further health and
## environment may become have become exacerbated
## because people do not take animal abuse seriously
## um again i need to repeat this
## point because this is really
## powerful to know and understand that these
## crisis that we're facing that we're facing
## that we're facing with our
## environment and our health
## is just an indication merely a a sign that's all
## it is of how bad animal abuse is on this planet
## again i was supposed to press start there
## um oh no i haven't finished this all right
## um the last point trying to hook people with
## an approach that revolves around what benefits
## them does not let me start again trying to hook
## people with an approach that revolves around what
## that revolves around what benefits
## them does a disservice to the animals
## focus on the root cause of
## the issue the animal abuse
## i kind of stumbled through that one but you
## get the point you can see it i'm going to
## start this 30 seconds if you guys have anything
## you'd like me to expand on here let me know
## people say this is fake that it's not
## true what to say just point at the screens