##  FISH
## 2700 BILLION MARINE ANIMALS
## KILLED EVERY YEAR
## DRAG-FISHED FROM THE OCEANS
## AND LET YOURSELF CHOK
##  FUR
## THEIR WHOLE EXISTENCE
## ALL THIS SUFFERING
## FOR FASHION
##  FEATHER
## SPENGE WITHOUT ANESTHESIA
##  EGGS
## THE MALES OF THE SAYING HENS
## THEY ARE CONSIDERED USELESS
## A FEW MINUTES FROM BIRTH
## ALL ARE KILLED
## THIS IS STANDARD PRACTICE
## ALSO IN OUTDOOR FARMINGS
## BIOLOGICAL
## THE FEMALES ARE SORTED
## AND SENT TO AGRICULTURAL COMPANIES
## THEIR WHOLE EXISTENCE
## EXPLOIT FOR THE
## THEIR EGGS
## OUTDOOR FARMING
## RAISED OUTDOORS
## WHEN NO LONGER PROFITABLE
## THEY ARE SENT TO THE SLAUGHTERHOUSE
## TO A FRACTION OF THEIR
## NATURAL LONGEVITY
## ALL THIS DEATH FOR AN OMELETTE
##  ANIMAL TEST