## people ask me more questions about it so
## i do understand what you've just been
## through and i do understand that this
## was a shitty thing to do
## and i really do appreciate you coming
## and doing it and i'm sure i'm sure there
## are other people
## who have people have already been saying
## in the chat you can check later that
## they also really appreciate you coming
## doing this and
## and they support you and um one person
## even said
## they originally didn't support you but
## after
## seeing some of your videos they were
## like okay no i actually really hope that
## they can work this out so
## you know this is people i feel like
## people want
## to support and i hope this can bring
## some of that support back for people who
## have maybe
## got lost or confused along the way
## because of all this [ __ ] um
## so yeah thank you so much is there
## anything you want to say clutton closing
## any points you want to add just thank
## you also david
## thanks for uh taking the time because
## it's important i think as a
## member of the animal rights movement to
## want to clarify these things
## it's not really about us again it's
## about the tone
## it's about the precedent we set for
## others in this movement
## absolutely saw any any final words
## just thank you and um
## thank you to anyone who sent their
## questions or you know anyone who joined
## this live
## and they were commenting and watching
## this live so yeah
## that's it thanks for having us david
## awesome and a little bit more
## housekeeping just before we go
## um there is another live stream today
## and it will be
## at 8 pm my time so i don't know what
## that is your time this is
## just completely separate this is just to
## discuss uh all of the
## different topics that i went through in
## the five minute friday so people
## watching if you're if you want to come
## to that and do come to that
## and it'll be the usual style of live
## stream where we just go through topics
## and
## uh and also laugh at some anti-vegan
## [ __ ]
## kind of standard stuff uh so come on
## come along for that
## and um don't forget to share this video
## with anyone who's giving you [ __ ] if
## they are giving you [ __ ]
## and also of course don't expect that
## this video will make a difference some
## people don't want to understand some
## people aren't interested in av anymore
## and they just they're just done
## that's totally fine don't get upset if
## it happens just just you do you and let
## them do them and
## and that's it you know don't don't take
## it personally
## yeah i would say it's the same with
## non-vegans who
## many non-vegans aren't reachable aren't
## willing
## and there's no point in continuing to
## outreach those individuals either
## it's the same thing with vegans yep sure
## all right cool we'll end it there thanks
## so much bye everyone
## thank you