## also throwing those animals onto the ice every
## time they score a goal and he was going nuts
## and then the radio guy said whoa gary chill
## chill what did you have for dinner last night
## and then gary was like a salad
## and it was that moment that he realized that no
## other answer could have been acceptable and the
## hypocrisy was what got gary yourofsky to go vegan
## that night he said was the night that he went
## vegan i heard stories about the elephant story
## in michigan he talked about a circus incident and
## then there was this other incident but it wasn't
## that he was going to thorn apple valley pig farm
## in in michigan and seeing pigs being slaughtered
## every day he kept going and witnessing he couldn't
## believe that this was going on he hadn't gone
## vegan until that guy said you're a hypocrite
## so please understand how powerful that is even the
## best activists that we know of the most effective
## this is what caused them to go vegan it's
## the same thing for me it's the same exact
## story for me when i realized from listening to
## gary that i was a hypocrite if i wasn't vegan
## and there's no way you can justify
## even a little bit of animal consumption
## that's when i became vegan but prior to that i
## was bullshitting i was plant-based i would eat
## salmon sometimes i'd wear leather i was
## raw vegan while wearing leather jackets
## i could take you through a typical interaction
## if you'd like from start to end would you like
## that yeah yep so we start the conversation
## by would you like to know why we're here
## they need to say something affirmative for the
## conversation to go ahead they either say yes or
## they try to guess and that's an affirmative answer
## so you continue yes what we're doing here is we're
## showing the standard practice footage of what
## happens in the meat dairy in egg industries and
## other industries that abuse animals and we're also
## showing free-range grass-fed organic cage-free
## humane certified hey guys would you like to know
## why we're here i'm guessing against animal cruelty
## that is a good guess what we're showing on
## the screens is the animal industries meat
## dairy and eggs and other industries also that
## abuse animals for products would you like to
## hear what we're doing here um sure cool yes what
## we're doing is we're showing the behind the scenes
## of industries that abuse animals so this is in
## the meat industry dairy industry egg industry
## we're showing is also the best of the best so
## this is free range cage free humane certified
## all right would you like to hear what we're doing
## here yes what we're doing is we're showing the
## behind the scenes of industries that abuse animals
## like meat dairy eggs leather the next question you
## have to ask them is how do you feel about animal
## abuse usually they say well it's obviously wrong
## 100 against it that's what they usually say
## people say okay so you think this is wrong
## would you say this is evil this is me doubling
## down to make sure i've owned them on this point
## would you say this is evil would you say that
## this is evil yes treating animals like our slaves
## yeah would you say that stabbing animals to
## death for a sandwich is wrong yeah yeah yeah
## that's hard what are your initial thoughts how
## does this kind of stuff make you guys feel guilty
## yeah so it's safe to say that you guys are
## against animal abuse yeah for sure i want you
## all right i just want to clarify that again there
## was an update here that we've made um i don't
## think that closed-ended questions are actually as
## effective as open-ended questions in this segment
## of the interaction so instead of saying do you
## think stabbing an animal to death for a sandwich
## or torturing animals to death is evil
## do you think that's evil do you think
## that's wrong it's a closed-ended
## question it's an obvious question
## it's in fact more important for you to say how do
## you feel about animal abuse and then when they say
## i feel guilty i feel horrible it's terrible and
## then the next thing you need to do to just confirm
## their position on animal abuse is to say is it
## safe to say that you are against animal abuse
## and in in some circumstances i might even
## triple down and say would you say it's evil
## so you need to ask that open-ended question
## first and then the closed-ended question
## just to confirm and seal it off now
## that will make sense why you need to
## do that as i continue on with the approach
## here showing you the step-by-step process
## the footage how does it make you feel it makes
## me cringe cringe why do you think it makes you
## feel that way because i love the animals you love
## animals interesting so safe to say you're against