## what part of this is fake challenge them to go
## into a farm for themselves and see what happens
## in a slaughterhouse specifically say because
## that's where all the animals end up right
## uh i
## i feel that i don't want to be friends with
## people after giving information anymore
## who won't go vegan well that's
## the right position i think
## you wouldn't again when you compare this
## to any other injustice you wouldn't stick
## around and be friends with people who continue to
## enslave torture and murder once they know better
## if we were the victims we would not want our
## advocates to prioritize the environment or our
## oppressor's health no and it would it would be a
## huge spit in your face to do that that's the whole
## point of clarifying this for you guys because
## the victims deserve so much better from us to
## be advocating directly for them and they they do
## deserve a direct message that's dedicated to them
## yes yes okay um what are some variable ways
## to start the conversation other than have
## you seen this type of footage before we don't
## actually ask that anymore have you seen this
## type of footage before we do sometimes
## but in this approach with this update
## you don't need to ask that in fact what we do
## is we say would you like to know why we're here
## um so vegan mark i'm not sure if you're just
## joining the stream but we did cover this you
## might want to watch this video back and it will
## be available for everyone to watch back once i'm
## done and we did cover that raping is bad for
## your health yeah that's what it sounds like
## never met a 100 zero waste and whole food
## vegan so why expect non-vegans to care
## exactly summer it's so obvious isn't it i always
## say health and environment are just consequences
## of animal abuse and our mentality towards animals
## and if we want to solve a problem we have to pull
## the root of evil out very well said david if
## you said that to me when i wasn't vegan that
## would punch me in the stomach in the best way you
## can see you can say would you like to know why
## we're here today yes thank you jaz you've been
## paying attention all right cool let's move on
## why don't people care about ethics let's explore
## that because vegans don't advocate for animals
## correctly they focus on things like plant-based
## recipes restaurants weight loss or deforestation
## another reason is they lead with
## phrases like friends not food
## or animal lovers don't eat animals this
## is not a conversation about sympathy
## this is a conversation about accountability
## don't plead with bystanders make them understand
## the consequences of their choices by
## placing them in the victim's position
## 30 seconds i don't have anything else to add
## to this unless you guys want me to expand on it
## um check out the majority of vegans online
## rather not just on instagram vegan king
## they don't even talk about animals yeah
## it seems like in this movement that the
## animals barely get a mention they barely get a
## shout out and we quickly move on to humans and
## humans humans humans how does this
## affect humans let's talk about that
## when humans are the oppressors it's just
## backwards
## all right cool you guys don't have anything uh you
## want me to expand on here so i'm going to move on
## all right next slide morality is black and white
## when it comes to this issue specifically i'm
## talking about guys okay i'm not talking about
## these fringe gray area examples that could be
## brought up with very insignificant choices
## you could say this is very significant and
## it's involving in it's involving oppression so
## when you're talking about an issue of oppression
## where there are victims involved morality is black
## and white when it comes to that if bystanders tell
## you that you aren't considering the other side
## to this or you aren't open-minded enough that is
## a distraction there is no other side to needless
## animal abuse you either support it or you don't