## but i'm only telling you this because it's the
## truth and it's what i've learned to be true
## people avoid animal rights and make you
## think they don't care about animal rights
## for a reason it's a distraction like i said
## they create distractions they don't want to
## face something that's obviously wrong and then you
## buy into that by then pandering to environment and
## health people don't care about animals because the
## way that we advocate veganism to people doesn't
## care about animals it seems like in this movement
## the more i hear people advocating for veganism
## the less i hear animal rights being tied into it
## they quickly get mentioned and then we move on to
## how this is really bad for the environment and
## really bad for your health so that's why people
## don't care about animal rights the vegan movement
## hasn't been promoting animal rights i also just
## want to say this those who say that what i'm doing
## is aggressive that this isn't compassionate well
## the irony the way i see it is the irony is that
## when people aren't advocating for the animals
## in the way that they communicate directly then
## you're actually putting the compassion you want
## to receive from the abuser before the compassion
## you're supposed to be extending to the victim
## i think that's hypocrisy right if we truly
## are compassionate beings then we need to
## extend compassion to the victims and when we're
## talking to the abuser like i've already explained
## it is actually the truest form of compassion to
## offer the abuser education what do we usually
## do with abusers we put them in prison don't we
## right if these beings were any other species
## other than a non-human so if they were human
## these people would be put in prison wouldn't
## they there would be no conversation
## on the streets no trying to convince
## people so this is compassion this is the most
## compassionate thing we can possibly do is try to
## wake people up with our words but if we pander
## and we move away from animal rights when we're
## talking to people then we're only doing more of
## an injustice more of a disservice to the animals
## it's not about how people feel about animals do
## you have a dog at home do you have a cat at home
## a lot of the times we as vegans try to lean on
## the compassion that we think they already have
## for animals for non-human animals we use dogs
## as examples a lot in this movement we try to say
## would you do this to your dog how would you
## feel if your dog was eaten what about if a
## dog was getting beaten up right in front of us
## right now would you act on it that blows up in
## our face a lot of the time replace all those
## cows with dogs just for a moment in your mind
## dogs don't produce milk yes they do yeah they do
## but not like yeah it's hard to i don't i try just
## morally i make that comment just for you to
## consider it morally what is the difference between
## puppies being raised all the female puppies to
## get milk out of them instead of cows i don't feel
## different you don't feel any different why do we
## think we live in a society that cares about dogs
## why do we think that i don't understand why our
## movement thinks that we live in a society full
## of dog lovers if we truly love dogs would we have
## shelters that kill dogs by the thousand every day
## around the world clearly if we lived in a
## society of dog lovers just the same way that we
## love human children then we'd have people
## protesting at the front of shelters all the time
## but that's not happening if you said that stuff
## to me it wouldn't really work because i was never
## really a dog lover growing up but my point is
## to say that this isn't an animal conversation
## this is an accountability conversation if you
## were talking to me about the blood on my hands
## if you're talking to me about the harm i'm
## causing to beings who suffer like i suffer
## it doesn't matter about how i feel about animals
## it matters but how i feel about causing suffering
## i also need to make this clear a lot of people
## out there think that morality is subjective when
## it comes to this morality is as objective as
## it gets it's as black and white as my t-shirt
## when it comes to animal rights people will love
## for you to think that there's a great area that
## there's something that you're not considering
## you're not open-minded enough what about
## if you're on a deserted island or those who don't
## have you know access to they always try to bring
## up great areas to this to see where the morality
## can slip it doesn't ever slip you're never going
## to wake up one day and think animal abuse is
## justified are you you're not gonna go back