## been
## communicated better um and that's why
## before we removed it we actually went in
## and edited the post a little bit so we
## changed the wording in certain parts
## um so that there was more
## empathy or you know it didn't come
## across as insensitive
## like you said but absolutely no
## it wasn't yes so i think i think that's
## that's a
## a wider issue really isn't it
## insensitivity versus
## uh versus racism or or whatever ism you
## want to attach it's uh
## it's not bigoted to be insensitive um
## it's
## some people are i don't know harsher
## than others
## and i think um on a personal level i
## think i think that's
## where a lot of the criticisms and
## accusations come from with av
## i don't think it's uh i think it is that
## our movement is quite a sensitive
## movement with very sensitive people and
## av isn't isn't very sensitive and that's
## that's not i don't mean that as a
## criticism at all i mean that as in
## some people don't like that and that's
## that's you know that's where we get a
## lot of
## a lot of people who come up and speak up
## about it whereas if you look at an
## organization like save for example
## they're the complete opposite side
## they're extremely sensitive
## and so they attract a lot of people who
## are uh you know also extremely sensitive
## which happens to be
## the vast majority of of the animal
## rights movement and
## the vegan movement people tend to be
## very sensitive
## in these groups so you know i can see i
## can see where the accusations come
## flying in from but um
## i think if they were accusing you of
## insensitivity and and being too mean
## i think that would probably be not as
## nowhere near as harmful as
## throwing the word racist at every turn
## you know
## that's my observation anyway that's what
## i'm observing from the outside
## and this kind of track this this
## continues really with the social media
## people
## have been upset by your social media
## quite a lot and i know some of these
## examples are going to be very easy to
## discuss but we'll start off with the
## most difficult one
## just to uh kick it off with this um
## i want to discuss the whole uh the whole
## hitler thing
## and george because a few people asked me
## about this they asked me about george
## they asked me about this post this
## this uh which obviously i know you
## removed it um
## but they kind of want to know how it got
## to the point where
## someone in the organization would think
## about making a post
## a comment like that and kind of what you
## guys think about it so
## if again for those who don't know there
## was the um
## there was a post made i believe it was
## it was avs page as well wasn't it on
## facebook it was a comment
## um where the comment was talking about
## hitler
## and it was comparing hitler and the it
## was saying basically
## out of context here by the way
## completely out of context and i've not
## got the screen shot so i'm not going to
## put it up but out of out of context it
## was making a comparison
## and saying that the holocaust that
## hitler did
## had more justification than the
## holocaust of the animals i'm
## paraphrasing here it was put into a
## better context than that but that's
## that was the takeaway message that it
## was it had more justification because a
## book was written about
## it practically or have i missed a big
## point there but either way
## that seemed to be the take away point
## from it um out of context and that was
## obviously posted by
## i believe george in the in the
## organization on as av
## so like what happened with this have i
## got that wrong have people got that
## wrong
## and
## he's not saying that he wasn't saying
## like legitimate justifications were
## were afoot in those cases he was saying
## that
## more reasons were provided by hitler and
## his regime uh
## to the public then then the re then then
## what non-vegans offer
## to the public regarding the injustice
## that they're involved in that's what he
## was saying
## but the way that he said it lacked eq
## you got to have iq george is a smart guy
## but you got to have eq2 you got to read
## the room and not be an idiot about how
## you communicate emotionally
## uh so that's the thing it wasn't clear
## enough the communication we identified
## as something that needs to be improved
## and that's why we
## addressed the whole
## blm post to begin with
## uh the way that we did it was about the
## communication
## um and we still feel justified in
## addressing
## what we addressed and we will continue
## to do so
## but um i think you know sometimes
## yeah the issue there was um
## sometimes there is bias that's brought
## into the work
## that people are doing within ab
## they bring their own biases whether
## they're political or
## otherwise in the way that they
## communicate
## and people need to remember if they're
## working with av they're representing ap
## just like
## with any other org or group that they're
## working with
## and when you're representing us
## we don't want that and you know he also