## hmm
## moving on
## we're nearly nearly finished
## with these slides also guys
## typical outreach structure ask them do
## they think it's possible to be against
## animal abuse while demanding
## products like meat dairy and eggs
## i don't think we covered this in the uh
## presentation but this is a powerful point
## i'm going to read it again ask them do you
## think it's possible to be against animal
## abuse while demanding products like meat dairy
## and eggs ask them what is stopping them from
## not abusing animals and being vegan what
## do you feel like would be stopping you from
## not abusing animals and being vegan this
## will lead to their objections 30 seconds
## how to respond if they
## don't consider those footage
## wow let me read this question out um how to
## respond if people don't consider the footage
## to be animal abuse you have no conversation to be
## having with that person move on to the next person
## if blood flying everywhere and heads being cut
## off is not animal abuse if baby male chicks if
## baby chicks are being grinded alive in a big
## blender and they don't think that's animal abuse
## you're not talking to a rational person so i would
## say you need to move on to the next person jezebel
## if they say they don't care about animal
## abuse is it best just to end the conversation
## i would say what if you were the one being
## abused would you care then or it's easy to
## say when you're the abuser what if you were the
## one being abused that's the upgrade there for you
## and then move on if it goes
## downhill from there because
## this is not a rational open and
## willing person you're speaking to
## carlo recently you said in a video
## we have to avoid the word vegan i'm
## a little confused about it now so you suggest
## to openly say we are promoting veganism or not
## i never said to not use the word vegan in
## fact i say i said that i used the word vegan
## it's just what i'm saying carlo is that
## it's far more effective for us to explain
## what the meaning like to say
## human supremacy or animal abuse
## you know to detail what it really means to be
## vegan like if in this point um if i mean at
## this point in the conversation you're saying if
## we are saying that we're promoting veganism um
## this is it depends this is something that i would
## say if someone says you're promoting vegetarianism
## i would correct that and say we're not promoting
## vegetarianism because that doesn't address the
## issue at all we're promoting veganism so i would
## not shy away from saying the word vegan however
## it's usually best for you to talk about what that
## word actually means than to just use the word
## why because the word has a lot of confusion
## around it within the animal rights movement
## you can see how there's so
## many definitions flying around
## and that's why we started this with
## the definition of veganism itself
## even if they are killed quickly it is
## still animal abuse of course because again
## if you were the victim it is still abuse to take
## your life even if it's done quickly of course
## you would see it as abuse in that circumstance you
## know the jews who were killed in the concentration
## camps if they were gassed and killed quickly
## that doesn't make the injustice any less worse
## cool um moving on next slide objection handling
## whenever a bystander brings up an objection
## place them in the victim's position
## and allow them to analyze the objection
## from that perspective every single time
## this happens the objection will fall apart
## most objections are easy and quick to respond
## to some are more nuanced and require a deeper