## like the major donations coming in
## um so the biggest
## part of it would obviously be the
## payments to the team members so
## including myself paul and um at
## some point we had just over 30 people
## working with av
## so you can imagine how much that would
## cost roughly
## and then now we've got i think
## i don't know actually how many people
## we've got like around 20 people working
## with us
## including us too so the the bulk of it
## is going towards payments so that those
## people
## can continue to work for av and then
## the second biggest um thing
## has always been the av fund which is
## something that we started
## um and we would dedicate a certain
## amount of money to go towards chapters
## that were
## um you know active chapters that needed
## some help getting their equipment so
## that was always like
## the second um biggest expense for us
## and then yeah the rest of it is just you
## know if if people look into
## what costs are involved in terms of you
## know all the admin stuff all the
## programs that you need the software's
## the subscriptions
## and then all the big campaigns that we
## were doing as well so
## okay and with the staff they were 30
## were they all full-time
## 30 staff um no we had
## so we um
## we have people that work with us as
## contractors so av doesn't have like
## staff
## necessarily but um everyone's like an
## independent contractor that comes in and
## they can do
## um part-time or full-time and
## um i think i would say maybe it's
## half-half
## half of the people that work with us are
## full-time half are part-time
## um or just come in as volunteers even
## sometimes
## they they do some work casually yeah
## cool okay so i'm just trying to like put
## a number on it i think for
## anyone who maybe is not following um so
## like 30 staff if you had 30 staff that
## were
## only working let's say like not
## full-time hours they so they're working
## part-time hours right so let's imagine
## it's 30 staff working 20 hours a week so
## we'll go
## like we'll go low right we'll pitch low
## here 30 staff working
## 20 hours a week and let's imagine that
## the
## i'm going to work in yearly salaries
## here like base yearly salary in euros
## for example
## the absolute minimum you could earn a
## year to survive in a
## place like i don't know let's pick a
## cheap let's baseline everything low
## let's go low on everything the minimum
## you could earn in a year
## in somewhere like spain for example
## would be like because that's where i
## know
## it's like 16 000 euros a year it's the
## absolute minimum and that's really
## pushing it like it's really difficult
## and that would be a full-time salary
## so that's like that's half that 8 000 a
## year
## and let's imagine that's 30 staff that's
## 240 000 euros a year
## that's it that's pitching low that's if
## you have no full-time staff that's if
## all of your staff are only working like
## like half-time hours let's imagine right
## so just to put that into perspective for
## anyone who's wondering how much that
## would be so like it could it could be
## anywhere upwards from 240 000
## euros a year which would be like i don't
## know 300 000 us dollars maybe something
## like that
## so that is that is a huge chunk yeah and
## i think when i when i first watched a
## video and i heard that
## and i worked it out myself at that time
## and i was like yeah that's actually a
## chunk of money
## that i don't think many people
## understand right
## um it doesn't it doesn't sound like a
## lot but when you actually calculated it
## is quite a lot so
## um the next thing then you talked about
## the the av
## uh fund the for the for the chapters
## where does it come from then that that
## does this apparently this is a rumor
## okay there's no i don't have evidence of
## this and i'm sure there isn't evidence
## of this
## uh maybe there's one or two organizers
## who have caused this problem
## but where is it coming from that the
## chapters are not getting the funding
## where has that started do you know where
## that came from
## or do you know what's going what what is
## actually behind it like are they getting
## the funding
## i'm sorry to ask the question but it
## came it came up a lot again
## no i think it's the same thing as
## everything else like
## somebody just started this rumor that av
## keeps the money
## or specifically paul and style keep the
## money to themselves and they don't
## send any money to the chapters i think
## it's just
## again we don't even know where this came
## from but
## if people were really interested this is
## one thing that can be easily tracked
## we have a full list of everyone who ever
## received the fund
## how much they received it what they
## spent it on
## and um because everyone who receives the
## fund
## they were supposed to send us the
## invoices so it's like
## we have all the records and
## um i guess the only thing is that p
## we weren't um doing it in a way that
## just as
## as soon as you become an organizer you