## that video
## there's no way to determine this we i
## i'm only
## uh making an educated guess here okay
## so even after hours and hours of
## research being put into that video that
## was her conclusion
## but how are these individuals coming to
## this conclusion when
## is where is his daughter even being
## logged
## how all those marine animals that are
## slaughtered in the fish industry are
## they being logged
## who's who's noting how many animals are
## being murdered like
## it's all an assumption and um i wouldn't
## trust
## any any piece of information coming from
## animal agriculture
## of course or any study that's funded by
## animal agriculture of course
## if it says something to the effect that
## their products are on the rise and
## they're doing really well and all this i
## wouldn't trust that
## and especially since we know actually
## that the dairy industry is on its way
## out
## there's many indicators of that so it
## depends on
## what you're looking at and i need more
## data and more evidence
## to even entertain the notion that uh
## that it's going in the opposite
## direction in terms of the numbers
## however
## in terms of public perception and the
## way that animal rights is perceived
## publicly now animal rights has been
## pushed even further back than it was
## last year i do agree with that
## yeah no totally i agree all right that
## brings us to the end of my topics
## um and now if you if you i guess it's
## late for you guys actually but if you do
## have another like let's say let's limit
## it to maybe like
## i don't know would you agree for another
## 20 minutes is that okay 30 minutes or is
## that is that too much for you guys right
## now
## 20 minutes sounds good all right i can
## see
## yeah i'm waking up and you're and you're
## going to bed so this is kind of like
## yeah yeah how late is it sorry what time
## 40. all right okay cool yeah we can
## start to wrap up then so
## um guys you got to put some questions in
## um
## i didn't see you putting any questions
## in so far i'm not going to go back
## through
## all the way back to the beginning
## because i know some of you aren't even
## here anymore so if you've got questions
## now's the time
## and if you really really want your
## question to be asked like right now and
## you want it to make sure you fit it in
## 20 minutes in the next 20 minutes then
## you can uh
## do a super chat and that will 100 be
## asked as long as it's not
## something shitty um to be to put it
## bluntly
## uh but yeah we're open to questions now
## for the next like
## 20 minutes or so but after that i'm
## going to let them go to bed so
## i'm going to run to the toilet go go no
## worries
## no worries and whilst whilst waiting for
## that yeah i just want to say i do
## really appreciate you both coming on
## here i know it's it's mentally
## exhausting to go through these things
## um especially considering that some of
## them are really ugly
## accusations right um i've i've the
## reason one of the main reasons i wanted
## to do it as well is because i feel like
## i can
## empathize with this because i've also
## been on the receiving end of equally
## ugly accusations so i know
## i know how it feels when you read that
## like we all we all pretend like yeah
## well
## whatever you know whatever but like
## really it does
## it does get you right when you read
## something so horrible and someone's
## saying it about you
## i know how it feels so i'm happy we
## could get through this and and you know
## i hope a few people have had uh i hope
## it's given a few people something to
## think about at least so they don't go
## and
## repeat this nonsense uh over and over
## again because it doesn't
## it doesn't feel good to read it does it
## you know
## yeah i just hope that what people can
## take from
## this maybe is that they start thinking a
## bit more critically and if they hear
## something they ask for evidence they ask
## for proof
## you know they look into it before
## deciding that somebody is a racist
## sexist etc
## because these are horrible things that
## you can say and
## yeah i just it's sad that people can
## just use this term so loosely now and
## they don't realize
## how insulting and destructive that is
## and how much it actually takes away
## from the real victims of these
## um depression so yeah
## no for sure um
## yeah i'm gonna be honest with you it
## doesn't look like there's any questions
## coming in i guess i guess we kind of
## answered so much
## i guess they don't have any anything
## else that's not being answered to be
## honest i thought about this earlier in
## that we've gone through so many topics
## that maybe there aren't going to be
## questions
## because there's like 60 people watching
## right now and so far
## there's no questions so if that's the
## case we can we can wrap up
## there's a lot of statements though i can
## put some of those on the screen you know
## just like for the last like maybe like
## 10 minutes or so just
## being king saying here they don't have
## evidence for their claims and when they
## do it's hilarious
## i i mean this is how it seems to be
## right that they there's no evidence or
## there is
## evidence but it's not evidence like it's
## something they have made a
## i don't know they've made it some kind
## of assumption from or they've twisted
## right
## yeah this seems to be happening most of