## don't get lost in these distractions compare
## animal abuse to a comparable injustice to get
## you back on track and like i was saying earlier
## on in this video the best injustice to compare to
## is the one that involves the individual you're
## speaking to as the victim so if they imagine
## themselves as the victim of the injustice that
## you're speaking about when you compare it that's
## going to be the best way for them to feel what
## it is they need to feel in that moment 30 seconds
## good night daniel thank you
## for being a part of this man
## uh i don't know who epa is david
## all right we've done 30 seconds i
## don't see anything you guys want me to
## expand on here so we're going to move on
## all right moving on so the next
## slide where we got to the 12th slide
## okay which injustices to compare to so i
## actually break this last point i just made
## even further down in this slide it is most
## effective to compare to injustices such as
## child abuse or human trafficking child abuse and
## human trafficking are the most comparable human
## injustices that we've found to compare to the
## most effective comparison to make is to place
## the bystander in the victim's position i just
## explained that but that's there for you again to
## absorb i really want you to take that
## into consideration and really absorb that
## avoid dog comparisons this goes
## back to not leading with compassion
## it's not about the love people feel towards
## animals it's about the hate they feel towards
## injustice and i would say injustice in their name
## or because of them not in their name but because
## of their actions right in their name is kind of an
## ego thing it doesn't come down to whether you can
## imagine your dog in a slaughterhouse it comes
## down to whether you can imagine yourself in a
## slaughterhouse right i'm going to repeat that it
## doesn't come down to whether you can imagine your
## dog in a slaughterhouse it comes down to whether
## you can imagine yourself in a slaughterhouse
## that's the truth that's what makes
## you really wake up to this 30 seconds
## yeah so carlo about the moralities
## black and white you have to
## clarify that specifically we're talking
## about injustices that involve victims
## oppression these things are black and white
## if it's needless and this is it needs to stop
## it's really simple you don't need to
## necessarily say morality is black and white
## i'm just pointing this out in this in
## this workshop for you guys that you need
## to understand morality is black and white and the
## way that you communicate this to other people but
## you don't necessarily need to say morality
## is black and white in those words but yeah
## if people want to get into a philosophical
## discussion you know just put an end to that
## america's environmental protection agency is
## the epa which is a broken government system
## uh yeah i wouldn't i don't have any interest
## um okay yeah people just say they don't mind
## eating dogs as well it happens so often yeah
## what about dogs yeah well if i had to eat a dog
## i would it just immediately blows up in our face
## um and i'm talking about most of the time here dog
## comparisons seemingly work niraj they seemingly
## work because your indicator of an effective
## conversation might be someone doing this uh-huh
## yes i agree yes uh-huh that's not necessarily
## effective it's very easy to agree with things like