## into everything that's right here before us it
## starts with us and then here on this planet we
## want to try to find a home on mars and yet we
## don't even know how to get things right here
## it makes no sense so that's my answer
## to that all right so next question um
## um
## all right so
## long day yeah cool that sounds good laura
## both three hour cubes you're doing
## two for international cube day awesome
## cool a question here about whether it has
## started or not we are about to get started
## i'm taking some questions just to get this started
## and then we're going to get into the meat of this
## uh much love sylvia thank you for the support
## and thank you for representing us
## how to talk to a parent or turn how to talk to
## a parent to turn them vegan if he or she doesn't
## want to hear about animal suffering anytime
## i try to talk about he she walks out of the
## room and hangs up the phone etc agatha aguita's
## question regarding parents it's no different to
## talking to anybody else you hold human beings
## accountable for the evils they commit against
## non-human animals whether they're family or
## friends doesn't matter because they're guilty just
## the same as anybody else the thing with family is
## you obviously have more of an affinity with family
## and that means that you should give them more
## patience more effort more of an explanation more
## not an explanation it's just more time more time
## but at a certain point you have to say to yourself
## i have done my best and they aren't open
## and willing to end their human supremacy
## and i know it's a hard road to walk but it's the
## truth and i have dedicated myself to truth on this
## planet i want my life to be dedicated to that and
## nothing else so so that comes first i'm a human
## being dedicated to truth before i am a human being
## that belongs to a family does that make sense
## um i also do think that family could be
## one of the biggest downfalls of society
## but i'm not going to get into that all
## right so moving on another question here
## about overpopulation i'm just going
## to quickly answer this but this is
## going to be the last question i answer
## before we get started and i want to
## thank you for your patience guys all
## right so the next question here is
## when we've solved the overpopulation of pet
## animal issue do you think that we can still have
## companion animals but create a solution when none
## die in shelters yeah absolutely like sanctuaries
## all of these shelters should be turned
## into sanctuaries instead of a kill business
## all right i'm going to get started
## now guys thanks for your patience so
## i'm going to share my screen i'm going to
## need your feedback in the comments so please
## light it up with feedback
## about the video and the audio
## okay down that's come on
## uh okay