## did admit to doing this himself um so
## it's not just an opinion that we had
## this was really happening and that that
## was the issue that you're pointing out
## david
## sure and and george and another
## individual they were
## removed from the team was was that
## because of this specific example or was
## there another reason that these
## individuals were removed
## there was another question somebody
## asked that was one of the comments
## but there were other comments left
## um by george but also it was the
## conversations we had in private with
## them
## about the issue i believe the comments
## were about
## um denying that systemic oppression
## exists
## and how that comment was left by our
## social media
## members without them running it by us
## and that's not something that um
## just didn't align with us or av or other
## team members so that's why
## we had to have private conversations to
## clarify this and that
## and during those conversations we
## realized that we're just not aligned
## and it was just not possible at that
## point to have them on the team
## yeah just to clarify yeah because it
## might be confused by people
## in what we're saying here uh that like
## gemma and george were
## like fired on the same premise they
## weren't removed from av
## on the same premise there was a
## different uh scenario for those both
## individuals like we
## a different decision process for both
## those individuals there were different
## things that occurred with george as well
## it wasn't just one thing it wasn't one
## comment
## or one point multiple comments and then
## multiple conversations that we were
## having that
## made it clear that yeah but it was
## different
## and and it wasn't just this no i was
## like another example was about
## how because the comment that you just
## read out i didn't remember that one but
## i know there was another one
## going around what our team said
## systemic oppression doesn't exist in the
## west or something like that which
## we were getting lots of messages about
## and so i do remember that very clearly
## right there were i think there were
## multiple things
## otherwise we wouldn't just ask someone
## to leave the team over one
## comment especially someone who was an
## asset to the organization
## george was a prized member of the team
## whom i really liked working with and i
## thought that he was a great
## member so it's ridiculous that we would
## um yeah it's tough to be in this
## position um
## you know that's the thing also like
## it sucks to have to fire someone like
## george yeah i just want to add because
## it's okay to have
## your own political views your religious
## views
## but if you are commenting as a v
## as a part of the team and then those
## views are coming
## through your comments and your messages
## then that's not okay
## because within the team like i said we
## have over 20 people or something
## and we all have different views and then
## we have our own political views or our
## own
## views on god or religion or whatever but
## you never see us
## commenting about it when we're
## commenting as a v because
## av is supposed to represent something
## that is just about the animal so
## regardless of your views you can be a
## part of that and
## that was the issue that it was just not
## possible to
## to have that with those individuals and
## people don't seem to be
## wanting to work with us to create
## the most conducive organization
## that is dedicated to the animals
## people don't seem to be working with us
## to achieve this
## we seem to be dedicated to it and
## everyone seems to be pushing back and
## pushing back and pushing back
## we are open to ideas we want to see how
## we can help
## other like other things here but
## we have like us i was saying we have
## other people in the organization
## who have even stronger political views
## than george do
## than george does even stronger political
## views than than george does
## think i mean think about that you know
## yeah sure and they don't they don't ever
## they never let their advisors come
## through their work
## so that's but again when it's not to
## focus on just one point here because it
## wasn't just one a one-dimensional
## decision
## it was multi-dimensional and that that's
## also kind of entwined with the uh
## intertwined the
## with another kind of criticism i had
## about the
## comments like uh there were i don't know
## if there still are i haven't seen any
## since this but
## there were quite a lot of let's say rude
## comments
## um on on the av social media let's say
## like
## sometimes i think i even saw one someone