## and the way that they try to make vegans think
## that plants have feelings for example like they
## really get deep into it and they're like yeah
## like they feel stuff and like yeah they're like
## they act like they really believe it but it's
## just their cunningness is a lie it's really
## their guilt trying to double down you know so um
## are there any questions here i'm not even going
## to do the 30 seconds thing because i've given
## you guys plenty of time while i've been talking
## yes it does stay online afterwards malia
## this will be available online once i'm done
## you can tell by their body language when they're
## not even looking at the footage because they're
## only there to waste our time yeah if they don't
## want to be there just get them to go just go
## indirect distractions and so on yes exactly
## indirect distractions that's what it is
## all right moving on guys it doesn't seem like
## you guys want me to expand on much here so i
## might even just keep this moving at a quicker
## pace activism is not sales sales training does
## not equal good activism using slick talk to trick
## people into veganism doesn't work your job is to
## hold the bystander accountable it's up to them
## which actions they take initially av made too
## strong of a connection between sales and activism
## tools taught in sales training only go so far
## any questions about this or anything you
## want me to expand on it 30 seconds but
## [ __ ] i might even reduce this
## down even further 10 seconds
## now i'll keep it at 30 seconds but uh
## let me let me know guys if you want me to break
## anything down further for you five seconds
## moving on so the next slide activism is not
## sales we're still continuing on this thing
## a successful conversation is not one
## where the bystander says i'm going vegan
## that's not necessarily the thing that you should
## be looking for it's where you say the right things
## most people become vegan after they hear the truth
## from us how long it takes is up to the individual
## 30 seconds
## okay so uh there's a question here i'm you're
## still confused about the sales thing could you
## give me an example or more could you be more
## specific about what you're confused about
## good question summer do you still promote feel
## felt found i never really understood what that
## means again that was just a communication tool i
## thought it would be helpful i don't use it anymore
## and it's not in this outreach workshop for a
## reason that you have pointed out and i appreciate
## that we've removed it because again we make too
## strong of a connection to sales and i don't want
## people to think that these communication tools are
## the approach like this is that's not an approach
## that's just a tool a little tiny little tool
## that can help with your communication but feel
## fat found no you don't really need to use
## that and we've removed it it's unnecessary
## what you said about giving fair warning
## before asking a question or commenting
## is a good way to proceed awesome like
## how do we know if we've made an impact
## on their perception apart from their
## guilt you don't uh you well you don't
## there are certain indicators but like we say here
## most people become vegan after they hear the truth
## from us how long it takes is up to the individual
## and that's why i say i want you to connect to this
## approach in in i want you to connect to
## understanding that if you say the right things
## on behalf of the victims then you have succeeded
## in your outreach because that's the best you can
## do the next step is physically forcing people
## to become vegan which we can't do does that help