## was going on
## in america during the protests in
## minnesota and throughout
## other states said really nothing about
## what happened in lebanon
## for example yeah they are very selective
## yeah the causes that they choose to
## speak up about and that's the thing
## because when people ask us to do the
## same thing
## they're asking us to to speak up for
## those specific
## issues um because you know how
## many different things are out there that
## you could be speaking about when it
## comes to human rights
## there are so many different things and i
## don't know
## anyone who claims to be an
## intersectional and
## they actually cover all of those issues
## there's literally
## thousands of different things that you
## could talk about and i
## i only see these people focusing on two
## or three different categories and they
## want us to do the same
## and that points out that you do have to
## choose your cause
## yeah because if they're claiming you
## have to speak up for all of them
## well there's literally thousands of
## injustices occurring right now
## around the world all the time so
## it's not only impractical it's
## impossible
## for you to physically pull that off to
## actually speak up for
## all of them yeah and to fight
## to end all of them all at once i mean
## think about how insane that is so these
## people are being hypocrites
## because these people are choosing their
## causes
## which is guess what we have you have our
## support
## you have our full support to do that
## because we chose a cause
## yeah and that's how it is you guys are
## doing the same thing that we're doing
## how about we i'm actually taking this
## moment to see where we have
## something in common and maybe you
## should do the same thing instead of
## looking at where we have a difference or
## where you think you're more holier than
## that
## or something to that effect have you
## considered this before
## there's a concept that actually if i
## i'll tell you who who
## introduced me to it but um this was
## actually back in the day when things
## were a little bit nicer but it was
## actually anita
## who introduced me to this concept um
## years like maybe a year and a half ago
## two years ago when i
## i brought up the i brought up some
## comments about insectionality and i kind
## of warned anita that it looked like this
## was going to start to take a turn for
## the worse
## people were starting to attack me for
## not you know saying
## certain things or for saying certain
## things and i felt like it was starting
## to seep into organizations and i
## mentioned this and
## she told me we won't do this because we
## are all about positive
## intersectionality and she had this
## concept and this mindset and it really
## inspired me actually because she said
## we can fight for the animals 100 always
## but when there are situations where it
## also benefits humans
## we can also note it for example look
## these
## vegans went out and gave free food to
## the homeless because
## they're suffering they're doing animal
## rights activism by teaching the homeless
## about veganism
## and they're helping the homeless for
## example that would be a positive
## intersectional message right it's not no
## one loses out here the animals are
## focused
## and the the homeless people have a focus
## in lebanon for example with the blast
## the the vegans the local vegans
## were doing incredible work they were
## getting like food out to everyone they
## were like
## you know um helping the vegan businesses
## in the area they were helping the
## animals in the area it was it was
## amazing
## but you're also raising awareness of
## that corrupt government and how this
## even happened in the first place
## it's it's two in one it's easy right um
## and this was great when she said this i
## was really inspired but obviously we
## know how that went and it didn't end up
## staying
## um staying that way unfortunately but
## for you guys like what do you think
## about av in that sense do you think this
## is something av could do
## like with social media i mean not with
## the cubes but like with how you
## represent yourselves on social media is
## that something that you've thought about
## or would ever consider or you do you
## have do you disagree with that that kind
## of
## way of doing things
## what way of doing things specifically
## what is being suggested
## so so like for example when there are
## some um
## when there is there are issues that
## potentially could be both benefited by
## raising awareness of it for example you
## obviously av is 100 focused on the
## animals but let's imagine
## there is uh some of your av organizers
## or your av
## team goes out and gives food to the
## homeless raising putting that on av
## social media
## and saying like look look look at what
## our awesome activists are doing they're
## fighting for the animals and they're
## helping the homeless
## do you see some pro a problem with doing
## something like that or do you think that
## that you agree with that as a as an idea
## that specific suggestion
## just sounds like we would be
## i don't see how that helps
## a human cause of any kind by making a
## post like that
## i don't see that as activism to help a
## human cause
## i mean at best it's congratulatory and