## you know about humans have been through
## so
## it's not something that should be
## accepted um
## just because it's big and because it's
## being pushed
## but at the same time for good or for bad
## there are people out there who
## uh yeah like specifically it is it is
## very much
## intertwined with trends with the trans
## issues which is why it keeps coming up
## and this you didn't you said earlier i
## don't understand why people keep saying
## it's about trans
## it's because i feel i feel personally i
## don't tell me if i'm wrong i feel like
## that
## that um i wouldn't say popularity but
## the
## the more exposure let's say the more
## awareness of trends and what it means to
## be trans
## has also come tied in with gender and
## and gender identity
## yeah because right yeah confuse the
## issue though i think deliberately they
## have to
## use the two now it's like all mixed in
## but it doesn't need to be because when
## we're talking about gender pronouns and
## gender
## we're talking about gender roles and
## like
## you can you can be a female like you can
## be born a female in a female body but
## you may not necessarily
## feel like you are fitting into that
## you know that i don't know mindset or
## that
## gender role and that's totally fine but
## that's not what we're talking about when
## we're talking about like someone
## transitioning you're talking about them
## changing their their
## body and that's the sex it's like when
## you go to the doctor they they care
## about knowing your birth sex because
## you know the doctor needs about your
## body and your biology so that's why
## sex and gender are different and if
## anyone wants to confuse the two
## that's just not gonna you know that's
## fine but that's that's just not the
## reality of it
## they're completely separate uh
## and my trans um supporters tell me this
## and and i agree with them convoluting
## conflating gender politics
## uh the gender pronoun
## issue in society that's been brought up
## uh with the trans movement and struggle
## of trans people
## is actually diminishing them as victims
## of their struggle so it takes away from
## what they're really dealing with and
## uh they're not struggling with gender
## pronouns necessarily like the
## the the struggles are different they're
## they're struggling
## with uh with just being accepted as a
## trans person and that's a different
## discussion
## completely to what we're discussing here
## this is what they tell me
## and i agree with them and uh
## it's disrespectful to the trans movement
## to just attach all these other things to
## it and say that's a trans issue too
## yeah if you care about the trans
## movement
## then you wouldn't do that i understand
## so yeah
## there's a distinction between just
## wanting to identify
## as one of the limitless genders and
## actually
## suffering from gender dysphoria and and
## changing your sex and wanting to be
## referred to as a different pronoun
## because
## it it validates who you are and it's
## something that you have
## struggled through yes you're drawing
## there's a distinction between the two
## basically
## is what you're saying right there
## absolutely is and
## trans people around the world feel
## diminished because of this
## this incessant um obsessive
## need to link it to everything else and
## have already
## finished on top okay but
## it's but although although you hold this
## belief and obviously av
## operates on this um not belief i
## wouldn't say but let's say opinion
## and the av operates also on this opinion
## like that av will not accept
## um people bringing in ideologies
## um without let's say like obviously
## trans trend the trans movement isn't an
## ideology um
## not for the not for the people who are
## actually uh you know suffering from
## gender dysphoria anyway although there
## are people who are calling themselves
## trans who are actually not
## don't have gender dysphoria then that's
## an ideology i would say that's different
## that's a political
## um ideology or or some i don't know
## ideology of some sort
## um but unfortunately i would say it is
## it is difficult to actually determine
## who is who
## right and and who is for real and who is
## doing this because they genuinely
## you know are a trans person and who is
## doing this because they have
## they want to get on board with an
## ideology and and kind of i don't know
## be different um i guess
## how does av how does it how is av going
## to operate with that because
## i know that you like you've just said
## you'll you accept people who have
## uh and you accept and will respect
## people who are genuinely
## you know are trans or or whatever if
## they have whatever condition the av
## will respect them and people will be
## booted if they don't respect them
## but then also in the same breath you're
## saying that the political ideology is
## not actually welcome
## and so if somebody isn't actually trans
## and they are just identifying as someone
## else because it's something they want to