## on your morals if you understand that this is
## wrong you're not gonna go back on child abuse
## you're not gonna wake up one day and think child
## abuse is okay i think today i'm comfortable with
## this idea i'm gonna do it today it's black and
## white it's always wrong and it's never justified
## another thing that vegans will focus way too
## much on when advocating for animal rights
## is being liked by the other person we think that
## being likable vegans is going to get people to
## take veganism seriously raise your hand if
## you've fallen into this trap i know i have
## thank you for being honest because we don't want
## to be the preachy vegan we don't want to be the
## pushy vegan we don't want to be the annoying
## vegan we don't want to be the vegan that turns
## people off veganism here's the thing non-vegans
## have been trying to bully us psychologically
## into this thinking and you need to realize that
## and you know better this is just manipulation
## people are trying to make you feel insecure about
## this because they're shooting down the messenger
## because they don't want to take the message
## seriously and face it when we play into this
## they win when i say they the abusers and the
## animals lose it's a flaw to care about being liked
## more than what you're saying and the rights
## of these animals the rights of these beings
## in no other situation do we actually use
## this line of thinking so we're actually
## being hypocrites here you probably noticed
## that people actually like people who don't
## really care what other people think of them when
## you don't care what other people think of you
## and to the contrary when you care so
## much about what other people think of you
## people actually don't like that they don't like
## that about you because it comes off as a weakness
## and i actually think that telling people the
## truth is the best way to achieve this anyway
## so it's counterproductive if you want to be liked
## then do things that are deserving of being liked
## and this shouldn't be your goal being life
## shouldn't be your goal because if somebody
## likes you and goes vegan for that reason
## what happens when they don't like you anymore
## which will happen
## imagine civil rights activists
## focusing on being liked by white people
## in order for them to take black rights
## seriously how weird would that be trying to be
## accommodating in whichever way socially to have
## them taking black rights seriously it would be
## insane to even witness that happening and this is
## also a tool that you should use in your advocacy
## to make sure that you're in line with what you're
## supposed to be doing here as an activist if you
## ever feel like questioning what you're
## doing compare it to any other injustice
## would you be advocating this way in
## any other case for any other injustice
## if not don't do it here animals deserve
## way better from us when we first started av
## i noticed that the outreach that
## we were doing on the streets
## i noticed that there was a lot of
## things that i learned in my previous
## work experience in doing sales all
## the sales training that i had received
## there were things in that that i could carry
## over into outreach that were applicable here
## and so if you go on our website it says we use
## a value-based sales approach i want to explain
## what that means because i think there's been
## a bit of a confusion about this i definitely
## don't mean the kind of sales that we're
## commonly used to and that we commonly know
## i'm talking about certain aspects of sales that
## are applicable here because at the end of the day
## what we're doing is trying to convince somebody
## of something they're not already convinced on
## and that's what sales is really i'm trying to
## convince you right now to apply this approach when
## you're doing outreach and that's why i brought
## this into this equation but i want to explain
## that i really do not mean schmoozing people and
## telling people what you think they want to hear
## and using hooks like psychological hooks to trick
## them into signing on the dotted line that's not
## how this works at all activism is a different
## ballpark to sales one of the traditional things
## that occurs in sales is the three-step process for
## any sale so i'll talk you through that right now
## the three-step process is really simple
## the first step is all right i'm gonna
## okay i'm gonna pause right here because this
## is the part where i find that there's the most
## confusion and it's the whole sales message so yes
## i'm going to break down this three-step process
## but the only reason i'm doing that here is to
## show you where sales tools and really they're