## eat less now i'm just going to leave you with
## this to think about because you said try would
## we say that with any other injustice would we try
## to not be a child abuser or would we just do it
## yeah so please don't compromise on this injustice
## because the animals suffer as a result of that
## you really just need to get out there and do
## this and see how effective it is for yourself
## that one guy he was talking to so anyone
## can do this and i highly recommend it and
## the tallies as you know we've removed our tallies
## we used to try and measure how effective we are
## and that was the reason why we had the tally
## there we tried to have some kind of metric
## that we wanted to use to show that these events
## this form of street outreach is really effective
## but the mistake that we made is that you can't
## really tell if someone is going to go vegan or not
## you just have to speak for the animals in
## the way that you would want to be spoken for
## if you're in their position say the correct
## things and that's a successful conversation and
## a lot of the times people say they're going to
## go vegan and while that's still a good thing i'm
## not saying that's not a good indication if someone
## says they're going to go vegan they may very well
## stick to that but i actually have examples of many
## cases of people saying they're going vegan after
## listening to me and they do not go vegan you don't
## know what's going on in people's minds and what's
## going on in their hearts and what they're going
## to experience after they've talked to you you
## don't know if they're going to continue arguing
## with their friends about what you've talked to
## them about and then that leading to them going
## vegan because all of their friends made stupid
## comments and one of their friend held them to
## account again and that rang in their head and
## they were thinking about it for a week and they
## couldn't let it go and then finally they conceded
## to the hypocrisy and they became vegan you
## just don't know you don't know the process
## another thing is that hypocrisy i just want to
## go back to that real quick it's the reason why
## each of us went vegan for sure there's a story
## that i have on my youtube of gary yourofsky
## i was in the car with him he was
## telling this really awesome story that
## all right okay guys i want you to pay attention
## to this point i'm making here because i only
## realized how powerful and significant this
## point was when i watched this workshop back
## what i have successfully pointed out here
## is well you'll hear my point in a moment but
## this is so tremendously profound and i really want
## you to understand what i'm saying here but it's a
## story about gary and i haven't even pointed this
## out to gary yet but i'm going to do so soon but
## one thing i learned from him is that he didn't go
## vegan because of that elephant in the circus and
## he didn't go vegan because of the pigs that he saw
## being tortured and murdered at thorn apple valley
## um pig pig slaughterhouse the pig sloth house
## there so that's the story he's told the world
## and i believe that that's what he felt was
## the catalyst for a long time but when i was
## chilling with him in detroit he told me a story
## which i recorded and i put up on my youtube
## and that story he tells a new story about how he
## went vegan and what was really the catalyst to
## change him and it's really powerful if you want
## to understand what it takes to truly get people
## to go vegan because if we can understand how
## the best activists in the world have gone vegan
## then that's a pretty good indicator because that's
## what we're trying to shoot for here not just
## people to go vegan but we need people to speak up
## and to be effective when they speak up and let's
## look at how activists went vegan that's a great
## thing to observe and learn from so without further
## ado please pay attention one of their friend held
## them to account again and that rang in their head
## and they were thinking about it for a week and
## they couldn't let it go and then finally they
## conceded to the hypocrisy and they became vegan
## you just don't know you don't know the process
## another thing is that hypocrisy i just want to
## go back to that real quick it's the reason why
## each of us went vegan for sure there's a story
## that i have on my youtube of gary yourofsky
## i was in the car with him he was telling this
## really awesome story that i'd never heard before
## about how a hockey team in detroit used to throw
## octopuses onto the ice and he was an animal rights
## guy at the time every time someone would score
## a goal they would do this and he was an animal
## rights guy at the time who was protesting this
## and he called a radio station and he started
## saying what's next are we going to have all these
## other teams with sharks and lions and their names