## about nuance
## uh like if hitler shows up to the cube
## should he be respected
## like if he just is resurrected from from
## the earth
## uh comes back to life and shows up to
## keep will he be respected
## uh uh do i have to answer that well we
## said
## everyone should be respected we said we
## meant the person
## who chooses a different pronoun or name
## as well as the person who might disagree
## with that ideology
## oppressed that's what we meant we didn't
## say the bully
## or the oppressor so oppression is not
## respected
## i thought that like because we led into
## that point
## with saying that actually and
## so yeah no totally totally i i
## understand this is i think i watched a
## uh
## this thing with uh bilbao you know the
## comedian bilbao
## he he he was talking about new ones as
## well do you know the ginger guy
## and speaks really quickly i don't know
## if you know what i'm talking about yeah
## cool
## so he he talked about nuance as well and
## he was saying that like
## everything i say is twisted and he said
## something like
## he said he was talking about consent
## right and i'm gonna by the way
## for anyone that's looking for something
## to get me on here this is bill burr's
## words not my words all right don't
## [ __ ] start here um but basically he
## said
## like today's world like how how do you
## even work right so he said like it's all
## about consent and there's
## you're at risk all the way always and he
## said how do you
## have it rough now like if a girl wants
## it rough how do you do that
## because you know how does it work right
## and this guy in the crowd shouted
## you need to get consent first and he was
## like
## this is why you can't make jokes anymore
## he was like this [ __ ] [ __ ]
## thinks that i'm saying that i was not
## going to get consent i never said that
## he was like when did i say that why
## would you assume that that's what i
## meant
## right and he was like it's [ __ ]
## ridiculous you assumed the worst of me
## and he called this guy an idiot and a
## [ __ ] and like really slammed him
## for shouting that because it's like i'm
## not a monster dude like i'm making a
## joke about
## rough sex i'm not making a joke about
## not getting consent are you insane
## there's a very big difference and this
## is i'm saying it because he commented on
## it and it's kind of what's just happened
## here it's like you guys said respect
## everyone and someone understood that as
## respect
## transphobic people it's like no that's
## not what i
## said no one said that jesus do you think
## i would have let that fly
## in the conversation do you really think
## i am that morally
## corrupt that i would just let someone
## say that on my channel and just not
## question wait a minute you've just said
## you want to respect transphobes it's
## like no
## i would never let that go even if i had
## someone like some monster on the channel
## i would never let that go but that's not
## the case you know
## anyway i'm just i've just got off the
## handle a bit there but we're at the end
## anyway it's fine
## it's just as silly as having to say
## oh with the exception of intersex
## when you're saying there's two sexes
## like why should we even have to say that
## it's an anomaly of course that's an
## exception to the rule
## and like you know
## you don't need to say certain things i
## guess if you are
## reading between the lines and you are uh
## attuned
## to nuance and you don't just see things
## through
## this uh cancel culture lens where
## you know is it what what billboard said
## is these days you say something and what
## you say goes into someone's brain and
## then it gets cut
## with all of the things that they're
## conditioned with
## and you know and then it comes out of
## their brain they spit it out after that
## you know according to what they perceive
## it to be and it's usually completely
## different to what
## you said and uh it's the same thing here
## it shouldn't that shouldn't that's
## something that shouldn't in my opinion
## shouldn't need to be clarified you
## should assume the best in people not the
## worst
## i i don't understand what you what you
## have done or even what i have done
## because i'm involved in this that
## question was for all of us right because
## i
## they're assuming that you have said that
## and i have
## i have been like yeah great cool like
## what did i do to deserve that what did
## you do to deserve that assumption like i
## i don't think any of us has done
## anything particularly you know that
## horrible to think that any of us would
## like believe that or let it go it's such
## a strange
## and i think the person's saying it
## innocently enough i don't think they're
## trying to attack
## but at the same time it's like dude be
## reasonable here come on
## it's a fair enough question um but
## i mean i i don't know is it fair enough
## actually am i trying to be nice
## i don't think it's fair enough at all in
## my opinion i think it's something that
## if you watched the whole conversation
## and listened
## without assuming the worst in all three
## of us you would come to the conclusion
## that that that's not
## what was being said like that you're not
## going to respect a bigger you're not
## going to respect someone who hates trans
## people like
## what the [ __ ] like what kind of rational
## person would ever
## have irrational hatred or acceptance of
## irrational hatred
## like it's not it's not rational to
## accept that
## and we've i don't believe we've been
## acting irrationally in this conversation
## so i