## this for a while i learned this the hard way gary
## told me told everyone and i didn't think it was
## necessarily true either at first but i've come
## to learn this very much so humans what can i say
## it's terrible but one thing that gives me optimism
## and hope is that there are plenty of us out there
## who vibrate on this frequency and that's all
## we need to do to continue moving forward is
## us supporting us so when i read your comments
## supporting av supporting me and asal and the
## whole av team we appreciate it so much
## because it means that we are working
## together we do have unity between those who
## vibrate on this frequency and that's important
## where can you get the new outreach cards from
## your organizer if there's no organizer in
## your city go over to our website and go to the
## join section and apply to become an organizer
## so that you can launch a cube of truth a chapter
## in your city where cuba truth events operate
## lots of questions coming through
## how do i respond to people that
## say they can't go vegan because of
## medical advice point them to
## all of the medical advice that
## that says otherwise we have empirical data
## that shows that it's perfectly adequate for
## all human beings to be on a plant-based diet
## point them to the evidence there's only one
## source of scientific data there's only
## one database okay so michael greger is
## a great person to look into because he breaks down
## the data so nutritionfacts.com but the thing i
## just want nutritionfacts.org is the website there
## but i just want to say that this person saying
## this most likely woody is using this as an excuse
## to not go vegan if they're truly wanting to end
## the abuse that they cause to animals the needless
## suffering or in their case they think it's
## required but if they really want to end it then
## they'll look into it and they'll do their very
## damnedest to make it happen to to end it
## and so if you are talking to someone who's
## truly trying to end it then just give them that
## information that should be enough but usually
## it comes back to accountability in those cases
## usually people are just using that as an excuse
## is it cruel to raise kids
## non-vegan it's cruel to the animals
## yeah and it is cruel to humans on some
## level but it's not even comparable to
## what we do to the animals so i'm not even
## going to say it's cruel to the humans um so
## what was the other part of that
## question um saying this as a mother
## it's cruel to the animals and you're robbing
## children and you're robbing children over there
## you're making them confused and you're robbing
## them off i mean every vegan will say they wish
## they were vegan since birth so you're robbing
## them of that opportunity to do the right thing
## when kids are just doing what their parents
## tell them to do so when non-vegans say don't
## force this on your children they're forcing
## non-veganism on their children parenting is
## forcing that's what parenting is they do what
## their parents tell them to do up until they're 18.
## so it's if you're gonna have to choose a diet for
## them why wouldn't you choose the one that doesn't
## involve bloodshed abuse torture suffering when
## it's needless that's my answer to that question
## much love jeanette appreciate your comment
## um
## how do you convince religious people or anyone
## who is used to seeing animal abuse since young
## to feel something for the animals that's two
## different questions there religious people
## it's no different this whole approach is no
## different if people say i
## believe god said it's okay
## classic gary quote if god says this
## is okay then what does the devil do
## just you're not going to get through
## to most religious people you just
## need to ask them these really tough questions
## and treat them no different to anyone else
## with the approach that we're giving you
## okay um and that second question
## i think i've already answered