## you tell them they go vegan on the spot
## that's the dream circumstance but i'm
## saying most people are not like this if they're
## vegetarian imagine if all vegetarians were vegan
## the percentage of vegetarians is always way
## larger than the percentage of vegans when
## they do those statistics imagine if all the
## vegetarians were outreached effectively and
## they went vegan we would have way more vegans
## on our side also when people at the end of your
## outreach will say i'm gonna try to do better
## i'll try i'm gonna try to go vegan please
## do not use the word try and do not let people
## use the word try would you try to be a non-racist
## would you try not to be a child
## abuser or would you just [ __ ] stop
## once you realize that it's wrong again
## don't let them off the hook let them
## know that there is a moral imperative here
## when someone says i'm gonna try what i say
## in order to get them to rid themselves of this try
## nonsense is to compare it to any other injustice
## like i just compared it to child abuse and
## racism etc would you say that you would try
## or would you just stop and that usually
## corrects that for people very quickly
## um i'm going to get into this a little bit more
## later but i want to add this piece in here and say
## that we have had another update to this section
## we're constantly seeking to improve here
## guys we're constantly making software updates
## and one of them is this one here when we
## compare to other injustices we've actually found
## see okay so my analysis on this is that
## human beings only truly care about themselves
## that's it so when we say child abuse racism
## sexism feminism whatever it is we're relying
## upon how much they care about those issues and
## if they're not an activist when it comes to those
## issues we shouldn't expect that they care
## a great deal about those issues should we
## so we've found that the most effective thing to do
## in all situations is in fact hold them accountable
## to themselves so in other words instead of
## comparing it to an injustice that involves
## other groups of humans how about you just ask them
## about themselves how would you feel if someone
## was torturing you enslaving you and was going to
## murder you and the excuse your oppressors used was
## i'm trying to do less of it i'm only going to cut
## they say they're only going to cut your leg off
## uh you're probably gonna die from a doe
## so is that better than not killing i mean
## you know it's essentially putting them in the
## victim's position and saying what if someone was
## to enslave torture and murder you less but
## never ever liberate you from your oppression
## how would you feel would you want to
## be liberated if you were the victim
## or would you want these nonsense baby
## steps that don't really go anywhere
## so when you're comparing to other groups of humans
## it might be most effective for you to in fact
## according to our latest update and my
## analysis on this is that if you just
## rely on the fact that human beings truly only care
## about themselves uh more than more they at least
## care more about themselves than than anything
## else any other group of humans and i'm speaking
## generally for most people here this is why i'm
## trying to get deep into what is the most effective
## because there is no perfect approach for every
## single individual on the planet that doesn't exist
## what i can only teach you is most effective
## for most people and i'm going to continue
## to expand that and improve on that as
## much as possible let's get back into it
## would you say that you would try or would you just
## stop and that usually corrects that for people
## very quickly i want to try to be better
## there's no trying when it comes to justice
## you can't try to be non-racist you're either
## non-racist or you're a racist and i say that
## comparison because you understand injustice
## in that context but justice is justice
## what's evil is evil you can't have it both ways
## what's right is right what's wrong is wrong so
## don't try you have to do it do you think
## you'll go vegan um i can definitely try yeah
## wow i love my family here but i can stop i can
## spread it through my family make sure that they