## use environmental facts when it keeps changing
## on us when it comes to these things studies can
## come back to us that may prove us wrong on the
## environment tip in fact i've seen it proven that
## you can be environmentally way more
## better off as a non-vegan than a vegan
## in many circumstances if you live in a rural area
## you're a minimalist and you fish from your kayak
## you're way more environmentally friendly than
## a person who lives in new york procreates
## eats processed foods so environmentally this is
## not a surefire argument this really isn't and i
## just want to say from the health point of view can
## also be justified you can eat a piece of cheese or
## you can eat a salmon once a week and justify that
## from a health perspective because you just bounce
## back very easily from a health point of view you
## can feel better pretty quickly so there's no point
## of even arguing the health and the environment for
## those reasons next question even if that were true
## reply like because i found that to be quite
## good and when you say even if that were true
## how do you justify this do you ever use that at
## all i do i've been using that recently people
## say i think there's bigger issues in the world
## right human issues are more important well even
## if there are bigger issues in the world which
## we actually know that this is the biggest issue
## with the health and environment the only reason
## why we're talking about it is because animal
## rights is such an issue that it's impacted our
## environment it's become that big of an issue that
## it impacts our environment and it impacts human
## health to the extent that it does but we can give
## them that still and say even if there are bigger
## issues what justifies you doing this to them
## any other questions yes i've found on the internet
## so you put something up about veganism a lot of
## people just put like you know means to take the
## piss out of the veganism people sort of just go
## straight to that and they won't listen to
## you after that like so they take the piss
## out of what you're trying to do and then you just
## can't get through to them at all because they're
## so fixated on taking the piss out of us how
## would you get through take the piss out of them
## roast them in return they're the ones that
## are supposed to be roasted yeah but if they're
## just trolling they're not reachable but my simple
## response would be to roast them back but sometimes
## it's just like people are more drawn to a picture
## or something because the bulk amount of people
## can just you know gang up on you like that and
## it makes you feel like you know you should just
## stop talking like it's sort of hard it feels
## like you're trapped in that position where
## you know like there's no actual response that's
## worth and then it just makes you think oh you know
## what i'm doing am i actually doing the right thing
## is it worth me spending my time doing this you're
## definitely doing the right thing when you speak
## up for the animals it's always a good idea it's
## always worth doing i think your question is is
## it effective to be doing that is that what you're
## asking yeah so i don't know like with regards to
## the comments that coming in on your facebook or
## instagram i don't know if those individuals are
## going to go vegan but it may be more about who's
## reading it you know what i'm saying the imprint
## that you leave on those individuals it's important
## that you only focus on what you're saying and how
## you advocate for the animals so that if anybody
## ever does stumble across the comment thread that
## they read the right thing they hear what they're
## supposed to hear from you know what i'm trying to
## get at yeah yeah and that's the best you can do
## whether you should be doing this with those
## individuals i don't know because you'd have
## to give me more specific examples about what
## they're saying and how they're saying it
## but if they're dropping memes about
## eating meat and how tasty bacon is
## i've actually found that roasting
## those people can be pretty effective
## don't waste too much energy on it you may want
## to block them after a certain point once you've
## made your point for people to read so you may
## want to manage it that way on social media
## but as long as you say the correct thing you're
## in the right space yes um paul um i just wrote
## down this thing that i was going to say when you
## were talking about the blood on your hand on their
## hands so i found it actually harder to speak to
## people that i know personally that love animals
## um also they love animals they actually i've
## lost four people that i've known for a long
## time because they they seem to think that my
## message is hateful so people who have tried
## to break down the barriers um around animals
## in agriculture they reject any notion of even
## so when my compassion for the animals involved
## into more what you would call aggression and
## like passionate speaking and ask why they can
## ignore those animals quite um and can be hateful
## how do we get people to abandon a lifetime
## of adoption and views around farm animals