## explanation but they should still be quick to
## respond to your response should always anchor
## back to individual accountability this can't be
## more simple this is so simple again 30 seconds
## all right moving on
## bring it back to the individual if they try to
## create excuses that try to remove accountability
## for example pointing to rural communities lions
## low income families etc don't get lost in lengthy
## explanations bring it back to the individual
## by placing themselves in the victims position
## and asking how that excuse justifies their
## personal contribution to animal abuse
## i don't know if contribution is the right word
## i might update that but you
## guys know what this is saying
## uh yeah 30 seconds i'm gonna
## shave five seconds off that so 25
## seconds
## objections are good they can
## be good yes they can be good
## all right moving on next slide
## um tying the benefit tying the benefit only
## once they concede by saying if they're against
## animal abuse then it's not possible to be
## against animal abuse while supporting it
## the number one benefit of going vegan for the
## animals the benefit is that they no longer have
## to be tortured and abused because of you for
## you if you say you are against animal abuse
## and what you see on the screens then when you're
## vegan you no longer have to be a hypocrite
## and so we're going to update this part like i said
## to say when you're vegan you have the opportunity
## for the first time in your life to not be
## a hypocrite so that's the update there when
## you're vegan you now have the opportunity
## to no longer be a hypocrite this drives home
## the accountability and makes them understand
## the consequence of their actions 30 seconds
## wow this has gone on for ages i saw it like five
## hours ago govi well jen you know i'm trying to
## make sure that this workshop is as thorough
## as possible but we're almost about to wrap up
## do people only care about being
## hypocrites yeah because it affects
## people care about themselves
## and the image of themselves and
## if you want to hit people and and mess up
## their ego about themselves that's how you
## do it you you call them out on things like
## this and this is unfortunately how people
## work i mean i wish that it was just as
## easy as saying guys we have 50 less than
## 50 years left on this planet animal abuse is
## the biggest pressing issue of our time we have
## no right to be abusing animals please stop
## if that was it was just as easy as that
## i would i would that's what i would be telling
## you to do in this outreach workshop but it's not
## moving on
## 26 all right close the conversation
## always end outreach conversations
## by asking what the individual will personally
## do to take action ask them open and ask
## the open-ended question after our conversation
## what are you going to do about this injustice
## after a long conversation they may still
## say that they'll only reduce or do nothing
## if they can if you can sense that the
## interaction will keep going in circles