## i'm just teaching you guys what i've learned
## and what we've learned together actually so
## not verbal leafleting is the biggest
## part of this slide no verbal leafleting
## that's just cancer in the animal rights movement
## i've seen it so many times i've done it myself
## it gets you nowhere and it makes this message
## seem even more of a like a mockery to people
## like it's it takes it takes it down a notch to
## then being taken less seriously so all right
## that's 45 seconds moving on veganism is not
## love or compassion veganism is about justice
## your likability does not determine your rights so
## out i'm going to repeat that just because someone
## doesn't like you it doesn't mean they have
## the right to take your rights away from you
## so that's why we don't need to lean into how much
## people like animals that's just the wrong way to
## communicate this message outreach is not about
## how you or anyone else feels about animals if
## you don't go around beating children you aren't
## instantly a compassionate individual refraining
## from injustice does not make you compassionate by
## default and we can see that because in the animal
## rights movement vegans are some of the least
## compassionate people that i have to deal with
## veganism is a non-action it's not loving
## it's merely the right thing to do 45
## seconds
## all right i'm reading your comments guys if
## there's anything you want me
## to expand on now's your time
## you know what i'm going to reduce this back down
## to 30 seconds uh and if you guys like need more
## time to write your comment just start off with
## a comment that you can just send out real quick
## that says i have a comment or i have something
## i want to add and then i will wait for you to
## write your longer question if this is too quick
## so i'm going to reduce this back to 30 seconds
## and that's what you can do if you have any
## questions but there are questions coming in now
## so i will answer them what does leaf litting mean
## leafleting means handing out pieces of information
## to people and then it's just like all these little
## factoids about like how old chickens are when
## they're murdered and all these things and you know
## the the irony of how counterproductive this is is
## obvious to me because so many non-vegans already
## know about how much of a shocker the meat dairy
## and egg industries are they already know that they
## treat animals horribly they already know about how
## young the animals are when they're murdered and
## all these crazy statistics and it's very easy
## to find out but it doesn't make people go vegan
## because knowing all these factoids is one thing
## and yes that might cause some people to go
## vegan i take that back i know some of you
## thinking well i went vegan when i looked
## into the dairy industry but at some point
## there was accountability for your actions and
## wanting to be accountable for yourself for what
## you're doing to them and yeah that's what it
## comes down to these factoids don't really push
## people towards it it just puts them in a position
## where they just feel like they need to continue
## arguing the points and all this stuff and it's
## just it's not it's not very effective at all so
## let's see if there's any other comments here
## ariane huge comment very well said people
## will forget about the facts anyways
## what they will remember is the
## guilty feeling when they hear
## that they are animal abusers so just to expand
## on ariane's point here and point out how
## how true that is there's a really great quote that
## everyone knows and it's just so true people don't
## remember what you said they remember how they felt
## when you said it and that's what this is all about
## yeah veganism is about justice we
## can't point that out enough seemingly
## so we cannot point it out enough all right moving
## on guys thanks for your comments i appreciate it