## which is really just trying to be liked
## which is really focusing on getting
## compassion from the abusers as opposed to
## focusing your compassion on the victims
## does that help
## all right moving on thank you for your comments
## guys but um i'm going to move on so on to the next
## people already know how to go
## vegan this is the why versus how
## people already know how to go vegan with the
## constant availability of google and the internet
## people are literally glued to their phones in
## 2020. anybody can figure out how to become vegan
## instantly in order for people to feel the need to
## become vegan they need to be held accountable for
## why they said for why they should do it my vision
## is going blurry at this point i'll read that again
## in order for people to feel the need to become
## vegan they need to be held accountable for
## why they should do it with any other injustice you
## would never focus on the how by talking about how
## to not participate in the violence so i'm
## reading this incorrectly let me start again
## with any other injustice you would never
## focus on the how by talking about how
## to not participate in the violence focusing on the
## how in the context of any other injustice would be
## an insult to the victims and the entire movement
## fighting to end their oppression 30 seconds
## how do you convince intersectionals to
## be vegan intersectionals to be vegan
## i'm assuming they're not vegan then usually i
## find intersectionals are vegan but if they're
## if they're not even vegan you i would just
## say to talk to them like you talk to anybody
## else
## yes moving on guys thank you on to the next
## slide vegetarianism is cancer to animal rights
## vegetarians are non-vegans and should be
## outreached in the same manner as anyone else
## and in most cases even harder because vegetarians
## act so pompous vegetarians are our target market
## they're no different to paleo eaters
## why should we treat them any differently
## they are not allies don't let other non-vegans
## and vegans manipulate you into thinking that
## they are 30 seconds i don't have
## anything to add to these points if
## if i'm just moving straight into looking at
## the comments and it doesn't look like you guys
## want me to expand on this
## it's pretty straightforward
## all right five seconds vegetarians
## are proper carnists yeah well said
## they should get tenfold harsher
## activism especially if they're pompous
## especially if they're pompous all right
## moving on typical outreach structure ask
## them if they would like to know why
## you're here this was asked earlier
## ask them if they would like to know why you're
## here and with the context of the footage playing
## tell them what the cube of truth sets out to
## do what we are doing is showing the reality of
## what happens to animals and the meat dairy
## egg and other industries everything you see
## here is standard practice here and around the
## world asking the following open-ended question
## what are your feelings on animal abuse
## then confirm their stance to form moral
## consistency with something like so it's safe to
## say that you are against animal abuse 30 seconds