## generally all right guys um there are other
## questions here and if you're not going to stay
## on this stream you can watch this back when this
## video goes up and i will respond to your question
## at some point but i'm now going to get into
## the slides in the interest of time management
## right i'm gonna share this
## and i'm just gonna go through
## each of the points that were raised
## in that workshop for you guys
## all right sharing my screen once again whoops
## all right can you guys see that okay
## i'm confident that you can but just to make sure
## let me know in the comments if you can
## see that slide i'm about to go through
## i just need one of you guys to
## confirm and then i'll continue
## can you see the outreach workshop slides
## okay
## all good cool thanks guys all right so let's get
## into it so this is our outreach workshop in slides
## you might see organizers in your city or town and
## if you are an organizer or you become an organizer
## your organizer may run through a workshop with
## you in your city and they'll use these slides
## and these slides may be updated from time to
## time but right now this is our most updated
## outreach workshop in slide format so let's let's
## go so we start with this important question
## what even is veganism if you ask a
## group of people what it means to be
## vegan you most likely will get multiple
## versions of what they believe it to be
## veganism has nothing to do with our health the
## environment human rights or affection towards
## animals it is not about justice for non-human
## animal rights vegan equals anti-animal abuse
## now i'm not going to make any extra points
## here unless they naturally come to me
## but if you guys in the comments want to make any
## points or any questions about this slide be as
## quick as you can while this slides up i'm gonna
## wait two minutes between each slide so that if
## there's anything specifically that you would like
## me to address regarding the points on each slide
## i'll address them as we go so two minutes starting
## now i'm going to start my stopwatch on my phone
## you know we have to start with the definition
## of veganism before we even talk about activism
## so two minutes if anyone wants to
## discuss anything here let me know
## it's two minutes too long maybe
## i should just do one minute
## yeah common sense and self-explanatory
## this slide all right well i'm i'm gonna
## reduce that to one minute so we've got 30
## seconds to go i think one minute is plenty
## i don't have anything i'd like to add to
## this it's very straightforward like you said
## so 10 seconds i'm assuming
## there's no questions here
## i'm an admin of the malaysian vegan facebook
## group one question we ask people who request
## to join is what veganism means to them most
## of them say it's kindness and great health
## wow yeah that's just typical isn't it it's a
## very common thing in the animal rights movement
## and the other thing i want to point out is
## you know when you ask what the benefit is
## most people say health or the environment which
## just goes to prove we don't need to talk about
## health and the environment with people and talk
## about them as benefits and act like that's what
## animal rights is all about people already know
## about those things what they really need to hear