## particularly as people seem to not acknowledge
## their sentience or even have any regard for
## them as if they're not relevant other
## than as a commodity so i've found that
## by trying to get people to engage their
## compassion or even their sense of justice around
## animals yeah and you're the only one who's
## making them visible or attempting to at
## this point yes like they know that that you know
## advertising exists but they actually don't connect
## they have to disconnect in order to sleep at night
## and what you represent is a mirror you're a mirror
## and when they call you hateful you are actually
## hateful but not to them you're hateful to their
## actions they're the abuse that's occurring to the
## animals so don't again don't let people shame you
## out of these things yes you are hateful own it
## you are hateful you do hate what they're doing
## to animals that's why you're speaking up and
## that's why you're passionate you're not just
## passionate this is an art we're talking about
## you're not just passionate about this this is
## an injustice and you are angry you hate the fact
## that your friends people you love are so willing
## to make excuses for something
## so unbelievably unjustifiable
## right that's what you hate the fact that they're
## yeah but like even the people that you outreach to
## like actually trying to make them feel something
## though because it could be on their radar
## what from what you've told me i actually think
## that they do have it on their radar because
## that's why they're trying to disconnect and call
## you hateful things when they say things that are
## inaccurate and irrational it's a sign that they
## do have guilt and guilt is a sign of them caring
## about the subject it's just so far buried down
## there because that's where it needs to be for
## them to sleep at do you understand these people
## do care about this issue you're just living proof
## of it being made into action and having your your
## actions aligned with your morals and you represent
## something to them that makes them feel
## inadequate and they should [ __ ] feel that way
## you do hate what they're doing
## to the animals let them know that
## that you don't respect what they're doing to
## the animals and there's no way that they can
## justify it keep asking them how do you justify
## this even if you think that a cow doesn't feel
## the same way as a dog or the same way more
## importantly don't use a dog as an example use them
## how would you feel if you're in a cow's position
## what crime has a cow committed other than being
## born non-human there's no way they can justify so
## asking these basic questions usually will lead you
## to having them face the facts and a vegan well
## they may temporarily but if that's the reason i
## don't talk to you anymore for someone who is a
## concerned citizen speaking up against injustice
## then they're not really your friend are they
## friends don't abandon friends over something so
## obviously righteous like that even if they're
## the perpetrator again they can't justify it
## a real friend would be like you know what i
## respect the fact that you called me out and
## there's nothing i can say like i am hypocrite
## and i am an animal abuser or even if they don't
## admit to that they would at least keep you in
## their lives if they respected the fact that
## you're speaking up against this and then it's
## up to you how long you keep them in your lives
## does that help yeah thanks a lot cool
## stop share so there it is that was the holding
## non-vegans accountable 2.0 from perth australia
## that was the second stop on the australian leg
## of the world tour that we
## embarked on in february which got
## put to an end due to the coronavirus
## so i will take questions and i will also
## start using this presentation with the
## slides to break down this whole thing once over
## just to reiterate all the points that were made
## it is good to feel bad about
## something that is bad simple
## i love simplicity and effectiveness
## the simpler the better
## in terms of effectiveness it has
## to have that effectiveness there
## but the simplicity i just love that so much okay
## so i'm gonna get these slides downloaded
## but if you guys have any questions
## lace me up in the comments