## you will actually get the health benefits from
## doing this as well and i used to say that it's
## better for the environment if you do this as a
## benefit you have a lower footprint it's a mistake
## because i'm conflating animal rights with
## environmentalism and with human health
## i know that it's going to be tempting for you to
## do this even after this workshop you're going to
## be very tempted to go there still i i you only
## know whether this is true if you apply this
## but if i can save you some time it's a
## mistake focus on why as opposed to how
## way more focus on why how is so eat i
## mean it's so easy to go vegan all right
## so i just want to add some commentary there
## to that piece that i just shared with you
## guys and i'm not sure if i made this clear in
## that last piece of commentary i offered but
## that three-step process is not something you
## necessarily need to follow at the cubes i'm just
## breaking that down to explain the traditional
## sales process and how it can be like how it's
## applicable here and how we usually get people you
## know what the process is to get them to that point
## of taking veganism seriously but i'm going to
## break down the process for you at the end of this
## in in slides so i'm gonna break it down for you
## even more um simpler and make it more clearer for
## you guys so just stick around for that at the end
## after this presentation is complete so i just want
## to clarify i'm not asking you to do the three-step
## process at the cubes that's not what we're asking
## you to do we're just explaining the three-step
## process and showing you how this one little thing
## in sales is actually something that we can learn
## from and apply some of that here in activism
## in this day and age do we really think it's
## difficult for people like we create our
## way more focus on if you apply how is
## so eat i mean it's so easy to go vegan
## it's a mistake focus on why as opposed to
## how way more focus on why how is so eat
## i mean it's so easy to go vegan in this day and
## age do we really think it's difficult for people
## like we create all these programs and recipes and
## we try to make sure people have all the support
## in the world is it really that difficult though
## aren't we babying people aren't we coddling people
## because if you're convinced on why you need to
## be vegan you just need to go and use google in
## 2020 we have the internet you can use google and
## ask any question there is about any ingredients
## about any recipe any product and you'll find out
## pretty quickly if it's vegan or not and that's the
## only compass you need to be vegan is this vegan
## or is this not there's two types of people in
## the world those who say being vegan is easy those
## who say being vegan is hard those who say being
## vegan is easier focus on the victims those who
## say being vegan is hard to focus on themselves
## so whenever they bring up that distraction
## oh i don't know how i could do this
## how whatever form of how that comes
## up how is completely a distraction
## if they're sold on why how is easy plus we
## give them a card anyway so they get support
## they get whatever they need at the end so
## don't focus on how another good question
## i just want to let you guys know also we
## updated our resource page in our cards so when
## you're so when you're at the end of the
## interaction and you hand over a card
## it it's now updated and it says will you stop
## um what does it say will you stop being a human
## supremacist this was just updated and it has
## our website cubeoftruth.com and that link now
## takes you to our resources page so it's a lot
## more simple i'm really proud of this new update
## and if you go over to our resources page we've
## updated that as well to make that even simpler
## specifically the video section we've now put up a
## video that is the best of the best gary yourofsky
## moments in speeches and other other content
## he's put up mainly his speeches but we've
## put the best of the best of gary yourofsky
## all in one video and it's about three hours
## so that's pretty cool because if they need
## further convincing that's the video we're
## still going to keep the georgia tech speech up
## there the best speech you'll ever hear because
## it has all of the translations available and i
## think it covers like 30 languages or something so
## that's important we need to keep that up there
## for that reason but this other one that's up
## there you can play using the caption feature on
## youtube so it may still translate through that