## i don't well yeah i don't know how that works in
## other countries or if it just creates a caption
## in in english um yeah i'm not sure how that works
## but anyways we have that three-hour video for at
## least the english-speaking people of the world and
## uh that's pretty cool so let's get back into this
## is it's we give them a card anyway so they get
## support they get whatever they need at the end
## so don't focus on health another good question
## is when you're tying in the benefit at the end
## of that three-step process to ask the question
## do you think it's possible to be against this
## to be against what you're saying you're against
## while also supporting it and it's a good question
## to just tie in hypocrisy again and also to tie
## in the fact that there is no way around this
## there's no alternative you're either an animal
## abuser or you're not another thing i want to say
## about this approach that i'm teaching you right
## now is that this is way more satisfying to do
## than all these other approaches that involve
## pandering and compromising on the message
## and focusing on being liked and all this stuff
## this is way more satisfying i've noticed that
## over the last four years there was a huge surge
## in 2017 2018 for street outreach in our network
## and then it sort of dropped and i feel like people
## have lost interest in doing outreach they don't
## really see the benefits and how successful
## it is and they're not really convinced on how
## effective it is anymore when you're doing this
## approach you'll come to learn that all of your
## interactions are successful even if the individual
## doesn't say that they're going to go vegan
## you've at least told them what they need to hear
## which is probably the only time they're going to
## hear it and when you have that perspective every
## interaction is successful because again we're
## mediums of truth we speak for the animals in the
## same way that we would want to be spoken for if
## we were in their position we have a rule that
## we only talk to people who stop at the cube and
## that's because we want to talk to people who are
## open-minded and we also have an opening question
## that we ask would you like to know why we're here
## because we need a commitment from them so that
## this is a two-way conversation so you shouldn't
## be talking to people who are obviously unreachable
## but at the end there they don't say they're going
## vegan then there's no reason for you to think that
## wasn't a successful interaction so many times
## people don't even say anything affirmative to
## the outreacher and they become vegan this happens
## so often now we had someone at the melbourne
## workshop who was sitting and learning who said
## i don't think that the outreacher who got me to
## go vegan at a cube a year ago in melbourne even
## knows that i went vegan because i argued with the
## outreacher and walked off that's another reason
## why we've removed the tallies but i'll talk a
## little bit about that at the end who here has not
## heard about socratic questioning raise your hand
## alright fair few of you this has been
## blown out of proportion a little bit too
## socratic questioning is a tool and it's a very
## good tool but it is only a tool it should be
## used within your interaction wherever you see fit
## wherever it's supposed to be used because asking
## questions is always a good idea it's always a
## good way of gathering information from the person
## to see where they're at psychologically when it
## comes to this but don't just use it throughout
## the whole interaction don't just ask question
## after question after question there's gonna be
## many times during the interaction where they give
## you the flaw to speak and lecturing them in that
## moment is actually the right way to go the reason
## why socratic questioning is there is because
## um so when i say giving you the like they're not
## necessarily giving you the flaw it's just a part
## in the a moment in the interaction where they're
## not saying anything and it would be completely
## appropriate for you to say something and to
## make a statement at that point because and i'm
## gonna break this down a little bit later when
## i do the slides because at that point when you
## make a statement or a closed-ended question or
## you don't even ask a question at all at that point
## what you're doing is pushing the conversation
## forward and that's necessary sometimes i'll break
## this down a little bit more detail like i said
## but i just wanted to add that commentary let's get
## back to it because we we wanna they give you the
## flaw to speak and lecturing them in that moment
## is actually the right way to go the reason why
## socratic questioning is there is because we want
## to ask questions instead of make statements but it
## doesn't mean that making statements is a bad idea
## so i know that after i teach you guys this
## stuff it's just human nature that you will