## um like if they had a dog with them and they
## obviously care about their dog like they're
## walking with the dog and then they're showing
## you know like empathy for their dog in some way
## and you say well what if that dog was stabbed to
## death yeah it's an easy thing to agree with yep
## but what happens when that dog dies in the family
## how long will they take to grieve that dog's life
## compared to a human compared to how sad
## they would feel about their own death and
## if they were going to be
## murdered you see what i'm saying
## all right i'm going to move on i don't
## see any comments here wanting me to
## expand on this particular slide i think i've
## covered as much as i can so let's move on
## statistics keep them minimal outside of what is
## asked of you state minimal information during
## outreach conversations we are not on the streets
## to verbally leaflet again let the footage provide
## the context to the conversation you aren't at a
## cube of truth to be a statistician you're there
## to have a concise conversation that holds people
## to account for their unjustified animal abuse a
## conversation will go on for longer than necessary
## if it turns into an argument over statistic
## over statistics this is another reason why you
## should bring up health and environment talking
## points why you shouldn't pardon me this is another
## reason why you shouldn't bring up health and
## environment talking points because that usually
## leads into a never-ending debate about nothingness
## seconds if you guys have any points
## you want me to expand on let me know
## yeah this is a good point
## here if the conversation went
## to logic i usually believe the person won't
## go vegan try to keep it about the abuse and
## here it says best of a logic person is to
## go plant-based veganisms from your heart
## you do need to hit people in the chest people
## talk part of me you're talking about how
## you know it's how you make people feel
## that's what people are going to remember
## moving on
## yeah it's not a debate club on the streets very
## good point street activism is not a debate club
## moving on guys reachability and conversation
## length not everybody on the streets is worth
## talking to part of your role is to assess
## who is reachable and who is not many people
## are not reachable if they want to have a short
## conversation with you keep it short with them
## don't entertain bystanders who want to engage
## in long argumentative debates we just covered
## that do not underestimate the cunningness
## of non-vegan guilt and the ability that non
## vegans many non-vegans will have to waste
## your vital time at work for the animals
## that's a huge point that last one 30
## seconds
## yeah part of the game here
## is assessing who is reachable
## you get better at this with practice by the way
## yeah well jezebel you're right it's also logical
## the point here is to not get lost in the logic
## you have to also have what
## hits people in the chest too
## cunningness what is cunningness you
## mean the actual definition of the word
## let's look it up the actual definition of
## the word according to miriam webster is
## skill in achieving one's ends through
## indirect subtle or underhanded means
## and here's an example it took a certain amount of
## cunningness on the photographer's part to obtain
## such revealing portraits of his rich and famous
## subjects anyhow the way it applies here in this
## context is that non-vegans are very cunning in the
## way that they address these arguments with vegans