## you guys are probably thinking [ __ ] i
## don't know if i could say that to people but
## i'm telling you this is the most satisfying
## thing that you can say to somebody
## because it's effective because that is the most
## effective thing that you can say to somebody
## and again this has been applied i mean we've got
## a very keen student in the back here hudson do you
## want to tell people what kind of reactions you've
## had or if you've had any negative interactions
## yes at first i was really worried about it about
## this whole approach and paul was like no we gotta
## try it you gotta try it and then i went up to
## people who were twice my size hold up hold up
## start from the start when you didn't want to do
## this you thought that this was too aggressive
## yeah i thought it was way too aggressive i got
## brainwashed by the vegan movement and thought
## that it's the wrong approach and anyway i recently
## tried out this approach being direct and what i
## found is people have so much more respect for me
## because i don't come across as some politician
## trying to sell them something and i found it's
## worked so much better because people recognize
## that we're not calling them hypocrites because
## we don't like them we're doing it because we
## don't like animal abuse and we're against the
## torture of animals that's a big point unless
## you have an ego issue this shouldn't be seen
## as malicious by the person you're speaking to
## unless you have an ego issue and you just want
## to be right all the time and you're trying to own
## people and that's the only reason why you're doing
## activism then people may respond negatively to you
## but what they pick up on is that your heart is in
## the right place when you say this stuff you're not
## saying this stuff for any other reason you
## only know this to be true if you apply it
## no matter what i say no matter what hudson just
## said you need to apply this put aside everything
## you've learned about outreach about everything
## you've learned about animal rights activism and
## just apply this not just today but for the
## following cubes that occur after today keep
## doing this and see what results you have because
## again this is the reason why you went vegan
## because you don't want to be a hypocrite you don't
## want to be an animal abuser and someone called you
## out on your hypocrisy if it wasn't someone else
## it was yourself that made this distinction oh
## i know it's crazy but apparently i need to
## make this distinction for people when i say
## holding non-vegans accountable i don't mean
## forcing people to go vegan you can't hold
## people accountable in the true sense of the word
## because people have to hold themselves accountable
## in the end it has to be a choice that comes from
## them when i say holding people accountable it's
## to the greatest extent that we can
## possibly do so through verbal interaction
## okay i didn't think i needed to clarify that but
## i've been getting comments and dms from people
## saying you can't force anyone to be vegan
## this holding non-vegans accountable approach
## is off base because people can
## only hold themselves accountable
## well this approach puts people in the best
## position to hold themselves accountable
## and that's the truth does this make sense to
## everybody so thanks for the uh comments about
## the audio there i'm doing my best here with the
## technical end of things but let's just go back
## doing this and see what results you have because
## again this is the reason why you went vegan
## because you don't want to be a hypocrite you don't
## want to be an animal abuser and someone called
## you out on your hypocrisy if it wasn't someone
## else it was yourself that made this distinction
## does this make sense to
## everybody are you feeling this
## all right now i'm going to take questions your
## hand went up lightning fast i got to respect that
## quickly what's your opinion on joaquin
## phoenix's oscar speech on the long reaching
## effectiveness of that i loved it but it's
## i wouldn't have said exactly what he said
## but i love the fact that he used his platform
## to talk about what happens in the dairy industry
## i didn't like how he conflated it with love and
## compassion so much because i don't think you need
## to love animals to not stab them to death you
## don't need to love black people to know that
## they deserve their rights you don't need to love
## any being to know that they deserve their rights
## it's not the perfect message but i still think
## it was great that he did that i also want to
## point out that joaquin phoenix said that meat and
## dairy is the third leading cause of environmental
## destruction or climate crisis but didn't we
## hear in conspiracy that it was the leading cause
## so why the [ __ ] are we even doing this why are
## we even promoting environmentalism and trying to