## sales is too much practical veganism
## is more from the from our internals
## not sure what you mean there soilless magician
## is it good to start with the socratic method
## to get to know where the individual is
## at well socratic questioning is
## something that we touch on in this
## so jazz just stick around and i'll get into
## that further all right guys i'm gonna move on
## okay that does help good let's move on
## the socratic the very next slide there it is jazz
## maybe we sensed the line of questions that
## might come from you guys and that's why we
## put this slide next all right so socratic
## the socratic method socratic questioning
## is a communication tool that we use within our
## approach it is not an approach in and of itself
## and neither is the sales thing where we ask
## questions to lead the bystander to their own
## conclusions so yes jazz you're right and i'll
## read that again okay so credit questioning is
## a communication tool that we use within our
## approach it is not an approach in and of itself
## where we ask questions to lead the
## bystander to their own conclusions
## use open-ended questions such as why are you sorry
## let me start again use open-ended questions such
## as why are you against animal abuse instead of
## a closed statement such as animal abuse is wrong
## open-ended questions are
## generally prefer preferred
## i've got a problem with speaking today open-ended
## questions are generally preferred to anchor
## and progress the conversation you should use
## closed-ended questions and statements 30 seconds
## would it be possible to ask the non-vegan to give
## us feedback on the conversation they had well
## we kind of do at the end we say what do you
## think you'll do that gives you the answer
## and danya if i'm saying
## you're not your name correctly
## dania could you also point out the tip about
## open-ended questions are generally preferred
## to anchor and progress the conversation you
## should you should use closed-ended questions and
## statements so we're not saying use open-ended
## questions all the time that's just ridiculous
## but generally they are preferred i'm
## going to move on now to the next slide
## you versus we we don't torture animals and kill
## animals for products non-vegans do using we
## undermines individual accountability when you tell
## non-vegans that we as a society are responsible
## for animal cruelty in farms it takes away the
## imperative for the individual accountability it
## makes them think of lobbying government programs
## etc instead of personal responsibilities people
## need to feel guilty to change they'll only change
## once they understand that there is a difference
## between you the vegan and them the non-vegan
## and that difference needs to be very clear
## 30 seconds
## i can add and say that guilt is the only way
## in my opinion to get people to go vegan not
## plant-based but transform them into a vegan
## activist that's gonna change the [ __ ] world
## amen
## um can we mean i was in the same boat as
## the non-vegan well that's the thing it's
## being used that way but when you say we you no
## longer do it so it's just completely inaccurate
## you're making an inaccurate statement
## in an effort to seem more humble