## animal abuse animal cruelty yeah absolutely most
## people say yes absolutely now if they say no
## they're either drunk or trolling and either
## way you shouldn't be having a conversation
## with those people they're not reachable
## again this is so obviously wrong i mean
## you're seeing animals being hacked apart on
## the screens how could anybody say this is okay
## so usually they say that then the next step would
## be okay what do you think you can do about it as
## an individual so we've gone from the first step
## of the process within the three-step process of
## emotional conviction really quickly moving to
## the second step which is accountability what
## do you think you can do about it and again most
## of the time i actually get i think i could stop
## eating them i could become vegan so what do
## you think you can do about it as individuals
## stop become vegan yes we can vegan it's very
## simple isn't it yeah that's why i'm saying
## this is so [ __ ] obvious to people it's not that
## complex it's really not it's very obvious so the
## interaction so then you say what do you think
## you can do about this as an individual usually
## they say well i can stop being vegan but if they
## say something that a lot of the times they'll
## actually try to distract and say well you can
## protest the government protest these industries
## again you deal with the objection bring it
## back to accountability that's all you're doing
## deal with the objection anchor it back to
## accountability once you have the concede
## after dealing with all of those back and
## forth back and forth once you have them
## concede then you bring in the benefits do you
## know what the number one benefit is to be vegan
## usually their ears perk up when you say
## benefit and they look at you like what is it
## i want to know and that's when you say
## well obviously the benefit for them is
## they're no longer tortured and abused
## for you you're no longer the reason
## that this happens to them but the benefit for you
## is that you no longer have to be an animal abuser
## right so a new update again and i'm gonna
## break this down in the slides that i do later
## but the update here is to
## say for the first time um
## you will have the opportunity to stop being a
## hypocrite instead of saying you will no longer
## be a hypocrite and i'm saying this because
## many vegans are straight-up hypocrites
## but when you become vegan it is the first
## time in human life you can stop you have the
## opportunity to stop being a hypocrite uh because
## you address the biggest hypocrisy i think humans
## are engaging in so i just want to clarify
## that it doesn't automatically remove you
## from hypocrisy when you become vegan but it does
## give you an opportunity to truly end hypocrisy
## and you no longer have to be hypocrite and abused
## for you you're no longer the reason that this
## happens to them but the benefit for you is that
## you no longer have to be an animal abuser and you
## no longer have to be a hypocrite because you say
## that you're against animal abuse do you guys know
## what the number one benefit is of not supporting
## what's on the screen from being vegan any guesses
## so the number one benefit obviously
## for the animals once you're vegan
## then they're no longer tortured and abused
## because of you so they're relieved of that
## and then the best benefit for you guys is that
## because in the beginning of the conversation
## you stated that you're against animal abuse
## you're horrified by what's on the screens
## when you're vegan for the first time
## then you no longer have to be a hypocrite
## never thought of it like that do you know the
## number one benefit of going vegan the number
## one benefit obviously for the animals once you're
## vegan then they're no longer tortured because of
## you so they're relieved of that and then the best
## benefit for you is that because you said you're
## against animal abuse when you're vegan for the
## first time you no longer have to be a hypocrite
## and do you know the number one benefit when
## you stop supporting animals and be vegan the
## number one benefit of that you're not part of a
## crazy-ass society that's actually really close
## it would first be for the animals would no
## longer be abused by you but as an individual
## this is really important on an individual
## level since you've told me in this conversation
## that you are against animal abuse and you're
## clearly disturbed of what you see on the screen
## when you become vegan for the first time
## you no longer have to be a hypocrite
## do you know the number one benefit of being vegan
## like the number one benefit any guesses like