## okay where is this
## here we are
## all right so i'm going to go
## over everything once more just
## to reiterate all these points and make
## sure you guys fully understand them
## there was a complaint about my speaking voice
## how is the audio coming through let me know
## oh
## nope this isn't it
## this is it um
## um okay so question by carlo hi paul
## once you understand that the person
## you are talking to is not going to be interested
## in the topic and continues justifying animal abuse
## what do you say to them before going away all
## these examples you saw and everything that we
## said in the approach applies to these
## individuals the only difference is that
## at some i'm assuming that these people
## probably at a cube of truth probably
## won't even stop but if they do stop and
## you're talking to them at some point
## it could be really powerful for you to just end
## the discussion with that that uh statement that
## was made at the end of the interaction you saw
## examples from hudson and jacob um just know that
## for as long as you remain non-vegan these animals
## will be tortured and abused because of you and
## just decide what side of history so i'll
## i'll leave this with you to think about but
## you ultimately will need to decide which side of
## history you want to stand on something powerful
## like that a statement like that is all you can
## really do with those individuals and i i just want
## to say that it's important that you respect your
## time as an activist and that you're not wasting
## your breath on people so it's very powerful to
## say to the individual that you would like to
## carry on your work with those who are like you'd
## like to move on you know so ending the discussion
## and moving on after you make that statement is
## super powerful and that's what you should do
## audio is fine good thank you guys
## i've got the slide ready i'm just
## going to read through your comments
## and see if there's any questions
## david's saying i would only say i
## wouldn't mind if an animal killed me
## but i would say i would eat you would say
## that you would eat a human okay david you uh
## you sound a bit confused buddy i don't
## think you would be okay with an animal
## eating you if you had a choice and
## you have a choice not to eat animals
## so you're the oppressor and the power is in your
## hands to end the suffering and abuse and torture
## that you would inflict on these animals otherwise
## if you choose to continue to be a non-vegan human
## supremacist because that's what non-vegans are
## human supremacists and you are subscribing to this
## death cult you're subscribing to this
## idea that animals should be reduced
## to a sandwich through violent
## beheadings and enslavement and torture
## david says it's an excuse but i'm
## addicted addiction isn't a justification
## so let's hope that david gets the message
## here and does actually connect his actions
## to his words and ends his hypocrisy for real but
## let's move on to your other questions here guys
## can you say something about infighting between
## vegans and outreach organizations i hate it and
## how to stop this welcome to the animal rights
## movement if you know how i can stop this i'd
## like to know um vegans are the biggest threat
## to the animal rights movement i've been saying