## they were talking about animals every
## single time even people like joe rogan
## who's a [ __ ] avid hunter and loves to justify
## not being vegan at every opportunity he gets
## even he said he supported the wildlife in
## australia and he was referring to the koalas
## and the other animals people around the world have
## only shown empathy or sympathy towards the animals
## that were suffering in the wildfires right that
## just goes to show that this is very obvious in
## people's minds and that's why i'm saying this is
## a lot more obvious than we think it is it really
## is people already care about animal rights
## and the reason i know that is because nobody
## unless they're a psychopath would be comfortable
## with the label of being an animal abuser
## and that's what non-vegans are they're abusing
## animals the only reason why they feel comfortable
## is because the guilt is shared by everybody we've
## broken out of that now we can see straight now
## but it doesn't mean that it's not completely
## obvious still for everybody else we've just
## taken action on this none of these excuses are
## ever going to trump you they should never have
## you feeling flustered they should never have you
## feeling like you don't know the answer because
## the answer is always very simple and it's the fact
## that they can't justify abusing animals needlessly
## end of story whenever in doubt
## just compare to any other
## but it should injustice like a
## delicacy and something that we eat
## maybe once a week instead
## of i don't think that the
## the rate that we use it is natural we're
## at the extreme end of this lifestyle now
## would you say that with any
## other injustice like sexism
## child abuse no but i'm saying would
## you take that position would you say
## that it would be too extreme to avoid at
## all that we should still do it sometimes
## yeah that was good that was a good rebuttal we're
## not vegan but we're vegetarian delivered chicken
## yeah so we're fish chicken so would you take the
## same position with any other injustice let's say
## we're talking about sexism or racism would you
## have the same view on that where are we going here
## so let's say we're talking about racism yeah
## would you be like i'm against racism i don't
## want to be a racist but then maybe
## like on sundays i make an exception
## to be racist yeah so this is a form of
## discrimination against another species
## while you're still having a little bit of egg or
## chicken whatever i'm not sure what you're having
## you're still really supporting animal cruelty
## and more exploitation we will do it slowly i
## understand it might seem like a big jump would
## you take that on any other issue for example
## if somebody said i'm going to slowly stop
## beating my child i'm going to slowly become
## a non-racist no you wouldn't be uh that's we
## got to do it right do you think that we should
## contribute to this last or do you think that we
## should say hey we should just stop hurting animals
## stop stop right people will talk a good game about
## reducing or making excuses for why they won't go
## vegan just compare to any other injustice in that
## moment we are an animal rights organization we've
## never deemed ourselves to be an environmentalist
## group a group of environmentalists trying to
## change the world for the betterment of the
## environment we've never claimed to be a
## nutritionist organization a group of nutritionists
## trying to change the world for the betterment of
## human health we've only ever claimed to be an
## animal rights organization but there's this myth
## that exists in the vegan movement that when you
## promote health and environment these things will
## get people more interested in animal rights and
## that's the reason why we've been talking about
## these things is to try to get them hooked if
## someone doesn't seemingly care about animals
## well i guess i'll talk to them about health
## because they have heart disease i guess i'll
## talk to them about how they can reverse their
## heart disease by eating a plant-based diet if they
## don't seemingly care about the animals we think
## we'll talk to them about the environment this
## is destroying the rainforest this is destroying
## our climate crisis the idea that this will lead
## someone to animal rights and caring about animal
## rights is a complete myth animal rights is obvious
## nobody in their right mind would be comfortable
## with the label of being an animal abuser so
## it's not a matter of people not caring
## about animal rights it's a matter of you
## not promoting animal rights correctly it may
## seem like a tough pill to swallow to hear that