## end the conversation with the statement 30 seconds
## from a outsider point of view this vegan
## approach is genius david velas is in the comments
## and seems effective and david is not vegan joining
## us and giving his feedback on this approach
## i appreciate it david i appreciate your
## feedback but you know that this is going to be
## a huge thing for you that you have to
## face because this whole conversation
## if you're telling us it's effective what we
## really want to know is how effective is it for you
## all right let's move on
## so this is the last slide guys
## closing the conversation an effective statement
## in this situation can be so keep in mind that for
## however long that you're not vegan animals
## will be abused and tortured because of you
## so when you're ready to stop abusing animals
## and align your actions with your words
## you know what to do so think about what side
## of history you want to stand on and that closed
## um that closes the conversation but this is also
## the question that we have for you david this
## question is for you what are you going to do
## your question david i'm not sure on
## uh how would i respond to someone
## saying that they would hire animals
## it's i don't i've never heard that before but
## hiring i'm not sure if you've used the wrong word
## there but hiring animals is still exploitation
## that's just another word for enslaving animals
## but i'm not quite sure i
## understand your question there
## and this is the end of this live stream
## and this workshop so i want to thank you
## each of you for being a part of this it's
## been really energizing for me to do this
## leading into international cube day which
## is tomorrow and this is something that i've
## been wanting to roll out for a few months
## now so thank you for being a part of this
## and if you have any questions that you want to
## send me directly on social media about anything
## we've discussed here feel free to do so you can
## follow me on instagram paul bashir underscore av
## um i also have a youtube channel paul bashir
## and uh yeah connect with me on social media
## after this if you need any further support thank
## you for the support you've shown us and if you're
## going to be at a cube tomorrow have a good one i'm
## going to be out in melbourne with a very limited
## number of people and we're gonna do what we can
## to make it happen and i will go live at some point
## so i'll see you there see you on the
## streets hopefully at some point too
## much love everybody i'm gonna
## stop this share and stop