## very simple issue seriously animal abuse is
## wrong and there's no justification for it
## we don't need statistics to prove that to people
## necessarily if people want to talk about this to
## you and they bring up statistics and they want
## to debate statistics make sure that you're not
## feeding into the distraction too much i
## want to talk about vegetarianism real quick
## i think vegetarianism is a cancer
## to the animal rights movement
## and we think that for some reason in this
## movement we think that vegetarians are closer
## to this message they're our allies again we would
## never do this with i just wanna i just wanna take
## a moment to call myself out this is the holding
## non-vegans accountable 2.0 workshop but i'm going
## to take a sweet moment to hold myself accountable
## because i just said in this movement we think
## that vegetarians are the same whatever i said i
## don't think that anymore in fact i've probably
## been the most vocal about this in the animal
## rights movement but yeah i was just talking
## about how we need to be accurate with our words so
## i just want to pull myself up there and say that
## i no longer talk like this about vegeta i never
## really did ever so yeah any other injustice and
## you and they bring up statistics animal abuse
## is wrong and there's no justification for it
## make sure that you're not feeding into the
## distraction too much i want to talk about
## vegetarianism real quick i think vegetarianism
## is a cancer to the animal rights movement and
## we think that for some reason in this movement we
## think that vegetarians are closer to this message
## they're our allies again we would never do this
## with any other injustice and vegetarian is no
## different to paleo i mean vegetarians will stop
## eating meat then that's no different to what the
## paleo crew are doing because they don't eat dairy
## and it's been argued that the dairy industry could
## be the cruelest industry in the world we should
## really be calling the paleo crew our allies
## not vegetarians but do you see how insane
## that sounds me even saying that we would call
## the paleo guys our allies just because meat is
## obviously cruel to animals it doesn't mean dairy
## isn't and eggs isn't and you all know that because
## you're vegan and you already know this information
## but when we even slightly give in to this
## idea that vegetarians are on our side then
## we perpetuate this myth even further we are the
## ones who are spreading the wrong message here
## so when someone says don't worry i'm
## vegetarian you don't need to talk to me
## your response should be you're actually our
## target market and in fact you have more of a
## responsibility to go harder on those individuals
## because they already think they're doing enough
## they feel entitled and how dare you tell them
## they're doing any different is the attitude
## they usually give you i appreciate all that
## you're doing just once you know that i'm a
## vegetarian that drinks almond milk okay that's
## good local farm interesting i'm just saying like
## you might want to just focus your food versus
## somewhere else because i i totally am already
## on board i got that so was animal cruelty
## one of the reasons why you became vegetarian
## since i was 19 i'm 45 okay that's about 27 years
## of vegetarian one of the footage that we chose
## here is also from local like free range like egg
## farms let me ask you a question because you say
## that you usually get your eggs from like local
## like free range farms where did they get their
## hands from like for example her father's chickens
## that run around his yard so like they are i don't
## know where he gets attention because um what sex
## is important in the egg industry males are females
## obviously the females so when people get hence
## they get them from a breeder in hatcheries even
## like for people that just want to get like
## a egg laying hence males and females are
## born a different color if you're born female
## you're thrown to the left if you're a male
## you're thrown to the right where do you think
## the males go i get it directly into a blender
## so i'm doing everything i can to
## minimize my impact but i'm not good
## would you consider animal cruelty to be an
## injustice yes yeah would you take that same
## stance with any other injustice because you do
## recognize that there is cruelty and eggs right
## sure so i found with the majority of vegetarians
## actually they're harder to get through they're not
## our allies they're not closest to this message
## they're pompous sure there's vegetarians out
## there who didn't know better and i've met many
## of those too they just didn't know better once