## um if you have any questions
## please try to save them until i do a q a but
## if you can't wait until then drop them in the
## chat and i'll do my best to respond to them
## at some point happening now on youtube cool
## all right
## isaac you can moderate that would be a huge
## help yeah i just it won't take much work
## ah yeah cool no worries if someone wants to
## moderate though it won't take much work i
## just want to i just don't want to be dealing
## with trolls and [ __ ] but it's no big deal
## even if they do come up you know if they
## want to come on and try to wreck my stream
## they're welcome all right
## so let's do this swipe up
## cool all right about to get
## into what we need to get into
## so the first thing i'm going to be doing
## is i'm going to play this live for you guys
## and then what i'm going to do is review it for
## you live and the first thing i need to do here
## is since i haven't done this in a while i need to
## i need to remember how to share the screen
## correctly i remember how to do it but not
## correctly so just give me a moment bear with me
## and i'll have it ready you know what i think i
## will take some questions to begin with let me
## know if you have any and i'll kill some time
## during that whilst i get this ready so if you
## have any questions hit me up in the comments
## damn
## struggleville trying to get
## this video to download properly please
## do more of these streams paul it's good
## to interact with you well i would
## like to do more streams all right
## why is it doing that yeah so again if you have
## any questions let me know in the comments and
## i'll go ahead and answer them for you now here's
## a question what's your opinion on wild animal
## suffering it's a topic i recently discovered
## i don't know if you've heard of it or not
## might have seen it in might have seen it from
## humane hancock okay so i did respond to this
## uh on my instagram so i forget what i
## said exactly but i said something like
## let's just focus i mean my answer to this question
## is pretty straightforward let's just focus on the
## human inflicted suffering on animals that we
## are currently i mean it's the biggest issue
## that we have to be accountable for so we need
## to look in the mirror before we start trying
## to intervene further in the animal kingdom
## can we just stop murdering animals first can
## we stop enslaving torturing and murdering them
## that's what i would like to address this whole
## thing and i think this is what i said in my
## instagram post this whole thing is such an
## odd discussion to me it's so strange and uh
## it reminds me of how off-base it is for human
## beings to explore and discover the universe and
## space to the extent that humans do and yet we
## still have 80 percent of the ocean 80 percent
## completely undiscovered unobserved unexamined
## you know this is just very typical of humans
## i think that we don't address we don't look