## because you engage in carnivorous bestiality
## on a daily basis sometimes multiple times a day
## you eat things that come out of the hen's
## ass and shove things into a turkey's ass
## you eat breast legs and thighs and then you pay
## somebody else to sexually molest a cow and squeeze
## her nipples for you so you can steal her milk man
## you guys are obsessed with bird asses and cow tits
## enough already seriously is it
## possible to step into the 21st century
## and stop mimicking the behavior of cavemen
## and cave women you got a choice today
## when you leave this room you can choose
## to never intentionally harm another animal
## for breakfast lunch or dinner ever again
## these animals have never violated you or
## taken advantage of you in any way the
## least you can do is return the favor
## or stay radically cruel keep the status quo as
## is make sure animals have their babies stolen
## from them make sure their horns are cut off
## be sliced off testicles ripped out make sure
## they're raped make sure they never experience
## one drop of human kindness and make sure there's
## a knife in their throat every second of every
## minute of every hour of every day for eternity
## i hope you make the right choice isn't it rough
## enough being an animal on this planet with us
## around as we claim everything for us the
## land is ours we pollute the air the water
## destroy the forest and the mountains do we have to
## maximize the cruelty that they already endure by
## eating them on top of it all you want to talk
## about pouring salt into somebody else's wombs
## 98 and i want to leave you with this stat 98 of
## animals who are abused and killed on this planet
## are abused and killed by the meat dairy and egg
## industries the least we can do is minimize the
## cruelty by living a vegan lifestyle i want to
## thank you guys for listening i do appreciate
## the open minds that's out there today hello
## everyone my name is kate timko before gary
## begins with the formal presentation this evening
## i'd like everyone to stop and think for a moment
## stop and think about the certain rights and
## freedoms that many human beings have just received
## over the last 150 years now these are rights and
## freedoms that many of us take for granted we don't
## think about every single day for instance 150
## years ago and in the grand scheme of things really
## that's just a blip but 150 years ago in america
## we still had slavery 100 years ago not one child
## in the united states had any rights whatsoever 85
## years ago women could not vote and 40 years ago
## only 40 years ago segregation was still thriving
## in america meaning that black people could not
## drink from the same water fountain as white people
## only 40 years ago now one of the most amazing
## traits that human beings possess is our short-term
## selective memory process now we do love to believe
## we've been good decent compassionate to each
## other for a very very long time but decency and
## compassion are pretty much brand new concepts
## when it comes to the treatment of most human
## beings now it is our hope that in the next 150
## years we will all continue to evolve with decency
## continue to evolve with compassion and extend it
## to the entire animal kingdom humans and animals
## together the entire animal kingdom so if anyone
## came in today thinking animal rights is radical
## or extreme outrageous or maybe even silly please
## stop and think about those certain rights and
## freedoms that human beings have just received over
## the last 150 years and then one could logically
## conclude that animals will be the next group of
## disenfranchised beings to obtain their freedom
## so i guess it's safe to say that this room is full
## of people who eat meat i'm sure most people here
## own shoes or belts or jackets made from the
## skin of cows kate and i used to wear leather
## shoes belts and jackets too and i ate meat for 25
## years k-8 meat 4 23 before i talk about veganism
## in detail all the ethical and health reasons
## for living a vegan lifestyle and discuss what
## it's like to be an animal in the food industry i
## want to talk about the blinders that everyone has
## on blinders that kate and i used to have
## on too blinders that absolutely destroy
## compassion blinders that make people unconcerned
## about cruelty and killing and blinders that
## give some people the audacity to laugh and make
## jokes about the suffering of animals now those