## hitler did have a lot of power didn't he if he had
## all this power that he had why didn't he mandate
## veganism if he were a vegan or a vegetarian do you
## know that himmler the guy that constructed all the
## gas chambers was a chicken he wanted to slaughter
## jews this is why he had another idea a complete
## other idea two of his biographers albert spear
## and robert payne talked about hitler's love for
## liver dumplings and pigeon which is known as squab
## his main chef dion lucas wrote a book in 1964 the
## gourmet school cooking book and she wrote his
## favorite recipes which were all meat based recipes
## this is the power of propaganda the
## power of gerbils still alive and well
## do you know why people think hitler was veg
## gerbils wanted to make hitler seem as peaceful
## as somebody else in the world at that time who was
## loved and adored and his name was mohandas gandhi
## and gandhi was vegetarian and gerbils will say
## wait hitler's just like gandhi he loves animals
## too and he's peaceful to the animals and he's a
## vegetarian he's not and just so you know all the
## concentration camps did have animal slaughter
## houses there too and when the allied forces
## came in to rescue the jews and the gypsies they
## left the animals behind this is why i call this
## the world's largest and longest-running holocaust
## the animal holocaust was happening long before the
## jewish holocaust during the jewish holocaust and
## it's still happening today every second just so
## you know of every minute of every hour of every
## day female animals are raped to impregnate them
## every second animals are being killed every
## 60 billion animals every year do you accept
## or do you understand or the people are calling
## you terrorists sure what else are they going to
## call me and as we go back in time and look at all
## the other people that we adore now collectively
## we all agree gandhi and dr martin luther king
## and all these people rosa parks and cesar chavez
## do you know they were not loved during their time
## they were despised they wanted to make change
## massive change it's only later on that a society
## looks back at revolutionary activists and says oh
## man he was great he was just trying
## to break bring peace and justice it's
## amazing that i'm called a terrorist and if
## i'm called a terrorist for saving animals
## what do we call people that kill animals
## and torture animals and eat animals
## one last thing before we have 30-20 seconds what
## did you have for lunch i had a vegan schnitzel and
## a vegan burger from the vegan shawarma place in
## town my favorite restaurant vegan schnitzel vegan
## shawarma vegan schnitzel a vegan hamburger uh gary
## thank you very much coming to our studio and thank
## you our viewers for being with us tonight we
## and we will be back on sunday at the same time