## uh
## um
## so
## thank you
## down
## so
## now not that any law could ever alleviate
## the suffering and slaughter that you folks
## just witnessed but i want to read an excerpt to
## everyone right now from the animal welfare act
## of 1966 this is a pathetic piece of legislation
## if and i say if if you can even call this a law
## because the animal welfare act states verbatim
## that the term animal excludes birds rats
## mice horses and other farm animals such as but not
## limited to livestock and poultry and anything used
## or intended to be used as food or clothing it also
## states that the term exhibitor excludes retail pet
## stores organizations sponsoring state and county
## fairs livestock shows rodeos purebred dog and cat
## shows and any fair or exhibition intended
## to advance agricultural arts and sciences
## that's some law they've laid out for the animals
## but even if this animal welfare act decided to
## include all of the animals you just heard
## it leaves out i want to be clear about this
## there is no peaceful compassionate way to shoot an
## animal between their eyes or slice their throats
## it is the taking of an animal's life that is the
## ultimate violation all of the mutilations that
## happen to these animals along the way which we're
## going to discuss in a moment only serve to prove
## that animals have been reduced to objects they
## are mere commodities that have to meet certain
## specifications in order to maximize profits and
## during this speech when we say the word farm we
## are not just speaking about factory farms we are
## talking about all farms factory free range organic
## and mom-and-pop farms because all farms that raise
## animals for food kill animals for food so all we
## ask from here on out is that you folks give us
## an open mind and truly hear what we're about to
## tell you now each year in the us we kill about 10
## billion land animals and 18 billion marine animals
## because people have acquired a taste for meat
## and i stress acquired a taste for meat worldwide