## chicken or an organically raised chicken they all
## end up dead from unnatural causes because people
## have acquired a taste for animal flesh comedian
## dennis miller who was not an activist one
## sarcastically yet truthfully made this statement
## about free-range chicken farms free-range chickens
## they all end up dead don't seem that free to
## me don't be duped by the free range industry
## cows turkeys ducks sheep and other animals
## are subjected to the same barbaric treatment
## bulls are castrated because cows are artificially
## inseminated in fact nearly every male animal is
## considered expendable because nowadays just
## about every animal raised and killed for food
## on this planet is artificially inseminated and
## genetically engineered in case you don't believe
## me i'm sure everybody read the latest edition of
## pork everybody got their latest edition of pork in
## the mail right right along with sports illustrated
## newsweek cosmopolitan pork big industry trade
## journal if you flip around the pages of pork
## you'll find an advertisement for a ginetta pork
## better pigs better pork better profits ginetta
## pork better pigs better pork better profits
## genetic one of dozens of companies now creating
## the food that you eat every woman in this room
## should think deeply about the frightening fact
## of animal reproduction because many feminists
## throughout history from annie besson and susan
## b anthony to alice walker and gloria steinem
## became animal rights humanitarians because these
## great women not only understood that animals had
## an inherent right to be free but these great
## women understood that their non-human sisters
## were being exploited for their reproductive organs
## the female animal is viewed as nothing more than
## a baby machine by the greedy callous malefactors
## who run the animal flesh industry l.j taylor of
## walls meat limited once said this in a national
## hog farmer magazine i'm sure everybody has read
## their latest edition of national hog farm the
## breeding style should be thought of and treated
## as a valuable piece of machinery whose function
## is the pump out baby pigs the sausage machine
## last year in the u.s alone 17 billion fish
## shrimp lobsters and other aquatic animals
## were killed and eaten many were raised on fish
## farms they were genetically engineered yes
## fish farms farming is not just
## relegated to the land anymore
## l.a times one of its 2002 editions bounty
## farms one of dozens of companies now
## creating fish genetically engineering them
## if you look at the photo in the upper left
## you'll notice that they have genetically altered a
## salmon to be twice as big as its wild counterpart
## the rest of the aquatic animals were either
## hooked by the mouth or netted in huge trawlers
## gigantic high-powered vacuum cleaners that
## sucked up catch and kill everything in its
## path in order to explain why fishing is cruel
## vicious and unethical i decided to use an analogy
## today to help you empathize imagine reaching for
## an apple on a tree and having your hands suddenly
## impaled by a metal hook that drags you the whole
## weight of your body pulling on that one hand
## dragging you out of the air and into an
## atmosphere in which you cannot breathe
## that is what aquatic animals experience
## they are removed from their watery habitat
## civil rights activist animal rights activist
## humanitarian alice walker once eloquently summed
## up the reason for animal freedom the animals of
## the world exist for their own reasons they were
## not made for humans any more than black people
## were made for whites or women were created for men
## go by the books diet for a new america or the food
## revolution both by john robbins for an amazing
## comprehensive look at veganism and john robbins
## happens to be quite a remarkable individual
## you might recognize him by his last
## name if you think about it long enough
## his family owns the billion dollar baskin robbins
## ice cream empire however about 20 years ago
## john robbins removed himself from the family
## business because he wanted no part of an
## industry that exploited and murdered cows and
## no part of an industry that made people ill
## by feeding them animal secretions cow's milk
## is a secretion and secretions are filled with
## delicious fluids like pus and mucus i hope you
## realize that when a dairy cow can no longer give
## quality milk or produce huge amounts of milk she's
## sent to the slaughterhouse and killed there are
## no cow sanctuaries in the dairy industry in fact
## when it comes to pain and suffering the dairy cow