## an unfair comparison you're not a lion and just
## so you know lions are carnivores humans are not
## we are herbivores one hundred percent up and
## down you put a two-year-old child in a crib
## with a bunny rabbit and an apple let me know
## when the child eats the bunny rabbit and plays
## with the apple we are purely herbivorous we have
## no carnivorous or omnivorous instincts whatsoever
## and physiologically if your jaw moves from side
## to side in a grinding motion and you chew you're
## 100 herbivore if you were a meat-eater like a lion
## your jaw would only go like this up and down rip
## and swallow if you sweat through your pores to
## cool yourself your herbivore what is your main
## purpose because most of the world won't become
## vegan it depends on which day you ask me the world
## injustice can't live forever the world will become
## vegan one day just like just like every woman on
## this planet will one day have their equality with
## men just like one day all oppression will fall
## by the wayside injustice doesn't live forever and
## it seems insurmountable don't get me wrong i mean
## i'm in the trenches believe me it looks like it
## seems like it can't happen but remember it took
## 400 years to convince white people in america
## not to own black people you can see why this is
## taking so long we can't even treat each other
## with kindness let alone treat the chickens and
## the pigs and the turkeys and the insects of the
## world with kindness but i think we can treat each
## other with kindness one day once we learn how
## to treat the animals with kindness you know i'm
## i'm i'm feeling a little bit uncomfortable
## because i just had a steak for lunch and um
## i and it's still i'm not convinced convinced 100
## that i should stop eating meat for the rest of my
## life it's not that i'm eating meat every day but
## i do love my steak on the plate once a week so
## you have now two minutes to try to convince me eat
## meat once in once a month i don't want to convince
## you to do it once a month i want to convince you
## never to do it okay you have to put yourself in
## the animal's position imagine that you were raped
## to impregnate yourself okay somebody raped you to
## impregnate you you gave birth to this baby this
## baby was stolen from you at birth that baby was
## fattened up with corn and soy and wheat and oats
## that baby was put on a concentration camp truck
## sent to a slaughterhouse hung upside down fully
## conscious in front of all of her own species
## screaming terrified in fear knife shoved into you
## know her throat cut up into pieces where's the
## justification for this and it's not your steak you
## said my steak i'm very big on language that steak
## was never yours okay that steak is a euphemism
## by the way that's cow flesh that flesh belonged
## to another living being where do humans get off
## owning and controlling living beings where do
## we get off thinking that we're the most special
## thing that has ever existed on this planet when
## in reality we're the most unspecial thing that has
## ever existed on this planet are you aware that if
## humans were removed from the planet the extinction
## of humans would benefit everything that exists
## are you also aware that if the bees died off
## as we've been talking about this for about 10
## years in the news the whole system collapses
## if the ants were exterminated the whole system
## would collapse this is how important and
## special ants and bees are to the world
## why do we think we're better than they are
## when they serve a vital role and we serve no
## vital role whatsoever we're tormentors we're
## oppressors where do you think it's come it's
## coming from the arrogance yeah i'm not sure i
## don't know i don't know what has gotten into us
## besides death and torture and murder i think
## when you put violence in you get violence out
## you consume discrimination and death you're
## going to you know exude some people may say the
## same things about you because some people may say
## that he's arrogance he thinks that he knows better
## he thinks that he's better than us and actually
## we're all actually um we're all let's say
## how can i put it i'm i'm the one to be charged and
## you are the the judge who is judging me right now
## yeah and well there's two people in this world
## there's there's people that judge and people
## that lie about judging we judge people every
## day we judge child molesters we judge rapists
## we judge nazis uh we judge murderers um and i
## know this is a shock to the meat dairy and egg
## eaters of the world but vegans are more ethical
## than they are hands down and of course just like
## a person that doesn't rape is more ethical than
## a person who does rape a person who doesn't kill
## cows pigs chickens and turkeys is better than
## a person who does a vegetarian hitler was not a
## vegetarian that's a complete lie a complete and
## utter lie from gerbils his propaganda minister