## pollute their environment destroy their habitat is
## there a reason we have to maximize the suffering
## and maximize the cruelty and the
## death that they already endure
## by eating them on top of it all you want to talk
## about pouring salt into somebody else's womb
## 98 and i repeat this stat 98 of animals who are
## abused and killed on this planet are abused and
## killed by the meat dairy and egg industries
## this is where all the harm is taking place and
## in america from birth until death each meat eater
## consumes around 3 000 land animals and thousands
## of other marine animals those are usda stats
## now with all this being said we've established
## the four reasons why people eat meat cheese
## milk and eggs no debating no discussing them
## have it tradition convenience taste it now
## i want to get back to taste good though
## because i think meat tastes great it might shock
## you to hear me say that but if you're doing some
## kind of extra credit essay on my speech you
## want to quote me quote me right now i love
## the way meat tastes love it cheese love it
## cow's milk and eggs love it guilty as charged
## i did not stop eating this stuff because of
## the taste issue i stopped for ethics morality
## decency how come when i talk about mock meat i
## always catch a handful of people in every crowd
## and we got a big crowd today so i stopped counting
## at about eight or nine how come there's always a
## handful of people that wrinkle up their noses make
## big wide eyes and start glancing at the people
## next to them across the aisle like soy chicken
## is this guy crazy soy bacon he must be out of his
## mind how come this stuff that is made of soy wheat
## vegetables grains and spices contrary to the lies
## being spread about these products by the meat and
## dairy industries how come this stuff is considered
## gross to most people but meat meat's got five
## components let me break it down for you blood
## flesh veins muscles and tendons the cut up
## corpse of a dismembered body how does meat
## not qualify as gross and disgusting everybody
## how in the world is a beverage a liquid that
## oozes out of the others of cows a secretion that
## drips from the mammary glands of another being
## that's loaded with pus by the way oh yeah let
## me tell you how the pus in your child milk it'd
## be my pleasure when you hook machines up to the
## others of cows three times a day to suck them dry
## those machines cause massive amounts of infections
## on the inside and outside of the utter now let's
## add all the bovine growth hormone they put in cows
## to make sure they produce huge quantities of milk
## which always leads to another infection the
## machine doesn't know what not to suck out
## pus mucus and infections right in with your
## milk and yeah milk is pasteurized but when did
## pasteurization become a removal process it's a
## sanitation process you're only sanitizing pus
## and you want to look this up online you
## don't think the dairy industry would ever
## use the word pus when they write about
## this problem in their own trade journals
## and they're going to deceive you again with
## this look up the scientific term for pus
## somatic cell count and by the way our
## government the usda they allow the dairy
## industry to have a maximum amount of one eye
## dropper full of pus in every glass another
## drink up does anybody know what an egg actually
## is from a hand and don't say embryo or aborted
## fetus not even close it's unfertilized so
## it can't be either hen is a female though
## unfertilized egg through a female system it's
## part of her menstruation cycle it's a hens
## period people scramble up hand periods in the
## morning and all of a sudden i'm weird because i
## don't make omelets anymore and what about vomit oh
## we're going to take those blinders off today come
## on you guys love vomit you adore it all over your
## food got you give this one a pretty name though
## no one's gonna buy and eat vomit unless we call
## it honey instead honey comes directly from a
## bee's stomach it is regurgitated right through a
## bee's mouth look it up with any wildlife biologist
## but nobody wants to eat bee bonnet and
## nut cheerios we want honey nut cheerios
## so we hire ourselves to play euphemism games the
## standard diet of a meat eater is blood flesh veins
## muscles tendons cow secretions hen periods and b
## vomit now we're not done yet i am not going to let