## so
## i am forever embarrassed to be a human being to
## stand upright like that's something to be proud of
## did you ever wonder why mcdonald's and burger
## king and wendy's never use those images in
## their tv ads no severed heads dismembered limbs
## corpses blood guts always showing you a happy
## singing smiling cartoon caricature
## instead lying to you brainwashing you
## and programming you not to care about
## things you would normally care about
## things that you used to care about when you were
## young innocent and uncorrupted by society's lies
## so how come if the animals in that video were
## dogs and cats people would be outraged and if they
## were kids the world would scream bloody murder
## instead the victims are cows and chickens and fish
## and all of a sudden it's okay so i am a
## little confused here is the slaughterhouse
## the problem or is the problem just who's
## getting killed in the slaughterhouse
## because it's a house of slaughter why does it
## even exist especially when peace begins at the
## dinner table with what you put into your body on a
## daily basis good people don't talk about kindness
## they practice it and they certainly don't pray
## about love on the weekends for an hour or two they
## actually give it all the time i know you have
## the capability of understanding right from wrong
## because you all hate people who harm children why
## not hate people who harm animals it's hypocritical
## why protect one victim and then violate and
## ignore the other victim when neither victim wants
## nor deserves the abuse they just wish it would end
## stop praising the innocents in children and then
## ignoring and making fun of the exact same
## innocence in the animals and everyone has
## to stop making these idiotic claims that
## humans are the only ones who are capable
## of being rational and aware and that animals
## operate on instinct only can i explain something
## everybody in a pretty simple way breathing
## is instinctive everything else is a thought
## attached to an action it's not an accident
## that animals can build a home if given a chance
## and return to that home but they can care for
## their babies that they can find shade on a sunny
## day or seek warmth when it's cold figure out when
## to sleep or stay awake locate water to drink fly
## in a bee formation hide when they don't want to
## be seen defend their territories all these actions
## prove beyond a reasonable doubt that animals
## have the capacity of being rational and aware
## the human animal is the only animal that spends
## the majority of time not thinking eating at steak
## and shake in the golden corral and applebee's
## and long john silvers is not rational thought
## but this isn't a competition of intelligence or
## awareness this is about justice when we were kids
## each and every single one of us when our parents
## our grandparents sat us down and read us a story
## that story was about animals and when that
## story was read to us we smiled and giggled
## uncontrollably we even mimicked the noises they
## made their language we wanted to play with them
## so badly not have someone shove a knife in
## their throat and cut them up into pieces
## what happened to you along the way who
## stole your empathy and your conscience