## no logical person could choose to continue
## to eat animal flesh and the things that come
## out of animals so what is your final goal
## to to kill the meat industry to kill the
## farms i want to destroy all animal exploitative
## industries they're unjust the animals are not
## willing participants in this holocaust what about
## the people that take place in those uh industries
## i read this somewhere that you said that uh a
## man that hurts an animal uh uh you could kill
## him or should die or something like that there's
## a justification for killing anybody who harms
## a human or an animal intentionally again you have
## to understand nobody's opposed to violence and
## i've been asking the audience here every day raise
## your hand if you're opposed to the allied forces
## coming into auschwitz and birkenau and murdering
## nazis to save jews and nobody raises their hands
## the problem is nobody thinks animals are
## important enough to kill for i think the
## animals disagree i think the cows and the chickens
## disagree so if i went into a slaughterhouse i'm
## the peaceful person if i even if i had guns
## drawn i don't know what's not about operator
## i would say drop your weapons you're done killing
## you're going to let these cows and these pigs and
## these chickens go i'm the one that's justified i'm
## stopping murder there's a justification there's
## nobility in killing somebody who has no the allied
## forces were noble do you think they weren't noble
## do you think that they should have let nazis
## kill jesus they did what they should have done
## and that's what we need to do as human beings if
## we claim to be compassionate claim to know right
## from wrong we have to kill beings who kill evil
## people but with that saying you give legitimacy to
## people who murder other people you know every each
## um every person could choose his own goal like uh
## the person who killed our prime minister igalami
## he said okay i did it to save the country to save
## more people getting killed but you know why that
## was unjust who was he killing the prime minister
## no who was the prime minister killing nobody you
## understand the difference between a murder for no
## reason a psychotic murder a psychotic murder that
## a fundamentalist jew a fundamentalist christian
## the fundamentalist muslim takes part in and going
## into a slaughterhouse and saying leave these cows
## alone nobody chickens have harmed nobody we are
## murdering innocent beings so if it ever came down
## to that but that's not the issue that is not the
## issue the issue is we just need to change the way
## we view animals we have to realize humans aren't
## the only beings on this planet and we're not
## more important than animals so why are aren't
## you allowed in some countries you can't enter
## canada uh or the uk i think because we live on
## a planet that murders animals a speciesistic
## plant and understand like a racist who thinks that
## their race is better than another race speciesists
## think that the human species is superior to
## animals and we have the right to harm and kill
## any species we choose so why would countries
## who murder animals want me to come in there
## and open people's eyes and get people to change
## were you surprised from your success in israel
## i've always noticed that over the years if
## i talk to people who have been oppressed
## if i do a classroom full of jewish
## people if i do a classroom full of women
## full of hispanics black people people who have
## been oppressed understand oppression so i'm
## not surprised that israel is embracing veganism
## right now and embracing me we've been oppressed
## way back into egypt times and to this day still
## depending on what part of the world you're in
## so people who have been harmed understand why
## it's wrong to harm somebody else so you really
## think you have a chance i think there's a chance
## i mean it kind of depends on which day you ask me
## you ask me when i'm in israel for the last 10
## days and people are embracing me i think yeah
## i think israel could become the first nation
## on this planet to abolish concentration camps
## once and for all you ask me on a bad day when
## people are screaming and yelling at me wanting
## to fight i'll say no i don't think it's possible
## but keep in mind no injustice can live forever
## sadly injustice can live for hundreds or
## even thousands of years but no lie can last
## forever and people are becoming aware and i
## think animals will obtain their freedom one
## day and be treated equally and fairly well
## thank you very much for coming you know uh
## the jewish new year's day is uh in two
## days hashanah hosh hashanah as you say
## in america i would like to give you a rosh
## hashanah gift it's a special organic seed
## we bought it from an organization who helped
## the disabled and happy new year to you thank you