## it needs from a meat-based diet diseases come
## and have been proven to come time and time again
## from meat and dairy and i'm still looking for the
## first medical report in history that can indict
## broccoli or bananas or carrots or apples as a
## cause of illness i want to take a few moments
## now and destroy this myth about human beings being
## on top of the food chain because tools and weapons
## power and intelligence have not magically
## transformed our physiology and turned us into
## carnivores or omnivores sharks lions tigers bears
## wolves hyenas jackals even most dogs could easily
## kill a human being in fact most herbivores like
## rhinos elephants hippos horses bulls and gorillas
## could easily kill a human being if provoked these
## animals have always been ahead of us on the food
## chain because killing during a one-on-one
## confrontation without the use of weapons
## and the ability to consume bloody raw flesh right
## from the bone without the side effect of disease
## have always been the only two true factors in
## determining placement on the food chain this
## is why most medical experts will attest to the
## fact that human beings are completely herbivorous
## creatures dr william roberts editor-in-chief of
## the american journal of cardiology states quite
## simply human beings are not natural carnivores
## because when we kill animals to eat them
## they end up killing us because their flesh was
## never intended for human beings who are natural
## herbivores the dairy industry has done a pretty
## masterful job at convincing most people that cows
## naturally give milk i really hope you don't
## believe that i still come across children to this
## day you know the age-old we've got to milk them
## and they'll explode female cows are like any other
## female mammal on this planet they only give milk
## during and after pregnancy which is why every year
## like clockwork they are artificially inseminated
## it keeps their milk flow going and within a few
## days of giving birth their babies are stolen from
## them they are breaking up families now they steal
## their babies from them at birth because from a
## business standpoint you can't have a whole bunch
## of little baby cows sucking up all the precious
## milk they want to sell to us humans where do male
## babies go on a dairy farm males obviously don't
## give milk completely useless but unlike the male
## baby chicks they've discovered a use for them they
## are shipped off to the veal farm where they're put
## in tiny little crates and kept in the dark to keep
## them quiet ropes and chains around their necks to
## keep keep them completely immobilized see that
## is why veal is such a tender meat no movement is
## ever allowed on behalf of these animals because
## no muscle development is ever allowed they want
## these animals to get to a large weight more meat
## to sell but still retain their infant white flesh
## but if you knew all of that about veal and you
## don't eat it because you feel for little baby boy
## cows and i mean really who wouldn't if you don't
## eat veal but you do drink milk and eat cheese
## eat veal you can eat veal to your heart's content
## because it doesn't make a bit of difference the
## veal industry is only in existence because of the
## dairy industry and once again that's their words
## not mine and we kind of talked about this already
## but everyone in this room knows why a cow really
## makes milk right a mother cow makes milk for her
## babies so cow's milk is meant for a baby cow just
## like human milk is meant for a baby human the
## human body has no more need for cow's milk than
## we do for dog milk giraffe milk rhinoceros milk
## zebra milk i promise you there will come a day
## when our grandchildren will ask us where were you
## during the animal holocaust and what did you do
## to stop these horrifying crimes will you be
## able to say that you stood up against oppression
## even when doing so was
## considered radical or unpopular
## so please please reevaluate your belief systems
## ask yourself why is all this violence against
## animals being permitted for what reasons we
## hope you'll have the same revelation that we did
## that non-violence through veganism
## non-violence through animal liberation
## is the only ethical and acceptable way to live
## on this planet thank you very much for listening
## i just recently read this story about this nazi
## his name was ernst gerbel he and his men were
## executing children one day but he didn't like the
## way his guards were grabbing kids by their hair
## before they shot him in the back of the head and
## tossed him in a mass grave he actually ordered his
## men to stop grabbing the kids by their hair
## and i quote kill them in a more decent way