## oh you're bullying all right
## holy [ __ ] you break a tail
## mom get your head
## like this
## turn your head turn your head [ __ ]
## turn your ass turn your ass come on
## [ __ ] tears oh i got a bad
## i have my blood pressure
## i don't think they're feeling any pain i just
## keep going until the cows are oh i'm like yeah
## this is not an isolated incident
## don't for one minute think that this is an
## isolated incident this is how slaves are treated
## you don't really think that
## slaves get treated nicely do you
## you really think white people were nice when
## they ship black people over here on ships
## you don't think nazis were nice when they walk
## jews and gypsies into the gas chambers do you
## and this happens because you want to buy
## those products yeah that guy's a scumbag
## for doing that but he's doing that because
## you want to eat what comes out of her body
## and enough already you're not a caveman and
## you're not a cave woman anymore stop acting
## like neanderthals this is 2010 give
## it up it's not cute and it's not funny
## because animals are being abused it is not your
## right it is not your freedom to do this to them
## you don't get to have freedom when
## somebody else doesn't that's a violation
## and if you wonder why vegans get so upset
## sometimes like i am right now you just
## saw some of it every time we show up at a farm
## somebody's punching chicken and stabbing somebody
## and something else that i'm curious about how
## come when i show videos like this of people
## punching and kicking animals people are
## more upset with that than when they shove
## a knife in their throat so even if you find
## a farm where they're not punching and kicking
## when they shove a knife in their throat to put a
## bullet between their eyes how is that not cruelty
## did you know that 90 percent of hamburger
## meat in america comes from the dairy industry
## when cows no longer give huge amounts of milk
## after three to seven years slaughterhouse no
## exceptions if ever given a chance cows can live to
## be 18 to 25 and cows are like all female mammals
## i am not trying to talk down to you when i speak
## about animal issues it's just that people don't
## think that animals go through the same things
## the same emotions that you go through that we
## all go through in order for a female mammal
## to give to give milk she has to be pregnant