## every year every cow and every dairy farm is
## raped a long steel device shoving their vaginas
## to inject them with bull semen or sometimes
## they use a bare hand this forces the milk flow
## and after she gives birth babies are stolen and
## let me tell you something the worst scream i have
## ever heard and i've heard them all firsthand
## when i started finding out about this stuff
## a little over 15 years ago i was like everybody
## else i didn't believe it was that bad i thought
## everybody was exaggerating but unlike everybody
## else who just blows it aside brushes it off
## i actually went to see what was going on i
## spent six weeks at thorne apple valley page
## slaughterhouse in detroit in 1993. i broke into
## animal research laboratories i broke into fur
## farms i went behind the scenes of every circus
## and every rodeo that ever came through michigan
## worst scream i've ever heard
## a mother cow on a dairy farm
## as she screams and bellows her lungs out day after
## day for her stolen baby to be given back to her
## and i can only imagine the same scream every woman
## in this room would make if somebody held you down
## after birth and stole your newborn baby from you
## and why did they take babies away from their mom
## well the dairy is you can't have little babies
## sucking up all that milk that was meant for them
## when they'd rather sell it to you instead
## every time you have a glass of cow milk
## some calf is not and mother cows make milk
## for one reason anyways during q a we're about
## to have you can ask me whatever you want i'm no
## politician bring up anything if you went online
## before i got here saw my radical essays that
## got me kicked out of countries bring them up
## there is one question i will not entertain them
## you cannot ask me why cows make milk thus if
## it's good for us shouldn't we be feeding it
## to our kids gary shouldn't we be having it
## nature took care of this one at the beginning of
## time cows make milk for their babies and for their
## babies alone case is closed forever permanently
## no debate no discussion they don't make milk for
## baby elephants baby orangutans baby headshots
## baby rabbits baby rats baby humans adolescent
## humans or adult humans this body of ours has
## absolutely no need for cow milk like it has
## absolutely no need for giraffe milk and zebra milk
## and rhinoceros milk hippopotamus milk camel milk
## deer milk antelope milk horse milk pig milk dog
## milk or cat milk the only milk that we ever need
## is our own mother's breast milk when we're born
## that's it and when we're done weaning we never
## need one drop of milk ever again no species on
## this planet needs milk after they're done weaning
## but if you want to include some kind of milk in
## your diet like i do let me reiterate the good news
## soy milk rice milk almond milk hemp
## milk coconut milk oat milk hazelnut milk
## you don't give up anything you
## got the vegan version of stuff
## or eat things that are truly natural like fruits
## and vegetables beans and lentils and seeds
## so the new number one excuse to eat animals is
## no longer god says it's okay that's number two
## now it's now the circle of life so we're gonna
## look at the circle of life from the victim's
## point of view which nobody ever does as
## you're about to see this zebra does not
## want to be a victim to a lion any more than
## a cow or a chicken wants to be your victim
## about to see an alligator trying
## to take down a baby impala
## and there's an angry vegan looking on i
## empathize he's going to get involved and stop him
## he's about to give mouth to
## mouth and he never took the
## saturday morning cpr class at the local
## community college to figure out how to do that
## they're much brighter than we give him credit for
## but for the record not all animals are brilliant
## some are stupid just like human beings some
## are bright some are stupid they're just like us
## if a bunch of violent thugs kidnapped your baby
## threaten and kill him and
## you are out muscled and man
## you might go get some backup too
## by the way the only bright
## lion in this whole pride