## hello and welcome back to this eye 24 news
## evening edition i'm lucia outreach and this
## is one on one joining me tonight is animal
## liberation activist gary yourofsky who has
## made a name for himself by becoming something of
## a controversial figure in animal in the animal
## rights arena apart from giving lectures mr
## yarovsky is best known for his approaches
## in which to get his point across such as
## breaking into a fur farm in liberation 1500
## soon to be murdered minx for reasons such as this
## mr yurovsky has been arrested numerous of times
## and has been banned from entering the united
## kingdom and canada while mr yarovsky means of
## putting an end to what he calls an animal
## holocaust his message has reached millions of
## people all around the world and has influenced
## many in changing their perspective of the food
## industry good evening and thank you very much for
## coming to our studio thanks for having me so um
## i will start like we said you affected millions
## and millions of people around the world
## why is it so effective here in israel
## how come that it's catching in israel
## i'm not clearly sure why but
## the only thing that i can
## figure out is that over the years as i've talked
## to tens of thousands of people i've noticed that
## people who have been oppressed jews hispanics
## women blacks they always respond better to
## this revolution that i'm involved in because
## they understand oppression they've been through
## it they know what it's like to be treated
## like nothing like their lives don't matter
## so that's what i think is going on here jews
## have been an oppressed people for thousands of
## years we understand oppression and we're supposed
## to not support it so i'm just pointing this out
## to everybody because people don't realize how much
## they're harming animals in their daily lives so as
## i point out the steak the hamburger the chicken
## sandwich that you're eating the schnitzel okay
## these these pieces of meat came off the bodies of
## living animals who didn't want to be murdered who
## didn't want to suffer and die who didn't want
## to be tormented so once i pointed out to people
## most people same people logical people make that
## next step to veganism we like to use euphemisms
## which is why these atrocities take place so we
## always want to say leather when it's cow skin
## and we want to say even even the term bacon
## what's bacon you mean pig flesh so once you
## start thinking about what we're wearing and what
## we're eating again this is why i say sane people
## will make a choice towards veganism it makes no
## sense because if you let's put it this way i like
## to explain how this is the biggest holocaust that
## has ever existed people get upset at those terms
## i have to tell you that i am upset about
## hearing like holocaust comparing the holocaust
## to like every single person that that heard your
## lectures and to hear this holocaust comparing it
## to animals it's a little bit limited and you know
## what and i'm not even jewish okay but it's hurts
## me well let me explain how how this this holocaust
## is actually worse i'm offended that we compare
## human holocaust to the animal holocaust which is
## the biggest holocaust in the history of humankind
## if you went to the nearest cow or chicken
## slaughterhouse and remove the animals
## and replace them with jews you have now
## recreated auschwitz there's no difference
## you have a building that exists to dismantle to
## torment to torture and murder innocent beings
## let's play a time game war a time warp game ghosts
## go back 60 70 years you go back to auschwitz or
## you go back to birkenau you remove the jews
## and replace them with cows and chickens
## you still have a holocaust taking place
## this in fact we learn how to kill jews
## in the hall like the nazis did because they
## studied what the meat industry was doing
## we've learned how to torture and kill each
## other because we practiced on the animals first
## but animals are eating animals some animals
## 75 of animals on this planet are herbivores
## but the it's it's part of our circle of life now
## this is the circle of torture and death when you
## see uh a lion eating a zebra it's it's blue and
## you're but i noticed you have clothes on and i
## noticed that you have a cell phone and you have a
## computer it is unfair to pick one thing that lions
## do that you want to mimic when you don't want
## to mimic anything else they do when lions walk
## up and greet each other they sniff each other's
## ass when i came in this room you did not kneel
## down and sniff my ass okay lions sometimes kill
## their young when their runts okay if a human being
## killed their baby because they didn't want him we
## arrest them and charge them with murder could you
## go to a courtroom and say hey but your honor lions
## kill their babies can't i it's a survivor it's