## in their tiny cages please extend some freedom to
## those who have none go to this website or call us
## today
## oh
## get everything you've got
## you hear that screaming did you
## know you've got their attention
## oh
## god
## this
## foreign
## german philosopher arthur schopenhauer once said
## that all truth passes through three stages first
## it is ridiculed second it is violently opposed
## and third it is accepted as being self-evident
## unfortunately the hatred and i mean hatred
## that humans have towards non-human animals
## is so vicious vile and powerful animal rights
## has not yet reached schopenhauer's third stage
## of common sense the human intellect remains
## so remedial and self-absorbed the notion of