## just might suffer more than any enslaved animal
## on this planet chino california for instance
## they had the largest concentration of dairy farms
## on this planet more than 350 000 cows lived there
## kept alive for three to seven years machines
## hooked up to their udders for several hours
## a day sucking milk out with hormones and
## antibiotics forced into their bodies to make
## them produce tremendous amounts of milk until they
## can no longer produce tremendous amounts of milk
## you know the dairy industry has done a masterful
## job at convincing everyone that cows naturally
## give milk i hope you don't believe that cows
## are like any other female animal they can only
## give milk during and after pregnancy so once a
## year dairy cows are artificially impregnated to
## keep the milk flow going and within two days of
## giving birth within two days their babies are
## taken away from them which is outright cruelty in
## and of itself their babies are stolen from them
## at birth most of the male babies sent off the
## veal farms putting crates so tiny they're never
## allowed to stand up ropes and chains put around
## their necks to completely immobilize them and
## prevent any muscle development whatsoever which
## is why veal flesh is tender no muscle development
## as for the females most of the females kept on
## the dairy farm enslaved like their mothers they
## will be turned into dairy cows as well the rest
## of the females and some of the males sold to the
## beef industry where they will be killed at nine
## months of age thank you very much for listening
## okay i'm going to take you guys on a
## journey today and like all journeys in
## life there's going to be ups and downs highs
## and lows you're going to like certain parts
## and dislike other parts in other words you
## will love me and hate me today all at once
## but if you listen with an open mind i promise at
## the end of the speech the love will outweigh the
## hate the first 30 minutes will be very intense i'm
## going to make you feel angry frustrated and guilty
## fortunately the last 15 minutes will be like
## a comedy roast so we're gonna laugh and giggle
## you guys are getting roasted by the way so i'm
## gonna speak for around 45 minutes and then we'll
## do a q a session after so hold your questions
## until the end right now i want you to think
## about how you would feel if the moment you were
## born someone else had already planned the day
## of your execution that's what it's like to be a
## cow a pig a chicken or a turkey on this planet
## they're not born free they're born to be murdered
## even though freedom is supposed to be a birthright
## a god-given right i mean no god would be
## a slave master a torturer and a killer
## of his animals his babies if he was then
## he wouldn't be god he'd be the devil
## if that statement shocks you or brings up feelings
## of animosity towards me the problem isn't with me
## and what i've just said the problem is that humans
## have victimized animals to such a degree that they
## aren't even considered victims they aren't even
## considered at all they're nothing they don't count
## they don't matter they're commodities like tv sets
## and cell phones we've actually turned animals into
## inanimate objects sandwiches and shoes it
## is the greatest magic trick ever performed
## the animation switch and besides the money
## made from selling their flesh and skin and
## the things that come out of their bodies there's
## not even decent value on them as inanimate objects
## the american flag for example which is nothing
## but a piece of fabric the bible which is nothing
## but a book comprised of ink and paper stir
## up more emotions than the murder of animals
## if there were a barbecue near campus today and
## people were cooking up steaks and hamburgers man
## there'd be a party people would actually celebrate
## the cow who was killed the person who killed the
## cow and the chef that seasoned her dead body but
## if someone poured gasoline on the flag or a bible
## struck a match and set it on fire lord have
## mercy there'd be an angry mob ready to kill
## somebody these lifeless inanimate objects the flag
## in the bible are more sacred than animals living