## cows and pigs and chickens these trucks are being
## driven to concentration camp slaughterhouses
## that we've carefully constructed all across
## america when the trucks arrive the animals are
## so frightened they won't even get off the truck
## they're not stupid they know what's next so people
## go on the trucks with electric prods and force
## them to walk down the chutes to their own death
## or if the animals are small enough to manhandle
## like chickens we'll just grab them off the trucks
## and toss them inside inside these innocent living
## beings are hanged upside down fully conscious
## in other words they go in alive against their will
## and come out chopped up into hundreds of pieces
## but you know what's more insane than that meat
## eaters walking around like their lifestyle isn't
## causing any harm like it's normal and natural
## to be consuming violence and death how would you
## feel if the day that you were born somebody else
## had already planned the day of your execution
## that's what it's like to be a cow a pig a
## chicken or a turkey on this planet i think
## i think this type of behavior is inexcusable an
## unbecoming of a species that claims to understand
## right from wrong the animals have not done
## one single thing to us to deserve the wrath
## and the cruelty that we hurl on them and i hope
## you all understand what i'm offering you today
## when you hit the door after my speech are
## you aware that for the first time ever
## you can now directly participate in ending a
## massacre instead of sitting around and paying
## lip service to all the massacres and all the
## problems that are always going on on this planet
## what is so frustrating to me when i travel this
## country doing around 250 lectures every year to
## some 7 500 students is that everybody talks a good
## game i've noticed that people are quite the smooth
## talkers when it comes to peace and compassion i
## mean people always want to tell me never show me
## just tell me how peaceful they are because of
## what they believe in or what makes them sad
## hey gary i believe in god and i believe in angels
## and i pray all the time and those earthquakes the
## one in chile and haiti oh that was so sad and no [
## __ ] it was sad since when does feeling sad about
## an obvious tragedy or believing in something
## make the world a better place or make somebody
## a good person and listen folks i am not trying
## to dog you out when i talk like this i'm not
## i'm just not a politician i'm not a [ __ ] artist
## i don't know how to schmooze people as you can see
## it's kind of beyond me i hope you appreciate my
## honesty and my genuineness today and i'm not a
## salesperson i got no books to sell you after my
## lecture no dvds and no documentaries no collection
## plate going around i don't want your money i
## don't want your email addresses and i don't want
## your mailing addresses keep all that stuff i am
## here to talk about the worst form of cruelty and
## violence taking place on this planet even though
## most people don't seem to care about it but when
## you sit back in the comfort of your living room
## and you start condemning atrocities elsewhere
## that is pure unadulterated lip service that's the
## definition of lip service but veganism this is now
## a chance to actually walk the compassionate
## talk that everybody's always talking about
## this is your chance to show others how truly
## peaceful you are this is a chance for a personal
## revolution to leave your mark on this planet by
## causing the least amount of harm possible always
## being vegan now come on what's the argument
## for not causing the least amount of harm
## inconvenience indifference apathy selfishness
## i want you to know i don't live in fantasyland
## i'm well aware that animals
## are suffering and dying
## just because we're here on the planet with
## them we build homes through their habitat we