## all right in 2013 i went vegan as a result of
## watching the georgia tech speech by gary yourofsky
## and this gentleman's also responsible for
## inspiring me to become the most effective
## animal rights activist that i can be and
## has really changed the game for me in many
## ways and i think has shaken up the world with
## his speeches so i think it's only right that
## i give back myself and my team have put together
## this video it is the best of the best what we
## think is the creme de la creme of gary yourofsky's
## speeches and other moments in his activism
## all right good afternoon everybody my name is
## gary yourofsky please take a moment and jot down
## my email address and my website in case you want
## to contact me later on today we're going to talk
## about the world's forgotten victims animals and
## the world's oldest and strongest addiction meat
## i'm going to challenge your belief systems today
## so certain parts of the speech will be intense
## but let me start with a quick disclaimer
## i am not here to be your enemy the views
## expressed today do not necessarily reflect the
## views of your professor or this institution
## i am not trying to take you away from your
## religion no religion mandates meat eating
## the golden rule states do unto others as you would
## have done unto yourself animals qualify as others
## and thou shalt not kill the four most important
## yet most ignored words in all religious teachings
## there's not an asterisk next to that commandment
## saying unless you walk on all fours have fur
## feathers horns beaks or gills you can keep
## your friends your politics and your patriotism
## still watch your favorite tv shows and listen to
## your favorite music even if it's ted nugent i'll
## be making some sarcastic yet truthful comments
## throughout the speech please feel free to laugh
## while i'm being sarcastic just don't laugh
## during the serious parts now i'm going to
## speak for around 65 maybe 70 minutes but then
## we'll do a q a session after for about a half
## an hour so hold your questions until then in the
## meantime i have some rhetorical questions for you
## is slavery owner victim profit domination
## exclusive to the human race have blacks
## jews women and children been the only victims
## of this atrocity have not cows been enslaved
## what about pigs chickens turkeys fish sheep if
## they're not enslaved then what are they free
## can slavery have a victim that is neither human
## nor animal have not the oceans the forest the
## earth itself become victims of ownership too and
## what about a slaughterhouse house of slaughter
## slaughterhouse do you really think there's such
## a thing as humane slaughter exactly what is your
## definition of humane besides psychological
## and physical abuse torture dismemberment
## and murder what else do you think happens to
## animals inside of a slaughterhouse you think
## they get belly rubs and tushy slaps and if you
## think there's such a thing as humane slaughter
## i'm curious do you also think there's such a
## thing as humane rape humane child molestation
## humane slavery about a humane holocaust in
## fact what is your definition of a holocaust
## is it a massacre of human beings
## or a massacre of innocent beings
## i thought it was innocent which brings us to the
## biggest holocaust massacre of all every year in
## america without mercy we murder 10 billion land
## animals and 18 billion marine animals not for
## health survival sustenance or self-defense people
## eat meat cheese milk and eggs for four reasons
## habit tradition convenience taste i want
## to define a word that might be new to
## some people right now and it's vegan
## it's up there on the screen v-e-g-a-n
## vegans like vegetarians do not consume the meat
## of any land or marine animal vegans however
## unlike vegetarians also refrain from eating cheese
## milk eggs honey or any animal product whatsoever