## and it brings to mind a quote that made me go
## vegan way back in the day from a bishop from
## england william ralph inge inge in
## an 18th century sermon this man said
## that we have treated our cousins in fur and
## feathers so horribly that beyond a doubt
## if they ever formed an organized religion
## the devil would be depicted in human form
## that broke my heart the day i read it and it still
## breaks my heart today because again they must look
## at us like we are devils we cut things off their
## bodies their horns while they're fully conscious
## off the cows we cut the beaks off of hens we rip
## the testicles out of baby pigs when they're born
## we torment them put them on concentration camp
## trucks we send them to slaughterhouses they know
## what's going on they're aware they're conscious
## they smell death and fear and blood in the air
## we cut them up into pieces this ad this this stuff
## has to stop over and over again once and again uh
## you um go to uh ways of of describing that we are
## used to you to to to hear concerning the holocaust
## it's uh pretty sensitive around here
## but you you stand for it uh isn't it
## over the top to uh to uh use the holocaust the
## animal holocaust was happening long before the
## jewish holocaust during the jewish holocaust and
## it's still happening today i find it over the top
## that the jewish holocaust is compared to the
## animal holocaust because when you compare numbers
## we're talking about six million jews and if you
## add up the other six million gypsies and blacks
## and catholics and mentally [ __ ] people we're
## talking 12 million people were killed by the nazis
## in one year alone on this planet 60 billion land
## animals 90 billion marine animals are tortured
## tormented and killed in the world's most massive
## holocaust that's just in one year alone in america
## today 30 million land animals will be tortured in
## chicago in one day one day alone that is a massive
## holocaust and jews don't own the term holocaust
## i know jewish people like to think it's our term
## like black people like to think that they own
## slavery and i have to say i hate to admit that
## the numbers are more than impressive but uh the
## moral argument um is is quite uh difficult because
## one of my colleagues here asked you were you
## two uh to decide ilana dayan asked you that
## and i listened to your answer and i want to go
## back there she asked you if you had a three years
## old baby and a three-year-old puppy that you have
## to save one of them would you choose i think it's
## a horrible question to be asking somebody and
## when i asked her back would she save a black
## baby or a white baby would you save a palestinian
## suicide bomber or would you save a flea because
## we act like human life is valuable and it's not
## especially when you talk about mass murderers and
## rapists and hitler and himmler and stalin and idi
## amin and slobodan milosevic and muammar gaddafi
## i mean is anybody going to save muammar qaddafi's
## life how come people didn't come to his rescue
## when they pulled him out of a sewer and took a
## knife and shoved it in his anus nobody cares about
## gaddafi osama bin laden this is so false we are
## all speciesists we think that animal life isn't
## valuable and we falsely believe that human life
## is valuable if i can further explain how how how
## unvaluable human life truly is do you know that
## if you took humans off this planet the extinction
## of humans would benefit everything that exists the
## animals the forest the air the water the mountains
## we are completely not special to this planet if
## you removed ants this is how special ants are the
## whole ecosystem would collapse without ants and
## i know you've been following the news with bees
## if the bees disappear everything falls apart this
## is how special and valuable bees are to the world
## where do we get off saying that we are valuable
## when all we do is destroy and torment and think
## that we're superior and we dominate others and
## this is why you wished you said you wish that
## people that work in slaughterhouses and get
## slaughtered themselves or something very bad
## happens to them listen i wish evil on evil people
## all the time and any sane person would do the same
## thing was anybody upset when the nazi hunters went
## track down at all people like men and brought them
## back here and killed people that work in some
## party in the streets i like nazis sure to the to