## and finally to top off the barbarity their
## testicles are ripped out as well oh in order
## to mark them to keep track of them they have
## holes punched in their ears it's called ear notch
## can you imagine being hated so vehemently
## that someone would rip out portions of your
## ear or castrate you or cut your teeth off
## down to the gum line all without anesthetic
## did you know that the animal welfare act of the
## 1960s which happens to be a pathetic piece of
## legislation kind of like our constitution when it
## was first created which left out many more humans
## than it ever led in originally the animal welfare
## act unequivocally allows people to torture
## enslave terrorize and murder all animals even
## endangered ones if you apply for the proper permit
## the animal welfare act is a how-to guide
## to animal exploitation torture them this
## way don't torture them that way and slave them
## like this don't enslave them like that and kill
## them this way don't kill them that way circuses
## slaughterhouses and research labs love to say
## hey gary hey peta leave us alone we're in
## complete compliance with the animal welfare act
## well my dear friends you'd have to be a vicious
## idiot not to be in compliance with the animal
## welfare act once again since the basis
## of the awa is torture terror and murder
## how could an animal exploiter not be in compliance
## the awa's mandate for food and water does not ease
## the terror nor stop the murder smithfield
## the number one killer of pigs in the world
## generates 8 billion dollars every year by
## killing eleven hundred pigs every hour in
## fact smithfield's five biggest concentration
## camps kills 78 000 pigs every day you know what
## government agencies in charge of enforcing the
## awa the u.s department of agriculture the same
## agency that oversees the murder of 10 billion
## land animals seem a little incongruous why don't
## we put pedophiles in charge of child protection
## laws misogynist in charge of domestic abuse laws
## and hunters in charge of wildlife management my
## bad we do that one already little sidebar for you
## every single state and national wildlife agency
## is run solely by hunters and hunt supporters
## period point blank there are no animal
## rights humanitarians on these committees
## you know how the hunting community always claims
## that killing animals is sound scientific wildlife
## management if that were the case and
## how come in every single newspaper
## in the usa hunting stories are always placed
## in the sports section not the science section
## of the 10 billion land animals killed for food
## chickens represent 9 billion with
## another 250 million enslaved on egg farms
## now raised in huge buildings these factory farm
## warehouses enslave anywhere from 5 thousand
## to eighty thousand birds in one building eighteen
## by twenty inch battery cages for the egg length
## tens while the chickens the males are
## strewn about in a chaotic free-for-all
## the tiny battery cages are a staple of the egg
## industry where 5 to 11 birds share one cage but
## inside or outside of the cage these places
## of horror deny natural behaviors to chickens
## and hens like dust bathing preening and happily
## roaming freely something we all take for granted
## for the record hens prefer more space than 18
## by 20 inches and chickens do not like to live
## in groups larger than 30. therefore fighting
## is common in the chicken and egg industries
## how do they treat the fighting problem two ways
## one ignore the situation two vicious intervention
## chickens and hens are de-beaked
## meaning the sensitive portion
## top two-thirds of the beak is seared off with
## a red hot blade heated to 800 degrees celsius
## egg laying hens are shot off with so many
## antibiotics they're forced to lay up to 300 eggs
## every year because of this their uteruses have
## been known to bleed and protrude from their bodies
## when hens can't keep up with the demands of the
## egg industry they don't go to sanctuaries people
## they're sent to slaughterhouses and killed let's
## not forget that egg farms have to breed birds
## so there's always a fresh supply of hens to lay
## eggs but upon hatching if those babies turn out
## to be males in the egg industry they're considered
## useless to the egg industry because they don't lay
## eggs only females can do that so male babies are
## put in plastic bags suffocated tossed in the trash
## or they're thrown into huge rendering
## machines where their live bodies are ground up
## and used as feed bottom line whether it's an egg
## length and a factory farmed chicken a free-range