## with a bare hand or a long steel device to eject
## them with bold sperm female mammals have to be
## pregnant to produce and give milf mother cows then
## have their babies stolen from them after birth
## because once we eliminate the babies from the
## equation we get to drink all that milk instead
## and when mother cows can't produce huge amounts
## of milk after three to seven years they get a
## happy day at the slaughterhouse where if they're
## really lucky they'll get turned into a happy meal
## other companies love to lie about
## happy animals too what about that
## wish i wear an oscar meyer wiener jingle
## that's pretty cute except for the fact that when
## they're born male babies have their testicles
## ripped out without anesthetic standard practice
## the meat industry always controls procreation all
## the female pigs get raped every year to impregnate
## them just like the cows baby pigs then have most
## of their teeth cut off right down the gum line
## and their tails cut off too all without anesthetic
## to try and reduce flesh damage from fighting and
## biting each other in their overcrowding conditions
## and when pigs reach 300 pounds in six
## months thanks to genetic modification
## they get a happy day at the slaughterhouse too
## where they get chopped up into a thousand pieces
## the egg industry though man they just might
## possess the greatest marketing propaganda of
## all time because they've actually convinced
## you to eat something that came out of a hens
## all inclusive all in one ass vagina and
## the backside of a bird is called a cloaca
## it is one hole where the poop the p the vaginal
## fluid and scrambled eggs and omelets come from
## hate to be the bearer of more bad news
## but mommy and daddy lied to us too
## we're not that special and we're not perfect just
## the way we are but at least when you become vegan
## you are trying trying to reduce and eliminate
## gratuitous amounts of cruelty and violence
## which is all i'm asking of you today so how
## come when one human dies it's a tragedy but when
## billions of animals are killed with premeditation
## it's a celebration and what's really odd about
## this tragedy celebration dichotomy is that
## besides some kind of a self-defense situation
## everyone knows that killing is evil and
## wrong because every time a bear kills a hiker
## what do we do start saving hakuna matata praise
## the hiker for being part of the circle of life
## tell his family well he just wasn't fit enough to
## survive [ __ ] we scream bloody murder label that
## bear a homicidal maniac and get a bunch of people
## with guns and go kill that bear for killing the
## hiker funny how the circle of life never comes
## into play when we're getting killed and that's
## because the circle of life ain't nothing but an
## aggrandized arbitrary [ __ ] excuse to torment
## and kill somebody else with impunity it's a cute
## story it really is written directed and produced
## by us the killers the dictators the victimizers
## the victims in this psychotic scenario are not
## willing participants as you clearly saw on
## that opening video but here's something even
## more interesting than that sometimes even
## the killers question their own behavior
## kindness is a choice so is violence spare
## me the animals can't think or rationalize
## because they operate on instinct only nonsense
## because if you go to my website at dap.org check
## out the animal intelligence essay and click
## the link that says leopard saves a baby baboon
## and watch a big carnivorous cat have
## second thoughts about the circle of life
## she kills a baboon but doesn't realize the
## baboon is a mother with a newborn baby so she
## intentionally lets a skulking hyena have the dead
## mother's corpse to chomp on while she gently picks
## up the baby puts the baby in a tree and stays
## in the tree to protect the baby from the hyena
## if the circle of life was genuine and
## animals couldn't think that leopard would
## have instinctively instantly killed that baby
## instead she chose to comfort him to protect him