## now i know these statements sound
## pretty harsh and controversial to you
## but that doesn't mean they aren't true the fact
## that anyone would fight against veganism against
## animal liberation which means you are against
## compassion just proves how completely irrational
## meat dairy and egg eaters can be vegans
## are only asking you to change what you eat
## not who you are stay jewish christian or catholic
## stay muslim buddhist hindu atheist agnostic stay
## left or right in politics if you honestly
## place yourself in the animal's position
## there's no way you can justify the things that
## we do to them and walk away from today's speech
## saying that you don't care the ethical compass
## that most people use to gauge right from wrong
## is the golden rule do unto others as you
## would have others do unto you since no one
## in this room wants to be treated the way we treat
## cows and pigs and chickens and turkeys and fish
## there's no need to search for an excuse
## today not to be vegan 60 billion land animals
## 90 billion marine animals are killed every year on
## this planet for a sandwich for addictions of greed
## and gluttony what kind of society justifies mass
## murder stop thinking that animals aren't victims
## because they aren't human it's the mindset of the
## victimizer that's wrong and this is what needs to
## be examined and corrected because it never changes
## no matter who the victim is have you noticed it
## always goes something like this no you don't count
## no you don't matter no i'm more important than you
## i laugh at the suffering i inflict on you i'll
## kill you and your family whenever i want however i
## want prove to me why i should be kind to you it is
## not your right to deny someone else their freedom
## and their rights so you can harm them enslave them
## and kill them that's not what rights are about
## that's injustice there is no counter argument
## to veganism except that you can't be right all
## the time apologize for the way you've been
## living make amends and evolve move forward
## now all throughout history there's a pretty
## good reason why most people most good people
## have always been on the wrong side of what's
## right and that's because the truth has never been
## accepted overnight it always has to pass through
## three stages first it is mocked and ridiculed
## second stage denial and violent opposition
## people refuse people refuse to believe there's
## an atrocity taking place and they fight tooth
## and nail to keep the status quo as is third stage
## acceptance there is no longer need to explain
## it because we all get it now unfortunately it
## usually takes hundreds sometimes thousands of
## years for the truth to pass through these stages
## i'm going to try and do it
## today in around 45 minutes
## and in order for the truth to be accepted and
## understood we do have to witness the atrocities
## the five and a half minute video we're about to
## watch that footage was taken throughout america
## britain and israel and if you feel the need to
## turn away or close your eyes during this video
## you should probably ask yourself a question
## if it's not good enough for my eyes
## then why is it good enough for my stomach and
## before i press play i have to say something about
## all this humane meat humane milk humane eggs [
## __ ] that's going on in our society right now
## that stuff does not exist under any circumstances
## whatsoever even when animals reside in cage-free
## free range grass-fed local organic antibiotic-free
## facilities by definition alone slavery and
## slaughter are radically cruel and can never
## be humane so don't be so gullible with slick
## marketing ads that want to convince you that
## animals enjoy being on the menu as if they're
## all saying hey stab me yeah kill me sure take
## everything from me because that's why i'm here