## we also don't wear animal skins no fur leather
## wool silk or down now i want to let you all know
## that i was not raised vegan i ate meat cheese
## milk and eggs for around 25 years i used to wear
## leather shoes and belts and jackets like everyone
## else in fact around 20 years ago i even owned
## a fur coat needless to say i understand your
## lifestyle it used to be mine and for people
## involved in politics let's get this out of the
## way right now i am not a democrat an anarchist
## or some hippie with a closet full of tie dye
## shirts i'm not a republican a socialist or a
## fascist i'm an activist root word is active
## i've been banned from five countries so far
## and arrested 13 times for random acts of kindness
## and compassion on behalf of my animal brothers
## and sisters if you want to read up about that
## check out my website and today i would love to
## give you a chance to actually do something and
## truly get involved because i understand a lot of
## people want to get involved honestly i do but
## putting a co-exist bumper sticker on your car
## wearing a what would jesus do bracelet or
## sporting a peace and love and sunshine t-shirt
## that is not getting involved i understand
## that we're all on a journey in life
## we all have different likes and dislikes
## different nationalities and religions
## too but there's one thing that we need to have in
## common with each other and that's peace contrary
## to political and religious dogma animals do not
## belong to us they are not commodities they're not
## property and they're not inanimate stupid objects
## who can't think and feel that descartes cartesian
## way of looking at animals like their machines it
## is outdated and quite frankly 100 percent insane
## because if we all understand that animals can
## use their eyes to see ears to hear noses to smell
## mouths to eat legs to walk feathers to fly fins to
## swim genitalia to procreate bowels to defecate i'm
## always perplexed and most people don't believe
## that they can also use their brains to think
## feel be rational be aware and be
## self-aware am i supposed to believe
## that every body part on an animal
## functions just like it's supposed to
## except the brain those lies are thick the
## propaganda from the animal abusers is enormous
## i mean when was the last time you turned on
## tv and saw a commercial for shiitake mushrooms
## people singing and dancing down the streets having
## a good time eating mushrooms about alfalfa sprouts
## quinoa it's a seed radishes raspberries tofu you
## don't see that stuff advertised on tv what do you
## see instead have some more meat have some more
## cheese have some more cheese on your meat meat
## cheese double cheese extra cheese and how about a
## little more cheese with your meat have some more
## cow's milk have some more eggs and then what do
## you see interspersed between those advertisements
## not feeling so well need to see a cancer
## specialist how about a heart doctor need some
## lipitor zocor crestor plavix needs some diet pills
## how about some energy drinks some k.o pectate
## you've been duped and those blinders are on nice
## and tightly but if you give me an open mind today
## that's all i ask for an open mind i'm going to
## take your blinders right up my goal is simple
## all i want to do is reconnect people with animals
## awaken some emotions and some feelings and some
## logic that has been buried and suppressed
## intentionally by our society and the reason
## why i say reconnect it's because each and
## every person in this room used to be a real
## animal rights person at one time a true animal
## lover and a real friend of the animal kingdom
## and it's when we were kids when we were young
## we were kids man we used to be in all animals