## hello
## oh
## hey
## um
## so
## john never down
## there was nothing wrong with killing
## animals and eating meat was okay
## how come mcdonald's and burger king and
## wendy's never show those images in their tv ads
## are we showing you a happy singing
## smiling cartoon caricature instead
## people are up in arms right now about all the
## beheadings taking place in the middle east
## meanwhile 30 million innocent animals
## every day in america are beheaded
## and no one says a damn thing about it
## so i'm a little confused is beheading evil or
## does it matter who's getting their heads cut off
## i will forever be embarrassed to be a human being
## to stand upright like that's something
## to be proud of you got to be kidding me
## a retired marine in north carolina once
## heard me lecture at east carolina university
## and he said gary i believe everything
## you said got no arguments for you at all