## the numbers are staggering about 45 to 50 billion
## land animals and about 85 billion marine animals
## are killed and eaten every year on this planet now
## in america we kill and eat more than 100 million
## pigs every single year and for their entire lives
## the female pigs are locked up in tiny crates and
## stalls so they can be forcibly impregnated against
## their will with long steel devices that shoot hog
## semen into their uterus basically they are the
## unwilling baby machines of the meat industry
## and when female pigs can no longer make babies
## after years of being forcibly impregnated
## they're shipped off to the slaughterhouse and
## killed now meanwhile shortly after birth the
## male piglets they have their tiny bodies mutilated
## in four horrific ways first somebody holds them
## upside down and cuts their tail off without
## anesthetic because tail biting is common in
## the overcrowded unnatural conditions of today's
## farms and then each baby pig has anywhere from
## two to eight teeth cut off they actually cut their
## teeth off down to the gum line with a pair of wire
## cutter like devices so when they go to fight and
## bite each other there are no teeth to damage the
## flesh and since female pigs are forced to produce
## twice as many piglets in captivity than they
## would in the wild teeth cutting is also a big
## money maker for the meat industry cutting teeth
## allows the mother to nurse even more piglets who
## will eventually be killed for profit because when
## the babies suckle without teeth wear and tear
## on the mother's nipples is kept to a minimum
## and they're always marking pigs to keep track
## of them so they rip out portions of their ears
## it's called ear notching and then finally in
## a sick attempt and i repeat a sick attempt to
## pacify the industry-induced anger of the male pigs
## their testicles are ripped out as well and that's
## castration without anesthetic now castration
## also gives the meat industry complete control
## over reproduction because natural reproduction in
## the meat industry in this day and age is obsolete
## neither god nor evolution created 10 billion
## land animals in this country alone every year
## human beings did that and that is because every
## aspect of raising animals for food is controlled
## from genetic engineering and artificial
## insemination to quoting and killing
## this is why many females empathize with the
## animal rights movement and practice veganism
## humanitarian patrice jones once explained that
## women and animals along with land and children
## have historically been seen as the property of
## male households women and animals are viewed as
## less rational and both suffer by being reduced
## to their bodies or even worse their body parts
## now of the 10 billion land animals killed and
## eaten in america every year about 9 billion 9
## billion of those are chickens on egg farms they'll
## stuff anywhere from five to eleven hens into each
## tiny battery cage with that many hens in a single
## cage you can imagine fighting is very common
## which is why these hens have the top two thirds of
## their beaks sliced off it's called de-beaking they
## actually slice off a portion of the beak with
## a red-hot blade heated to 800 degrees celsius
## so that when they go to fight and peck each other
## they have no beaks to damage each other's flesh
## and with chemicals and other drugs that are
## injected into their feed each hen is forced to
## produce around 300 eggs every year until of course
## her egg production tapers off and then she's
## killed without exception each and every egg-laying
## hen is killed so egg farms will also breed birds
## so there's always a fresh supply of hens to lay
## the eggs but if babies in the hatchery turn out
## to be male pretty obvious they're completely
## useless to an egg industry and they are killed
## off instantly they're either thrown into the
## trash alive and crying out for their lost mothers
## or they're thrown into huge rendering machines
## alive so that they can be ground up and used
## as feed for other animals on chicken farms
## they'll have anywhere between twenty thousand
## and thirty thousand birds in each building
## after six or seven weeks of concentration camp
## like conditions and living in tons of feces and
## urine they are killed too their bodies are then
## soaked in a chlorine bath to remove the slime and
## odor off their carcasses and then placed on your
## dinner plate see no one wants to admit it but
## eating meat really does mean eating a dead body
## and eating meat means that your body has been
## reduced to nothing more than a walking graveyard
## of murdered animals and very quickly i want
## to destroy this myth about free-range farms