## uh i was charged with b e and i was sentenced to
## six months in a maximum security detention center
## and even those prisoners knew that it was crazy
## that i was there because when they started asking
## questions they saw me on the news and they said
## what are you doing here with us you freed some
## rats and you're here with us i said no no i also
## caused 2.1 million dollars in damage that night
## and put the put the make murder out of
## business permanently and we don't tolerate
## economic sabotage in our society because we
## don't worship god i saw a stat that 96 of the
## population believes in god i don't deny that
## i just wish they worshiped god because people
## worship the root of all evil people worship money
## and that's why all this violence takes place too
## it is the most profitable business on this planet
## since the beginning of time animal slavery nothing
## comes close not cars not gasoline not oil not
## computers nothing compares to the amount of money
## being made off the backs of animals literally do
## you believe in god yes i do absolutely we'll talk
## openly about god i don't believe in organized
## religion but i absolutely believe in god
## i believe in the garden of vegan oops the
## garden of eden i believe and thou shall not
## kill i believe genesis 1 29 god's first law
## is i give you seed bearing plants for food i
## believe that god created humans animals and the
## earth therefore god is inside humans animals and
## the earth therefore if you murder humans animals
## and the earth you are murdering god i notice that
## religious people love to worship things that
## we created in god's name the bible the koran
## stars of david and the cross but nobody worships
## anything that god created animals kill them
## kill them right now those horns and that
## cow cut them off right now while that
## cow was fully conscious that's the
## water pollute it the air pollute it
## every the force cut it down anything that god
## made we destroy anything that we made in god's
## name we worship so my condemnation isn't
## about god it's about what religious people do
## in god's name well i'm very glad you came to our
## studio thank you for coming thanks for having me
## do you think it's really necessary is it do
## you really believe it's the same i think it's
## killing people and killing animals yeah i think
## it's worse when we talk about the holocaust we
## have six million jews you can add the other six
## million blacks gypsies mentally [ __ ] people in
## america today 30 million innocent beings will be
## murdered for a sandwich every year on this planet
## 60 billion land animals and 90 billion marine
## animals are killed that's a holocaust of mine
## these are cows and we're talking about people
## but that's what the nazis said these are jews
## they don't count i'm a nazi and i count and so you
## really don't see a difference between animals and
## people absolutely not especially when it comes to
## pain and suffering we all suffer in the same way
## we all feel pain in the same
## way a knife in my throat
## is just as painful and harmful as a knife
## and a cow's throat in a chicken's throat
## and the jew don't you get a strong reaction
## for using the that comparison it's usually
## positive i'm having nothing but success here
## remember i don't do things to be a politician
## i don't say things that people want me to
## say i speak the truth and the truth is harsh
## i know people don't want to hear that there's a
## holocaust taking place that they're taking part in
## but that's a fact i'm not being dramatic again if
## you go back 60 70 years jewish women had babies in
## their arms and the nazis ripped those babies away
## in the dairy industry every cow not only has her
## baby stolen she's raped to impregnate her and then
## when the baby is born they steal the baby away
## they tattoo jews we tattoo animals we brand them
## as you see it we are all nothing to you well
## not to me you have to think about the victims
## the victims think you're a nazi remember isaac
## bashevis singer great jewish humanitarian who
## was vegan he's the one that said in relation to
## animals all humans are nazis for the animals it
## is an eternal treblinka so it's not so important
## what i think it's what the animals are thinking
## we're now seeing uh currently seeing uh uh short
## uh that's shocking shocking it's
## it's cruel and it's disgusting and uh
## you want to prove what i want to show people
## what's going on because if you watch the news
## if you watch tv the advertisements are happy cows
## right if they're never showing you slaughterhouses
## think about this if a slaughterhouse wasn't such
## an evil place how come mcdonald's and burger
## ranch why don't they show you slaughterhouses
## and say hey this is where your hamburger comes
## from this is where your chicken nuggets come
## from they intentionally lie to you i don't lie
## i intentionally tell you the truth because i think
## if you saw what was going on in the slaughterhouse