## two most perfect places now i want to destroy
## some other lies you've heard way too much about
## first people often ask me why we can't eat eggs
## from some hens living in our backyard or from a
## free range farm their bodies do not belong to us
## commodification is the crime as much as cruelty is
## and i've noticed that nobody ever wants to adopt
## old hens to live in their backyard the ones who
## have stopped laying eggs they only want the
## young ones who are still freshly modified
## genetically to lay 300 eggs every year
## instead of their normal 17 eggs every year
## pens just like sheep in the
## wool industry always get killed
## when they stop producing things that we want them
## to produce and finally let's talk about the plants
## and whether they suffer because the latest idiocy
## and lunacy being tossed my way the last couple
## of years has been hey man carrots suffer and
## die just like cows do so what's the difference
## okay in case you were unaware of this difference
## you have to have a functioning central nervous
## system connected to a brain in order to suffer and
## this is not up for debate which is why people in
## the hospital who are brain dead but still alive
## but can't feel anything are cold how about that
## little truth in science for a change yeah we don't
## call these people fish we don't call them chickens
## and turkeys and cows and pigs we call them
## vegetables but even if someone somehow proved
## that in sentient life forms like plants were
## capable of suffering we're causing more harm
## to the planet by harvesting all the plants
## and feeding all those plants to the animals
## and killing all the animals to get
## the nutrients they got from the plants
## which were all the nutrients that we needed to
## begin with with all the crop land in america alone
## america could be feeding 10 billion people again
## there's only and a half billion on the planet
## which means less land would be used less plants
## would be harvested less violence committed
## if we ate plants directly and if plants really
## can't suffer how can firefighters never rescue
## them and don't say it's discriminatory
## because animals are the most discriminated
## species on this planet but there's still a
## plan in place to save them during a fight
## humans get safe first but if it's safe to do
## so even if it's unsafe to do so they'll go
## back inside and save the animals but even if it
## were safe to do so again no fire fighter in the
## history of the world has ever gone back in a
## third time to save the chrysanthemums hey bob
## quick you saved the basil plant from the kitchen
## i'll get the road identity from the second floor
## do you think that if i gain lectures about cruelty
## to vegetables especially root vegetables like yams
## called my speech the silence of the yams
## because everybody knows that yams scream
## for about 30 to 45 seconds after you gank
## them out of the ground before they die that
## i would have been invited into 180 schools
## to give 2600 lectures to 60 000 students in 30
## different states and i was just thinking about
## this the other day but what do we say about fruits
## and vegetables when they get old they're ripe
## ready to eat or rot and what do we say
## about animals when they get old they're old
## because animals are alive in
## the exact same way that we are
## and plants are food so can we please stop making
## up idiotic excuses to torture and kill the animals
## and make up an excuse to care about them instead
## to become vegan actually live by the golden rule
## instead of just paying lip service to it do
## unto others as you would have others do unto you
## good evening my name is gary yourofsky in 1996
## i founded adapt which became michigan's most
## outspoken and radical animal rights organization
## in 2002 i became the official orator of peta
## people for the ethical treatment of animals
## because of my michigan ties many midwestern
## law enforcement agencies government officials
## media people and politicians know me as the
## most outspoken and radical activist not only in
## the state of michigan but in the entire midwest