## i have been arrested 13 times for random acts of
## kindness and compassion following in the footsteps
## of other routine radical law breakers like dr
## martin luther king jr mohandas gandhi nelson
## mandela and jesus please do not misconstrue what i
## am saying i do not think i am king nor gandhi nor
## mandela nor jesus but i am following in their
## routine radical law-breaking footsteps in 1997
## i liberated 1542 mink from an animal concentration
## camp in canada euphemistically referred to as a
## fur farm subsequently i received a six-month
## sentence in maximum security where i spent 77
## days there before being deported back to michigan
## once a liberator and now an educator before i talk
## about the vegan ethic i need to let everyone know
## that i did not come here today to be your enemy i
## came here to educate and enlighten tell you things
## you're not supposed to be told and show you things
## you are never supposed to see if you want to make
## me your enemy today hey that's fine join the club
## i have thousands of enemies nationwide heck i
## can even put you in contact with some of them
## if you'd like today's speech is intended to
## uplift you morally now before we continue i
## need to show you seven minutes of graphic video
## about the vicious traditions of animal abuse that
## still exist in our society i am not showing this
## video to shock you though you will be shocked
## i am showing this video to let you know that i
## never engage in exaggeration when i'm describing
## the disgusting rituals of human to animal slavery
## let me also mention this for some reason crying
## has become a taboo in our society but if you feel
## the need to cry while you're watching this video
## crying is the proper emotion to exhibit while
## you're watching an atrocity take place if you
## feel the need to laugh during this video you
## might want to consult with a good psychotherapist
## you're about to witness the killing of a perfectly
## healthy puppy every year us shelters execute 10
## million perfectly healthy puppies kittens dogs and
## cats simply because nobody wants them but you can
## stop this senseless killing in three easy ways
## have a vet spayer new to your dog or cat today
## never buy an animal from a breeder or pet
## shop and adopt your next dog or cat from a
## city shelter financial assistance is available
## please go to this website or call us today
## there is nothing but blood trails misery slavery
## and murder behind the propaganda spread by the fur
## industries spin doctors the fur trade is truly a
## death trade in the name of vanity and greed every
## year 40 million animals have the fur ripped off
## their bodies in a disgusting display of inhumanity
## manual neck breakings mass gassings and anal
## and genital electrocutions are the standard
## killing techniques used on every animal murdered
## for profit baby seals are clubbed to death in a
## violent annual carnage while the vicious steel
## jaw leg hole trap kills millions of free roaming
## animals like coyotes raccoons foxes and beavers if
## companies insist on selling misery boycott them at
## once and tell them that the blood is on their
## hands martin luther king jr once said injustice
## anywhere is a threat to justice everywhere this
## is injustice go to this website or call us today
## behind closed doors every year millions
## of monkeys dogs cats rabbits and mice
## are injured tortured and killed in unscientific
## research experiments outrageous lies from the
## national institutes of health and emotional
## ploys from other animal researchers only mislead
## you about this inhuman practice does this sound
## like science that could benefit your well-being
## please help us stop this insanity
## go to this website or call us today
## the circus meets every definition of slavery
## animals chained and caged and forced to perform
## unnatural tricks against their will animals
## bought rented and sold and shipped around like
## cargo in boxcars and semis while someone else
## profits off their labor and from their misery
## humanitarian dick gregory once proclaimed when
## i look at animals held captive by circuses
## i think of slavery animals and circuses represent
## domination and oppression they wear the same
## chains and shackles all circuses use violence
## to train elephants lions bears and tigers and
## the training sessions are comprised of beatings
## with hooks iron bars whips and sticks fear is
## the only way to make these wild animals submit and
## perform most circus animals also develop neurotic
## behaviors elephants sway from side to side lions
## and tigers pace and bears rock back and forth