## does meat not qualify as disgusting and gross to
## everybody how in the world is a liquid a liquid
## that oozes out of a cow's udder a secretion that's
## loaded with pus that drips from an animal's body
## how is this not considered gross oh and let me
## tell you about the pus in the cow's milk it could
## be my pleasure when you hook machines up to the
## udders of cows three times a day to suck them dry
## those machines cause massive amounts of
## infections and irritations on the inside
## and outside of the utter then when you add all
## the bovine growth hormone and all the genetic
## engineering that's been done to a cow's body
## to make sure she produces huge amounts of milk
## which always leads to another infection the
## machine doesn't know what not to suck out pus
## and mucus and infections right into the milk
## and yes milk is pasteurized but exactly when
## did pasteurization become a removal process
## last time i checked it was a sanitation process
## meaning you're only sanitizing pus and if you
## want to look this up online well you don't think
## the dairy industry would ever use the word pus
## when they write about this problem in their own
## trade journals do you now they're going to deceive
## you again look up the scientific term for pus
## somatic cell count s-o-m-a-t-i-c oh and
## let's talk about some other disgusting
## things that you guys love to eat did you know
## that the back side of a bird is called a cloaca
## c-l-o-a-c-a it was the only scene in the video
## you could pop that back in if you want to see
## it's one hole it is one whole but it serves
## many purposes it's the poop hole it's the pee
## hole it's the vaginal fluid hole and it's the hole
## where your omelettes and scrambled eggs come from
## yeah i remember back in the day used to love
## my scrambled eggs with [ __ ] sprinkles urine
## splattering goo juice all over it too because
## you know when you crack that shell over the
## ball all those microscopic particles fly
## every which way and if you guys think it's
## normal and natural to eat something that's been
## marinating in feces and urine for hours and hours
## i got a brand new challenge for everybody i always
## like to have a new challenge every single semester
## this is the egg challenge when you get home
## from school later today i want you go to the
## bathroom fill her up everything don't flush
## though then i want you to stroll on over to
## the kitchen open up the fridge grab yourself
## an egg take it back to the toilet drop it in
## if you even have the courage to stick your hand
## in there and grab it back out and you can wash
## it when you're done bleach it do whatever you
## want to it are you still gonna want to eat it
## and that's your own [ __ ] that's your waist now
## you're talking about a hand that you don't even
## know her butthole and what about vomit come on you
## guys love vama you adore some vomit in on and all
## over your food better give this one a pretty name
## no no one's gonna want to buy any vomit unless we
## call it honey instead honey comes directly from
## a bee's stomach it's regurgitated right through
## a bee's mouth you can look that up with any
## wildlife biologist but nobody wants to eat
## bee vomit nut cheerios we want honey nut cheerios
## so we lie to ourselves and play euphemism games
## the standard diet of a meat dairy and egg eater is
## blood flesh veins muscles tendons cow secretions
## things that come out of a hen's ass and b vomit
## and we're not done yet i'm not going to let you
## off the hook that easily while i got you here
## today because we top it all off in my opinion
## because every single year when people start
## cooking turkeys for the holidays boy people take
## a dead turkey carve out a really big hole in that
## dead turkey's ass take some stuffing and shove it
## inside their dead empty ass and use their little
## dead ass as an oven to bake some bread somebody
## else's dead empty bacteria laying ass to make
## bread ass bread and people think vegans are weird
## because we eat tofu i tell people one of
## my favorite meals nowadays yams and barley
## hook me up with some yams and barley for
## breakfast lunch or dinner and i'm a happy guy
## i know most people although i tell
## them this and they're like what
## you just eat vegetables and grains for dinner
## yeah i don't know man that's kind of weird
## okay somebody else's rib cage sitting
## on your plate that's not weird
## severed legs sliced up thighs and mutilated
## breasts on your plate isn't weird and doesn't
## make you think twice is bestiality weird anybody
## doing sexual things with animals because i used
## to think everybody thought so but not even
## close my meat cheese milk egg loving friends