## feeling breathing beings animals are victims the
## most oppressed ever and if you're having a tough
## time grasping this fact maybe it's because
## the only time you ever come into contact
## with cows and chickens and turkeys is when
## they're cut up and cooked on your dinner table
## so good afternoon everybody my name is gary
## yourofsky i'm a vegan animal liberation activist
## i'm not a politician and i'm not a salesperson
## that means i got no lies to tell you and no books
## and no dvds to sell you before i continue i want
## to define the word vegan for everybody v-e-g-a-n
## vegans just like vegetarians do not consume the
## meat of any land or marine animal vegans however
## unlike vegetarians also refrain from eating cheese
## milk eggs honey any animal product whatsoever
## we also don't wear animal skin no fur leather wool
## silk or down i want to let you know that i was not
## raised vegan i ate meat cheese milk and eggs
## for around 25 years and like most people
## i always thought that i cared about
## animals because i loved dogs and cats
## who were chipmunks and squirrels until one day
## after seeing some animals backstage at a circus
## chained up and caged up i not only
## realized that i was witnessing a slave show
## i realized i was a hypocrite a bigot a speciesist
## just like a racist who believes that their race is
## more special and more important than all the other
## races a speciesist believes that humans are more
## special and more important than all the animals
## and therefore have the right to enslave and kill
## any species they choose but if you honestly
## place yourself in the animal's position
## looking at this issue from the victim's point
## of view being denied your freedom and the right
## to live a long healthy life and then imagine
## yourself confined in a concentration camp truck
## on your way to a slaughterhouse so someone could
## slice your throat and cut you up into pieces
## i'm pretty sure you would understand
## why the psychotic addictions of meat
## cheese milk and eggs must be abolished if you eat
## animals and the things that come out of animals
## you are intentionally causing pain and suffering
## and polluting your soul with the blood of innocent
## beings humanity's main focus should always be
## extending compassion to others not engaging in
## rituals and traditions that are based on cruelty
## there's a massacre taking place right now it's the
## world's largest and longest-running massacre of
## all time because every second of every minute of
## every hour of every day female animals are raped
## to impregnate them so we can steal their babies
## separate families from each other so we
## can kill them and sell their flesh and skin
## if that's not the definition of injustice
## of an atrocity then i'd like to know what is
## you do realize that if you went to the
## nearest cow or chicken slaughterhouse
## and remove the animals and then
## replace them with human beings
## all of a sudden it's a tragedy auschwitz
## is resurrected slave ships sail again
## and don't think i'm the first person to make
## these valid comparisons civil rights activist
## dick gregory once said when i look at animals
## held captive by circuses i think of slavery
## animals and circuses represent domination and
## oppression they wear the same chains and shackles
## isaac bashevis singer who escaped nazi occupied
## poland once condemned our speciesistic world when
## he said what do they know all these scholars all
## these philosophers all the leaders of the world
## they have convinced themselves that man the worst
## transgressor of all the species is the crown of
## creation and all the animals were made for us to
## be food and pelts to be tormented and exterminated
## in relation to animals all humans are nazis
## for the animals it is an eternal treblinka