## animal rights is usually mocked or ignored but i
## think it's high time that humans climb down off
## their make-believe pyramids of domination
## and extend some simple decency some simple
## decency to our planetary companions before this
## discussion continues i need to let everyone know
## that i am not an animal lover do not refer to me
## as an animal lover this might shock you but i do
## not love animals oh i have the utmost empathy
## for their plate but you cannot refer to me as
## an animal lover i fight for animal liberation and
## peace because i loathe injustice and despise the
## way humans mistreat the animal kingdom i spend
## less than one percent of my time watching animal
## planet national geographic or discovery
## channel sharing the mating habits of the
## blue-footed boobie does not make the world a nice
## eclipse only veganism can do that which is why i
## am vegan vegan means i do not eat anything
## that had a face a mother or a bowel movement
## vegan also means i do not consume any product
## that was derived from anything that had a face
## a mother or a bowel movement if you're still
## consuming food that once went to the bathroom
## that once defecated and urinated you might want
## to change your diet repeat its veggie starter kit
## and go vegan vegan also means i do not wear any
## animal skins obviously fur but that includes
## leather wool silk and down payless 15.99 fake
## leather let me mention this about leather you
## know most people find it morally reprehensible
## for people to wear fur yet those same people
## don't find it morally reprehensible for people
## to wear leather but besides size shape and color
## there is no inherent difference between
## a cow and a mink or a cow in a fox
## cow skin is mink skin is fox skin cows feel
## the same amount of pain is making foxes
## and a cow wants to keep her skin attached to her
## body as much as a fox wants to keep hers so you
## must condemn both fur and leather condemning
## one and not the other would be hypocritical
## of all the exploited beings on the face of the
## earth animals are the most violated that's why
## i'm here today to ask you to join millions of
## others in a remarkable crusade against oppression
## but before anyone decides to engage in this
## compassionate crusade understand there is one
## important stipulation that you must adhere to all
## of your prejudices must be extinguished there is
## no room for any racism sexism heterosexism or
## of course speciesism which might be a new word
## to most people today speciesism the unfounded
## unethical and unprincipled view that the human
## animal has every right to mistreat exploit and
## murder the non-human animal and just like the
## previous isms speciesism lacks coherent thought
## and is a narrow-minded view of the life that
## comprises this planet nobel prize winner isaac
## basha this singer who escaped nazi-occupied poland
## and lost family members in concentration camps
## once called speciesism the purest form of racism
## 2600 years ago the great philosopher pythagoras
## said this about speciesism as long as humans
## continue to be the ruthless destroyer of other
## beings we will never know health or peace for
## as long as people massacre animals they will kill
## each other indeed those who sow the seed of murder
## and pain will ever reap joy or love after studying
## those statements and others i now understand
## that speciesism is the root of all hatred of all
## violence of all discrimination that exists on this
## planet and we will never destroy the branches
## of hatred like racism sexism and heterosexism
## unless we destroy violence and hatred and
## bloodthirstiness at its root and that root
## is speciesism the first form of hatred that human
## beings are taught is to eat the animal translation
## mistreat the animal translation hate the animal
## translation view the animal as an inanimate object
## and a mere commodity before anyone is ever taught
## to hate or discriminate against a gay person they
## are taught to hate and discriminate against
## animals for anyone has ever taught to hate or
## discriminate against a certain race or ethnicity
## they are taught to hate and discriminate against
## animals before any man was ever taught to mistreat
## a woman he is taught to mistreat an animal
## did you know that each person
## who chooses to eat animal flesh
## is responsible for the murder of 3 000
## land animals throughout their lifetime
## whether you kill thousands in 78 years or 78
## minutes you are still a killer and a terrorist