all right we are live welcome all to this
very special david rams live stream where
we're going to be joined by paul and nassau from
anonymous for the voiceless to discuss a load of
different rumors accusations i laugh because some
of them are pretty funny but no some of them are
very serious rumors accusations and a whole load
of questions that you've been sending to me um
that you want to ask paula nasal the co-founders
of anonymous for the voiceless we're going to
go through all of these things but first of all i
just want to do a bit of housekeeping with you so
if you are watching this later
as in you're not watching it live
if you check across the bottom the progress bar
you will see it's been split up into sections
so if you want to find the specific question room
or accusation or whatever that you're looking for
you can find it right there if you have questions
yourself right now and you are watching this live
right now you have questions uh we're gonna do a q
a at the end so save them for that but if you have
a topic or a question that you really really want
to be asked right now or or sooner you can use the
super chat if you use a super chat i will pause
and we'll answer your question right away but
but there is a caveat there is a disclaimer here
if you are spamming trolling or abusing anyone
in any way including if you send a super chat and
you pay for a super chat and it's a spam or abuse
it won't be discussed so you'll be wasting your
money i just want to make that very clear for you
and that also goes for the live chat
and it goes for the q a at the end
we won't be tolerating any spam or any trolling or
any abuse so the moderator will be handling that
i hope it doesn't come to that but i know a lot
of the topics that we're going to discuss are a
little bit controversial so i expect that there
will be at least one or two um so all that being
said yeah just keep it sensible keep it polite
and we'll have a a productive live stream that's
pretty much it so with that being said let's
bring in paul nasal welcome paul welcome myself
hey what's up how you doing good how are you
oh good all good all good i'm excited to get
through this and i think a lot of people in the
comments have been pretty pumped as well to uh
you know get through this um i know for you too
this is basically like you're repeating yourself
a lot of these things because over the years
i think i think we've been through this a few
times or your own channels and in your own social
medias but there are a few people at least a few
people here that have been asking a few of the the
questions already and a lot of people have been
sending me questions so i'm happy we can we can
do this and you know hopefully once and for all
get everything discussed in one place so i really
appreciate you coming on and doing this i know
it's not the easiest thing to do um so we can
kick off i suppose let's just kick straight in
right i mean let's not waste any time we're
here for a reason let's kick off with the
recent there's the most recent stuff that's been
going on right now i think most people watching
are going to be here probably off the back of that
i think i don't think we need to really introduce
what av is and who you are i think anybody
watching this is going to know that already
so let's just jump in with the recent
stuff and what's been going on with av with
the the whole situation with joey the situation
with animal safe movement anita the donor um
where are we up to with this now could you give
us an update on that just to kick things off
so we reached out to the donor
to find out if this was a genuine
um thing you know to legitimately
continue donating to av
and they replied with more demands on top
of everything that was discussed in the
videos we put out and everything that joey had
mentioned so even more demands on top of that
that we had to respond to but we of course
ourselves had things that we needed to communicate
to the donor i mean there's obviously a break
in trust at this point and we need to have a
conversation and re-establish that trust and
things like this and we haven't heard back
since we've replied so that was over almost
a month ago now and we haven't heard back
what were the extra requirements they were
they were giving you like what did they add
one of them was for us to delete
these videos that we put up
about joey and that that was pretty
telling of what this was really about
right right and what did they give her like
any kind of justification for wanting that done
or was it just a we request that you
do this well it seemed like it was
out of the uh concern for joey's image
or his uh reputation yeah so so far to
get it straight there the requirements so the
requirements for the donor to continue funding av
are that you delete those videos um give
them uh of some i don't know financial
organization access to all of your records
um is the board of directors things still
going they still want you to do that as well is
that still on the cards or did they pull that
like well here's the thing you know there were
things mentioned in the email that we got from
the donor but we don't even know what exactly are
the expectations on on their side and so that's
why we wanted to have a conversation with them
but at this point at this point we're not getting
we're not getting that do you think it's possible
that they did that to save a face as in they
that joey was involved and gave that response
to try to kind of yeah save face basically would
that be that's fair to say or do you think that
that he actually or she i don't know the donor
didn't they actually want to rectify things or
is it just to try to repair some of the damage
to the reputation of joey and the donor i mean
even in my most charitable of moods towards this
i can't see it any other way
yeah it feels like that i mean
from an outside perspective unfortunately it
does feel like it was just an attempt to maybe uh
i don't know get the upper hand take the high road
you know or appear to be taking the high road but
it's it's really sad to hear that actually
it's you you actually took the decision to
take the high road with them and then they just
didn't respond which um yeah it's disappointing
when we heard that there was this interest to
continue funding us and have another conversation
then we're like great let's have a conversation
but then you know we're not going to be bored
and bossed around and that's not what we designed
a v for it's in fact the opposite of that
and that's part of the reason
why we're at this point
that we're at and the reason why we
have an organic following and you know
it's i think there's just a misunderstanding
of what we do from the donor's perspective
and i think that they don't really understand
that work and they don't really understand us
and what our mission is and and they they perhaps
got involved without doing their homework and
we wanted to have a conversation so that we
could get on the same page about things and
we're not able to do that at this point so that's
where everything is left at this point yeah
i understand i understand and it's it's it's
something that it's not a surprise that that
the donor or anyone basically is having some
kind of uh you know let's say strong opinion
towards being like kind of anti-av this seems
to be quite a common thing right now and i was
just thinking about it earlier about what kind
of an example could i give you know to uh like
i don't know an analogy to give and um it's kind
of funny i don't know if you'll agree with me but
i feel like av has become kind of like
the nickelback of animal rights it's like
i'm sorry i'm sorry but nickelback
are extremely successful
awards end this stream
nickelback has won loads of awards they play loads
of gigs they're very successful they've got loads
of fans but it's also very in to hate them it's
almost like a trend to hate them right and that's
what i'm kind of getting at here is that it's not
a surprise to me that someone is holding really
negative opinions without even considering what
you're doing because that's the in thing to do
that's the kind of point i was making it seems
cool like when i put out some messages asking
people hey you know give me some questions for
av i had a few people just replying just just
with some you know real virtue signaling stuff
like just really like just explaining why they
won't go for av anymore and i'm like that's great
but like give me a question like give me something
you know it just seems like it's cool to say i
don't work with av i it seems cool to be like that
like it's cool to say i hate nickelback i'm sorry
to put you in that bracket but it really feels
like that you know uh i've got to say and and that
brings me on to go on go on sorry i think it's a
lot cooler though yeah i mean come on chad kroger
is not that that much of a loser is he come on
no i used to listen to them when i was younger
i have to admit i i i know it seems like it's uh
it's a bandwagon for us to disagree with
you on using that comparison but but it's uh
that's just a taste in music which i guess is
i guess it's a taste in activism i guess you
could that's the comparison you're making kind
of yeah kind of but i think with nickelback
um well anyway i don't want
to get into the comparison
maybe it's for the best yeah um but i'm going
to give an example actually because i i did have
a plan set up for this stream but you know
what i feel like this is relevant right now
so i want to tell the viewers a quick story
here about something that happened um i put
these messages out didn't i put these posts
out on my instagram asking people give me some
give me some questions give me some topics i put
it on facebook and by the way one of those posts
is blown up with a load of nonsense but anyway
that's another topic but some people responded
to me saying you know certain things and i want
to just bring up one of these responses that i had
um from somebody on my instagram who who had a
story to tell and i want to just kind of link
it in with what we just said about it's cool to
hate av it's cool to kind of just you know find
something wrong and just almost even sometimes uh
[ __ ] as well so i'm going to show you something
that happened and this is real by the way i'm
not this is not designed this wasn't planned this
is something that genuinely happened and i've
got the evidence because i can show you my um
i can show you this the literal inbox from my
instagram and you'll see why this is relevant
in a moment so i'm going to show the screen so you
can see it all right so here's my stories right i
don't know if you can can you see that right now
no how do i change those hold up i need to um
add the different screen i've never added
like a like uh this kind of screen i'm trying
to get the uh preview screen up okay hold
second all right open up um where are we
all right here we go so here's a story that uh i
put my story out that night saying like tell me
any topics you think should be discussed somebody
responded saying this why do you treat your
organizers like disposable garbage right now like
on the surface you're thinking wow okay that's
that's pretty intense right what's going
on here so i responded to this person
how do i have to switch this every time yeah i do
so i responded to this person very simply saying
basically i responded saying okay give us give
me some information i need to ask this question
properly so this is the response i got when the
allegations of fraud came up i commented on one of
paul's comments stating something along the lines
of it being standard practice to ask for financial
information paul was very aggressive in his
responses even abusive i told him i was one of the
organizers and he told me to [ __ ] off and leave
so i stood down these are not isolated incidents
unfortunately his temper gets in the way and
he burns his people his own people good luck so
i i'm not saying that i don't believe that person
and at the time i said you know okay i believe you
but i need some evidence right i need something
to show here do you have a screenshot do you have
something to show me that i can show to them and
uh you know i'm happy to discuss it and this is
the answer that i got i don't he cleans up his
message straight away i know you believe me but
understand you need for proof you could perhaps
pose the question more broadly is this is behavior
as a pattern of his and so will be hard to deny
sorry i can't help you any further david so
it's pretty damning right this is pretty damning
and at the time i gotta admit that i was a little
bit like swayed because look i know paul and
i know you both paul and the style and i know
that sometimes you know i lose my [ __ ] too i
say things that i later come to regret i've told
people to [ __ ] off i've told i told someone to
[ __ ] off live in a live stream by by accident
i thought they were saying something that they
weren't i told them to [ __ ] off and then they
were like why what's wrong i only said this i
got completely mixed up so it's not it's not
like you know we're infallible we make mistakes
but anyway i brought this up with you guys right
and um luckily paul actually had the screenshots
of this interaction now i'm going to show you what
the actual interaction was actually hold up i
just realized there's one little thing i need
to blur out but you're not going to believe you're
not going to believe what the actual interaction
went like um on the surface of this it looks
it obviously looks like it's a done deal right
and i'm going to explain why this is relevant
after i've shown you if you're wondering
watching this if you're wondering what how is this
relevant you'll see in a moment and i'd just like
to add that this is how people commonly talk about
they be when they say negative things about us
yeah definitely definitely this is this is
this is why i'm bringing it up it's it is
absolutely like this and i want to get
into this as a topic as well it's not just
a thing but hey look so here we go this is the
actual interaction so this is the individual
saying the information requested is pretty
standard for an audit so this is correct this
is what she said no lies there okay that's in line
with the message i received so here's paul being
extremely aggressive apparently i don't know
now requests bank login details to be handled
handed over to a non-accountant and a
former gang member how is that stuck
that's how stock standard audit is carried out is
it so that's the aggressive response apparently um
this person responds saying you know she's upset
because the it's calling joey a former gang member
um and saying that screenshots could be
manipulated and then paul goes to justify
himself saying well joey calls himself
an ex-gang member um okay so not not
nothing really going on there no [ __ ] off
nothing like that so far and it goes on you're
thinking okay so where is the [ __ ] off coming
where's the [ __ ] off and leave part coming right
because that's the main part here that sounds
horrible the aggressive [ __ ] off and leave
um all we've got here is paul saying get out
of here you said get out of here so let's not
[ __ ] off and leave and then this person who
was an organizer gets out of there she decides
to leave and that's it that's it that's the whole
interaction yeah can i just pause you there yeah
go ahead uh so at this point i didn't even know
that she was an organizer that's why she says in
the next comment oh no paul bless you i am one of
your organizers so she's now informed me of this
after you said get out of here yeah so after the
uh fact but yeah just wanted to that's it's okay
yeah and that that's exactly it's even this is
my point basically what i was talking about the
whole nickelback thing and how these rumors get
spread and it's cool to hate av it's because of
things like this don't get me wrong i know
there are examples out there of me being an
[ __ ] to people and i'm sure there are examples
out there of you guys being an [ __ ] to people
but to go and actually take something that didn't
happen and get it into your head that it happened
a certain way where you know you were told to [
__ ] off and leave as an organizer and you know
people believe this and and this goes and goes
and goes and i guess my question for you is how
does this happen how do we get to the point now
where we have people that believe that they have
been wronged by you they believe it so much that
they go and tell other people they were wronged by
you that they were told to [ __ ] off when there
is literal evidence that you have obviously and
it's online to show that this is not how it went
why does it happen and why do people believe it
instantly without even checking or questioning it
like how did we get to this point in your opinion
it's for the same reason that you get hate when
people choose to run hate campaign small or large
against you and their baseless claims it's the
same reason that anyone of any amount of influence
in this day and age in this age of outrage you
know in this council culture this is the way
that it works right people don't work off people
don't have standards for information anymore then
they don't hear something and then screen
it they hear something and they say well
he said it with conviction or she said it with
conviction or they said it with conviction and
therefore it must be true and if they said it
in the comments section of a post with emotion
it's true it doesn't you don't need
to do any more homework than that so
i guess that question is a bit more deeper it's
it's it's more of a question about why humans are
the way humans are yeah yeah and and yeah i can
see so you think you you're putting it down to the
the more the popularity aspect of it in that like
the more the more well-known an individual or a
group is the more of this that's going
to come is that is that am i right and
understanding this is kind of the point yeah
and you know a lot of our organizers have had
challenges in dealing with hate that they get when
they come on to become an organizer and represent
av in their cities because they're seen
as like working for hitler you know right
and yeah you know we we tell organizers
one of the things you learn about being
a human rights activist when you work
with us is dealing with that [ __ ]
right and that's part of it if you want to do
something of influence within this world and make
an impact i i i agree so um let's yeah i think
i think that's a that's going to be a recurring
topic to be honest with you so let's let's go
on to the like more let's go on to a solid topic
something we can really like get into and kind of
debunk so one of the more common things that came
up with my questions that came up questions that
came up sorry topics that came up was about money
now we talked about the donor obviously but we
didn't talk about the general things that people
seem to be obsessing over when it comes
to av so these general money concerns as
i've called on my general money concerns they
include things like people are upset because
you guys didn't want to release financial records
they're upset because apparently that they don't
know or you have not released where donations go
um they're upset because they the the chapters
are claiming they receive no money um so so i know
you've dealt with some of this on your own channel
and i'm on your own videos and i guess you're sick
of talking about it but again my aim today is to
get into it and and to ask maybe more questions
that maybe people haven't you guys maybe haven't
had before and to get really some solid facts and
detail out here so that people can't continue to
discuss this randomly like you said i feel like we
need to vet these things rather than just taking
people's words um so what what is that situation
then so let's let's be more specific with the
question there's money coming in and obviously
there's money going out um people are claiming
that there's a problem that they don't know what's
coming in and where it's going so how how would
you respond to that like what what do you think
uh how can you reassure these people that it's
going where it should be or you know what the
situation is what the financial situation is
i think going back to what you were saying
before about like how it's the cool thing
now to hate on av it's also the cool thing
to just ask these questions because you don't
you don't see other organizations or other
activists being asked the same questions and the
people that are asking these questions and making
the same claims don't have any kind of evidence to
back up their claim so it's just because somebody
brought it up in the comment section and they saw
it they're just going to repeat it and then the
next person is going to say the same thing so
um like the fact that we have never
done any financial reports is actually
[ __ ] because it's not that we're not
willing to do it as that we haven't been
required to do it yet and if anyone is actually
interested all of this information is public so
they can just go and look it up and they
will have access to and they can see that
um we're required to do our first financial um
what is it called like reporting this year end
of the year or it's probably going to be delayed
next year actually because of coverage but
because we registered av as a non-for-profit
i think it was in 2018 the way it works here
you don't you're not asked to do a reporting for
like the first year or the first couple of years
so it's not that we because otherwise we wouldn't
be able to run av if we hadn't done our um legal
requirements whatever it is that you know the
government is asking you to do as a not-for-profit
it's not like you can just say no i'm not going
to do my reporting and then you can continue to
run av as a not-for-profit so um yeah like i said
these claims are just faceless there's no evidence
and also people have no reason to think that
the money is not going where we say it's going
if somebody has proof that the money is going
elsewhere then they need to come forward and
show us where the money is going um we have
explained this like you said multiple times
we have told people where the money is going
like with all these different categories so we
can just repeat that but i feel like these people
are committed to think a certain way and no matter
what you say they're just not gonna believe you so
yeah i i just don't know if there's anything else
that we can say to clarify this for people yeah
i i guess for the sake of for the sake of this um
for the sake of this stream i don't want i i don't
i'm not interested in going through literally like
i wouldn't expect you to do this to go through
like okay we spend this much here and this much
i don't want to do that that's just it's not you
don't owe that to people watching this i think
what i'm more interested in is like maybe you
could just list off like the things that i
don't know the biggest spending from av and like
where it goes to give people an idea because uh
maybe some people genuinely have no idea where
an organization like av would spend money let's
assume they're asking it out of you know interest
rather than out of accusation like if somebody
asked you hey i'm just curious like where would
it go like where do you spend the most money how
would you answer that question like just just to
appear appease them let's say or just to you know
like the major donations coming in um so the
biggest part of it would obviously be the payments
to the team members so including myself paul
and um at some point we had just over 30 people
working with av so you can imagine how much that
would cost roughly and then now we've got i think
i don't know actually how many people we've got
like around 20 people working with us including
us too so the the bulk of it is going towards
payments so that those people can continue to
work for av and then the second biggest um thing
has always been the av fund which is something
that we started um and we would dedicate a certain
amount of money to go towards chapters that were
um you know active chapters that needed some help
getting their equipment so that was always like
the second um biggest expense for us and then yeah
the rest of it is just you know if if people look
into what costs are involved in terms of you know
all the admin stuff all the programs that you need
the software's the subscriptions and then all
the big campaigns that we were doing as well so
okay and with the staff they were 30 were they
all full-time 30 staff um no we had so we um
we have people that work with us as
contractors so av doesn't have like staff
necessarily but um everyone's like an independent
contractor that comes in and they can do
um part-time or full-time and um i think i would
say maybe it's half-half half of the people that
work with us are full-time half are part-time
um or just come in as volunteers even sometimes
they they do some work casually yeah cool okay
cause i'm just trying to like put a number on it
i think for anyone who maybe is not following um
it's like 30 staff if you had 30 staff that were
only working let's say like not full-time hours
late so they're working part-time hours right
so let's imagine it's 30 staff working 20
hours a week so we'll go like we'll go low
right we'll pitch low here 30 staff working
20 hours a week and let's imagine that the
i'm going to work in yearly salaries here
like base yearly salary in euros for example
the absolute minimum you could earn a year to
survive in a place like i don't know let's pick
a cheap let's baseline everything low let's go low
on everything the minimum you could earn in a year
in somewhere like spain for example
would be like because that's where i know
it's like 16 000 euros a year it's the absolute
minimum and that's really pushing it like it's
really difficult and that would be a full-time
salary so that's like that's half that 8 000
a year and let's imagine that's 30 staff that's
240 000 euros a year that's a that's pitching low
that's if you have no full-time staff that's
if all of your staff are only working like
like half-time hours let's imagine right so
just to put that into perspective for anyone
who's wondering how much that would be so like it
could it could be anywhere upwards from 240 000
euros a year which would be like i don't know 300
000 us dollars maybe something like that so that
is that is a huge chunk yeah and i think uh when
i when i first watched the video and i heard that
and i worked it out myself at that time and i
was like yeah that's actually a chunk of money
that i don't think many people understand right
um it doesn't it doesn't sound like a lot but
when you actually calculated it is quite a lot so
um the next thing then you talked about the the av
uh fund the for the for the chapters
where has it come from then that that
does this apparently this is a rumor okay there's
no i don't have evidence of this and i'm sure
there isn't evidence of this uh maybe there's one
or two organizers who have caused this problem
but where is it coming from that the chapters are
not getting the funding where has that started do
you know where that came from or do you know
what's going what what is actually behind it
like are they getting the funding i'm sorry to ask
the question but it came it came up a lot again
no i think it's the same thing as everything
else like somebody just started this rumor
that av keeps the money or specifically paul and
assad keep the money to themselves and they don't
send any money to the chapters i think it's just
again we don't even know where this came from but
if people were really interested this is one
thing that can be easily tracked we have a
full list of everyone who ever received the fund
how much they received it what they spent it on
and um because everyone who receives the fund they
were supposed to send us the invoices so it's like
we have all the records and um i guess the only
thing is that we weren't um doing it in a way
that just as as soon as you become an organizer
you can receive two thousand dollars or something
it was there were certain criterias that you
you need to meet as an organizer or as a chapter
you need to be active you need to be doing a
minimum number of cubes and you need to be you
know operating for a certain amount of time and
then even with that because the money was limited
we had to pick chapters so sometimes it
was just you know picking this chapter
over the other chapter and then next month they
would have a higher chance of getting it but
um yeah there will be many organizers that would
actually be able to come forward and say yeah we
received that and this is what we spent it on but
i mean our conditions for our criteria for being
accepted in in getting the funding was nothing
crazy like you had to be on board for six months
you know just six months and do one a month
i think that's what yeah one cube a month so
you had to do a total amount of six cubes before
we would we would look at giving you money yeah
and yeah you know that's nothing that's nothing
too strenuous i think what's happened is
a lot of organizers don't really pay attention
to what we do they they come on and they just do
their own thing in their own cities and they want
to be a king or a queen in their own on their own
mountains and and literally we've seen so many
people come and go who carry this attitude with
the navy they just do their own thing in their own
city and they aren't a part of what we're doing
as a global movement and uh and these
people don't really pay attention to
the things that we have going on yeah and they
don't really know about these uh things to any
20 details so they don't apply and then they
complain that they never got the money right um
how do you how do you think we can handle that i
mean this is uh not even an av specific thing but
we can we can talk about it for a second that it's
something i've also experienced not only in av but
in save and also in um in even you know grassroots
like none like local grassroots organizations
local grassroots groups is that there seems to
always be some kind of power struggle going on
in these groups i don't know if it's only within
animal rights or if it's also within i don't know
women's rights if it's in black lives matter i
don't know if it's in all these groups i i've not
been in those groups for enough time to know but
in animal rights it seems to be that in every
single group there is a power struggle of somebody
trying to take over and somebody else who's trying
to take over that person and you know somebody
who's trying to reject the leader they have or
whatever you want to call them leader whatever
it is it's it's it seems to be very common like
what do you think what's causing that and uh would
you have a suggestion on on how to how to fix that
well you know one of the things
i'm really proud of with av
is that we really took into account like
how we're taken by the public and the fact
that we want to be taken seriously and like we
want to address that within the public eye and
we don't necessarily expect people to trust our
leadership to like trust our decision making
but i think it's safe to say we've earned a
certain level of trust because you know we
stick to our ship pretty well and
we do what we do pretty well and
and uh those who choose to trust our leadership
aren't forced to choose that they choose it
on their own accord and i guess if you want
that entitlement that asylum i have earned to
run an organization the way that we choose
then you should start your own organization
sure if you come on to some come on board with
someone else you know you choose to volunteer
or you choose to work for an organization and
you're on boarding their ethos and representing
what their movement is about you really have no
right to say you shouldn't make the decisions
sure sure so the idea is kind of do you think
the baby should be some kind of i don't know
um let's say a self-reflection with people who
who join groups or who start to work with not
just av but with any group really that if
you are going to volunteer with a group um
i guess you need to learn that maybe your ideas
won't always be accepted by the current i don't
know manager leader organizer of that group and
if you don't like it then that's absolutely fine
you either continue volunteering or you create
your own thing and do it your way it's basically
is that am i is that what you're saying basically
what yeah because like of course we always welcome
feedback but welcoming feedback doesn't mean we're
going to take it on board we're going to discuss
it between us too and then the team that we have
and then we might take it on board or we may not
but to expect that every single feedback is just
going to be accepted and we're going to implement
that idea whatever it might be i think that's very
unrealistic yeah it will be very chaotic so yes if
somebody doesn't like the fact that you know their
feedback wasn't accepted then i think if they feel
like they're not aligned with the organization
then they should just do their own thing i mean
that just makes sense to me it's just very common
yeah and you know i think you clarified but just
to make sure just to make sure that no one is
confused by what we're saying here we're not
saying you know if you if you have any input you
know you have any feedback you have any criticism
as a represent as a representative of
ab whether you're an organizer volunteer
we're not saying that we're just going to
say [ __ ] you and go do your own thing
that's not how we operate we and like to think
that we've only ever enacted ideas that have come
from either my brain or a cell's brain is insane
we've always taken on feedback from others
and taken it into account and i think the
last thing i want people to consider here is
where would av be today like really think
about where a baby would be today if we
weren't operating the way that we are if we
ran a system where we had like a board of um
you know board of directors
where we only had a vote
into what was and we only had two votes of many
into what was being decided on i mean i think it's
i i think it's clear that av wouldn't be clear
about the message and i don't think that we would
be where we are today that leads on to another
point quite nicely actually because i think what
i feel like you're hinting at here is that that
if you didn't maintain control you feel
that av would go down the same road as
pretty much every other ar organization
has gone down where they are bringing in
uh human issues um human rights issues and
basically kind of i guess i guess if you could put
in a way that they're moving with the times rather
than staying true to what they started for if
that makes sense um and some people would say that
that is a positive thing you know to move with the
times because let's be honest the you know the the
times are very much changing and you know a lot of
human rights issues have very much been thrown to
the front and that's not necessarily a bad thing
um but you could argue that ar organizations
also taking those fights on board is some
some and i guess you would argue that is a bad
thing and that brings me to another question that
has been asked or let's say a topic that has been
brought up uh the topic of anti-intersectionality
and uh and you know what this means with with av
what intersect or not intersectionality i don't
think that's even the correct thing to talk to
to say because i don't intersectionality itself
i'm sure we all if there's anybody in this in
this chat or even you guys that say disagrees
with the concept of it i would just say you're
disagreeing with facts right if the fact is that
intersexuality as it was originally coined
it's it's factual it's like you know someone
who's female or black will experience the world
differently to someone who's male and white or
someone who's female and white or someone who's
you know transgender and black or transgender
everyone experiences the world differently and has
different challenges right that's what it means
that's literally what it means not what vegans
have made it that's [ __ ] so we all will agree
that that's what it means i'm sure and i you
know i guess no one really would would say it
would argue against that it's just logic it's just
factual but let's say uh the they call themselves
consistent anti-oppression crowd let's say and and
this is something that you have get like more than
once you've stood out stood up against and you've
said said some things about you know the animals
first um approach non-humans first approach um
and this has been widely criticized and a lot
of people have even you know people make videos
about this they are constantly attacking you guys
for this they are people um saying they won't they
won't go to av events because of this um so yeah
this is the topic we're going to get into i'll ask
you a question someone just asked this question
earlier uh why do intersectionals intersectionals
not like you that's what someone said so that's
an easy question to start with why do these
people hate you why are they coming for you
why are they trying to cancel you why are
they trying to ruin um your organization
you want to go only um yeah i i guess
yeah like you you already explained that
it's not that we're anti-intersectional um we
just made a decision that av is going to be 100
dedicated to the animals non-human animals and
there are many reasons why we decided on that
but that doesn't mean that we don't think or
anyone within the organization not just us too
doesn't believe that other groups of beings need
um voices to speak up for them or we shouldn't be
doing activism in different areas so it's again
it's just the way that people decide to interpret
this like someone decided that because av is 100
dedicated to non-human animals that means that
we have hatred towards humans or we there's
discrimination when it comes to certain groups
of humans and they're just running with that
idea i think it's easy to paint that image of us
given that we are aware of the fact that we
dedicate av 100 to animal rights in light
of a temp the temperament currently in society is
that anyone who does such a thing must also pander
to human rights otherwise it's totally out
of place so we're completely aware of this
and we still won't pander so it's easy to
paint us like that but we don't care because
we want for this to exist in the world we
want a movement who is still willing to just
do the right thing in the face of what is popular
in the moment and you've been also a popular thing
that comes up when discussing these things
is the the idea of a hierarchy of oppression
of which it it appears that you that you guys do
um have a hierarchy as in you i've heard at least
you paul especially i've heard this but i
don't know if i'm sure you've said it as well
and this is not an attack it's just you
know just quoting um that the animals
are by far the most depressed beings on the
planet right and some people get upset about
that because they say that you're creating a
hierarchy of oppression and apparently this is
this is uh this is wrong um how do you
respond to that um that's disrespectful
and it's a spit in the face of every animal
that that is subjected to that injustice
you know you can you can act like you're
offended by these semantics all you want
but just remember that while your charade is going
on you're spitting in the face of the victims who
are involved in the injustice that you're carrying
on about and that's my response to that it's just
simple that we shouldn't have to explain that
we're not saying that humans aren't oppressed
um yeah like what you said doesn't sound
like something that resonates with me
the hierarchy of depression but it is a fact
that the animals well okay so in terms of the
number of individual animals who have been
tortured and abused and murdered compared to
any other injustice that's literally what we're
talking about so i don't think it's i don't think
it means like if anyone takes that as so you're
saying there is a hierarchy of oppression meaning
this group is more oppressed or we should speak
up for them first that's not what we're saying you
can't take that from from saying you know animals
are the most suppressed meaning they have been
um they have been oppressed for the longest and
the number of individual victims is higher than
any other injustice that's just the fact that's
the reality of it and you're right if somebody
gets upset because of that then i think they
need to just reflect on why that is because
i know that there are people out there that were
more oppressed than me as as a woman of color
and so therefore anyone else in any other
group then they should know that there are
other beings you know that are more oppressed than
themselves and that doesn't take away from their
pain or their suffering that's how i see it i
mean how more audacious could you possibly be
as a human being any human being to say
you're more oppressed than a group of beings
enslaved tortured and murdered by the trillion
with a t every year when was the last genocide
of one billion with a b humans oh wait crickets
a billion i'm talking three trillion with a t
are subjected to this injustice every single year
it's happening every second of every day doesn't
need to be explained to vegans of course but hello
don't get mad at us for being a medium of truth
yeah i think um just to add to that i think this
is this is a point that i i agree on i mean i'm i
guess i'm not supposed to be sharing my personal
views here i am interviewing you but i have to
say i agree with you because um i don't believe
that it's down to emotions this point i believe
it's down to the facts and it's objectively
true it's it's it's not something that can
even be argued against and anyone who's tried to
argue against even with me the arguments it just
falls to pieces because you can't possibly claim
that any other animal on the planet is abused
or any any human animal on the planet is abused or
or exploited or objectified more than a non-human
the non-humans don't even have political rights or
voices like it's it's not even about how much they
say even if we forget how many of them are abused
in the severity the fact that they literally have
no say at all in their own lives um like none
none whatsoever no legal almost no legal rights
you know um it's it's enough you know it's enough
to just even go from that even if it wasn't three
trillion that alone is enough of a point you know
but at that and the fact there's three trillion
of them being you know horrifically murdered
it's it's it's yeah it's a crazy point to try to
to try to argue against that in my opinion and i'm
always surprised when vegans try to argue against
it it's i mean i mean nothing really surprises
me anymore actually but but yeah it's slightly
more surprised with that um i've got a question
uh do you think this is this came from a a uh
instagramer i think uh do you think it's
speciesist to ignore human oppression while
fighting for non-human animals that was that was
a question that somebody wanted to ask you guys
you know i know that people aren't
attuned to nuance and context but
it is required for us to answer this
question uh as a general statement yeah like
the way you ask that of course not like yeah
sorry the question was is it is it speciesist
do you think it yeah do you think it is personally
do you find it to be is that is that an example
of speciesism basically yes when i hear that
question as a blanket statement like that yes
because it sounds like otherwise you're going to
say otherwise you're denying that group of things
like their existence and their suffering and
their oppression so yeah of course it is but
yeah like we need an example or an explanation
of why because is that because again because
av is 100 focused on non-human animals or is this
question directed at us personally and people are
wondering if we do other forms of activism or we
care about other poison forms of injustice every
every day we make a post on social media about
non-human animals every day we set up cube of
truth action on the streets those energies are
spent on fighting for non-human animals while
human injustices are occurring within human human
to human injustices are occurring around the world
at that time so if at a general level you
want to say because of our answer we're
technically ignoring all of these other
injustices while we're doing that well
there's no such there's no point of even
trying to like there's no nuance at all
in a way that someone would think if
that's the conclusion they're trying
yeah yeah i think i would add to that and i
don't think it's speciesism because you're not uh
you're not not fighting for humans i'm not i'm not
not fighting for humans because i think humans are
somehow inferior i'm choosing to fight for
non-humans because i believe that well not
i believe they are um in more need simple as that
so that's my how i answer that question is is that
way it's not speciesism because i'm not doing
it because of the species i'm doing it because
of the severity of the situation we've never
even said the term animals first human second
like that's come from other people we've
never said that before right right what we've
never said is animals deserve to have a cause
dedicated solely to them and so av will be that
sure i actually i i don't know if i've ever heard
you say that i don't think i don't think i have
and something but some people have messaged
that so if anyone's watching right now and you
you feel like you have some evidence of that then
you're more than welcome to send it and we'll
discuss it and you know but i i yeah it's it's
something that does keep coming up and that goes
for other things by the way if you're watching
now and we we go through something and and you
know but we discuss our poorness i've never said
that or this has not happened and you think it has
you just send me a message with what you think has
happened or within with evidence of it and we'll
we'll talk about it right now we're not we're not
here to hide away from things and you know paul
and us how you agreed to come on here to actually
directly face some of these things you know so if
anyone does have something that they feel should
be directly faced just send it me on instagram or
a messenger or email or you know tag tag me in
the comments and tell me you're gonna send it on
messenger or whatever and i'll and i'll pick it
up and we'll bring it up on the screen and we'll
talk about it like we're not we're not hiding
anything but i've got a sneaky suspicion that
that's not gonna happen because most of the stuff
we're talking about is just rumor and you know
it's i don't think there's a lot
of evidence behind it to be honest
um yeah but um let's let's i think we're still on
intersectionality and i think i feel like we maybe
want to delve into that just a little bit further
um i guess what i guess your guys stance on it i
mean somebody asked the question here saying what
are you doing to make your activism intersectional
somebody asked that uh of you guys and and i was
thinking like how can i really ask that because i
don't i don't know if it's something that you
actually are trying to do um i don't i know
that there was a i know there was a change of
direction recently as to i don't know not be so
i don't know what the word is to be more sensitive
i think with your own words um because maybe in
the past there was a little bit of insensitivity
but i guess yeah what would you say to someone
who's asking you that how what are you doing
to make your activism more intersectional
we're not trying to do that like you said but
that's not the goal there's no need for us to
try to do that and let's just cut the [ __ ] here
people who say this are not actually asking us
to adopt anti-oppression values within
our organization because we already have
those what they're asking us to do is become
activists for human related issues and we are
dedicated to non-human animals sorry not sorry
so you draw you draw a line i guess uh between
not contributing to other oppressions
are they drawing a line sorry between
not contributing to other oppressions and being
active for other oppressions and they feel that
because you are on the not contributing side
of the line that therefore means that you are
wrong and that you should be actually active
for those oppressions too correct they want us
to be on the streets showing footage of
what's happening in the blm movement or
with regards to homelessness or feminism or
i guess whatever the mainstream issue is of
the times but going back to what you were
saying earlier about like the definition of
intersectionality it actually doesn't apply here
because sure you can be an animal rights activist
you can also be a human rights activist in what
that whatever area you want to work in but um
what's the relationship between like any of those
things that you mentioned and animals suffering
you know what i mean there is no relationship
so i i don't think it actually makes sense
to ask that of us so how are we gonna make it
work with that even if that was something we
were looking at doing how are you gonna connect
homelessness to animal suffering in the meat
dairy and egg industry i mean we get asked to
speak up about various issues and it is really
only about what is popular at that time what is
being spoken about at that time and it's not about
these issues that cause a vast number of deaths
around the world for example in the middle east
that never gets spoken about that we're aware
of because we have heritage in the middle east
we know about these things these people for
example who were outraged about what was going on
in america during the protests in minnesota
and throughout other states said really
nothing about what happened in lebanon
for example yeah they are very selective
the causes that they choose to speak up about and
that's the thing because when people ask us to do
the same thing they're asking us to to speak up
for those specific issues um because you know how
many different things are out there that you could
be speaking about when it comes to human rights
there are so many different things and i don't
know anyone who claims to be an intersectional
and they actually cover all of those issues
there's literally thousands of different
things that you could talk about and i i only see
these people focusing on two or three different
categories and they want us to do the same and
that points out that you do have to choose your
cause yeah because if they're claiming you
have to speak up for all of them well there's
literally thousands of injustices occurring
right now around the world all the time so
it's not only impractical it's impossible
for you to physically pull that off to
actually speak up for all of them yeah and to
fight to end all of them all at once i mean
think about how insane that is so these people are
being hypocrites because these people are choosing
their causes which is guess what we have you have
our support you have our full support to do that
because we chose a cause yeah and that's how it is
you guys are doing the same thing that we're doing
how about we i'm actually taking this moment
to see where we have something in common
and maybe you should do the same thing instead of
looking at where we have a difference or where you
think you're more holier than that or something
to that effect have you considered this before
there's a concept that actually if i i'll tell
you who who introduced me to it but um this was
actually back in the day when things were a little
bit nicer but it was actually anita who introduced
me to this concept um years like maybe a year and
a half ago two years ago when i i brought up the i
brought up some comments about insectionality and
i kind of warned anita that it looked like this
was going to start to take a turn for the worse
people were starting to attack me for not you know
saying certain things or for saying certain things
and i felt like it was starting to seep into
organizations and i mentioned this and she told me
we won't do this because we are all about positive
intersectionality and she had this concept and
this mindset and it really inspired me actually
because she said we can fight for the animals
100 always but when there are situations where
it also benefits humans we can also note it for
example look these vegans went out and gave free
food that are homeless because they're suffering
they're doing animal rights activism by teaching
the homeless about veganism and they're helping
the homeless for example that would be a positive
intersectional message right it's not no one
loses out here the animals are focused and
the the homeless people have a focus in lebanon
for example with the blast the the vegans the
local vegans were doing incredible work they were
getting like food out to everyone they were like
you know um helping the vegan businesses in
the area they were helping the animals in the
area it was it was amazing but you're also raising
awareness of that corrupt government and how this
even happened in the first place it's it's two in
one it's easy right um and this was great when she
said this i was really inspired but obviously we
know how that went and it didn't end up staying
um staying that way unfortunately but for you guys
like what do you think about av in that sense do
you think this is something av could do like with
social media i mean not with the cubes but like
with how you represent yourselves on social
media is that something that you've thought about
or would ever consider or you do you have do
you disagree with that that kind of way of doing
things what way of doing things specifically
what is being suggested so so like for example
when there are some um when there is there are
issues that potentially could be both benefited by
raising awareness of it for example you obviously
av is 100 focused on the animals but let's imagine
there is uh some of your av organizers or
your av team goes out and gives food to the
homeless raising putting that on av social
media and saying like look look look at what
our awesome activists are doing they're fighting
for the animals and they're helping the homeless
do you see some pro a problem with doing something
like that or do you think that that you agree with
that as a as an idea that specific suggestion just
sounds like we would be i don't see how that helps
a human cause of any kind
by making a post like that
i don't see that as activism to help a human
cause i mean at best it's congratulatory and
supportive of individuals within
our network who are doing that uh
i don't see that as activism though i don't see
that as like fighting a human rights cause of
some kind no i guess not but i guess it would be
raising awareness that homeless people need food
i know people know that or maybe inspiring other
vegans to go out and outreach homeless people and
give them food i don't know it's an idea it's
just it's just an idea as is what i mean it's
it's something that uh like i don't know if it
even would count as intersectionality in that
case but for example the lebanon example would
because they they have the corrupt government
they are they're oppressing their people um making
someone making a post or making a video on that
where you're saying hey look at what these
awesome vegans are doing they're fighting a
corrupt government and they're also saving animals
and they're getting people food that that would be
a better example of of how to raise awareness of
two oppressions um in one without either of them
losing anything if that makes sense because
it's not like we're just talking about
you know lebanon we're talking about vegan and
activists in lebanon so like then it becomes
something that encompasses all of it you
know but i mean i i'm a bit confused because
i don't see how it was like an animal rights
uh thing that they did they're just vegans
people who don't abuse and torture animals
animal rights activists who went and did
a deed for humans and that deed was a human rights
good that they did and when they were doing that
that act that deed had nothing to do with the
animals really it was just about i think david was
saying that they were kind of outreaching people
when they were giving them the food were they
yeah i believe they were i don't know
this for sure but i believe they were
sending out like leaflets and stuff with the
with the bags and also they were rescuing animals
too they were actually rescuing animals
off the street and getting them treated
they were raising money for that too so they
were doing a few yeah it was like uh it was
yeah they were doing a few a few different things
to try and help the animals and also the people
yeah i didn't know the full extent of the campaign
that they carried out over there uh i all i know
is at the time i reached out and you know i
checked in with them and i was just wanting to
know if they were okay during the whole blast but
i forgive my ignorance to those who were carrying
out that awesome campaign because it looked very
helpful i was just confused on how it was tied
into animal rights i just thought they were doing
a deed a good deed for humans at in that moment
i didn't see how maybe they were maybe they were
maybe they were maybe maybe they were only doing
that some of them um but i know for sure some
of them were also rescuing the animals i guess
i mean with a more concrete example if let's
imagine there is a concrete example of this
where they're actually doing that they're actually
advocating for animal rights whilst simultaneously
helping humans um i guess the question is like
would would that be something av would consider to
post about if it came up or or is is there some a
reason not to that's what i'm trying to understand
like hosting this you're asking specifically
about posting about it on social media
our platforms are for animal rights for non-human
animal rights so that's our general response to
that but we do carry out what you're saying we
do take the opportunity to how did you want it
to benefit humans while benefiting the
animals you know in those moments when we see
any form of oppression or discrimination
occurring within our organization
we stamp it out with the quickness and we have
a process that we go through to rid it from the
organization in those moments we're taking
action that benefits humans and the animals
we're just not posting about it i guess because
our platforms and network is for non-human animals
okay i understand i understand so it's kind of
like um yeah so your base your base kind of um
i don't know what to put it here your
let's say default your your focus your
baseline i keep using that word is is that you
know the the account is for non-humans and that
that's kind of the be that's it basically that
that's how it's going to be like social media
and also the cubes it that that's where it's
going to stay and that that's your core kind
of value basically that's what you're saying here
right yeah like again going back to the numbers
thing you know three trillion animals every year
if you think about the amount of victims that are
involved in this injustice you know how many more
times uh more urgent would you say in terms of the
numbers this injustice is than other injustices
on the planet how many more times more urgent
would you say totally it's like it's not a it's
not a criticism for me i'm actually just trying
to uh you know clarify yeah no no maybe that was
framed like i was like being defensive but i'm
asking a genuine question because my next thing
i was going to say because i say that to say this
like that's how much more urgent it is for us
to maintain a focus on using those platforms
for that reason so it's not you know okay yeah
totally i i don't i don't see it as a a negative
the reason i got into this this discussion now
is because i i personally i i see some benefit
in that for myself personally that's why i make
some of the videos i make where i talk about
vegans doing good work also for people i see some
benefit in it and and that's my choice but that
doesn't by default mean that your choice is wrong
and i think this is um it's very important for
anyone that watched this section and thinks oh but
you know but some people are going to agree with
you and they'll be like no keep keep the people
off right i just just keep keep it really really
focused and some people are going to agree with
me and say well there's no harm in doing this
and maybe it'll help and that's totally fine to
have different opinions um it doesn't mean one
of us is wrong and deserves to be cancelled and
the others are you know deserve to be celebrated
it's just you align with who you align with and if
you're aligned with paul and asylum this then you
great keep you do that for your page and
if you align with me then great you do
what i said and if you don't align with either of
us then i don't know alive with someone else and
do do that then it's it's not um this isn't a case
of being right or wrong i just wanted to see what
you thought about it on this specific example
the specific topic okay cool um let's let's uh
all right let's go to a more direct
thing then because i've got a few like
let's say more direct accusations direct uh rumors
and um we talked about humans quite a lot now and
actually um it's kind of shitty that i bring the
co-founders of anonymous for the voiceless on and
we just talk about people but um that's what we
came here for uh maybe we can do another live
stream where we actually get into the you know
into animal rights and activism and really you
know go for that i think that would be nice to do
um to kind of balance having to talk about this
for such a long time but um these
uh main accusations we've had and
this also comes in with the intersectionality and
also comes in with the things you just discussed
about your uh your policies um the number one
that came up multiple times was accusations of
transphobia and pronouns and you've dealt with
this uh obviously paul you've dealt with this
personally and you've spoken about this in other
places but we are gonna talk about it a bit here
and some specific questions and somebody's
asked the question uh well i'll go for like
the longer one actually there's a few questions
but this one's actually quite a well written one
so they said and they left av this individual
because um because apparently av was focusing on
they said focusing on the animals instead of
encouraging respect between activists uh they said
that there was a situation where you guys decided
to call people by birth names rather than calling
people by their preferred pronouns and for them
this was extremely offensive and wrong um and the
discussion around the pronoun politics or what you
called uh i think you call it something like uh
identity politics um they found this to be
a lot of people i guess found this to be
controversial or controversial enough for them to
leave av or at least not go to cubes anymore so
i guess the question is um why why why is that
why is this decision been made to not use people's
pronouns and use their first names instead even
if they want to be referred to by a pronoun
i guess i'll answer because there's our
main interaction yeah uh gender pronouns
are clearly ideological and uh we don't so
you're just specifically asking about the cubes
like in nab i guess yeah let's keep
it focused on like cubes av yeah so
i've never like personally being asked to refer
to someone as a particular like name and uh
where where i've refused to call
them that name that's never happened
you know it's obviously the polite thing
to do to use the requested name of someone
but at cubes we don't even really need your name
so it makes no sense for us to apply
a protocol regarding one's gender
so we don't even have a protocol regarding
gender at all because it's not required it's
we barely need your name at the cube and uh and
that's what we said regarding this whole thing
yeah so if if like putting this into real life
like if someone actually did uh come to a cube and
uh let's say it was it was one of your organizers
or you whichever and they said okay i when you
refer to me as like you know if if they are like
doing something and that you're talking about them
like they can't hear you or whatever or maybe
they're in the conversation whatever they want
to be referred to as a she um because now they're
a trans woman and and is that something that you
would respect or you would tell your organizers
to respect or would you tell them no only refer to
them by their name like they're his name but if if
by respect you mean are we going to then call them
a man in their face in order to make a point that
we reject the notion that they identify as a woman
well of course we're not going to do that that
that would be impolite and counterproductive for
our mission on the streets to begin with which is
to get on with non-human animal rights activism
not get caught up in issues between humans human
centric issues and the reason why i'm pointing out
that i initially started with pointing out that
this is clearly ideological is that we don't
allow any other political ideologies to be
carried out or political agendas to be carried
out at the cubes of any kind so when we've never
specifically targeted this in any way you
know it's just across the board not welcome
sure and what what what about in the case that
someone doesn't actually believe or doesn't really
agree with you that it's political because a lot
of people who are become become a trans woman or a
trans man they don't do it out of some political
ideology they do it because they have gender
dysphoria right it's a medical condition and them
being referred to as a he or she um it's nothing
to do with their politics is to do with them being
like validated as a person right so it's actually
really important i know i know there are a lot
of trans activists out there who are making this
very very political i understand that they exist
and there are people who are not even trans who
make it political by forcing others to call them
a he or she when they've they don't have gender
dysphoria you know what i mean i understand
this is happening and i understand standing
up to that but in the case where these people
are genuine um and you know they are asking as a
as like a you know as a courtesy to help them
adapt to this new life for example uh would that
be a policy of av to to tell people right you
refer to them as they want to be referred to or
is that not a policy navy and it's no you
just you call them by name and that's it
so just to clarify here because i think there's
some things being communicated that in this
interaction that might lead people to think that
we've commented on trans people when we haven't
even commented on trans people at all ever ever
uh my comments were only about gender pronouns
and uh gender pronouns are a completely different
discussion to trans issues gender pronouns
are used by people who don't even identify as
trans so i'm not talking about trans people i've
never talked i've never said anything about trans
people and neither is a cell and that needs to be
clarified 100 i think because i don't appreciate
getting tossed into that category of someone who
has spoken about trans people when i haven't said
a single word about trans people uh my comments
are about my skepticism towards gender pronouns
and the use of gender pronouns and then being
50 plus gender pronouns that was my comment and uh
this like i said at the cube there's no real need
for even even for someone's name so if if this is
happening this interaction is happening at a cube
where someone is offended because you
haven't used their correct gender pronoun
that's what i mean by becoming political
and someone bringing a political agenda into
that space when we don't even really require
your name so if that discussion is occurring
at the cube it's likely because someone is
choosing to make a rise out of it and you know to
uh to you know obviously if someone is like i
said already going out of their way to disrespect
somebody like this yes we would take issue
with that 100 we would see that as bullying
it would be implied and it would be bullying
to say no i don't not only do i not believe
what you believe but your belief is stupid that's
bullying right so of course we don't condone that
but at the same time forcing others to believe
what you believe at the cube is not welcome
that's not what we're there for right everybody
has a different belief system when it comes
to this topic and people are entitled
to have different opinions about this
and that's it's not a time and a space at a cube
of truth to be fighting each other to be engaging
in this kind of discord when it's human-centric
and we are supposed to be there for non-human
animals we should be respecting each other
to have the right to have a different opinion
and to just get on with the one thing we're
supposed to be on the same page about which is
non-human animal rights deserve to have this three
or four hours dedicated to them on the streets
yeah i guess i guess to kind of close this
off or i hope we can close it off as if
so if if uh we have i mean obviously there
are there are obviously trans activists right
i'm focusing on trans here because i understand
what you're saying about gender pronouns in that
if somebody has chosen a pronoun because it's
whatever it's something they want to identify as
i understand why there's some some skepticism here
because it's kind of like all right that's fine
you'll go ahead and do that and people can
respect that but if if they forget or if they
i don't know if they don't want to and there's
no real logic behind the reason that the view
identifying is that i can understand why
someone you know not being into that but
where i'm specifically focusing on here and
and i'm focusing on it because it is it is
medical it is it is it is a psychological
thing it is not something that's like
opinion is that you know gender dysphoria
exists like trans people exist we have to
time but now it's becoming more acceptable to
discuss it right so you see a lot more people
who are coming out this way whereas in the past
they wouldn't have done they would have hidden
it because they were embarrassed or ashamed and
they just go through their whole life with this
situation you know with this this problem nowadays
uh people are being encouraged to speak up about
it and you know go public and get the operation
and and re-identify themselves so that they're
more they are who they are right what i'm trying
to get here is that does does av have like uh
something in place that is also accommodating that
so that so that if somebody does come to a cube as
a trans person um and they want to be identified
as a he um or she or they if they're not sure um
and somebody is is you know if they get it wrong
by accident okay i get that that's something that
you know it shouldn't if it's a complaint you
just say okay hey please you know don't don't
get it wrong by accident in the future like do us
a favor but if if they're choosing to get it wrong
if they're like actually saying no i don't accept
that are you saying that yeah bullying yeah that
could that could be bullying yeah um but also i
kind of i'm kind of trying to understand where
the line's drawn between well that's your
ideology so tough [ __ ] versus well okay no
this is something that this is you this is who
you are and look this person needs to respect
that or or they're the one that'll be kicked
out like where are you where are you drawing
the line between the ideology versus the bullying
if you understand what i'm saying because maybe
an organizer says well i don't need to respect
that because i don't agree where's the line drawn
the line is simply drawn at if the interaction
at the cube requires your gender then okay we'll
use whatever gender you choose us to use however
whatever name because in that case they can also
use the name if the organizer or the volunteer
feels uncomfortable or they don't align with the
same ideologies they don't have to use the pronoun
they can just refer to them with their chosen name
yeah that's what i was going to say is that the
interactions that you don't actually require
don't actually require the gender so that's what i
was saying is that if i'm trying to be charitable
and open-minded here by saying if there is
a circumstance of the cube that requires the
gender and the interaction to be successful in
the communication sure no not using that would
be rude it would be bullying and when there's
no case at a cube of truth never within ab
where this has happened where we've bullied
people and said [ __ ] your beliefs that's
never happened it's just ridiculous to even
suggest that that has happened but you know
but it's not required that's what we're saying
it's not required it's it's yeah this this notion
that it is required is a new notion that's being
brought into a b it's never been required and um i
i think i know something that was brought up a
while ago was um people are suggesting that at the
start of the cube because we do a briefing right
when everyone's there getting ready to do the cube
somebody or maybe a few people suggested that
we do this like we go around and get people to
introduce themselves and choose their preferred
like announce their preferred pronoun and this
is something that brought was brought up to us
and that was our response because something like
that 100 takes away from what we're doing because
it's not necessary and it's irrelevant so to put
time aside 15 20 minutes for everyone to go around
and say my name is blah blah blah and this is my
preferred pronoun which is unnecessary because in
case we need to refer to you you let us know then
if we got it wrong you correct us that's fine we
can get on with our day um i know that that was
something that was brought up and i just wanted to
clarify that there are many other things that are
human-centric that we don't allocate our activism
our time to at the cubes to engaging in and so you
could use this same logic if you're claiming that
we are discriminatory towards those who have uh
again we've never even spoken about trans
people so i reject the notion of even
commenting on trans people people with gender
pronouns uh the same argument could be used
for uh not um honoring the custodians of the
land and saying something about like the original
custodians the land the aboriginals or or the
native americans depending on the of the region
that we're talking about here we don't do that at
the cubes either does that mean that we are also
racist or we're also colonial colonialists
or whatever the word is that's being tossed
around regarding that discrimination no of
course not because we're there for non-humans
and non-humans deserve a cause dedicated
to them that's what this comes down to
is if you think that we're being discriminatory
under that logic then you really just don't think
that animals deserve a cause solely dedicated to
them that's what we're disagreeing about yeah yeah
i guess i guess my my what i'm what i was trying
to get out of it here is try to get to clarify
what for 100 this which i think you have clarified
now is that like the the you know what you don't
want people you don't want to bring up um like
let's say identity politics into into cubing
you don't want it to become part of av you don't
want it to become part of an action or an event
um however if somebody has personal a personal
thing where they want to be referred to as
a certain pronoun or they've recently transitioned
that av is part of av policies to respect that
because not respecting that would be considered
bullying that's what i'm trying to clarify here
so this is you're making a distinction between the
two i also need to make the distinction here that
we're referring to sex if anything whenever the
word gender is being used in this conversation
we are not referring to anything other than
sex we are not referring our repeat to anything
other than sex and the conversation keeps getting
skewed by others to be referring to gender but uh
regarding trans issues or regarding this
whole thing uh with my comments on being
skeptical of gender pronouns it was regarding
sex that i was skeptical of this there aren't
more than two sexes in my opinion and i think
that people are entitled to have that opinion
trans people are transitioning between those
two sexes i think they have the right to do that
so i support the trans movement if that's what it
is right i have trans people that follow me that
support me that like me in the face of my comments
and the hate i receive getting called a transfer
does not waver these people i'm not trying to use
them as a token i'm just giving people context
because context is lost in our in our culture
and yeah that's all i have to say okay um
yeah yes i'm trying to wrap my head around it
and also i just sorry i was just taking care of
a troll as well i'm just asking annie to get rid
of a troll in the chat as i was also trying to get
that sword it seems like they're bothering people
so you obviously you make a separation between um
sex and gender which i think most well i mean
that's just that's that's scientific um there
is there is actually i think um some people would
argue including myself that there are three sexes
because there's intersex which is very rare but
it exists right it's it's when someone's born with
both or like like you know both um genetics or
whatever i don't know too much about it but i
know that it exists um and then yeah and then and
then you're drawing the line because because um
yeah because genders it's a new it is an ideology
the ideology gender ideology is new it is new
if anyone's upset about this then i'm not sorry
because you need to do some research on this and
how realize how gender ideology is a very recent
thing and it hasn't been put through the rigorous
testing that most other psychological and science
scientific you know concepts have you know about
humans have been through so it's not something
that should be accepted um just because it's big
and because it's being pushed but at the same time
for good or for bad there are people out there who
uh yeah like specifically it is it is very much
intertwined with trends with the trans issues
which is why it keeps coming up and this you
didn't you said earlier i don't understand why
people keep saying it's about trans it's because
i feel i feel personally i don't tell me if i'm
wrong i feel like that that um i wouldn't say
popularity but the the more exposure let's say
the more awareness of trends and what it means
to be trans has also come tied in with gender
and and gender identity yeah because yeah confuse
the issue though i think deliberately they have to
use the two now it's like all mixed in but
it doesn't need to be because when we're
talking about gender pronouns and gender
we're talking about gender roles and like
you can you can be a female like you can be
born a female in a female body but you may
not necessarily feel like you are fitting into
that you know that i don't know mindset or that
gender role and that's totally fine but that's
not what we're talking about when we're talking
about like someone transitioning you're talking
about them changing their their body and that's
the sex it's like when you go to the doctor they
they care about knowing your birth sex because
you know the doctor needs about your body and your
biology so that's why sex and gender are different
and if anyone wants to confuse the two that's
just not gonna you know that's fine but that's
that's just not the reality of it they're they're
completely separate uh and my trans um supporters
tell me this and and i agree with them convoluting
conflating gender politics uh the gender pronoun
issue in society that's been brought up uh with
the trans movement and struggle of trans people
is actually diminishing them as victims of their
struggle so it takes away from what they're really
dealing with and uh they're not struggling
with gender pronouns necessarily like the
the struggles are different
they're they're struggling
with uh with just being accepted as a trans
person and that's a different discussion
completely to what we're discussing here this is
what they tell me and i agree with them and uh
it's disrespectful to the trans movement to just
attach all these other things to it and say that's
a trans issue too yeah if you care about the trans
movement then you wouldn't do that i understand so
yeah there's a distinction between just wanting
to identify as one of the limitless genders and
actually suffering from gender dysphoria and and
changing your sex and wanting to be referred to
as a different pronoun because it it validates who
you are and it's something that you have struggled
through yes you're drawing there's a distinction
between the two basically is what you're saying
right there absolutely is and trans people
around the world feel diminished because of this
this incessant um obsessive need to link it to
everything else and they've already finished on
top okay but it's but although although you hold
this belief and obviously av operates on this um
not belief i wouldn't say but let's say opinion
and the av operates also on this opinion like that
av will not accept um people bringing
in ideologies um without let's say
like obviously trans trend the trans movement
isn't an ideology um not for them not for the
people who are actually uh you know suffering from
gender dysphoria anyway although there are people
who are calling themselves trans who are actually
not don't have gender dysphoria then that's an
ideology i would say that's different that's a
political um ideology or or some i don't know
ideology of some sort um but unfortunately i would
say it is it is difficult to actually determine
who is who right and and who is for real and who
is doing this because they genuinely you know are
a trans person and who is doing this because they
have they want to get on board with an ideology
and and kind of i don't know be different um i
guess how does av how does it how is av going
to operate with that because i know that you like
you've just said you'll you accept people who have
uh and you accept and will respect people
who are genuinely you know are trans or or
whatever if they have whatever condition the av
will respect them and people will be booted if
they don't respect them but then also in the same
breath you're saying that the political ideology
is not actually welcome and so if somebody isn't
actually trans and they are just identifying as
someone else because it's something they want
to do so how is av going to actually how would
you operate with these two individuals let's say
being around how are you going to determine who
who should be respected and and you know should
be dealt with in a very in a respectful way
and who should actually be told no don't
bring your ideologies here leave it at home
well everyone everyone everyone needs to be
respected okay everyone including yeah that's
the answer everyone needs to be respected so i
mean uh everyone is entitled to their opinions
but no one is entitled to use their to weaponize
their opinions against others and that's my
most accurate answer to that okay sure everyone
is respected for their opinions and their right to
have an opinion no one has a right to weaponize
their opinion against others in any way and so
that's it i mean you know where do we draw
the line with human stuff as well because
we allow people who are disabled to come
to our cubes and rock a wheelchair in the
cube we've had so many people in wheelchairs
in our cubes around the world we don't say
we don't you know we welcome these people i don't
know why i'm using that as a point i guess it's
just of course we welcome different uh struggles
and we accommodate different struggles within nav
but only as far as getting the job done is
required because we're there for the animals and
that just needs to be respected
also everyone needs to be respected
for the mission when we're at the cube but
i think we should move on now to the next
subject all right all right okay can
i close off of the bottom line and
bottom line yes or no question and then
we'll move on is that all right with you
but it's bottom line yes or no then so what
i'm understanding is that someone comes to the
cube they request to be called a certain thing
and people in the cubes people the organizers
are requested to respect that and if they get it
wrong by accident no worries don't do it again
if you get it wrong on purpose you're being
disrespectful and you'll be you'll be if it
comes up you will be told either told off or or i
don't know warned and saying that that's bullying
am i right is that correct is that if i understood
this correctly or is there something i've missed
um sorry i sorry i just kind of zoned out for a
bit so you said right somebody got it wrong by
accident no worries obviously what are we gonna
do um and then if they did it on purpose they're
gonna get kicked out is that always not kicked
out whatever it may be they'd be either warned
or if it's been multiple times let's say you
would you you would take a further action if
it's if it's becoming a habit you know if it's
something they've done more than once for example
yeah um yeah basically but like what i was saying
earlier if somebody feels that strongly about
it that they're not willing to because they
feel like they're accepting that ideology
by referring to um say you showed up at a
cube and you want to be referred to as she
and like i just can't accept that then in that
case they could refer to you with your name
and if they're not willing to do that then yes
that would be an issue because then that person
buying this thing on not wanting to refer to
you as whatever then that that person is taking
away from the event in the queue because they're
good yeah they're making good about anything else
yeah they make yeah okay but i think that yeah
that seems reasonable to me but i'm i'm i guess
it's not good enough for everyone for a lot of
people but i i feel like it's reasonable i just
wanted to clarify it before we moved on though
yeah when we move on i just want to say one more
time like this has literally never happened in
our personal experience has never happened and i
haven't heard of a specific um event where this
was the issue and this this was brought up and
somebody you know had an issue with referring to
someone else with their preferred name or pronouns
i just want to say how uncommon this is but yeah
i guess it's just about future proofing because
this is the world we're in um now you know uh
it's it's i don't think it's a bad world that
we're in i think it's good i think uh that's why
i wanted to really get into it because i i am 100
certain that as as we go into the future this
is going to become more and more and more common
and not just in av in other organizations
like you know jobs like people working in
offices and stuff like that this is going to
start becoming more and more common because
people you know in general people don't like
change um in general uh so you're gonna have to i
think we i feel we hope we all have to expect that
we're gonna be some people out there who are gonna
cause problems on both sides of this you know not
only on the people rejecting the idea side but
also the people demanding they be referred to as
a certain thing it's gonna oh it's only going to
become more prevalent i guess that's why i feel
like it's an important topic to get into well
again like you know yeah just cap this off with a
black and white answer and then sure you know it's
it works the other way as well like no bullying
will be allowed but also if you're bullying others
to believe what you believe at the cube that's not
a lot either if you're not required to hand it to
to give us your gender in that interaction and
you're forcing it anyways that's an issue yeah
that's a problem because that's not that's not
productive communication and uh and teamwork
when the goal is supposed to be non-human
animal rights yeah it goes both ways yeah
sure just but basically just just respect each
other it's the bottom line earlier the answer to
it is everyone will be respected
that's the rule all right got it
all right cool cool let's uh we're going from
one to another i guess uh in terms of this i
think these might be a little bit easier to
get into though because there's just some
there's a few more like more direct accusations
that came through however they didn't really come
through with any kind of backing but i wanted
to put them to you as like a topic of like why
do you think people are saying this right and you
can tell me why you think people are saying this
so there's been accusations of of of racism
as well against av as an organization and also
i'm sorry paul but it tends to be coming at
you most of the time um with these things the
sal seems to get off the hook um but um this
racism apparently av is racist and apparently
paul is racist and i think some of this did
come from the the blm post um but that was
an av thing that wasn't necessarily a poll
thing why why do you think people are coming
at you and and making accusations that you
are a racist individually paul or not av
we'll deal with av in a second but why do you
think it's coming for you that people say this
who isn't called a racist in 2020
i'm suss on anyone not being
called a racist in 2020
uh why is i mean i'm answering quantum physics in
that question i don't know the answer it's like
uh yeah i don't know why why humans
the way they are i i just i really
i don't know it's uh i i actually haven't ever
heard anyone directly call me a racist because
of the blm poet like me personally yeah no no
that's that's like an av thing i think it's
a general thing yeah i mean we have been called
a racist both of us not over that post though but
yeah i don't know why i'm not sure why actually
i'd like to see evidence your honor the evidence
please yeah i think there was there was there was
a post i'm just remembering now i think that it
could have i don't know contributed to it i
think where you would you were talking to a
you were outreaching a black guy and you said some
things about you know you defended the animals
um and i think some people found it to be
somehow racist because of the words you used
and do you remember that at all like yes black
guy was a black girl so you misgendered her
you should really be ashamed of
yourself let's cancel david immediately
trust me trust me out of this video this is not
going to be the thing that gets taken there's
things we've said already that
i've as they came out of my mouth
i was like yeah that's going to be that's
going to be screenshotted that's going to
be all over the place soon so no don't worry
we're already that boat was sailed we're done
um so if you watch the video guys she was
making a point to me that she doesn't need
to take animal rights seriously especially
even if she is the oppressor in this scenario
as a non-vegan because black people are oppressed
that was her argument that she put to me
and she even said something to the effect that
speciesism doesn't apply to me and my people and
i said it applies to anybody who oppresses animals
who isn't vegan uh she carried on and i felt it
was only right to make the point that animals are
the most oppressed group of beings on the planet
it felt to me the most appropriate thing to say at
that time because i speak on behalf of the animals
if i was in their position that's
exactly what i would want to be
said in that moment so that that
person had the correct perspective
uh whether they accept the truth is not my uh i
don't i don't have any uh skin in that game my
mission is to tell the truth on behalf of the
victims because it's the least that we can do so
that's what i said and that was that was uh what
people have called me racist over so that was like
i mean it's let's let's let's be like that's not [
__ ] here it's definitely something that would be
considered to be like insensitive but but that's
not your the goal isn't to be sensitive um a lot
you know it's i don't think being insensitive is
necessarily something negative i think sometimes
it needs to be um like that but but how is that
translating to racism like if somebody said paul
you're [ __ ] insensitive i i wouldn't i don't
think i'd even bring that up because it's like
well yeah that's obvious like you you
know your outreach videos tend to be
towards the side of insensitivity and more towards
the side of like straight direct like you're going
to get the message whether it pisses you off or
not right if you're being sensitive you would
dress it up and be nice but you're not being and
that's not something to criticize in my opinion
or it is whatever but that's not the point here
the point is racism so how does that translate to
racism how do you think someone gets it from
that video that that's you somehow you know
disrespecting somebody because of their ethnicity
just because of her skin color right well no no
again no it's not just well it's not just that you
are speaking to a white woman would would you get
no of course not but it's not just that it's
also the fact what people are overlooking here
is if if we are going to entertain the notion
that there is insensitivity at play here
people are overlooking the fact that she
was being incredibly insensitive to the
animal victims that she is an oppressor of
directly responsible for victimizing herself
and so that's where it started that's where the
context of all of this began i was responding
to her not by saying [ __ ] black people and [ __
] black rights but by saying animals are the most
oppressed group of beings on the planet if me
pointing out a fact is insensitive while she's
literally saying [ __ ] the animals and [ __ ]
their rights well i guess you need to ask yourself
which like what does it take for you to see
injustice for what it is especially when it's
to the degree that it is he in this case with the
animals when they're subjected to the most brutal
violence that has ever been carried out on any
group of beings ever what does it take for people
to to to just literally just acknowledge them and
to acknowledge the fact that they are subjected
to oppression to the extent that they
are subjected to that oppression and for
simply just simply for people to simply say
that for people to simply speak about that
if that's offensive we have no hope as a species
evolving and developing into better ways of
of living on this planet and uh with truly
addressing injustice and oppression on this
planet it's never going to happen unless we
change the way we think around things like this
yeah i i i think honestly my opinion on
this is like to to label that as racism
is is offensive um to it's offensive because
it's not even offensive it's it's harmful
because it confuses what actual racism is right
how how can you call like and this is this
when you really lay it out like this
right you've got two people of color
you're not white so two people of color
having a conversation about the animals
and one of the people says that you know the
reality about the animals and somehow that
person is racist it's just such a strange thing to
call racism over and it completely takes away the
meaning of the word and i've said this before
people get really upset about it that the more
you use the word racist sexist transphobe the more
difficult it becomes to actually identify racists
sexists and transphobes and and i think nowadays
we're in a position where it's like you said who
hasn't been called a racist um or a transphobe or
a sexist in 2020 practically anyone who has dared
to even question the narrative has been called
one of those things it's either you you do what
you're told and you say what you're supposed
to say or that's what you get branded with
do you know how harmful that is to the people who
actually suffer from sexism racism and transphobia
the fact that you know that label is so used so
flippantly if you could you could say that for
every every other label that is thrown around
um to to to to try and cancel others when uh
when faceless whether it's the term fascist
or or sexist or racist or or whatever it is
it takes these people are supposed to care about
these injustices when they're literally spinning
in the faces of the victims that are subjected
by those injustices when they do that definitely
and move it on to the av racism claim the blm
post that was the uh the center of apparent
uh racism you know this is the uh apparently that
post was in itself racist and and those it's gone
now obviously but for those who didn't see it it
was the image the famous image that went around
of a blm activist a black man holding a pig's
head by the ears a severed pig's head by the ears
to protest against police brutality a navy av put
out a an image with the caption and that was it
ended up causing so much controversy and claims
of racism and all these things and it and it was
removed in the end right so like tell us the i
know you've done it before again i'm sorry you
have to keep repeating yourself but you know we
are we're aiming to get through everything today
but tell us the story behind that then and and you
know if you think that was racist as well and the
reasons you removed it so it wasn't removed um
it wasn't removed you know as a result of like
so just to clarify it's still up on our instagram
it's only been removed on facebook because
we stupidly took i want to say take the bet we
took the bait i don't know if that's the proper
term to use here but whatever with regards to
what the donor was demanding of us at the time
throughout the whole debacle that we went through
with the donor and uh so we made a decision
to remove that post only because this
donor was learning to remove our funding um
and it was it was the only thing that
we were willing to consider doing
uh out of all the demands that they gave
us we completely rejected the notion of
a board of directors and the other things we we
really push back on and we we try to be as as
charitable and open to these demands as possible
which is why we deleted that post as a decision
we made and at this point we had deleted it
probably a month and a half or two months
after the post was made so at that point it had
it had seen most of its traction you know so
uh i just want to clarify it wasn't removed
after getting heat from people in the comments
section or anything like that it was uh it
was a post that we believe needs to happen
it's just the way that we communicated in
that post that we felt we could improve
on and we have already addressed this within
the organization because recently we saw the
same thing happening at another protest
in spain and we made a post about that uh
it didn't you know it didn't get as much traction
but um you know so there's something to be said
about being direct about these things but
it's unpopular we share a lot of unpopular
opinions that's what we do because the
truth is unpopular at the best of times
uh and yeah and uh we are committed to speak up
against animal oppression wherever we see it so
if it's been if it's being paraded on the
on the main stage on in the mainstream on
the news every around the world as a appropriate
and acceptable way of addressing human um centric
injustices you know to hold decapitated heads
up to to say [ __ ] the police uh then we have
a responsibility to say something about that
um no oppression is acceptable ever no one
has the right to oppress anyone else ever in any
situation ever and uh and that's supposed to be
the ethos behind these protests that were
occurring this year and that's our ethos so
we should be seeing eye to eye but uh yeah that's
really our responsibility to do that but yeah we
remove that post um as a result of the donor and
we we regret that decision i don't know how else
to say it but it's i mean we we still have it on
instagram it's not being removed from instagram so
from that what you will sure sure so that's yeah
it clarifies a lot and and just to clarify here
like you don't you don't believe that post was
racist right no like what we said it could have
been communicated better um and that's why before
we removed it we actually went in and edited the
post a little bit so we changed the wording
in certain parts um so that there was more
empathy or you know it didn't come across as
insensitive like you said but absolutely no
it wasn't yes so i think i think that's that's a
a wider issue really isn't it insensitivity versus
uh versus racism or or whatever ism you want to
attach it's uh it's not bigoted to be insensitive
um it's some people are i don't know harsher than
others and i think um on a personal level i think
i think that's where a lot of the criticisms and
accusations come from with av i don't think it's
uh i think it is that our movement is quite a
sensitive movement with very sensitive people and
av isn't isn't very sensitive and that's that's
not i don't mean that as a criticism at all i mean
that as in some people don't like that and that's
that's you know that's where we get a lot of
a lot of people who come up and speak up about
it whereas if you look at an organization like
save for example they're the complete opposite
side they're extremely sensitive and so they
attract a lot of people who are uh you know also
extremely sensitive which happens to be the vast
majority of of the animal rights movement and the
vegan movement people tend to be very sensitive
in these groups so you know i can see i can see
where the accusations come flying in from but um
i think if they were accusing you of insensitivity
and and being too mean i think that would
probably be not as nowhere near as harmful as
throwing the word racist at every turn you know
that's my observation anyway that's
what i'm observing from the outside
and this kind of track this this continues
really with the social media people have
been upset by your social media quite a lot and i
know some of these examples are going to be very
easy to discuss but we'll start off with the most
difficult one just to uh kick it off with this um
i want to discuss the whole uh the whole hitler
thing and george because a few people asked me
about this they asked me about george they asked
me about this post this this uh which obviously
i know you removed it um but they kind of
want to know how it got to the point where
someone in the organization would think about
making a post a comment like that and kind of
what you guys think about it so if again for those
who don't know there was the um there was a post
made i believe it was it was avs page as well
wasn't it on facebook it was a comment um where
the comment was talking about hitler and it was
comparing hitler and the it was saying basically
out of context here by the way completely out
of context and i've not got the screenshot so
i'm not going to put it up but out of context
it was making a comparison and saying that the
holocaust that hitler did had more justification
than the holocaust of the animals i'm paraphrasing
here it was put into a better context than
that but that's that was the takeaway message
that it was it had more justification because a
book was written about it practically or have i
missed a big point there but either way that
seemed to be the takeaway point from it um
out of context and that was obviously posted by i
believe george in the in the organization on as av
so like what happened with this have i got
that wrong have people got that wrong and yeah
he's not saying that he wasn't saying
like legitimate justifications were
were afoot in those cases he was saying that more
reasons were provided by hitler and his regime
to the public then then the re then then what
non-vegans offer to the public regarding the
injustice that they're involved in that's what he
was saying but the way that he said it lacked eq
you got to have iq george is a smart guy but you
got to have eq2 you got to read the room and not
be an idiot about how you communicate emotionally
uh so that's the thing it wasn't clear enough
the communication we identified as something
that needs to be improved and that's why we
addressed the whole blm post to begin with uh the
way that we did it was about the communication
and we still feel justified in
addressing what we addressed
and we will continue to do so but um i think
you know sometimes yeah the issue there was um
sometimes there is bias that's brought into
the work that people are doing within ab
they bring their own biases whether they're
political or otherwise in the way they communicate
and people need to remember if they're working
with av they're representing ap just like
with any other org or group that they're
working with and when you're representing us
we don't want that and you know he also
did admit to doing this himself um so
it's not just an opinion that we had this was
really happening and uh that was the issue that
you're pointing out david sure and and george and
another individual they were removed from the team
was was that because of this specific example or
was there another reason that these individuals
were removed there was another question somebody
asked that was one of the comments but there were
other comments left um by george but also it was
the conversations we had in private with them
about the issue i believe the comments were
about um denying that systemic oppression exists
and how that comment was left by our social media
members without them running it by us and that's
not something that um just didn't align with us
or av or other team members so that's why we had
to have private conversations to clarify this and
that and during those conversations we realized
that we're just not aligned and it was just not
possible at that point to have them on the team
yeah just to clarify yeah because it might be
confused by people in what we're saying here uh
that like gemma and george were like fired on
the same premise they weren't removed from ab
on the same premise there was a different uh
scenario for those both individuals like we
a different decision process for both
those individuals there were different
things that occurred with george as well it
wasn't just one thing it wasn't one comment
or one point multiple comments and then
multiple conversations that we were having that
made it clear that yeah but it was different
and it wasn't just this no i was like another
example was about how because the comment that
you just read out i didn't remember that one
but i know there was another one going around
what our team said systemic oppression doesn't
exist in the west or something like that which
we were getting lots of messages about and so i
do remember that very clearly right there
were i think there were multiple things
otherwise we wouldn't just ask someone to leave
the team over one comment especially someone who
was an asset to the organization george was
a prized member of the team whom i really
liked working with and i thought that he was a
great member so it's ridiculous that we would
um yeah it's tough to be in this position
um you know that's the thing also like
it sucks to have to fire someone like george
yeah i just want to add because it's okay to have
your own political views your religious
views but if you are commenting as a v
as a part of the team and then those views are
coming through your comments and your messages
then that's not okay because within the team
like i said we have over 20 people or something
and we all have different views and then we have
our own political views or our own views on god
or religion or whatever but you never see us
commenting about it when we're commenting as a
v because av is supposed to represent something
that is just about the animal so regardless of
your views you can be a part of that and that
was the issue that it was just not possible to
to have that with those individuals and people
don't seem to be wanting to work with us to create
the most conducive organization
that is dedicated to the animals
people don't seem to be working with us to
achieve this we seem to be dedicated to it and
everyone seems to be pushing back and pushing
back and pushing back we are open to ideas we
want to see how we can help other like other
things here but we have like assa was saying
we have other people in the organization who have
even stronger political views than george do than
george does even stronger political views than
than george does think i mean think about that
you know yeah sure and they don't they don't ever
they never let their advices come through their
work so that's but again when it's not to focus on
just one point here because it wasn't just one a
one-dimensional decision it was multi-dimensional
and that that's also kind of entwined with the uh
intertwined the with another kind of criticism i
had about the comments like uh there were i don't
know if there still are i haven't seen any since
this but there were quite a lot of let's say rude
comments um on on the av social media let's say
like sometimes i think i even saw one someone
said you know shut the [ __ ] up like stfu in
a comment i personally saw that myself at one
point and i was like who the [ __ ] said that you
know that was quite a surprise for me to see um
you know is this something that you guys stand
behind are you are you okay with like you know
going out and telling people like if they're being
you know if they're acting silly or if they're
being silly is that is that with your social media
team are they like you know go and do that or was
this some bad actors in the team that are now
not doing that you know how has that changed i
haven't seen it since you know it seems like when
the whole thing happened with george um it seemed
after that that social media has been direct and
but there's not been any of this like shut up and
you know and the rude comments seem to have almost
stopped so it was am i right in assuming that
that was linked or or is this something you've
changed inside internally and now it's different
well it's not good it's not it's it's not
the george it's not that george was just
cursing people out using our account um i think we
need to see like specific examples of where this
has happened for us to comment more specifically
about those things but generally we don't just
curse people out no we don't but we do speak
in a real way and so sometimes you might see
us calling someone a dick because they're acting
like a dick and it's and it won't be without us
communicating effectively you know we're not
just calling them a dick and if you if you just
don't be a dick yourself and just conclude it that
way when you know there's more context involved
here if you read the entire comment usually you
can see us responding with an educated a response
that educates the viewer that the reader and
we're not just telling them to [ __ ] off or
to shut the [ __ ] up or whatever it is you know
that's not that's not what we do we're we're out
to edify people hold them accountable when you
hold people accountable sometimes you have to
be real with them and you have to pull them out
and say you're being a dick when they're being do
sure and and um this links in with the the
the vegetarian drama let's let's call it
so this is something that av does focus on quite
a lot and nasal i know you actually made a posted
a video on this relatively recently about
about uh vegetarians um that's a that's a
another big criticism that the criticism
being that av is av attacks vegetarians
that's the criticism like that that's come up a
lot actually and i've seen that not only in my own
you know me asking people for questions
but also when you're just scrolling and
if you're in reddit or something like that one
of the common things that comes up is like av
is counterproductive because they attack
vegetarians um i think i already know how
you're gonna answer this but um maybe it's a
bit of an easier one to deal with what do you
respond to these people who get upset about
that and say you're attacking vegetarians
which vegetarian we've never
targeted a specific vegetarian
we attack vegetarianism and i think
that vegetarianism is the single
greatest cancer in the animal rights
movement other than vegans themselves
being number one actually vegans vegans are number
one the number one threat to the animal rights
movement uh vegetarians are operating in society
under this idea this image of being on the side
of the animals to be there they're portraying
themselves as animal people quote unquote right
and whenever they speak to vegans generally
speaking of course majority of these individuals
are pompous and they tell you that you don't
need to talk to them because they're already
vegetarian is the way that they would frame
it i'm already vegetarian so these people
on paper in terms of the facts are
doing exactly as much as someone whose
paleo is doing for the animals because they
don't consume dairy vegetarians don't consume
flesh dairy is considered more cruel to cows than
eating their flesh is the dairy industry we as
animal rights activists tend to say this stuff so
it's not just me saying that so if that's the case
paleo people are more in alignment with us than
vegetarians are but that logic is flawed so
it's insane that they would get a pass for being
portrayed as animal people and as long as they
continue to parade and act like they are animal
people the longer it will take to get vegetarians
to become vegan and the more we make a mockery of
the real animal rights message for everybody else
and the longer the vegans cuddle vegetarians
and again i'm not talking about any specific
vegetarian talking about vegetarianism
the longer we cuddle vegetarianism
the longer it will take for animal rights
to be taken seriously in the public eye
i think i can't remember which one of you said
it or if it actually was one of you but um there
was a quote that vegetarians are contributing to
one less form of animal abuse than a meat-eater
they contribute to every other form of
animal abuse it's just not just not meat
just not flesh and that that was quite for me
that was very powerful and i feel like that
that was that was a quote that was a sentence that
really brought it home to me that actually yeah
we we we should be targeting vegetarianism
as you know just the same as we would target
anyone else you know who's a non-vegan because
it's just it's just there's only one between
them even more yeah even more because non-vegans
don't say you don't need to talk to me unknown
they know that they need that's the correct
conversation to have with them they know that
they're culpable right it's the same as someone
who's non-vegan who doesn't support animal testing
they never buy cosmetics that are tested on
on animals i mean they don't support one form
of animal injustice yeah there are many numbers
they don't claim that claim to be exempt from the
message regarding meat dairy and eggs vegetarians
do claim to be exempt from hearing that
yeah it's just very counterproductive to separate
like vegetarians and the rest of non-vegans
because i see that a lot from vegans and animal
rights activists they think that they should get
a different treatment but really vegetarians
are just non-vegan so let's not separate them
the reason why we focus on it is because we want
to change their mentality it's not because there
is any difference you know we're not like singling
them out it's the same it's just non-vegans
it's just clarifying the message on behalf of
the animals okay perfect yeah i yeah this for
me was an easy topic because i'm i also uh focus
on vegetarians for the same reasons um i think i
think it's something our movement really needs to
needs to shape people need to shake their head on
this and just realize that these vegetarians
they're not helping us they're not our allies
um understanding veganism doesn't help anyone like
oh i understand you or i'm supportive of you i'm
a vegetarian it doesn't mean [ __ ] and i think
the more we start to realize that the better and
the easier things are going to be in the long
term um so a style actually i have a specific
topic for you and this was this was actually only
brought up yesterday um so that's why i don't know
if you've got chance to um yeah i'll i'll i'll
explain it now so basically the impossible burger
all right uh you did your video when when was
it earlier this year i don't know if you've
thought about it since then but um i think
it's been like two years now is it two years
wow okay i don't know i watched it only recently
anyway so i don't know if you've had a chance to
catch up on on that and or if you still think the
same but um somebody brought this up and they're
very passionate about it and they wanted to uh
discuss this um apparently according to them
again don't know if this is true or not a lot of
people left or at least stopped going to cubes or
even some chapters maybe even closed over
a disagreement about the impossible burger
and the video that you made i watched the video
obviously i watched the video i i only watched
it yesterday so it's fresh in my mind um and your
position's on the impossible burger and i you know
went through it and what what how do
you respond to people who who have this
like they don't believe that av is abolitionist
because of you being the founder holding the view
that you hold that uh an impossible burger um is
it's it's vegan because they tested on animals um
i'll i'll explain the video if you want really
quickly for anyone that's watching real quick i
watched it yesterday so it's really fresh in the
video assal basically makes the position makes
the claim i don't know takes the position that
practically every single e number and additive
has been tested on animals at one point so pretty
much every vegan product you would buy has has
something in it that has been tested on animals
but not by the company that you're buying it from
uh the impossible burger and possible foods did
the testing themselves and but the product now
that's in the store technically hasn't been tested
on it's the product that the one thing that was in
it was previously tested so therefore it's in the
same category as another item that you would buy
um they're both been tested at some point um
and if you take issue with the impossible burger
then how long does it have to be before we don't
take issue with it anymore and it becomes in the
same category as the other products that have
once tested on animals that's the position that
a cell takes so if anyone's got a question about
that either superchat it or save it for later
but yeah how do you how would you
respond to someone now who says right
that that makes av non-abolitionist because
av is supporting a product that was tested
on animals and they take the position that
because impossible foods did the testing
and they have not actually said they wouldn't test
the gain so impossible have said they will test
again if they feel that they they say need to but
let's be honest we don't need that burger right um
so they say they would do it again and some
people are saying because of that the av
is not abolitionist and that's why they don't
want to work with av anymore how do you what
do you think of that well i just think that
to be consistent um exactly what you said if
we are consuming products that at one time in the
past they were tested or an ingredient was tested
we also use many products that um again were
either tested or they are produced by a company
that is not vegan and you know like we can just
keep going down this rabbit hole but ultimately to
be consistent with the values that we have i think
it's okay to say that if you're vegan and you
eat the impossible burger you're not suddenly not
vegan that's literally what i was saying i wasn't
promoting it necessarily but i was saying um the
impossible burger is as vegan as the beyond burger
because one of the things that i don't think i
mentioned in that video and i think it's something
that i actually learned after doing that video was
that when they were working on the beyond burger
they were buying burgers made of cow flesh
and they were testing them or they were maybe
just having a tasting session or whatever
to get the texture or the flavors right so
i don't see any difference between the two um
in one scenario cows are being murdered for the
burgers and in the other scenario mice are being
murdered because they're being tested on so i just
see them exactly the same they're just different
animals that are being used in the process but
i just think to be consistent you either have to
say i don't use anything that was ever tested or
is ever coming from a company that uses animals or
uses animal testing or you're just going to have
to accept that we do live in a non-vegan world and
as much as possible yes sure you can avoid it but
i just don't see the difference between like i
said that product and other products that we're
using um like the beyond virgo which nobody
has ever taken an issue with i haven't seen it
and if i can just add to this argument that
we as an organization have made essentially
regarding this topic uh the only arguments i've
ever heard from those who are trying to damn us
by uh saying that we're not like we're not we're
not abolitionists because we hold this position
the only argument i see coming from these
people is an argument for how impossible
foods as a company is not vegan to which we
totally agree with the company is not vegan
the product itself however is vegan and that's why
ourselves made the distinction between this and
any other company that sells a vegan product
a non-vegan company selling a vegan product
has always been a product that vegans consume and
are still considered to be vegan when they consume
it uh and we don't you know when you said we
don't we don't need the impossible burger that the
same could be said for every other product that
exists on the shelf so where do you draw the line
and how do we make veganism practical for people
by saying you can only support vegan companies
if you're only supporting vegan companies in
this modern world we live in i don't think
veganism is possible that's it's actually i think
an irresponsible message if we care about animal
liberation yeah so there's two points i'd like
to push on a little bit further with this um
one of them being that what do you think about
this is this these are this is internal okay
i'm with you and i think that i just want
to put this point away actually that this
will not in my opinion what we are discussing
here is the message we put out to the public
because i don't believe that that's it's it's
going to be in any way uh beneficial for us to
slam the impossible burger to the non-vegan public
right that doesn't make any sense um whatever they
tested it on animals yeah it's [ __ ] but um
it's making tracks with non-vegans and it's it's
i don't know it's it's i feel like it's more
of an internal thing that that we discuss in
this like as part of the animal rights movement
should this be an accepted thing like into the
movement or into veganism should this burger
be accepted should these products be accepted
i feel like that's what we're discussing more
than a public statement um and that being said
so a company like i mean that's where i
stand on it anyway that's why i don't really
i don't want to get into like should we
talk about it you know pushing it to the
public or not i don't really think advertising
vegan consumerism is i don't really agree with
that anyway i'm not posting about subways
vegan option or mcdonald's vegan options
has never done yeah no i know that's yeah i think
we're on the same page with that that's why i
just i think we can just kind of go on because
i don't i don't like that i see others doing it
i'm like okay cool but it doesn't sit right for
me to promote these massive monster companies uh
it doesn't feel right um but but if people do it
that's their call right it's not for me my point
i was going to make though with this is that so
for example quorn is a massive company in the uk
i don't know if they're in australia too but they
uh they're one of the oh cool so like the og like
um fake meat mock meat companies and they they
have this thing called microprotein and that was
tested on animals when they first released it but
the pushback was so intense and from vegetarians
that they had to like reconvene and they released
a statement where basically the uh i think it was
the ceo i can't remember it's on their website
right now um he basically says that he he regrets
it that he wishes that he did it differently
or she i can't remember if it's a guy or a girl
and they said they will never test on animals ever
again this company will never do it ever again
and we totally listen to your feedback and it's
done um versus unfortunately the impossible burger
impossible foods and i think beyond
foods as well i think beyond me also
say this they're saying the opposite like
they're saying they're going to continue to test
for me and for many i think that's where they
draw the line and say wait a minute okay testing
once is one thing testing once and saying yeah we
see you're pissed off and we know it's wrong but
we're going to do it again if we if we want to
they they draw a distinction between these two
companies and one being like okay we'll support
this one and the other one they say no we're not
going to support them because they're pro with
a section you know where do you stand on on that
comparison that logic doesn't work that logic does
not work because corn is still selling products
with cheese and egg in it um or at least egg yeah
they have a vegetarian range and a vegan brain
so yeah okay they're against animal testing
they're still not a vegan company however yeah in
exactly the same way that impossible foods is not
a vegan company so sure but comparison then yeah
yeah well no it's just people are getting
angry about what they choose to be angry about
yeah i think it's about being consistent
that's a great point because they're not
a vegan company and the whole range is not
vegan so why are we only taking issue with
animal testing and not what happens to
the animals in the dairy egg industry
sure sure it's about that's my bad that's a
bad comparison with corn um i guess what i
was trying to get at is is uh we've supported
a company that is going to say that they're
going to continue to test on animals but is
producing um plant-based burgers like is is
there no is is there no ethical consideration to
be hard here i guess is what i'm trying to say
of course come on man of course there it is of
course of course we need to ask impossible foods
to cut the [ __ ] and stop testing on animals and
to be vegan but the point here is that expecting
them to be vegan before you buy their product
which is vegan stand alone in and of itself is
just a ridiculous uh standard to apply if you're
going to do it you have to be consistent and that
would make it impractical to be impractical to
be negan it would make it impossible to be vegan
and i don't mean to use that pun
but we're in an impossible situation
sure okay okay um yeah i think that's all i
wanted to ask about that i don't think there's
anything else i can go through do you have
anything to close on that with it being mainly
the questions targeted at you is there anything
else you'd like to say to people who are still
like dubious about this or unsure about this i
think that's it just the last point that you said
about um you know how they've they've basically
said they will test in the future and then coin
saying they will never do it again i just think i
personally on a personal level i don't take that
seriously anyway just because the ceo came out and
said something i don't take it either way i don't
take it as seriously as others actually forget
because i just think okay i'll just wait and see
in future if impossible keeps doing it
then i will not be supporting it anymore or
um at the same time i don't trust that
company that says we will never do it again
i just don't trust people like that because they
might do it and at the same time they are abusing
other animals anyway so that's why like somebody
just making a statement on their website is not
i don't take it that seriously no one no one
is protesting magnums the vegan magnums the
company whether they put out a statement or not
uh are saying in their actions that they do not
reject animal abuse that they will continue to
condone it and sell products and make money off
the backs of animals because just look at the
rest of their range same could be said about
cliff bars same could be said about literally
every other product that we as vegans consume
and these companies that they come from are not
vegan companies so it's just asinine to expect
this uh from impossible like just because you eat
their burger it doesn't mean you condone them as a
company if that's the case you're condoning every
company you ever purchase anything from but you're
really just condoning that product you're really
just buying a product yeah and then to people
that take that position and some people do take
that position that by buying the product you're
in the company um and um and it's like you said
i think it's practically impossible uh to do that
but then they would argue that okay but it's not
it's practically impossible but then surely that
that's that's the same as saying it's practically
impossible to be vegan but we're just doing
the best we can and we're going to make extra
efforts to not buy from companies that we know
are are really bad though what do you think
that would be an incorrect statement because
that would suggest a different definition
of veganism veganism is literally defined by
avoiding animal abuse as much as
practically possible it's not practical
to carry out veganism in the way that
it's being suggested in in all this stuff
it's just that's not practical we're not
even talking about a scenario where you have
two options in front of you one from a vegan
company and one is an impossible burger and
you have no other food options because you're on a
desert uh you're on a deserted island or something
that's not the scenario we're in here uh because
in that scenario obviously the better thing to do
would be to choose the product from the vegan
company um but it's not as black and white as this
okay cool all right we'll close that chat to it
we've got just two more topics left and then we'll
we'll go to a q a so um i don't know how many
people are left from the beginning but there were
a lot of questions coming in earlier and i'm not
prepared to go through the chat to find them so
if you have questions uh you're gonna have to
save them and type them again when we do a quick
q a um and as i said if you if you're planning
on asking questions keep it sensible or we just
won't answer it it's a waste of your time typing
it if you're gonna be stupid so just keep that in
mind um all right the last last two points then
just the first one i want to talk about this it's
linked to something we discussed earlier actually
about the the people complaining or claiming they
weren't getting funded you know like they weren't
getting the av fund or whatever and it links into
an overall problem of organizers in av getting
somehow feeling that they haven't been supported
or they feel like they haven't been supported
by you or they feel like they've been actually
had the opposite like some some ex-organizers
go out there and claim that they were actually
um i don't know what you would say you guys were
rude to them or they were treated badly by av
and that's why they left or or um they were booted
out or something you know i'm being generic here
in general because every time i've pushed for
more information on these claims i've had i've had
nothing right so i'm bringing it up as a general
topic and you don't need to answer it as if it's
like oh this one individual or something because
they never provided me any screenshots or anything
so i've got nothing to show you um but what why
are they doing this why do you think this this is
coming up from ex organizers where they're saying
i wasn't supported or i was treated badly um where
where is that coming from do you think there's any
truth to it you know what are your thoughts on it
no there's no truth to this because we um
we provide support for every
chapter for every organizer equally
right we've got all these different things and
procedures and systems in place that provide
support from us um to the regional organizers
we have a manager that manages the regional
organizers and then so all of the organizers have
the ability to reach out to us personally in their
chat at any moment if they need support if they
need advice if they need any kind of help and we
always help them and we provide support where
we can so to just leave and say that they felt
um like they were not supported or they were
treated badly it's just yeah we need to see
the evidence because it's easy to just make these
statements but where is it coming from again it's
just because people think okay i'm going to leave
av because all these people said paul is racist
and this and that and so now i'm going to just
jump on the bandwagon and say abe treated me badly
that's the only thing i can think
of there's no evidence right
i don't think it's much of a help to anybody
for us to comment on this any further than that
because there's no specific thing to that we're
responding to yeah i'm just trying to get it you
know i i agree with you i don't like bringing
this up because there's no i've got nothing to
show you know what i mean and i feel like i've had
multiple conversations i've had conversations i'll
be honest with you i've had conversations with
people that i would consider to be good friends
and i've had to be quite harsh and say look
either give me something here or you're full of
[ __ ] like i'm sorry and we've kind of like got
into an argument and just agreed to disagree on it
because they wouldn't give it to me because they
didn't have it and um so i've got to say i hold
i hold a bit of a bias on this because i've
experienced the [ __ ] first hand and it's it's
really disappointing to see and it kind of happens
to me as well obviously people say things about me
and i say okay great give me some evidence tell
me where i've said that and they disappear you
know um so i it's it's it's a it's a symptom
of a larger problem i think yeah um yeah yeah
for sure yeah and then the final the final
thing we'll go into then is actually about
the effectiveness of av so this is a good thing
or not just av but of animal rights activism but
the activism that we're doing so somebody
did message me and they told me um ask them
they started off with a shitty message they said
ask them why why the cube of truth doesn't work
so i was like okay what are you talking about they
said right look the number of animals being killed
is on the rise and um the challenge 22 sign ups
for last year i think it was last year was only 2
000 in the entire world so clearly it's not
working so i broke that down into two sections
and this is two things i want to go through like
one side of this is that obviously if the number
of animals being killed is increasing it's not
just av that's not working it's every single
activism group that's not working because clearly
you know save isn't working dxe isn't working
direct action isn't working hunt's tabs aren't
working nothing's working because the amount of
animals being killed is on the increase right
so that's that's a topic why is that happening
um you know what can we do about it as one topic
and the other topic is um why the um challenge the
vegan 22 av signups um they seem to be a lot
lower than what would be expected of a of you
know considering how much work goes in into the
cubes right so i think let's maybe start with the
challenge 22 one because that might be an easier
quicker one to go into and then we'll close on the
on the set on the other one so what with
the challenge 22 reporting um firstly is
that accurate like what's going on with that or
how is it only at 2 000 for like the whole year
nah first of all it's not accurate because many
people wouldn't use it also at some point we
stopped promoting it and using it anyway because
we realized that challenge 22 is now really
aligned with av in terms of how they promote
veganism and so we stopped promoting it and maybe
some organizers some volunteers are still using
that link when they arrest someone at a cube but
it's not being done the same way anyway i think
when did we start doing this when we when did we
stop using the link last year at least a year and
a half yeah wait it's it could even be up to two
years now but it's at least a year yeah i think it
was last year at some point we realized that we're
just not aligned we stopped using it and um even
when we were promoting it and it was on the card i
can average someone and i can say you know you can
go and sign up and use this link but that person
is not necessarily going to do it even if they
do decide that they want to be vegan so that's
why it's not a good measurement and we all the
way that we communicate animal rights to people
is so simple and easy to digest and with so much
personal individual accountability attached to it
that the why factor is is something we focus so
heavily on hammering into people that the how
factor is something we empower generally we
empower other the the bystander to take on within
their accountability it's their responsibility
to be to be to you know properly plan how they're
going to be vegan by simply using google and we
we sometimes say exactly that you know google is
all you really need to be to be vegan uh we want
it to be simple for people we don't want to make
it sound like you need to be in a 22-day program
when that's not even true you don't the fact is
you do not need that is it helpful for some people
but not for everyone and that's not the message
that we believe is important we need to clarify
it further by saying all that's needed is the
why factor the how you will figure out if there
were vegans 50 years ago you can be vegan now
absolutely okay i think i think that's i'll give
you my personal opinion on that as well because
i think that's fair um and i think i don't know
to gauge the success or or failure by how many
challenge 22 sign-ups seems a little bit there
are seems a bit short-sighted uh considering
that you know you see conversations with someone
like you know hudson for example he was a great
activist and some of his conversations just you
blow someone's mind you know and do they sign up
for vegan 22 maybe not but but their mind has been
blown like you know you can't undo that like maybe
they don't do vegan 22 but the idea that they
could potentially go vegan is still is still there
you know they've definitely made some connections
so i think engaging the success based on that is
is a little bit well not a little bit it's very
short-sighted and it does it does bring up the
question though of of how can we gauge success
right because currently this leads on to the
next question that we can gauge our failure by the
amount of animals being killed on the rise right
so that that's something i feel that we all have
to take as a bit of a slap in the face like okay
we're trying but you know clearly something isn't
working as effectively as we'd like it to be or
we've got a long way to go right um so how can we
gauge success how can we know that we're working
towards you know the right place when it looks
like we're not if you look at the global statistic
hey look i would agree that animals and the
animal rights movement has been pushed back
even further this year than it was
last year i would agree with that
all right yeah but to say that we shouldn't
fight for animals in the way that we're doing it
is ridiculous uh i i would judge incremental wins
by saying that you know in our network i'm seeing
more and more people than ever before speaking
correctly about this and that's beautiful okay
we're ending human supremacy we're holding
people accountable and we're spreading a clear
vegan message on behalf of the animals so for
me that's what that's one win that i would use
as an indicator for us moving in the right
direction and i think more and more vegans are
taking on board this this need to to be serious
about how we're being perceived by others and like
taking that seriously and being wanting wanting
to be taken seriously when it comes to this
uh i don't even think that many others are really
even taking that into account but i think more
and more people are actually on boarding this
attitude which i think is another great indicator
uh i think there are other great indicators we
could point at but i guess it depends on the
way you see it and i guess also whether you're
an optimist or you're a pessimist and um and
we don't think that you should just do
one thing anyway like people should do
what they think is effective and they should be
as effective as they can possibly be doing it
and uh we need people fighting in politics we
need people fighting in government we need people
fighting in corporate we need people fighting on
the streets we need people fighting in hollywood
it doesn't stop this fight is is multi-faceted
and it needs to continue at every level
yeah absolutely i think also something that's not
being considered is that although some countries
uh there may be reductions in how much how much
animal products are being produced right or how
many people are consuming them or using them
um whereas other countries are on the rise like
for example unfortunately india is one of those
countries uh where i know we have a few indians
here in the chat who can you can also you know
vouch for this that the amount of animal products
specifically meat uh being consumed in india is
actually increasing and there are other countries
uh especially in the east who are having the same
situation previously they had very low consumption
and now because of the western influence they are
consuming more whereas it seems like some western
countries are on the flip side of that they're
consuming less so this is you know without without
the hard data to really show and really dive into
everything that's happening we can't just make
a general statement that we're losing you know
we need to actually look at which countries are
having an impact and which aren't and why and dig
deep into each situation right um and i agree with
everything you said also about um you know getting
the message right and it's reassuring to know that
the more people are starting to be more
unapologetic i think the word would be
about defending the animals yeah yeah and i also
want to say that we don't have definitive numbers
either way on this on the amount of animals being
oppressed so i am skeptical of whatever data
people are using to make these assumptions or to
make these declarations about where things are in
terms of the numbers so i i question that because
i remember when a bite-sized vegan did a video
and she was trying to in that video give people
the kill count and even she concluded in that
video there's no way to determine this we i i'm
only uh making an educated guess here okay so
even after hours and hours of research being put
into that video that was her conclusion but how
are these individuals coming to this conclusion
when is this where is this data even being logged
how all those marine animals that are slaughtered
in the fish industry are they being logged
who's who's noting how many animals are being
murdered like it's all an assumption and um i
wouldn't trust any any piece of information
coming from animal agriculture of course or
any study that's funded by animal agriculture of
course if it says something to the effect that
their products are on the rise and they're doing
really well and all this i wouldn't trust that
and especially since we know actually that the
dairy industry is on its way out there's many
indicators of that so it depends on what you're
looking at and i need more data and more evidence
to even entertain the notion that uh that it's
going in the opposite direction in terms of the
numbers however in terms of public perception and
the way that animal rights is perceived publicly
now animal rights has been pushed even further
back than it was last year i do agree with that
yeah no totally i agree all right that brings us
to the end of my topics um and now if you've if
you've i guess it's late for you guys actually
but if you do have another like let's say let's
limit it to maybe like i don't know would you
agree for another 20 minutes is that okay 30
minutes or is that too much for you guys right
now 20 minutes sounds good all right i can see
yeah i'm waking up and you're and you're going
to bed so this is kind of like yeah yeah how
late is it sorry what time 40. all right okay
cool yeah we can start to wrap up then so
um guys you got to put some questions in um i
didn't see you putting any questions in so far
i'm not going to go back through all the way back
to the beginning because i know some of you aren't
even here anymore so if you've got questions
now's the time and if you really really want your
question to be asked like right now and you want
it to make sure you fit it in 20 minutes in the
next 20 minutes then you can uh do a super chat
and that will 100 be asked as long as it's not
something shitty um to be to put it bluntly uh but
yeah we're open to questions now for the next like
20 minutes or so but after that
i'm gonna let them go to bed so
i'm gonna run to the toilet sure man go go
no worries no worries and whilst whilst i'm
waiting for that yeah i just want to say i do
really appreciate you both coming on here i know
it's it's mentally exhausting to go through these
things um especially considering that some of them
are really ugly accusations right um i've i've
the reason one of the main reasons i wanted to do
it as well is because i feel like i can empathize
with this because i've also been on the receiving
end of equally ugly accusations so i know i know
how it feels when you read that like we all we all
pretend like yeah well whatever you know whatever
but like really it does it does get you right when
you read something so horrible and someone's
saying it about you i know how it feels so i'm
happy we could get through this and and you know
i hope a few people have had uh i hope it's given
a few people something to think about at least so
they don't go and repeat this nonsense uh over and
over again because it doesn't it doesn't feel good
to read it does it you know yeah i just hope that
what people can take from this maybe is that they
start thinking a bit more critically and if they
hear something they ask for evidence they ask for
proof you know they look into it before deciding
that somebody is a racist sexist etc because
these are horrible things that you can say and
yeah i just it's sad that people can just use this
term so loosely now and they don't realize how
insulting and destructive that is and how much it
actually takes away from the real victims of these
um depression so yeah no for sure um yeah i'm
gonna be honest with you it doesn't look like
there's any questions coming in i guess i guess
we kind of answered so much i guess they don't
have any anything else that's not being answered
to be honest i thought about this earlier in that
we've gone through so many topics that
maybe there aren't going to be questions
because there's like 60 people watching right
now and so far there's no questions so if that's
the case we can we can wrap up there's a lot
of statements though i can put some of those
on the screen you know just like for the
last like maybe like 10 minutes or so just
being king saying here they don't have evidence
for their claims and when they do it's hilarious
i i mean this is how it seems to be right that
they there's no evidence or there is evidence but
it's not evidence like it's something they have
made a i don't know they've made it some kind of
assumption from or they've twisted right yeah this
seems to be happening most of the time really yeah
that's that's me as well you know that's kind of
i faced that personally uh we do have a question
though now from um i'm not even going to try and
pronounce your name i'm sorry i should oh should
knights disrespectful mr jackal let's say um do
you think donating money to animal sanctuaries
is worth the money oftentimes the same people who
say outreach doesn't work advocate for donating
to sanctuaries or fundraise themselves well of
course it's worth the money i think we need we
need people to donate to animal sanctuaries and
also donate to organizations like av so that we
can keep doing what we're doing i think it's all
needed so once we have these animals who are being
rescued obviously they're gonna need a home so
that's where the animal center is coming and
they can't just operate without the money so yeah
i think that's obvious that it's worth the money
yeah i think maybe they're also alluding to
the idea that a lot of these same individuals
will say don't donate to ed or james or av
or or whatever donate to a sanctuary because
it's better and you kind of give the impression
that it's one or the other you know that there's
people that that's it you can only choose one
and you know one should get all the money um
which which is nonsense obviously yeah um
all right this is from michael paul and assal
you're still young do you think we'll be living
in a majority vegan world in your lifetime
i want to say yes so badly
i just really don't know
doesn't feel like in the next 50 years
or so we're going to achieve that
to be realistic standing sure i
think for my side of this i think um
i agree but i also see it as positive that we i
feel like we lay the foundations for the future
generations that will achieve this so although
we won't see it be realistic we're not going
to see it but we can do a lot of good
work to help the future people to see it
yeah it's like two-pack said you know we may not
be the ones to see that but we will be the ones to
spark the minds of those who will create that
world and if we don't create it ourselves but
um i think it's more important to just
be focused on spending our lifetime
on fighting for a vegan world rather than being
attached to it coming to fruition in our lifetime
not that this question suggests that it's just
wondering whether we think it will happen or not
i guess i just stopped thinking about it and
caring i guess i just i'm focused on what
i can do day to day and uh in our lifetime that's
all that we can focus on cool agreed um a super
question this is a super chat by the way if anyone
was wondering what that looks like it looks like
this so you can put a price on it and it means
that will uh you'll pay for it it means you'll
get your question answered so any updates on
future campaigns for next year once covid is gone
we're gonna get back to our world tour that
we were doing i just um just started that tour
did two cities ended it as a result covered
so that tour will continue and then we will
pardon me we will do two weeks of truth
which we're really looking forward to doing
we're going to do one damn week and
we're going to do what was the other one
uh we're going to do the av academy
it's going to be a boot camp um and
yeah that's it yeah we will do those things
once this whole thing's over awesome cool
um i've got another question here
but i'll just give you a heads up
it's a it's a it's a one of those another kind
of accusational question all right so just gotta
give you a heads up on it it's one that i
forgot to cover with you actually i didn't
have time to cover it with you but i think i
was gonna cover it i guess we can cover it now
it's the about the rumor that uh about the
whole creation of av um this rumor has been
around for a long time as far as i know i think
i've seen you deal with it once before on another
live or something but uh yeah if you could
respond to this is it true that another activist
from melbourne created the idea i've never
this is actually new i've never had this one
okay okay ask paul to be a violent volunteer
for them yeah one have you well there's a
second half of it by the way this is this as
well this is the second half of that question
so there you go what's that yeah this is
a completely new thing i've never heard of
what a wise imagination um yeah that's
it's interesting because uh nah this is
i've never had this one before i'm wondering
where this has come from and i'm wondering
yeah i don't what's the what's the correct
political was the political correct term for
chinese whispers these days oh god i don't even
know i i would just say that but yeah you're
right i think people would get would get upset
about that actually no um i don't know okay well
that's what this is i'm trying
to use the correct term but uh
trying not to crucify me guys uh yeah so you know
i don't really know you know i don't really know
what this is but we know about
the original accusation that came
from individuals plural in melbourne and
uh and that's all documented actually it
came out with the whole liberation is inclusive
truth of cube uh video that was made about us
um they jumped on that bandwagon and contribute
contributed to the document that was linked in the
caption of that video wherever it's shared you'll
see the link and wherever you see that link you'll
see the document and in that document you'll
see these individuals who came out initially
and made this accusation that they created av with
us and that we stole it from them now this story
that we're being asked of here is is is is
claiming that it was uh we were volunteering
according to this person just to close this
off they say it's they're saying this is a
direct claim from the person who claims
to have had this conversation with you
so it's it's uh it seems like it's um i
don't know if you don't if you don't know
this and it's it's it's you know it seems
made up i guess yeah it's like when someone
becomes famous many people start coming out and
claiming that that person is their cousin right
uh and yet that's what this it's kind of like
the same thing here people are claiming that
they created a v but there's no basis for
any of this we've heard i've heard a couple
of different uh people trying to claim this over
the years but um these people aren't doing much
yeah so that's what they claim to to activism is
but i uh i i feel for these people if they really
want to tear like they want to try to steal that
from us all the hard work we've put in and all the
commitment we've given to this organization
if they want to try to steal that from us
it says something about what
they're suffering from internally
like i'm sorry that they thought
they need to take from us
in that scenario because it means that they
must be hurting somewhere somewhere else
and not feeling adequate for themselves and i i
really mean it that i feel bad for these people
fair enough um funny question okay it's kind
of funny um are you friends with joey carver
strong again nope no yeah i thought that might be
the case i genuinely like i didn't say this in my
video actually but um when i made the video
about this but i on a personal note you don't
have to respond to this but i i do hope i do hold
some hope that that can be fixed between you guys
that you can come to some kind of i don't know
i hope that you can be friends again because it
was you know you had a good thing going it was
supporting each other it was good it's a shame
to see it all go to [ __ ] but he did what
he did and what happened happened you know
yeah look i forgive him for making a
stupid mistake he's human humans make
stupid mistakes but for as long as he won't
acknowledge his mistake there's no room for
i don't i can't be friends with people who
lack accountability it's just not a part of
my quality that i hold myself to
and what i expect from friends
yeah that's understandable it's understandable
but i can't yeah as many most people i can't
help hoping that it can be worked out but it's
yes it's kind of in his court isn't that the
balls in his court on this um someone's asking
a question that it's it's an obvious question
uh but i'm gonna put it up anyway because
it's a yeah you can easily just answer it um
it's on the transgender topic again they're
saying you said everyone should be respected
we all agreed everyone should be respected does
this mean that if someone hates transgender
people should they be respected this is
what i mean this is what i mean about nuance
uh like if hitler shows up to the cube should
he be respected like if he just is resurrected
from from the earth uh comes back to life
and shows up to keep will he be respected
uh uh do i have to answer that oh we said everyone
should be respected we said we meant the person
who chooses a different pronoun or name as well as
the person who might disagree with that ideology
oppressed that's what we meant we didn't say
the bully or the oppressor so oppression is
not respected i thought that yeah like because we
led into that point with saying that actually and
so yeah no totally totally i i understand this is
i think i watched a uh this thing with uh bilbao
you know the comedian bilbao he he he was talking
about new ones as well do you know the ginger guy
and speaks really quickly i don't know if you know
what i'm talking about yeah cool so he he talked
about nuance as well he was saying that like
everything i say is twisted and he said something
like he said he was talking about consent right
and i'm i'm gonna by the way for anyone that's
looking for something to get me on here this is
bill burr's words not my words all right don't
[ __ ] start here um but basically he said like
today's world like how how do you even work right
so he said like it's all about consent and there's
you're at risk all the way always and he said how
do you have it rough now like if a girl wants it
rough how do you do that because you know how does
it work right and this guy in the crowd shouted
you need to get consent first and he was like
this is why you can't make jokes anymore he was
like this [ __ ] [ __ ] thinks that i'm saying
that i was not going to get consent i never said
that he was like when did i say that why would you
assume that that's what i meant right and he was
like it's [ __ ] ridiculous you assumed the worst
of me and he called this guy an idiot and a [
__ ] and like really slammed him for shouting
that because it's like i'm not a monster dude
like i'm making a joke about rough sex i'm not
making a joke about not getting consent are
you insane there's a very big difference and
this is i'm saying it because he commented on it
and it's kind of what's just happened here it's
like you guys said respect everyone and someone
understood that as respect transphobic people
it's like no that's not what i said no one said
that jesus do you think i would have let that fly
in the conversation do you really think i am that
morally corrupt that i would just let someone say
that on my channel and just not question wait
a minute you've just said you want to respect
transphobes it's like no i would never let that
go even if i had someone like some monster on
the channel i would never i wouldn't let
that go but that's not the case you know
anyway i'm just i've just got off the handle a
bit there but we're at the end anyway it's fine
it's just as silly as having to say oh with the
exception of intersex when you're saying there's
two sexes like why should we even have to say that
it's an anomaly of course that's an exception to
the rule and like you know you don't need to
say certain things i guess if you are reading
between the lines and you are attuned to nuance
and you don't just see things through this uh
cancel culture lens where you know is it what what
billboard said is these days you say something and
what you say goes into someone's brain and then
it gets cut with all of the things that they're
conditioned with and you know and then it comes
out of their brain they spit it out after that
you know according to what they perceive it to be
and it's usually completely different to what you
said and uh it's the same thing here it shouldn't
that shouldn't that's something that shouldn't in
my opinion shouldn't need to be clarified you
should assume the best in people not the worst
i i don't understand what you what you have done
or even what i have done because i'm involved
in this that question was for all of us right
because i they're assuming that you have said
that and i have i have been like yeah great cool
like what did i do to deserve that what did you
do to deserve that assumption like i i don't think
any of us has done anything particularly you know
that horrible to think that any of us would like
believe that or let it go it's such a strange
and i think the person's saying it innocently
enough i don't think they're trying to attack
but at the same time it's like dude be reasonable
here come on it's a fair enough question um but i
mean i i don't know is it fair enough actually am
i trying to be nice i don't think it's fair enough
at all in my opinion i think it's something that
if you watched the whole conversation and listened
without assuming the worst in all three of us you
would come to the conclusion that that that's not
what was being said like that you're not going
to respect a bigger you're not going to respect
someone who hates trans people like what the [
__ ] like what kind of rational person would ever
have irrational hatred or acceptance of irrational
hatred like it's not it's not rational to accept
that and we've i don't believe we've been acting
irrationally in this conversation so i just i
guess what i'm trying to say is like assume good
intentions stop assuming bad intentions of people
um whoever you're talking to really like give
them a chance to prove themselves to be you know
good don't don't look for bad look for good and
assume they want the best i think is it's really
important we'll have one more question and then
we'll close off it's it's a it's a nice question
i think um do the where's the money go people
have any idea how much unpaid work that you guys
have put into animal rights do you think thank
you generally that's a refreshing perspective
to hear and not just for our case and uh it's not
just refreshing for us to hear for you know when
i think about us and that and the criticisms that
we get it's also refreshing to hear that any other
activist on behalf of any other activist
that gets similar criticisms like this
you know i don't think that
animal rights activists
are um getting the opportunity given to them
all the respects given to them that they deserve
in terms of acquiring financial security whilst
being an animal rights activist full-time
if there's any question about
motives then you just have to look at
you know like this person has graciously pointed
out and i think i think it's refreshing because
it's it's the kind of perspective that really
people should have is looking more deeply at
the work that people do and that doesn't
lie and if it is a question about motives
then yeah look at all the work we've done
when we had no money towards any of this
and we put all of our own personal money
towards everything it's when we went broke
putting all of our money into a b from the
beginning and we will continue to do that
to the very end for the for the simple fact
that it's about the mission it's about what
the organization is intended for and uh well
you know that's the thing i yeah i don't know
what else to say about this i guess you want
to answer that yes i just want animal rights
activists to feel that it's a very viable option
for them to come into animal rights as an activist
to be an activist full-time part-time
and to have financial security and not to
expect that they're going
to be walking on on hot coal
just because they they do want financial
security while being by you know while being an
animal rights activists i know that we probably
entertain on this stream we probably entertain
the accusations maybe too much i don't know
i'll walk back and i'll judge later but uh
that's why i think it's important to just know
that you know we need to hold a certain priesthood
and set a certain tone for animal rights activists
in this movement who may be wanting to come into
this maybe they want to come into this movement
and become an activist or maybe they're maybe
you're already an activist and you know i want
them to understand that there's nothing wrong with
fighting for the animals whilst also acquiring
financial security as long as your motive is not
financial to begin with yeah absolutely and
we'll wrap it up there i'll just say that um
i hope that you said we gave too much attention
to some of these topics and i would be you know
likely to agree but um tended to agree but i think
what i was trying to achieve here is to have this
be in my opinion like the last the last time i'm
going to talk about any of this anyway and i hope
the last time you also talk about it because this
is going to go up on my channel now and it's going
to have sectors marked for every single topic so
that any time anything does come up about this
and and you know someone's saying asking you hey
what do i say to this you can literally say to
them go and find you know the topic that they're
talking about copy paste and if they don't want to
watch the video well [ __ ] them then you know
like they want to keep making accusations fine
but if they want to know the truth well we've
answered it it's right here that was the goal
for this so you're right we did give it too much
attention but that's because this was the goal
i don't think most of these accusations deserved
even five seconds of time but i i do i do i do
think it's important to have it somewhere so that
it's dealt with for good you know in my opinion
and that's kind of what i wanted to achieve today
and i hope we've achieved that um thank you both
for coming here and doing this you didn't have to
do it and i think people overlook that as well you
you you don't owe anyone anything and you did not
have to sit here and answer these questions and
they weren't nice questions they were shitty
questions um i know what it feels like to be
attacked i know what it feels like to be called
these things and i know how horrible it feels
when people ask me more questions about it so i do
understand what you've just been through and i do
understand that this was a shitty thing to do and
i really do appreciate you coming and doing it and
i'm sure i'm sure there are other people who have
people have already been saying in the chat you
can check later that they also really appreciate
you coming doing this and and they support you
and um one person even said they originally didn't
support you but after seeing some of your videos
they were like okay no i actually really hope
that they can work this out so you know this
is people i feel like people want to support and
i hope this can bring some of that support back
for people who have maybe got lost or confused
along the way because of all this [ __ ] um
so yeah thank you so much is there anything you
want to say clutton closing any points you want to
add just thank you also david thanks for uh taking
the time because it's important i think as a
member of the animal rights movement to want
to clarify these things it's not really about
us again it's about the tone it's about the
precedent we set for others in this movement
absolutely saw any any final words
just thank you and um thank you to anyone who sent
their questions or you know anyone who joined this
live and they were commenting and watching this
live so yeah that's it thanks for having us david
awesome and a little bit more housekeeping just
before we go um there is another live stream today
and it will be at 8 pm my time so i don't know
what that is your time this is just completely
separate this is just to discuss uh all of the
different topics that i went through in the five
minute friday so people watching if you're if
you want to come to that and do come to that
and it'll be the usual style of live
stream where we just go through topics and
uh and also laugh at some anti-vegan kind of
standard stuff uh so come on come along for that
and um don't forget to share this video with
anyone who's giving you [ __ ] if they are
giving you [ __ ] and also of course don't
expect that this video will make a difference
some people don't want to understand some
people aren't interested in av anymore and
they just they're just done that's totally fine
don't get upset if it happens just just you
do you and let them do them and and that's
it you know don't don't take it personally
yeah i would say it's the same with non-vegans who
many non-vegans aren't reachable aren't willing
and there's no point in continuing to outreach
those individuals either it's the same thing
with vegans yep sure all right cool we'll
end it there thanks so much bye everyone