all right in 2013 i went vegan as a result of
watching the georgia tech speech by gary yourofsky
and this gentleman's also responsible for
inspiring me to become the most effective
animal rights activist that i can be and
has really changed the game for me in many
ways and i think has shaken up the world with
his speeches so i think it's only right that
i give back myself and my team have put together
this video it is the best of the best what we
think is the creme de la creme of gary yourofsky's
speeches and other moments in his activism
all right good afternoon everybody my name is
gary yourofsky please take a moment and jot down
my email address and my website in case you want
to contact me later on today we're going to talk
about the world's forgotten victims animals and
the world's oldest and strongest addiction meat
i'm going to challenge your belief systems today
so certain parts of the speech will be intense
but let me start with a quick disclaimer
i am not here to be your enemy the views
expressed today do not necessarily reflect the
views of your professor or this institution
i am not trying to take you away from your
religion no religion mandates meat eating
the golden rule states do unto others as you would
have done unto yourself animals qualify as others
and thou shalt not kill the four most important
yet most ignored words in all religious teachings
there's not an asterisk next to that commandment
saying unless you walk on all fours have fur
feathers horns beaks or gills you can keep
your friends your politics and your patriotism
still watch your favorite tv shows and listen to
your favorite music even if it's ted nugent i'll
be making some sarcastic yet truthful comments
throughout the speech please feel free to laugh
while i'm being sarcastic just don't laugh
during the serious parts now i'm going to
speak for around 65 maybe 70 minutes but then
we'll do a q a session after for about a half
an hour so hold your questions until then in the
meantime i have some rhetorical questions for you
is slavery owner victim profit domination
exclusive to the human race have blacks
jews women and children been the only victims
of this atrocity have not cows been enslaved
what about pigs chickens turkeys fish sheep if
they're not enslaved then what are they free
can slavery have a victim that is neither human
nor animal have not the oceans the forest the
earth itself become victims of ownership too and
what about a slaughterhouse house of slaughter
slaughterhouse do you really think there's such
a thing as humane slaughter exactly what is your
definition of humane besides psychological
and physical abuse torture dismemberment
and murder what else do you think happens to
animals inside of a slaughterhouse you think
they get belly rubs and tushy slaps and if you
think there's such a thing as humane slaughter
i'm curious do you also think there's such a
thing as humane rape humane child molestation
humane slavery about a humane holocaust in
fact what is your definition of a holocaust
is it a massacre of human beings
or a massacre of innocent beings
i thought it was innocent which brings us to the
biggest holocaust massacre of all every year in
america without mercy we murder 10 billion land
animals and 18 billion marine animals not for
health survival sustenance or self-defense people
eat meat cheese milk and eggs for four reasons
habit tradition convenience taste i want
to define a word that might be new to
some people right now and it's vegan
it's up there on the screen v-e-g-a-n
vegans like vegetarians do not consume the meat
of any land or marine animal vegans however
unlike vegetarians also refrain from eating cheese
milk eggs honey or any animal product whatsoever
we also don't wear animal skins no fur leather
wool silk or down now i want to let you all know
that i was not raised vegan i ate meat cheese
milk and eggs for around 25 years i used to wear
leather shoes and belts and jackets like everyone
else in fact around 20 years ago i even owned
a fur coat needless to say i understand your
lifestyle it used to be mine and for people
involved in politics let's get this out of the
way right now i am not a democrat an anarchist
or some hippie with a closet full of tie dye
shirts i'm not a republican a socialist or a
fascist i'm an activist root word is active
i've been banned from five countries so far
and arrested 13 times for random acts of kindness
and compassion on behalf of my animal brothers
and sisters if you want to read up about that
check out my website and today i would love to
give you a chance to actually do something and
truly get involved because i understand a lot of
people want to get involved honestly i do but
putting a co-exist bumper sticker on your car
wearing a what would jesus do bracelet or
sporting a peace and love and sunshine t-shirt
that is not getting involved i understand
that we're all on a journey in life
we all have different likes and dislikes
different nationalities and religions
too but there's one thing that we need to have in
common with each other and that's peace contrary
to political and religious dogma animals do not
belong to us they are not commodities they're not
property and they're not inanimate stupid objects
who can't think and feel that descartes cartesian
way of looking at animals like their machines it
is outdated and quite frankly 100 percent insane
because if we all understand that animals can
use their eyes to see ears to hear noses to smell
mouths to eat legs to walk feathers to fly fins to
swim genitalia to procreate bowels to defecate i'm
always perplexed and most people don't believe
that they can also use their brains to think
feel be rational be aware and be
self-aware am i supposed to believe
that every body part on an animal
functions just like it's supposed to
except the brain those lies are thick the
propaganda from the animal abusers is enormous
i mean when was the last time you turned on
tv and saw a commercial for shiitake mushrooms
people singing and dancing down the streets having
a good time eating mushrooms about alfalfa sprouts
quinoa it's a seed radishes raspberries tofu you
don't see that stuff advertised on tv what do you
see instead have some more meat have some more
cheese have some more cheese on your meat meat
cheese double cheese extra cheese and how about a
little more cheese with your meat have some more
cow's milk have some more eggs and then what do
you see interspersed between those advertisements
not feeling so well need to see a cancer
specialist how about a heart doctor need some
lipitor zocor crestor plavix needs some diet pills
how about some energy drinks some k.o pectate
you've been duped and those blinders are on nice
and tightly but if you give me an open mind today
that's all i ask for an open mind i'm going to
take your blinders right up my goal is simple
all i want to do is reconnect people with animals
awaken some emotions and some feelings and some
logic that has been buried and suppressed
intentionally by our society and the reason
why i say reconnect it's because each and
every person in this room used to be a real
animal rights person at one time a true animal
lover and a real friend of the animal kingdom
and it's when we were kids when we were young
we were kids man we used to be in all animals
they used to make us laugh and giggle and
smile they made us pretty happy and there was
a time in our lives when we would do just about
anything in the world to make them happy as well
to protect them from cruelty or to at least
acknowledge the cruelty they were receiving
i mean if somebody was mean to an animal
in front of us when we were little
we would have screamed and cried and that's
because we all used to understand right from
wrong when it came to the treatment of animals
until somebody told us and taught us differently
you better believe somebody told us to ignore
their suffering to mock and excuse their pain and
their misery to make fun of their very existence
and this is something i want you to focus on today
tomorrow and beyond what in the hell happened
along the way who taught us to be so mean
and nasty and vicious and hateful or indifferent
towards animals when they used to be our friends
these are innocent beings who have done nothing
wrong to us because i'm pretty sure we can all
agree in at least one thing right now that hatred
in its purest form is a learned behavior racism
sexism heterosexism anti-semitism misogyny these
are all learned behaviors when kids are two three
four years old playing on a playground they could
care less about the color of their friend's skin
or their religious background i don't think
there's any doubt that hatred in its purest
form is learned so speciesism is no different
this could be a new word to a lot of people
it's up here on the screen right below vegan
the word species with an ism attached to it
and i want to define this word as the unethical
on principled point of view that the human
species has every right to exploit
enslave and murder another species
and all because we believe that our species is
so more special so more superior than the other
ones we're the only ones that count and we're the
only ones that matter now correct me if i'm wrong
but that line of thinking that thought process
that is the basis of all forms of discrimination
one group saying and thinking they're more special
than everyone else and they proceed to exploit
them oppress them denying them their right to be
free they treat them like property they enslave
them in many cases and in many other cases
they murder them with premeditation and without
penalty and understand something essential about
discrimination it is never okay to be picking and
choosing which forms of discrimination to be
opposed to which ones to say are evil racism
and which ones to say are okay speciesism
discrimination is evil on its foundation
or it's not you cannot have this one both ways it
doesn't work like that i want to ask you to use
some empathy right now and when i say empathy what
i'm saying is is place yourself in the position
of the animals and start to view this issue from
the animal's point of view from the victim's point
of view when you examine any form of injustice
whether humans are victims or animals or victims
please remember the victim's point of view if you
are not the victim don't examine it entirely from
your point of view because when you're not the
victim it becomes pretty easy to rationalize and
excuse cruelty injustice inequality slavery
and even murder but when you're the victim
things look a lot differently from that
anger now i want to show a do you ever wonder
why mcdonald's and burger king and wendy's
never show you those images in their tv ads
instead they show you smiling cartoon
caricatures of animals singing and
dancing and playing lying to you
brainwashing you programming you
not to care about things you would normally
care about things that you used to care about
right now at this very moment on american highways
there are no less than 5 000 concentration camp
trucks trucks that we've constructed inside these
trucks there are living terrified innocent beings
cows and pigs and chickens these trucks are being
driven to concentration camp slaughterhouses
that we've carefully constructed all across
america when the trucks arrive the animals are
so frightened they won't even get off the truck
they're not stupid they know what's next so people
go on the trucks with electric prods and force
them to walk down the chutes to their own death
or if the animals are small enough to manhandle
like chickens we'll just grab them off the trucks
and toss them inside inside these innocent living
beings are hanged upside down fully conscious
in other words they go in alive against their will
and come out chopped up into hundreds of pieces
but you know what's more insane than that meat
eaters walking around like their lifestyle isn't
causing any harm like it's normal and natural
to be consuming violence and death how would you
feel if the day that you were born somebody else
had already planned the day of your execution
that's what it's like to be a cow a pig a
chicken or a turkey on this planet i think
i think this type of behavior is inexcusable an
unbecoming of a species that claims to understand
right from wrong the animals have not done
one single thing to us to deserve the wrath
and the cruelty that we hurl on them and i hope
you all understand what i'm offering you today
when you hit the door after my speech are
you aware that for the first time ever
you can now directly participate in ending a
massacre instead of sitting around and paying
lip service to all the massacres and all the
problems that are always going on on this planet
what is so frustrating to me when i travel this
country doing around 250 lectures every year to
some 7 500 students is that everybody talks a good
game i've noticed that people are quite the smooth
talkers when it comes to peace and compassion i
mean people always want to tell me never show me
just tell me how peaceful they are because of
what they believe in or what makes them sad
hey gary i believe in god and i believe in angels
and i pray all the time and those earthquakes the
one in chile and haiti oh that was so sad and no [
__ ] it was sad since when does feeling sad about
an obvious tragedy or believing in something
make the world a better place or make somebody
a good person and listen folks i am not trying
to dog you out when i talk like this i'm not
i'm just not a politician i'm not a [ __ ] artist
i don't know how to schmooze people as you can see
it's kind of beyond me i hope you appreciate my
honesty and my genuineness today and i'm not a
salesperson i got no books to sell you after my
lecture no dvds and no documentaries no collection
plate going around i don't want your money i
don't want your email addresses and i don't want
your mailing addresses keep all that stuff i am
here to talk about the worst form of cruelty and
violence taking place on this planet even though
most people don't seem to care about it but when
you sit back in the comfort of your living room
and you start condemning atrocities elsewhere
that is pure unadulterated lip service that's the
definition of lip service but veganism this is now
a chance to actually walk the compassionate
talk that everybody's always talking about
this is your chance to show others how truly
peaceful you are this is a chance for a personal
revolution to leave your mark on this planet by
causing the least amount of harm possible always
being vegan now come on what's the argument
for not causing the least amount of harm
inconvenience indifference apathy selfishness
i want you to know i don't live in fantasyland
i'm well aware that animals
are suffering and dying
just because we're here on the planet with
them we build homes through their habitat we
pollute their environment destroy their habitat is
there a reason we have to maximize the suffering
and maximize the cruelty and the
death that they already endure
by eating them on top of it all you want to talk
about pouring salt into somebody else's womb
98 and i repeat this stat 98 of animals who are
abused and killed on this planet are abused and
killed by the meat dairy and egg industries
this is where all the harm is taking place and
in america from birth until death each meat eater
consumes around 3 000 land animals and thousands
of other marine animals those are usda stats
now with all this being said we've established
the four reasons why people eat meat cheese
milk and eggs no debating no discussing them
have it tradition convenience taste it now
i want to get back to taste good though
because i think meat tastes great it might shock
you to hear me say that but if you're doing some
kind of extra credit essay on my speech you
want to quote me quote me right now i love
the way meat tastes love it cheese love it
cow's milk and eggs love it guilty as charged
i did not stop eating this stuff because of
the taste issue i stopped for ethics morality
decency how come when i talk about mock meat i
always catch a handful of people in every crowd
and we got a big crowd today so i stopped counting
at about eight or nine how come there's always a
handful of people that wrinkle up their noses make
big wide eyes and start glancing at the people
next to them across the aisle like soy chicken
is this guy crazy soy bacon he must be out of his
mind how come this stuff that is made of soy wheat
vegetables grains and spices contrary to the lies
being spread about these products by the meat and
dairy industries how come this stuff is considered
gross to most people but meat meat's got five
components let me break it down for you blood
flesh veins muscles and tendons the cut up
corpse of a dismembered body how does meat
not qualify as gross and disgusting everybody
how in the world is a beverage a liquid that
oozes out of the others of cows a secretion that
drips from the mammary glands of another being
that's loaded with pus by the way oh yeah let
me tell you how the pus in your child milk it'd
be my pleasure when you hook machines up to the
others of cows three times a day to suck them dry
those machines cause massive amounts of infections
on the inside and outside of the utter now let's
add all the bovine growth hormone they put in cows
to make sure they produce huge quantities of milk
which always leads to another infection the
machine doesn't know what not to suck out
pus mucus and infections right in with your
milk and yeah milk is pasteurized but when did
pasteurization become a removal process it's a
sanitation process you're only sanitizing pus
and you want to look this up online you
don't think the dairy industry would ever
use the word pus when they write about
this problem in their own trade journals
and they're going to deceive you again with
this look up the scientific term for pus
somatic cell count and by the way our
government the usda they allow the dairy
industry to have a maximum amount of one eye
dropper full of pus in every glass another
drink up does anybody know what an egg actually
is from a hand and don't say embryo or aborted
fetus not even close it's unfertilized so
it can't be either hen is a female though
unfertilized egg through a female system it's
part of her menstruation cycle it's a hens
period people scramble up hand periods in the
morning and all of a sudden i'm weird because i
don't make omelets anymore and what about vomit oh
we're going to take those blinders off today come
on you guys love vomit you adore it all over your
food got you give this one a pretty name though
no one's gonna buy and eat vomit unless we call
it honey instead honey comes directly from a
bee's stomach it is regurgitated right through a
bee's mouth look it up with any wildlife biologist
but nobody wants to eat bee bonnet and
nut cheerios we want honey nut cheerios
so we hire ourselves to play euphemism games the
standard diet of a meat eater is blood flesh veins
muscles tendons cow secretions hen periods and b
vomit now we're not done yet i am not going to let
you off that easy while i got you here today
you know we topped this all off in my opinion
because every november during that certain holiday
people love so much people take a dead turkey open
up the dead turkey's ass or carve out a really big
hole in their ass take some stuffing and shove it
inside their dead empty ass and use their little
dead ass as an oven to bake some bread somebody
else's dead empty bacteria-laden ass to make
bread ash bread and people think vegans are weird
because we eat tofu and rice and beans and lentils
i tell people one of my favorite meals nowadays
yes boy dish me up a plate of yams for dinner
and i'm a happy guy i know how most people are
though i tell them this they're like but you just
see amsterdam i don't know man it's kind of weird
okay but somebody else's rib cage sitting
on your plate isn't weird doesn't make you
think twice severed legs sliced up thighs
and mutilated breasts sitting on your plate
doesn't make you think twice
and you want to know why
those blinders are on nice and tightly
aren't they and i bet most of you were
perturbed in me when the speech began and
i accused everybody of having blinders on
i am not here to be your enemy i am here
to call you out though you might have had a
pretty good excuse before i got here of being
uninformed and misinformed okay that's fair
honestly well i was the same way for a long time
i'm kind of curious though what's the excuse now
you got a choice today never to intentionally
harm another animal for breakfast lunch or
dinner ever again these creatures have
never harmed you violated you or taken
advantage of you in any way shape or form
the least you can do is return the favor
or you can stay radically cruel keep the status
quo as is make sure animals have no freedom
make sure they never experience one drop of human
kindness make sure their babies are stolen from
them make sure their beaks are sliced off their
horns are cut off and their testicles ripped out
make sure there's a knife in their throat every
second of every day for eternity i really hope
you'll make the right choice i want to wrap
this speech up so we can do our q a session
give me about six more minutes to say something on
the dairy industry as it pertains directly to cows
we talked about the pus in cow milk which is
gross but we have yet to focus on what the cows
are going through keep in mind veganism
isn't about your health that would be selfish
i'm trying to get people to
be unselfish for a change to
be altruistic and when you do that
don't expect something in return
but when it comes to cruelty i think there's
more cruelty in a glass of milk than a steak
i want to make my case visually and verbally
you're only the 11th class to see what i'm
about to show this just went down a few months
ago in plain city ohio at a mom pod dairy farm
there we go
all right
oh you're bullying all right
holy [ __ ] you break a tail
mom get your head
like this
turn your head turn your head [ __ ]
turn your ass turn your ass come on
[ __ ] tears oh i got a bad
i have my blood pressure
i don't think they're feeling any pain i just
keep going until the cows are oh i'm like yeah
this is not an isolated incident
don't for one minute think that this is an
isolated incident this is how slaves are treated
you don't really think that
slaves get treated nicely do you
you really think white people were nice when
they ship black people over here on ships
you don't think nazis were nice when they walk
jews and gypsies into the gas chambers do you
and this happens because you want to buy
those products yeah that guy's a scumbag
for doing that but he's doing that because
you want to eat what comes out of her body
and enough already you're not a caveman and
you're not a cave woman anymore stop acting
like neanderthals this is 2010 give
it up it's not cute and it's not funny
because animals are being abused it is not your
right it is not your freedom to do this to them
you don't get to have freedom when
somebody else doesn't that's a violation
and if you wonder why vegans get so upset
sometimes like i am right now you just
saw some of it every time we show up at a farm
somebody's punching chicken and stabbing somebody
and something else that i'm curious about how
come when i show videos like this of people
punching and kicking animals people are
more upset with that than when they shove
a knife in their throat so even if you find
a farm where they're not punching and kicking
when they shove a knife in their throat to put a
bullet between their eyes how is that not cruelty
did you know that 90 percent of hamburger
meat in america comes from the dairy industry
when cows no longer give huge amounts of milk
after three to seven years slaughterhouse no
exceptions if ever given a chance cows can live to
be 18 to 25 and cows are like all female mammals
i am not trying to talk down to you when i speak
about animal issues it's just that people don't
think that animals go through the same things
the same emotions that you go through that we
all go through in order for a female mammal
to give to give milk she has to be pregnant
every year every cow and every dairy farm is
raped a long steel device shoving their vaginas
to inject them with bull semen or sometimes
they use a bare hand this forces the milk flow
and after she gives birth babies are stolen and
let me tell you something the worst scream i have
ever heard and i've heard them all firsthand
when i started finding out about this stuff
a little over 15 years ago i was like everybody
else i didn't believe it was that bad i thought
everybody was exaggerating but unlike everybody
else who just blows it aside brushes it off
i actually went to see what was going on i
spent six weeks at thorne apple valley page
slaughterhouse in detroit in 1993. i broke into
animal research laboratories i broke into fur
farms i went behind the scenes of every circus
and every rodeo that ever came through michigan
worst scream i've ever heard
a mother cow on a dairy farm
as she screams and bellows her lungs out day after
day for her stolen baby to be given back to her
and i can only imagine the same scream every woman
in this room would make if somebody held you down
after birth and stole your newborn baby from you
and why did they take babies away from their mom
well the dairy is you can't have little babies
sucking up all that milk that was meant for them
when they'd rather sell it to you instead
every time you have a glass of cow milk
some calf is not and mother cows make milk
for one reason anyways during q a we're about
to have you can ask me whatever you want i'm no
politician bring up anything if you went online
before i got here saw my radical essays that
got me kicked out of countries bring them up
there is one question i will not entertain them
you cannot ask me why cows make milk thus if
it's good for us shouldn't we be feeding it
to our kids gary shouldn't we be having it
nature took care of this one at the beginning of
time cows make milk for their babies and for their
babies alone case is closed forever permanently
no debate no discussion they don't make milk for
baby elephants baby orangutans baby headshots
baby rabbits baby rats baby humans adolescent
humans or adult humans this body of ours has
absolutely no need for cow milk like it has
absolutely no need for giraffe milk and zebra milk
and rhinoceros milk hippopotamus milk camel milk
deer milk antelope milk horse milk pig milk dog
milk or cat milk the only milk that we ever need
is our own mother's breast milk when we're born
that's it and when we're done weaning we never
need one drop of milk ever again no species on
this planet needs milk after they're done weaning
but if you want to include some kind of milk in
your diet like i do let me reiterate the good news
soy milk rice milk almond milk hemp
milk coconut milk oat milk hazelnut milk
you don't give up anything you
got the vegan version of stuff
or eat things that are truly natural like fruits
and vegetables beans and lentils and seeds
so the new number one excuse to eat animals is
no longer god says it's okay that's number two
now it's now the circle of life so we're gonna
look at the circle of life from the victim's
point of view which nobody ever does as
you're about to see this zebra does not
want to be a victim to a lion any more than
a cow or a chicken wants to be your victim
about to see an alligator trying
to take down a baby impala
and there's an angry vegan looking on i
empathize he's going to get involved and stop him
he's about to give mouth to
mouth and he never took the
saturday morning cpr class at the local
community college to figure out how to do that
they're much brighter than we give him credit for
but for the record not all animals are brilliant
some are stupid just like human beings some
are bright some are stupid they're just like us
if a bunch of violent thugs kidnapped your baby
threaten and kill him and
you are out muscled and man
you might go get some backup too
by the way the only bright
lion in this whole pride
ain't no fun when the rabbits got a gun and they
saved their baby how about that he was still alive
looks like the buffaloes the zebra and the
hippo didn't get that memo about the way
meat eaters want the world to be good afternoon
everybody my name is gary yourofsky i'm a vegan
animal liberation activist been vegan more
than 18 years which means i do not eat or wear
anything that once had a face a mother or a bowel
movement no meat cheese milk eggs and honey no fur
leather wool silk or down and no animal byproducts
whatsoever instead i've decided to eat normal food
real food that wasn't tortured and killed
and covered in blood and guts and pests like
fruits and vegetables nuts and seeds grains
and lentils i wear clothing made of hemp
bamboo cotton and a host of other materials
that were not ripped off of somebody else's body
now i chose this lifestyle back in 1996.
when i finally understood that speciesism
believing that the human species can do
whatever it wants to any animal species
was the essence of bigotry and hatred more victims
are left in this path than all other forms of
discrimination combined worldwide we are torturing
and killing 150 billion animals every year
to satisfy our meat dairy and egg addictions
and billions more for clothing and entertainment
so when you're not vegan you end up paying
somebody to kill thousands of animals just
for you throughout your lifetime that's not
only violent commodification and selfishness
it's pure hypocrisy because what if you
were the victim remember you have to examine
all issues of injustice from the victim's point
of view and what if somebody commodified your body
labeled you stupid and dirty mocked your
entire existence and said that your life
didn't matter at all i suppose you'd want
the world to change its evil ways immediately
and hope that somebody like me would stand
up speak out and defend your right to be free
don't you think the animals we torture and kill
feel the same exact way and speaking of stupid
and dirty have you been to an airport lane seen
a public restroom the hudson river following the
rise of stds ever notice that the majority of
people have never once started out on the right
side of justice and we have the audacity to say
that animals are stupid and dirty so how come
small groups of people always have to convince
the masses why it's wrong to enslave discriminate
or kill innocent beings the answer
is quite simple technologically
we are brilliant ethically we're on par with
parasites we are a sick twisted mistake of
a species so the way we treat the animals and
each other doesn't even shock me anymore what's
shocking is that the masses are always shocked
when they're accused of acting inappropriately
it took 400 years to convince white people in
america not to own black people and another
100 years on top of that to end segregation and
if somebody wants to hang out after class and
explain to me why those abolitions didn't
take two seconds i'd love to hear about it
any injustice on that scale can only happen
if the general population supports it or
turns a blind eye to it so the key players
in the exploitation government religion
media corporations they become experts at lying
and using propaganda and deceit to trick people
into accepting the abuse the dairy industry for
example loves to tell you about happy cows but
what they don't tell you is that all these happy
cows get raped every year artificially impregnated
with a bare hand or a long steel device to eject
them with bold sperm female mammals have to be
pregnant to produce and give milf mother cows then
have their babies stolen from them after birth
because once we eliminate the babies from the
equation we get to drink all that milk instead
and when mother cows can't produce huge amounts
of milk after three to seven years they get a
happy day at the slaughterhouse where if they're
really lucky they'll get turned into a happy meal
other companies love to lie about
happy animals too what about that
wish i wear an oscar meyer wiener jingle
that's pretty cute except for the fact that when
they're born male babies have their testicles
ripped out without anesthetic standard practice
the meat industry always controls procreation all
the female pigs get raped every year to impregnate
them just like the cows baby pigs then have most
of their teeth cut off right down the gum line
and their tails cut off too all without anesthetic
to try and reduce flesh damage from fighting and
biting each other in their overcrowding conditions
and when pigs reach 300 pounds in six
months thanks to genetic modification
they get a happy day at the slaughterhouse too
where they get chopped up into a thousand pieces
the egg industry though man they just might
possess the greatest marketing propaganda of
all time because they've actually convinced
you to eat something that came out of a hens
all inclusive all in one ass vagina and
the backside of a bird is called a cloaca
it is one hole where the poop the p the vaginal
fluid and scrambled eggs and omelets come from
hate to be the bearer of more bad news
but mommy and daddy lied to us too
we're not that special and we're not perfect just
the way we are but at least when you become vegan
you are trying trying to reduce and eliminate
gratuitous amounts of cruelty and violence
which is all i'm asking of you today so how
come when one human dies it's a tragedy but when
billions of animals are killed with premeditation
it's a celebration and what's really odd about
this tragedy celebration dichotomy is that
besides some kind of a self-defense situation
everyone knows that killing is evil and
wrong because every time a bear kills a hiker
what do we do start saving hakuna matata praise
the hiker for being part of the circle of life
tell his family well he just wasn't fit enough to
survive [ __ ] we scream bloody murder label that
bear a homicidal maniac and get a bunch of people
with guns and go kill that bear for killing the
hiker funny how the circle of life never comes
into play when we're getting killed and that's
because the circle of life ain't nothing but an
aggrandized arbitrary [ __ ] excuse to torment
and kill somebody else with impunity it's a cute
story it really is written directed and produced
by us the killers the dictators the victimizers
the victims in this psychotic scenario are not
willing participants as you clearly saw on
that opening video but here's something even
more interesting than that sometimes even
the killers question their own behavior
kindness is a choice so is violence spare
me the animals can't think or rationalize
because they operate on instinct only nonsense
because if you go to my website at dap.org check
out the animal intelligence essay and click
the link that says leopard saves a baby baboon
and watch a big carnivorous cat have
second thoughts about the circle of life
she kills a baboon but doesn't realize the
baboon is a mother with a newborn baby so she
intentionally lets a skulking hyena have the dead
mother's corpse to chomp on while she gently picks
up the baby puts the baby in a tree and stays
in the tree to protect the baby from the hyena
if the circle of life was genuine and
animals couldn't think that leopard would
have instinctively instantly killed that baby
instead she chose to comfort him to protect him
just like most of you would do because once again
anyone can choose to be peaceful or violent either
way it is a choice and i have many other videos in
that section also showing carnivores refusing to
kill their supposed prey and for the people out
there right now who might be thinking yeah gary
but if animals want to be treated equally to us
and treated fairly then the animals who eat other
animals need to be arrested and charged with
murder you are missing my point completely but
i support that honestly i do as long as all
the humans who eat animals turn themselves
in to face the same consequences be careful
about throwing stones in your glass house
because if we really want to arrest animals
and charge them with crimes they actually need
equal rights they currently have no standing in
court meaning we can't even bring them to trial
but as soon as animals receive the same rights of
life and liberty as us meaning they can no longer
be the victims of slavery and murder i'll call the
cops and the next cat i see for killing a squirrel
until then i am placing the moral mirror in
front of your faces it's time for you to walk
the compassion and talk that you're always
talking about you can't just pray for peace
sing songs about love and happiness and
togetherness turn on the five o'clock
news hear about a tragedy and go oh that's so sad
and then go out and do violent things like those
damn hippies did in woodstock bunch of hippie
crits did you know that they consumed over one
million hot dogs during that four-day festival
and i bet you thought the hippies were on my
side peace and love and flower power my ass peace
begins at the dinner table with a vegan meal but
instead we always want to get together and see how
many dead animals and nasty animal products we can
eat at once bacon and eggs and cheese and steak
and chicken and cheese and lobster six cheese
pizzas with every pig product imaginable triple
cheese bacon burgers with a side of asparagus
wrapped in bacon we actually praise people
in our society for killing animals you've
seen all the tv shows glorifying fish killers
duck killers chefs who cook nothing but meat
guys who'll eat anything from testicles to brains
schmucks who win hot dog eating contests it's now
time to watch a five and a half minute video
about where breakfast lunch and dinner come from
and before i press play i need to
be pretty clear about something
there is no such thing as humane slaughter or
humane slavery meaning that humane meat cheese
milk eggs and honey do not exist if i told
you that there was a nice outfit in thailand
where they humanely raped kids for the child porn
industry you know they use condoms and lubricants
that are playing a big backyard every day
for six glorious hours in between the rapes
would you support it i didn't think so is that
because rape is always evil no matter how it's
being done so stop focusing on how animals are
being harmed and violated and start opposing
all the different ways of enslaving abusing
and killing innocent beings this means that
buying local organic cage-free free-range
grass-fed kosher all antibiotic-free hormone-free
is just as evil and no different than buying
conventional from afar from a factory farm
and if you feel the need to turn away or close
your eyes during this video you might want to
ask yourself a question if it's not good enough
for my eyes then why is it good enough for my
stomach
foreign
um
hello
oh
hey
um
so
john never down
there was nothing wrong with killing
animals and eating meat was okay
how come mcdonald's and burger king and
wendy's never show those images in their tv ads
are we showing you a happy singing
smiling cartoon caricature instead
people are up in arms right now about all the
beheadings taking place in the middle east
meanwhile 30 million innocent animals
every day in america are beheaded
and no one says a damn thing about it
so i'm a little confused is beheading evil or
does it matter who's getting their heads cut off
i will forever be embarrassed to be a human being
to stand upright like that's something
to be proud of you got to be kidding me
a retired marine in north carolina once
heard me lecture at east carolina university
and he said gary i believe everything
you said got no arguments for you at all
but we're a bunch of violent
monkeys what makes you think we care
to this day that statement still breaks
my heart but i refuse to believe that
no one cares because the only problem
is you've been programmed not to care
brainwashed to be a good little lifelong consumer
of animal body parts same thing happened to me for
the first part of my life for 25 years but if you
just put your defenses down i can un-brainwash and
deprogram you for free no gimmicks no books
to buy no email list to join i just want to
put you back in touch with your conscience again
the conscience that you had when you were young
innocent and uncorrupted by society's lies it
can't be that difficult to understand that each
animal values his or her life as much as you
value yours you might not care about cows and
pigs and chickens and fish but when your thoughts
are prejudicial who the hell cares what you think
believe whatever you want to believe but you
have no right to act out your violent desires and
listen if you want to sit around all day smoking
weed eating oreo cookies sipping on a two liter
of mountain dew be my guest because ain't nothing
wrong with smoking some kush and oreos and soda
happen to be vegan they're sugar and chemicals
pure garbage but if you want to harm yourself
you have every right to do so i am not the health
police but you have no right to harm somebody else
in the process of harming yourself so i am the
ethics police and vegans will defend animals from
you until this massacre stops you don't really
think the entire animal kingdom worships us
thinks we're special believes that we are the
image of god we're like a colombian drug cartel
we're a bunch of bullies criminals and killers
a symbiotic relationship between humans and
animals is not happening when all we do is
take and take and take and take a little more
we steal their milk their eggs their honey
their skin their flesh their lives symbiotic
relationships are supposed to benefit each
party when there's only one beneficiary
it's called slavery it's time to become the
rational beings that we always claim to be
and speaking of becoming rational got to say
something to my religious friends out there today
because the oldest excuse in the book god says
it's okay is the dumbest [ __ ] i've ever heard
in my life to harm somebody else because if you
believe that god gave us the architectural plans
to construct a house of slaughter so we can
cut the heads off of his terrified animals
that he doesn't mind when we steal newborn
babies from their mothers or cut their horns
and beaks and tails and teeth off while they're
fully conscious then what does the devil do
what could a cow a pig a chicken or turkey ever do
to deserve the wrath of god
himself or eternal damnation
and for the atheists and the agnostics in the
crowd you ain't off the hook either where's that
logical lifestyle you're always preaching about
because if you discriminate against animals and
eat meat cheese milk eggs and honey then you are
no different than all the religious people that
you condemn and for the record i do not condemn
god i condemn violent rituals and bloodthirsty
habits and traditions in god's name because i've
noticed something quite disturbing about all
religious people all over this planet they never
ever worship anything that god actually created
the only worship things that we created in god's
name bibles crosses churches synagogues korans
stars of david the wailing wall i
can assure you that god is completely
unimpressed with our creations and with us as long
as we act like barbarians living in peace though
i think you'd be pretty impressed with that you
can't possibly believe there are slaughter houses
in heaven or that violence against animals was
allowed in the garden of eden and those are god's
two most perfect places now i want to destroy
some other lies you've heard way too much about
first people often ask me why we can't eat eggs
from some hens living in our backyard or from a
free range farm their bodies do not belong to us
commodification is the crime as much as cruelty is
and i've noticed that nobody ever wants to adopt
old hens to live in their backyard the ones who
have stopped laying eggs they only want the
young ones who are still freshly modified
genetically to lay 300 eggs every year
instead of their normal 17 eggs every year
pens just like sheep in the
wool industry always get killed
when they stop producing things that we want them
to produce and finally let's talk about the plants
and whether they suffer because the latest idiocy
and lunacy being tossed my way the last couple
of years has been hey man carrots suffer and
die just like cows do so what's the difference
okay in case you were unaware of this difference
you have to have a functioning central nervous
system connected to a brain in order to suffer and
this is not up for debate which is why people in
the hospital who are brain dead but still alive
but can't feel anything are cold how about that
little truth in science for a change yeah we don't
call these people fish we don't call them chickens
and turkeys and cows and pigs we call them
vegetables but even if someone somehow proved
that in sentient life forms like plants were
capable of suffering we're causing more harm
to the planet by harvesting all the plants
and feeding all those plants to the animals
and killing all the animals to get
the nutrients they got from the plants
which were all the nutrients that we needed to
begin with with all the crop land in america alone
america could be feeding 10 billion people again
there's only and a half billion on the planet
which means less land would be used less plants
would be harvested less violence committed
if we ate plants directly and if plants really
can't suffer how can firefighters never rescue
them and don't say it's discriminatory
because animals are the most discriminated
species on this planet but there's still a
plan in place to save them during a fight
humans get safe first but if it's safe to do
so even if it's unsafe to do so they'll go
back inside and save the animals but even if it
were safe to do so again no fire fighter in the
history of the world has ever gone back in a
third time to save the chrysanthemums hey bob
quick you saved the basil plant from the kitchen
i'll get the road identity from the second floor
do you think that if i gain lectures about cruelty
to vegetables especially root vegetables like yams
called my speech the silence of the yams
because everybody knows that yams scream
for about 30 to 45 seconds after you gank
them out of the ground before they die that
i would have been invited into 180 schools
to give 2600 lectures to 60 000 students in 30
different states and i was just thinking about
this the other day but what do we say about fruits
and vegetables when they get old they're ripe
ready to eat or rot and what do we say
about animals when they get old they're old
because animals are alive in
the exact same way that we are
and plants are food so can we please stop making
up idiotic excuses to torture and kill the animals
and make up an excuse to care about them instead
to become vegan actually live by the golden rule
instead of just paying lip service to it do
unto others as you would have others do unto you
good evening my name is gary yourofsky in 1996
i founded adapt which became michigan's most
outspoken and radical animal rights organization
in 2002 i became the official orator of peta
people for the ethical treatment of animals
because of my michigan ties many midwestern
law enforcement agencies government officials
media people and politicians know me as the
most outspoken and radical activist not only in
the state of michigan but in the entire midwest
i have been arrested 13 times for random acts of
kindness and compassion following in the footsteps
of other routine radical law breakers like dr
martin luther king jr mohandas gandhi nelson
mandela and jesus please do not misconstrue what i
am saying i do not think i am king nor gandhi nor
mandela nor jesus but i am following in their
routine radical law-breaking footsteps in 1997
i liberated 1542 mink from an animal concentration
camp in canada euphemistically referred to as a
fur farm subsequently i received a six-month
sentence in maximum security where i spent 77
days there before being deported back to michigan
once a liberator and now an educator before i talk
about the vegan ethic i need to let everyone know
that i did not come here today to be your enemy i
came here to educate and enlighten tell you things
you're not supposed to be told and show you things
you are never supposed to see if you want to make
me your enemy today hey that's fine join the club
i have thousands of enemies nationwide heck i
can even put you in contact with some of them
if you'd like today's speech is intended to
uplift you morally now before we continue i
need to show you seven minutes of graphic video
about the vicious traditions of animal abuse that
still exist in our society i am not showing this
video to shock you though you will be shocked
i am showing this video to let you know that i
never engage in exaggeration when i'm describing
the disgusting rituals of human to animal slavery
let me also mention this for some reason crying
has become a taboo in our society but if you feel
the need to cry while you're watching this video
crying is the proper emotion to exhibit while
you're watching an atrocity take place if you
feel the need to laugh during this video you
might want to consult with a good psychotherapist
you're about to witness the killing of a perfectly
healthy puppy every year us shelters execute 10
million perfectly healthy puppies kittens dogs and
cats simply because nobody wants them but you can
stop this senseless killing in three easy ways
have a vet spayer new to your dog or cat today
never buy an animal from a breeder or pet
shop and adopt your next dog or cat from a
city shelter financial assistance is available
please go to this website or call us today
there is nothing but blood trails misery slavery
and murder behind the propaganda spread by the fur
industries spin doctors the fur trade is truly a
death trade in the name of vanity and greed every
year 40 million animals have the fur ripped off
their bodies in a disgusting display of inhumanity
manual neck breakings mass gassings and anal
and genital electrocutions are the standard
killing techniques used on every animal murdered
for profit baby seals are clubbed to death in a
violent annual carnage while the vicious steel
jaw leg hole trap kills millions of free roaming
animals like coyotes raccoons foxes and beavers if
companies insist on selling misery boycott them at
once and tell them that the blood is on their
hands martin luther king jr once said injustice
anywhere is a threat to justice everywhere this
is injustice go to this website or call us today
behind closed doors every year millions
of monkeys dogs cats rabbits and mice
are injured tortured and killed in unscientific
research experiments outrageous lies from the
national institutes of health and emotional
ploys from other animal researchers only mislead
you about this inhuman practice does this sound
like science that could benefit your well-being
please help us stop this insanity
go to this website or call us today
the circus meets every definition of slavery
animals chained and caged and forced to perform
unnatural tricks against their will animals
bought rented and sold and shipped around like
cargo in boxcars and semis while someone else
profits off their labor and from their misery
humanitarian dick gregory once proclaimed when
i look at animals held captive by circuses
i think of slavery animals and circuses represent
domination and oppression they wear the same
chains and shackles all circuses use violence
to train elephants lions bears and tigers and
the training sessions are comprised of beatings
with hooks iron bars whips and sticks fear is
the only way to make these wild animals submit and
perform most circus animals also develop neurotic
behaviors elephants sway from side to side lions
and tigers pace and bears rock back and forth
in their tiny cages please extend some freedom to
those who have none go to this website or call us
today
oh
get everything you've got
you hear that screaming did you
know you've got their attention
oh
god
this
foreign
german philosopher arthur schopenhauer once said
that all truth passes through three stages first
it is ridiculed second it is violently opposed
and third it is accepted as being self-evident
unfortunately the hatred and i mean hatred
that humans have towards non-human animals
is so vicious vile and powerful animal rights
has not yet reached schopenhauer's third stage
of common sense the human intellect remains
so remedial and self-absorbed the notion of
animal rights is usually mocked or ignored but i
think it's high time that humans climb down off
their make-believe pyramids of domination
and extend some simple decency some simple
decency to our planetary companions before this
discussion continues i need to let everyone know
that i am not an animal lover do not refer to me
as an animal lover this might shock you but i do
not love animals oh i have the utmost empathy
for their plate but you cannot refer to me as
an animal lover i fight for animal liberation and
peace because i loathe injustice and despise the
way humans mistreat the animal kingdom i spend
less than one percent of my time watching animal
planet national geographic or discovery
channel sharing the mating habits of the
blue-footed boobie does not make the world a nice
eclipse only veganism can do that which is why i
am vegan vegan means i do not eat anything
that had a face a mother or a bowel movement
vegan also means i do not consume any product
that was derived from anything that had a face
a mother or a bowel movement if you're still
consuming food that once went to the bathroom
that once defecated and urinated you might want
to change your diet repeat its veggie starter kit
and go vegan vegan also means i do not wear any
animal skins obviously fur but that includes
leather wool silk and down payless 15.99 fake
leather let me mention this about leather you
know most people find it morally reprehensible
for people to wear fur yet those same people
don't find it morally reprehensible for people
to wear leather but besides size shape and color
there is no inherent difference between
a cow and a mink or a cow in a fox
cow skin is mink skin is fox skin cows feel
the same amount of pain is making foxes
and a cow wants to keep her skin attached to her
body as much as a fox wants to keep hers so you
must condemn both fur and leather condemning
one and not the other would be hypocritical
of all the exploited beings on the face of the
earth animals are the most violated that's why
i'm here today to ask you to join millions of
others in a remarkable crusade against oppression
but before anyone decides to engage in this
compassionate crusade understand there is one
important stipulation that you must adhere to all
of your prejudices must be extinguished there is
no room for any racism sexism heterosexism or
of course speciesism which might be a new word
to most people today speciesism the unfounded
unethical and unprincipled view that the human
animal has every right to mistreat exploit and
murder the non-human animal and just like the
previous isms speciesism lacks coherent thought
and is a narrow-minded view of the life that
comprises this planet nobel prize winner isaac
basha this singer who escaped nazi-occupied poland
and lost family members in concentration camps
once called speciesism the purest form of racism
2600 years ago the great philosopher pythagoras
said this about speciesism as long as humans
continue to be the ruthless destroyer of other
beings we will never know health or peace for
as long as people massacre animals they will kill
each other indeed those who sow the seed of murder
and pain will ever reap joy or love after studying
those statements and others i now understand
that speciesism is the root of all hatred of all
violence of all discrimination that exists on this
planet and we will never destroy the branches
of hatred like racism sexism and heterosexism
unless we destroy violence and hatred and
bloodthirstiness at its root and that root
is speciesism the first form of hatred that human
beings are taught is to eat the animal translation
mistreat the animal translation hate the animal
translation view the animal as an inanimate object
and a mere commodity before anyone is ever taught
to hate or discriminate against a gay person they
are taught to hate and discriminate against
animals for anyone has ever taught to hate or
discriminate against a certain race or ethnicity
they are taught to hate and discriminate against
animals before any man was ever taught to mistreat
a woman he is taught to mistreat an animal
did you know that each person
who chooses to eat animal flesh
is responsible for the murder of 3 000
land animals throughout their lifetime
whether you kill thousands in 78 years or 78
minutes you are still a killer and a terrorist
i did not come here today to try and convince you
that animals are more important than human beings
because the issue of importance is
irrelevant to how animals should be treated
no one in this movement has ever said that a
mouse is more important than your mother your
father your sister or your brother because we
don't make an arbitrary list of who's important
and we don't care about anyone else's arbitrary
list of who's more important we care about peace
justice the mahatma mohandas gandhi once said this
i do not regard flesh food as necessary to us i
hold fresh food to be unsuited to our species the
life of a lamb is no less precious than that of a
human being i should be unwilling to take the life
of a lamb for the sake of the human body the more
helpless the creature is the more it is entitled
to protection from humans from the cruelty of
humans gandhi was just one of many luminaries
throughout history who adopted the animal rights
lifestyle he was a true humanitarian who opened
up his circle of compassion to include animals not
exclude them other people throughout history who
adopted the animal rights lifestyle and practice
vegetarianism and veganism pythagoras plato
socrates einstein george bernard shaw schweitzer
harry feature stone percy shelley tolstoy
da vinci and cesar chavez just to name a few
around six years ago when i fully embraced
the peaceful philosophy of animal rights
and understood that animals had an inherent right
to be free and live completely unfettered by human
dominance i wondered why it took me more than
20 years to attain this non-violent awakening
i asked myself who taught me that animals were put
on this earth for food who taught me to disrespect
animals and view them as mere commodities who
stole my compassion my empathy and my conscience
who lied to me who instilled that vicious
mindset of human to animal exploitation
as standard operating procedure each and every
person in this room should ask those same
questions think deeply about that who taught that
violence to you who told you that animals should
be your food your clothing your entertainment and
your research specimens who lied to you who took
your compassion your empathy and your conscience
who gave you the belief system that embraces the
misery and murder of innocent animals was it your
parents your friends your institutions of learning
your government your religion i'm sure you'll
find just like i did that it was one or more of
those aforementioned entities who taught you and
me to believe endless lies for they too have been
lied to or they will benefit from those lies i'm
asking everyone to reevaluate your belief system
ask yourself why is this violence
being permitted for what reasons
and i hope you'll have the same revelation
that i did the non-violence through veganism
non-violence through animal liberation is the only
ethical and acceptable way to live on this planet
let's begin a formal discussion on veganism and
don't forget after the talk check out govege.com
last year in the u.s alone 10 billion cows
pigs chickens turkeys and other animals
were raised in concentration camps euphemistically
referred to as factory farms they were sent to
slaughterhouses where knife-wielding carnivores
hang them upside down slit their throats drain
their blood and dismember their bodies then
because most people have acquired a taste for
animal flesh i stress acquired taste for animal
flesh their dismembered bodies were cooked
and eaten did you know that sows
female pigs are forced to live
their entire lives and give birth in
gestation crates and farrowing stalls
these prisons are so tiny a simple task like
turning around is a fantasy to a female pig now
this intense confinement slowly drives her insane
and she ends up exhibiting neuronic behaviors like
bar biting where she bites the metal bars that
can find her all day long she bites these bars
in the slightly larger areas where the male pigs
the hogs are kept other neuronic behaviors occur
fighting is common because of overcrowding and
when pigs fight they've been known to attack
each other's tails so how does the pig industry
solve the fighting problem two ways one ignore
the situation two vicious intervention first pigs
have their tails chopped off without anesthetic
then in a depraved attempt to reduce the
effects of industry induced aggression pigs
have up to eight teeth chopped off down to the
gum line with a pair of wire cutter-like devices
and finally to top off the barbarity their
testicles are ripped out as well oh in order
to mark them to keep track of them they have
holes punched in their ears it's called ear notch
can you imagine being hated so vehemently
that someone would rip out portions of your
ear or castrate you or cut your teeth off
down to the gum line all without anesthetic
did you know that the animal welfare act of the
1960s which happens to be a pathetic piece of
legislation kind of like our constitution when it
was first created which left out many more humans
than it ever led in originally the animal welfare
act unequivocally allows people to torture
enslave terrorize and murder all animals even
endangered ones if you apply for the proper permit
the animal welfare act is a how-to guide
to animal exploitation torture them this
way don't torture them that way and slave them
like this don't enslave them like that and kill
them this way don't kill them that way circuses
slaughterhouses and research labs love to say
hey gary hey peta leave us alone we're in
complete compliance with the animal welfare act
well my dear friends you'd have to be a vicious
idiot not to be in compliance with the animal
welfare act once again since the basis
of the awa is torture terror and murder
how could an animal exploiter not be in compliance
the awa's mandate for food and water does not ease
the terror nor stop the murder smithfield
the number one killer of pigs in the world
generates 8 billion dollars every year by
killing eleven hundred pigs every hour in
fact smithfield's five biggest concentration
camps kills 78 000 pigs every day you know what
government agencies in charge of enforcing the
awa the u.s department of agriculture the same
agency that oversees the murder of 10 billion
land animals seem a little incongruous why don't
we put pedophiles in charge of child protection
laws misogynist in charge of domestic abuse laws
and hunters in charge of wildlife management my
bad we do that one already little sidebar for you
every single state and national wildlife agency
is run solely by hunters and hunt supporters
period point blank there are no animal
rights humanitarians on these committees
you know how the hunting community always claims
that killing animals is sound scientific wildlife
management if that were the case and
how come in every single newspaper
in the usa hunting stories are always placed
in the sports section not the science section
of the 10 billion land animals killed for food
chickens represent 9 billion with
another 250 million enslaved on egg farms
now raised in huge buildings these factory farm
warehouses enslave anywhere from 5 thousand
to eighty thousand birds in one building eighteen
by twenty inch battery cages for the egg length
tens while the chickens the males are
strewn about in a chaotic free-for-all
the tiny battery cages are a staple of the egg
industry where 5 to 11 birds share one cage but
inside or outside of the cage these places
of horror deny natural behaviors to chickens
and hens like dust bathing preening and happily
roaming freely something we all take for granted
for the record hens prefer more space than 18
by 20 inches and chickens do not like to live
in groups larger than 30. therefore fighting
is common in the chicken and egg industries
how do they treat the fighting problem two ways
one ignore the situation two vicious intervention
chickens and hens are de-beaked
meaning the sensitive portion
top two-thirds of the beak is seared off with
a red hot blade heated to 800 degrees celsius
egg laying hens are shot off with so many
antibiotics they're forced to lay up to 300 eggs
every year because of this their uteruses have
been known to bleed and protrude from their bodies
when hens can't keep up with the demands of the
egg industry they don't go to sanctuaries people
they're sent to slaughterhouses and killed let's
not forget that egg farms have to breed birds
so there's always a fresh supply of hens to lay
eggs but upon hatching if those babies turn out
to be males in the egg industry they're considered
useless to the egg industry because they don't lay
eggs only females can do that so male babies are
put in plastic bags suffocated tossed in the trash
or they're thrown into huge rendering
machines where their live bodies are ground up
and used as feed bottom line whether it's an egg
length and a factory farmed chicken a free-range
chicken or an organically raised chicken they all
end up dead from unnatural causes because people
have acquired a taste for animal flesh comedian
dennis miller who was not an activist one
sarcastically yet truthfully made this statement
about free-range chicken farms free-range chickens
they all end up dead don't seem that free to
me don't be duped by the free range industry
cows turkeys ducks sheep and other animals
are subjected to the same barbaric treatment
bulls are castrated because cows are artificially
inseminated in fact nearly every male animal is
considered expendable because nowadays just
about every animal raised and killed for food
on this planet is artificially inseminated and
genetically engineered in case you don't believe
me i'm sure everybody read the latest edition of
pork everybody got their latest edition of pork in
the mail right right along with sports illustrated
newsweek cosmopolitan pork big industry trade
journal if you flip around the pages of pork
you'll find an advertisement for a ginetta pork
better pigs better pork better profits ginetta
pork better pigs better pork better profits
genetic one of dozens of companies now creating
the food that you eat every woman in this room
should think deeply about the frightening fact
of animal reproduction because many feminists
throughout history from annie besson and susan
b anthony to alice walker and gloria steinem
became animal rights humanitarians because these
great women not only understood that animals had
an inherent right to be free but these great
women understood that their non-human sisters
were being exploited for their reproductive organs
the female animal is viewed as nothing more than
a baby machine by the greedy callous malefactors
who run the animal flesh industry l.j taylor of
walls meat limited once said this in a national
hog farmer magazine i'm sure everybody has read
their latest edition of national hog farm the
breeding style should be thought of and treated
as a valuable piece of machinery whose function
is the pump out baby pigs the sausage machine
last year in the u.s alone 17 billion fish
shrimp lobsters and other aquatic animals
were killed and eaten many were raised on fish
farms they were genetically engineered yes
fish farms farming is not just
relegated to the land anymore
l.a times one of its 2002 editions bounty
farms one of dozens of companies now
creating fish genetically engineering them
if you look at the photo in the upper left
you'll notice that they have genetically altered a
salmon to be twice as big as its wild counterpart
the rest of the aquatic animals were either
hooked by the mouth or netted in huge trawlers
gigantic high-powered vacuum cleaners that
sucked up catch and kill everything in its
path in order to explain why fishing is cruel
vicious and unethical i decided to use an analogy
today to help you empathize imagine reaching for
an apple on a tree and having your hands suddenly
impaled by a metal hook that drags you the whole
weight of your body pulling on that one hand
dragging you out of the air and into an
atmosphere in which you cannot breathe
that is what aquatic animals experience
they are removed from their watery habitat
civil rights activist animal rights activist
humanitarian alice walker once eloquently summed
up the reason for animal freedom the animals of
the world exist for their own reasons they were
not made for humans any more than black people
were made for whites or women were created for men
go by the books diet for a new america or the food
revolution both by john robbins for an amazing
comprehensive look at veganism and john robbins
happens to be quite a remarkable individual
you might recognize him by his last
name if you think about it long enough
his family owns the billion dollar baskin robbins
ice cream empire however about 20 years ago
john robbins removed himself from the family
business because he wanted no part of an
industry that exploited and murdered cows and
no part of an industry that made people ill
by feeding them animal secretions cow's milk
is a secretion and secretions are filled with
delicious fluids like pus and mucus i hope you
realize that when a dairy cow can no longer give
quality milk or produce huge amounts of milk she's
sent to the slaughterhouse and killed there are
no cow sanctuaries in the dairy industry in fact
when it comes to pain and suffering the dairy cow
just might suffer more than any enslaved animal
on this planet chino california for instance
they had the largest concentration of dairy farms
on this planet more than 350 000 cows lived there
kept alive for three to seven years machines
hooked up to their udders for several hours
a day sucking milk out with hormones and
antibiotics forced into their bodies to make
them produce tremendous amounts of milk until they
can no longer produce tremendous amounts of milk
you know the dairy industry has done a masterful
job at convincing everyone that cows naturally
give milk i hope you don't believe that cows
are like any other female animal they can only
give milk during and after pregnancy so once a
year dairy cows are artificially impregnated to
keep the milk flow going and within two days of
giving birth within two days their babies are
taken away from them which is outright cruelty in
and of itself their babies are stolen from them
at birth most of the male babies sent off the
veal farms putting crates so tiny they're never
allowed to stand up ropes and chains put around
their necks to completely immobilize them and
prevent any muscle development whatsoever which
is why veal flesh is tender no muscle development
as for the females most of the females kept on
the dairy farm enslaved like their mothers they
will be turned into dairy cows as well the rest
of the females and some of the males sold to the
beef industry where they will be killed at nine
months of age thank you very much for listening
okay i'm going to take you guys on a
journey today and like all journeys in
life there's going to be ups and downs highs
and lows you're going to like certain parts
and dislike other parts in other words you
will love me and hate me today all at once
but if you listen with an open mind i promise at
the end of the speech the love will outweigh the
hate the first 30 minutes will be very intense i'm
going to make you feel angry frustrated and guilty
fortunately the last 15 minutes will be like
a comedy roast so we're gonna laugh and giggle
you guys are getting roasted by the way so i'm
gonna speak for around 45 minutes and then we'll
do a q a session after so hold your questions
until the end right now i want you to think
about how you would feel if the moment you were
born someone else had already planned the day
of your execution that's what it's like to be a
cow a pig a chicken or a turkey on this planet
they're not born free they're born to be murdered
even though freedom is supposed to be a birthright
a god-given right i mean no god would be
a slave master a torturer and a killer
of his animals his babies if he was then
he wouldn't be god he'd be the devil
if that statement shocks you or brings up feelings
of animosity towards me the problem isn't with me
and what i've just said the problem is that humans
have victimized animals to such a degree that they
aren't even considered victims they aren't even
considered at all they're nothing they don't count
they don't matter they're commodities like tv sets
and cell phones we've actually turned animals into
inanimate objects sandwiches and shoes it
is the greatest magic trick ever performed
the animation switch and besides the money
made from selling their flesh and skin and
the things that come out of their bodies there's
not even decent value on them as inanimate objects
the american flag for example which is nothing
but a piece of fabric the bible which is nothing
but a book comprised of ink and paper stir
up more emotions than the murder of animals
if there were a barbecue near campus today and
people were cooking up steaks and hamburgers man
there'd be a party people would actually celebrate
the cow who was killed the person who killed the
cow and the chef that seasoned her dead body but
if someone poured gasoline on the flag or a bible
struck a match and set it on fire lord have
mercy there'd be an angry mob ready to kill
somebody these lifeless inanimate objects the flag
in the bible are more sacred than animals living
feeling breathing beings animals are victims the
most oppressed ever and if you're having a tough
time grasping this fact maybe it's because
the only time you ever come into contact
with cows and chickens and turkeys is when
they're cut up and cooked on your dinner table
so good afternoon everybody my name is gary
yourofsky i'm a vegan animal liberation activist
i'm not a politician and i'm not a salesperson
that means i got no lies to tell you and no books
and no dvds to sell you before i continue i want
to define the word vegan for everybody v-e-g-a-n
vegans just like vegetarians do not consume the
meat of any land or marine animal vegans however
unlike vegetarians also refrain from eating cheese
milk eggs honey any animal product whatsoever
we also don't wear animal skin no fur leather wool
silk or down i want to let you know that i was not
raised vegan i ate meat cheese milk and eggs
for around 25 years and like most people
i always thought that i cared about
animals because i loved dogs and cats
who were chipmunks and squirrels until one day
after seeing some animals backstage at a circus
chained up and caged up i not only
realized that i was witnessing a slave show
i realized i was a hypocrite a bigot a speciesist
just like a racist who believes that their race is
more special and more important than all the other
races a speciesist believes that humans are more
special and more important than all the animals
and therefore have the right to enslave and kill
any species they choose but if you honestly
place yourself in the animal's position
looking at this issue from the victim's point
of view being denied your freedom and the right
to live a long healthy life and then imagine
yourself confined in a concentration camp truck
on your way to a slaughterhouse so someone could
slice your throat and cut you up into pieces
i'm pretty sure you would understand
why the psychotic addictions of meat
cheese milk and eggs must be abolished if you eat
animals and the things that come out of animals
you are intentionally causing pain and suffering
and polluting your soul with the blood of innocent
beings humanity's main focus should always be
extending compassion to others not engaging in
rituals and traditions that are based on cruelty
there's a massacre taking place right now it's the
world's largest and longest-running massacre of
all time because every second of every minute of
every hour of every day female animals are raped
to impregnate them so we can steal their babies
separate families from each other so we
can kill them and sell their flesh and skin
if that's not the definition of injustice
of an atrocity then i'd like to know what is
you do realize that if you went to the
nearest cow or chicken slaughterhouse
and remove the animals and then
replace them with human beings
all of a sudden it's a tragedy auschwitz
is resurrected slave ships sail again
and don't think i'm the first person to make
these valid comparisons civil rights activist
dick gregory once said when i look at animals
held captive by circuses i think of slavery
animals and circuses represent domination and
oppression they wear the same chains and shackles
isaac bashevis singer who escaped nazi occupied
poland once condemned our speciesistic world when
he said what do they know all these scholars all
these philosophers all the leaders of the world
they have convinced themselves that man the worst
transgressor of all the species is the crown of
creation and all the animals were made for us to
be food and pelts to be tormented and exterminated
in relation to animals all humans are nazis
for the animals it is an eternal treblinka
now i know these statements sound
pretty harsh and controversial to you
but that doesn't mean they aren't true the fact
that anyone would fight against veganism against
animal liberation which means you are against
compassion just proves how completely irrational
meat dairy and egg eaters can be vegans
are only asking you to change what you eat
not who you are stay jewish christian or catholic
stay muslim buddhist hindu atheist agnostic stay
left or right in politics if you honestly
place yourself in the animal's position
there's no way you can justify the things that
we do to them and walk away from today's speech
saying that you don't care the ethical compass
that most people use to gauge right from wrong
is the golden rule do unto others as you
would have others do unto you since no one
in this room wants to be treated the way we treat
cows and pigs and chickens and turkeys and fish
there's no need to search for an excuse
today not to be vegan 60 billion land animals
90 billion marine animals are killed every year on
this planet for a sandwich for addictions of greed
and gluttony what kind of society justifies mass
murder stop thinking that animals aren't victims
because they aren't human it's the mindset of the
victimizer that's wrong and this is what needs to
be examined and corrected because it never changes
no matter who the victim is have you noticed it
always goes something like this no you don't count
no you don't matter no i'm more important than you
i laugh at the suffering i inflict on you i'll
kill you and your family whenever i want however i
want prove to me why i should be kind to you it is
not your right to deny someone else their freedom
and their rights so you can harm them enslave them
and kill them that's not what rights are about
that's injustice there is no counter argument
to veganism except that you can't be right all
the time apologize for the way you've been
living make amends and evolve move forward
now all throughout history there's a pretty
good reason why most people most good people
have always been on the wrong side of what's
right and that's because the truth has never been
accepted overnight it always has to pass through
three stages first it is mocked and ridiculed
second stage denial and violent opposition
people refuse people refuse to believe there's
an atrocity taking place and they fight tooth
and nail to keep the status quo as is third stage
acceptance there is no longer need to explain
it because we all get it now unfortunately it
usually takes hundreds sometimes thousands of
years for the truth to pass through these stages
i'm going to try and do it
today in around 45 minutes
and in order for the truth to be accepted and
understood we do have to witness the atrocities
the five and a half minute video we're about to
watch that footage was taken throughout america
britain and israel and if you feel the need to
turn away or close your eyes during this video
you should probably ask yourself a question
if it's not good enough for my eyes
then why is it good enough for my stomach and
before i press play i have to say something about
all this humane meat humane milk humane eggs [
__ ] that's going on in our society right now
that stuff does not exist under any circumstances
whatsoever even when animals reside in cage-free
free range grass-fed local organic antibiotic-free
facilities by definition alone slavery and
slaughter are radically cruel and can never
be humane so don't be so gullible with slick
marketing ads that want to convince you that
animals enjoy being on the menu as if they're
all saying hey stab me yeah kill me sure take
everything from me because that's why i'm here
just for you and if for some reason my aforesaid
words in this video we're about to watch
aren't proof enough of the terrorism claims that
i am hurling at the meat dairy and egg industries
maybe the dismembered bodies of 150 billion
animals annually could count as proof
do
foreign
so
i am forever embarrassed to be a human being to
stand upright like that's something to be proud of
did you ever wonder why mcdonald's and burger
king and wendy's never use those images in
their tv ads no severed heads dismembered limbs
corpses blood guts always showing you a happy
singing smiling cartoon caricature
instead lying to you brainwashing you
and programming you not to care about
things you would normally care about
things that you used to care about when you were
young innocent and uncorrupted by society's lies
so how come if the animals in that video were
dogs and cats people would be outraged and if they
were kids the world would scream bloody murder
instead the victims are cows and chickens and fish
and all of a sudden it's okay so i am a
little confused here is the slaughterhouse
the problem or is the problem just who's
getting killed in the slaughterhouse
because it's a house of slaughter why does it
even exist especially when peace begins at the
dinner table with what you put into your body on a
daily basis good people don't talk about kindness
they practice it and they certainly don't pray
about love on the weekends for an hour or two they
actually give it all the time i know you have
the capability of understanding right from wrong
because you all hate people who harm children why
not hate people who harm animals it's hypocritical
why protect one victim and then violate and
ignore the other victim when neither victim wants
nor deserves the abuse they just wish it would end
stop praising the innocents in children and then
ignoring and making fun of the exact same
innocence in the animals and everyone has
to stop making these idiotic claims that
humans are the only ones who are capable
of being rational and aware and that animals
operate on instinct only can i explain something
everybody in a pretty simple way breathing
is instinctive everything else is a thought
attached to an action it's not an accident
that animals can build a home if given a chance
and return to that home but they can care for
their babies that they can find shade on a sunny
day or seek warmth when it's cold figure out when
to sleep or stay awake locate water to drink fly
in a bee formation hide when they don't want to
be seen defend their territories all these actions
prove beyond a reasonable doubt that animals
have the capacity of being rational and aware
the human animal is the only animal that spends
the majority of time not thinking eating at steak
and shake in the golden corral and applebee's
and long john silvers is not rational thought
but this isn't a competition of intelligence or
awareness this is about justice when we were kids
each and every single one of us when our parents
our grandparents sat us down and read us a story
that story was about animals and when that
story was read to us we smiled and giggled
uncontrollably we even mimicked the noises they
made their language we wanted to play with them
so badly not have someone shove a knife in
their throat and cut them up into pieces
what happened to you along the way who
stole your empathy and your conscience
because they stole mine too and they got me good
but i got it all back and that's the only reason
i'm here today to try and help you get yours
back as well most people eat dairy products three
times a day but you can't even get a sandwich
anymore without cheese people put cheese and meat
on salads too and by the way if you're
eating a salad with meat and cheese on it
it's not a salad stop that [ __ ] it's a sandwich
without the bread all chopped up little pieces put
inside of a bowl spare me the chicken salad tuna
salad crap a salad is comprised of vegetables and
plant products only and if you're lucky enough
to find this vegetable only salad somewhere
what's the first thing people have
to say to the waiter like an addict
yeah hey uh can i get some ranch or some thousand
island can you please pour some dairy all over
these vegetables for me so in our society where
everybody is hooked on dairy i mean hooked like
it's been laced with cocaine and percocet most
people can't even fathom one meal little in one
day or a lifetime without cheese in fact if you
want to know why vegetarians never become vegans
cheese cheese on a baked potato cheese on a
broccoli cheese on everything and say even
lactose intolerant people eat cheese i want to
spend a little more time right now condemning the
dairy industry because when it comes to cruelty
i think there's more cruelty in a piece of cheese
and a glass of milk in yogurt than there is in
meat first of all most hamburger meat comes from
the dairy industry when cows can't produce
huge amounts of milk after three to seven years
slaughterhouse if given a chance god forbid cows
can live to be 18 to 25 and cows are like all
female mammals listen i don't mean to be speaking
down anybody if that's how you're taking this
it's just that when i'm talking to addicts about
their addictions addicts have a tendency to become
irrational and illogical i know you understand
this concept you just never think about it when
it comes to the animals female mammals can only
produce and give milk during or after pregnancy
so once a year every cow on every dairy farm
is raped to impregnate her long steel device
shoved in her vagina to inject her with bull
scene and sometimes you just use a bare hand
to do it got to get that milk flow going somehow
and later on after she gives birth her newborn
baby is stolen away a couple months later they
repeat the process all over again one of the
worst screams i have ever heard and i've heard
them all firsthand i've been to slaughterhouses
vivisection labs behind the scenes of every
circus and rodeo that were passed through michigan
one of the worst screams i've ever heard
stealing newborn babies from their mothers
and why would they steal newborn babies from
their moms well the dairy industry can't have
calves sucking up all that milk that was meant
for them and they'd rather sell it to you instead
every time you have dairy some calf does
not and mother cows make milk for one reason
for their babies case clothes forever no debate
no discussion the jury is in they certainly don't
make milk for baby elephants and baby orangutans
and baby hedgehogs baby rabbits baby rats baby
humans adolescent humans or adult humans this
body of ours has absolutely no need for cow milk
like it has absolutely no need for giraffe
milk and zebra milk and rhinoceros milk and
hippopotamus milk chamomile goat milk horse milk
pig milk dog milk or cat milk the only milk that
we ever need comes from our own mother our species
that's it and after the first few years of life we
never need one drop of milk ever again and don't
think i don't watch your faces when i'm up here
that's what i do when i'm preaching i'm watching
all your expressions how come when i talk about
tofu and pizzas without cheese boy catch a
couple people in every classroom start to
wrinkle up their noses a little eyes get a little
wide and bold just start glancing around the room
with your friends like tofu is this good crazy
tempeh must be out of his mind what the hell is
seitan seitan by the way not satan seitan it is
wheat meat it is meat that is made from wheat
so how come tofu and even fruits and veggies
are considered gross to most people but meat
time to break meat down for everybody
you got five components to meat
blood flesh veins muscles and tendons the
cut up corpse of a dismembered body how
does meat not qualify as disgusting and gross to
everybody how in the world is a liquid a liquid
that oozes out of a cow's udder a secretion that's
loaded with pus that drips from an animal's body
how is this not considered gross oh and let me
tell you about the pus in the cow's milk it could
be my pleasure when you hook machines up to the
udders of cows three times a day to suck them dry
those machines cause massive amounts of
infections and irritations on the inside
and outside of the utter then when you add all
the bovine growth hormone and all the genetic
engineering that's been done to a cow's body
to make sure she produces huge amounts of milk
which always leads to another infection the
machine doesn't know what not to suck out pus
and mucus and infections right into the milk
and yes milk is pasteurized but exactly when
did pasteurization become a removal process
last time i checked it was a sanitation process
meaning you're only sanitizing pus and if you
want to look this up online well you don't think
the dairy industry would ever use the word pus
when they write about this problem in their own
trade journals do you now they're going to deceive
you again look up the scientific term for pus
somatic cell count s-o-m-a-t-i-c oh and
let's talk about some other disgusting
things that you guys love to eat did you know
that the back side of a bird is called a cloaca
c-l-o-a-c-a it was the only scene in the video
you could pop that back in if you want to see
it's one hole it is one whole but it serves
many purposes it's the poop hole it's the pee
hole it's the vaginal fluid hole and it's the hole
where your omelettes and scrambled eggs come from
yeah i remember back in the day used to love
my scrambled eggs with [ __ ] sprinkles urine
splattering goo juice all over it too because
you know when you crack that shell over the
ball all those microscopic particles fly
every which way and if you guys think it's
normal and natural to eat something that's been
marinating in feces and urine for hours and hours
i got a brand new challenge for everybody i always
like to have a new challenge every single semester
this is the egg challenge when you get home
from school later today i want you go to the
bathroom fill her up everything don't flush
though then i want you to stroll on over to
the kitchen open up the fridge grab yourself
an egg take it back to the toilet drop it in
if you even have the courage to stick your hand
in there and grab it back out and you can wash
it when you're done bleach it do whatever you
want to it are you still gonna want to eat it
and that's your own [ __ ] that's your waist now
you're talking about a hand that you don't even
know her butthole and what about vomit come on you
guys love vama you adore some vomit in on and all
over your food better give this one a pretty name
no no one's gonna want to buy any vomit unless we
call it honey instead honey comes directly from
a bee's stomach it's regurgitated right through
a bee's mouth you can look that up with any
wildlife biologist but nobody wants to eat
bee vomit nut cheerios we want honey nut cheerios
so we lie to ourselves and play euphemism games
the standard diet of a meat dairy and egg eater is
blood flesh veins muscles tendons cow secretions
things that come out of a hen's ass and b vomit
and we're not done yet i'm not going to let you
off the hook that easily while i got you here
today because we top it all off in my opinion
because every single year when people start
cooking turkeys for the holidays boy people take
a dead turkey carve out a really big hole in that
dead turkey's ass take some stuffing and shove it
inside their dead empty ass and use their little
dead ass as an oven to bake some bread somebody
else's dead empty bacteria laying ass to make
bread ass bread and people think vegans are weird
because we eat tofu i tell people one of
my favorite meals nowadays yams and barley
hook me up with some yams and barley for
breakfast lunch or dinner and i'm a happy guy
i know most people although i tell
them this and they're like what
you just eat vegetables and grains for dinner
yeah i don't know man that's kind of weird
okay somebody else's rib cage sitting
on your plate that's not weird
severed legs sliced up thighs and mutilated
breasts on your plate isn't weird and doesn't
make you think twice is bestiality weird anybody
doing sexual things with animals because i used
to think everybody thought so but not even
close my meat cheese milk egg loving friends
because you engage in carnivorous bestiality
on a daily basis sometimes multiple times a day
you eat things that come out of the hen's
ass and shove things into a turkey's ass
you eat breast legs and thighs and then you pay
somebody else to sexually molest a cow and squeeze
her nipples for you so you can steal her milk man
you guys are obsessed with bird asses and cow tits
enough already seriously is it
possible to step into the 21st century
and stop mimicking the behavior of cavemen
and cave women you got a choice today
when you leave this room you can choose
to never intentionally harm another animal
for breakfast lunch or dinner ever again
these animals have never violated you or
taken advantage of you in any way the
least you can do is return the favor
or stay radically cruel keep the status quo as
is make sure animals have their babies stolen
from them make sure their horns are cut off
be sliced off testicles ripped out make sure
they're raped make sure they never experience
one drop of human kindness and make sure there's
a knife in their throat every second of every
minute of every hour of every day for eternity
i hope you make the right choice isn't it rough
enough being an animal on this planet with us
around as we claim everything for us the
land is ours we pollute the air the water
destroy the forest and the mountains do we have to
maximize the cruelty that they already endure by
eating them on top of it all you want to talk
about pouring salt into somebody else's wombs
98 and i want to leave you with this stat 98 of
animals who are abused and killed on this planet
are abused and killed by the meat dairy and egg
industries the least we can do is minimize the
cruelty by living a vegan lifestyle i want to
thank you guys for listening i do appreciate
the open minds that's out there today hello
everyone my name is kate timko before gary
begins with the formal presentation this evening
i'd like everyone to stop and think for a moment
stop and think about the certain rights and
freedoms that many human beings have just received
over the last 150 years now these are rights and
freedoms that many of us take for granted we don't
think about every single day for instance 150
years ago and in the grand scheme of things really
that's just a blip but 150 years ago in america
we still had slavery 100 years ago not one child
in the united states had any rights whatsoever 85
years ago women could not vote and 40 years ago
only 40 years ago segregation was still thriving
in america meaning that black people could not
drink from the same water fountain as white people
only 40 years ago now one of the most amazing
traits that human beings possess is our short-term
selective memory process now we do love to believe
we've been good decent compassionate to each
other for a very very long time but decency and
compassion are pretty much brand new concepts
when it comes to the treatment of most human
beings now it is our hope that in the next 150
years we will all continue to evolve with decency
continue to evolve with compassion and extend it
to the entire animal kingdom humans and animals
together the entire animal kingdom so if anyone
came in today thinking animal rights is radical
or extreme outrageous or maybe even silly please
stop and think about those certain rights and
freedoms that human beings have just received over
the last 150 years and then one could logically
conclude that animals will be the next group of
disenfranchised beings to obtain their freedom
so i guess it's safe to say that this room is full
of people who eat meat i'm sure most people here
own shoes or belts or jackets made from the
skin of cows kate and i used to wear leather
shoes belts and jackets too and i ate meat for 25
years k-8 meat 4 23 before i talk about veganism
in detail all the ethical and health reasons
for living a vegan lifestyle and discuss what
it's like to be an animal in the food industry i
want to talk about the blinders that everyone has
on blinders that kate and i used to have
on too blinders that absolutely destroy
compassion blinders that make people unconcerned
about cruelty and killing and blinders that
give some people the audacity to laugh and make
jokes about the suffering of animals now those
blinders were not attached to us or anyone
else with malice a forethought necessarily
but the truth has been hidden from us
nonetheless today's speech will give you
the opportunity to write many horrible wrongs if
you give us 60 minutes of an open mind tonight
we promise you will walk out of this
room more ethical than when you came in
so instead of trying to find an excuse tonight
not to be vegan we're sincerely asking that you
find an excuse tonight to be vegan and i just
want to clarify the word vegan for everybody
vegans and vegetarians don't consume
the meat of any land or marine animal
but the difference between vegans and vegetarians
is that vegans don't consume milk cheese eggs or
any animal product whatsoever and keep this
in mind as well the best thing about veganism
there are millions of christian jewish muslim
buddhist black white asian latino male female
pro-life pro-choice pro-gun and anti-gun vegans
and millions of people who label themselves
republicans or democrats or independents are
vegan too matthew scully the senior speechwriter
for george w bush recently wrote a book called
dominion it's a right-wing faith-based christian
conservative views supporting veganism
and animal rights because your ethnicity
religious affiliation and political party have
no bearing no bearing on eating a veggie burger
tonight instead of a hamburger you see if you
honestly put yourself in the position of an animal
who is enslaved in the food industry confined to
an artificial world denied your freedom denied the
right to live a long healthy life denied sunlight
most of the time and then imagine yourself being
stuffed into a transport truck to be shipped to
your death hung upside down by your legs at the
slaughterhouse so someone could cut your throat
dismember your body so someone else could cook
it and eat it if you honestly put yourself in
that animal's position there is no way you can
justify the things that we do to animals and
walk away from today's speech saying that you
don't care the ethical compass that most people
use to gauge right from wrong is the golden rule
treat others like you would want to be treated do
unto others as you would have done unto you since
no one in this room wants to be treated like a
cow a pig or a chicken there's really no reason to
search for an excuse tonight not to be vegan now
we're going to show a graphic four minute video
about where food comes from at the slaughterhouse
and the video you're going to see is the harsh
truth but i want everyone to remember throughout
what german philosopher arthur schopenhauer once
said about truth schopenhauer stated that
all truth everything that we hold to be true
has to pass through three stages now first it is
ridiculed second it is violently opposed and third
it is finally accepted as being self-evident so
which stage of truth do you find yourself in now
and which stage of truth might you be in if
you give us an open mind an hour from now
thank you
down
so
now not that any law could ever alleviate
the suffering and slaughter that you folks
just witnessed but i want to read an excerpt to
everyone right now from the animal welfare act
of 1966 this is a pathetic piece of legislation
if and i say if if you can even call this a law
because the animal welfare act states verbatim
that the term animal excludes birds rats
mice horses and other farm animals such as but not
limited to livestock and poultry and anything used
or intended to be used as food or clothing it also
states that the term exhibitor excludes retail pet
stores organizations sponsoring state and county
fairs livestock shows rodeos purebred dog and cat
shows and any fair or exhibition intended
to advance agricultural arts and sciences
that's some law they've laid out for the animals
but even if this animal welfare act decided to
include all of the animals you just heard
it leaves out i want to be clear about this
there is no peaceful compassionate way to shoot an
animal between their eyes or slice their throats
it is the taking of an animal's life that is the
ultimate violation all of the mutilations that
happen to these animals along the way which we're
going to discuss in a moment only serve to prove
that animals have been reduced to objects they
are mere commodities that have to meet certain
specifications in order to maximize profits and
during this speech when we say the word farm we
are not just speaking about factory farms we are
talking about all farms factory free range organic
and mom-and-pop farms because all farms that raise
animals for food kill animals for food so all we
ask from here on out is that you folks give us
an open mind and truly hear what we're about to
tell you now each year in the us we kill about 10
billion land animals and 18 billion marine animals
because people have acquired a taste for meat
and i stress acquired a taste for meat worldwide
the numbers are staggering about 45 to 50 billion
land animals and about 85 billion marine animals
are killed and eaten every year on this planet now
in america we kill and eat more than 100 million
pigs every single year and for their entire lives
the female pigs are locked up in tiny crates and
stalls so they can be forcibly impregnated against
their will with long steel devices that shoot hog
semen into their uterus basically they are the
unwilling baby machines of the meat industry
and when female pigs can no longer make babies
after years of being forcibly impregnated
they're shipped off to the slaughterhouse and
killed now meanwhile shortly after birth the
male piglets they have their tiny bodies mutilated
in four horrific ways first somebody holds them
upside down and cuts their tail off without
anesthetic because tail biting is common in
the overcrowded unnatural conditions of today's
farms and then each baby pig has anywhere from
two to eight teeth cut off they actually cut their
teeth off down to the gum line with a pair of wire
cutter like devices so when they go to fight and
bite each other there are no teeth to damage the
flesh and since female pigs are forced to produce
twice as many piglets in captivity than they
would in the wild teeth cutting is also a big
money maker for the meat industry cutting teeth
allows the mother to nurse even more piglets who
will eventually be killed for profit because when
the babies suckle without teeth wear and tear
on the mother's nipples is kept to a minimum
and they're always marking pigs to keep track
of them so they rip out portions of their ears
it's called ear notching and then finally in
a sick attempt and i repeat a sick attempt to
pacify the industry-induced anger of the male pigs
their testicles are ripped out as well and that's
castration without anesthetic now castration
also gives the meat industry complete control
over reproduction because natural reproduction in
the meat industry in this day and age is obsolete
neither god nor evolution created 10 billion
land animals in this country alone every year
human beings did that and that is because every
aspect of raising animals for food is controlled
from genetic engineering and artificial
insemination to quoting and killing
this is why many females empathize with the
animal rights movement and practice veganism
humanitarian patrice jones once explained that
women and animals along with land and children
have historically been seen as the property of
male households women and animals are viewed as
less rational and both suffer by being reduced
to their bodies or even worse their body parts
now of the 10 billion land animals killed and
eaten in america every year about 9 billion 9
billion of those are chickens on egg farms they'll
stuff anywhere from five to eleven hens into each
tiny battery cage with that many hens in a single
cage you can imagine fighting is very common
which is why these hens have the top two thirds of
their beaks sliced off it's called de-beaking they
actually slice off a portion of the beak with
a red-hot blade heated to 800 degrees celsius
so that when they go to fight and peck each other
they have no beaks to damage each other's flesh
and with chemicals and other drugs that are
injected into their feed each hen is forced to
produce around 300 eggs every year until of course
her egg production tapers off and then she's
killed without exception each and every egg-laying
hen is killed so egg farms will also breed birds
so there's always a fresh supply of hens to lay
the eggs but if babies in the hatchery turn out
to be male pretty obvious they're completely
useless to an egg industry and they are killed
off instantly they're either thrown into the
trash alive and crying out for their lost mothers
or they're thrown into huge rendering machines
alive so that they can be ground up and used
as feed for other animals on chicken farms
they'll have anywhere between twenty thousand
and thirty thousand birds in each building
after six or seven weeks of concentration camp
like conditions and living in tons of feces and
urine they are killed too their bodies are then
soaked in a chlorine bath to remove the slime and
odor off their carcasses and then placed on your
dinner plate see no one wants to admit it but
eating meat really does mean eating a dead body
and eating meat means that your body has been
reduced to nothing more than a walking graveyard
of murdered animals and very quickly i want
to destroy this myth about free-range farms
now according to government regulations free-range
chickens raised for their flesh or for their eggs
are only required to have access to an outside
area meaning that most of these birds never
even get to see the light of day because having
access and actually being allowed getting to go
outside are two completely different things
now even if these birds manage to fight their
way outside these outside areas they're given
are usually no bigger than a standard backyard
so that's a few thousand chickens in a single
backyard how much happy space would you have
if you had to share your backyard with a few
thousand people the term free range is a scam and
all free range chickens end up dead anyway they
really don't seem that free to me but the term
free range is used to trick people into believing
that meat and egg production can be done happily
and humanely but really the only happy and humane
way is just not to kill them i want to talk about
cattle ranching for a moment because each year
in america we kill and eat about 37 million cows
and at first these animals are allowed to graze on
large grassy fields for about six months but after
that it's straight to the feedlot where there's
no grass no enclosed shelter just dirt and piles
and piles and piles of manure and these feedlots
have anywhere from a few hundred to a hundred
thousand cows there now for about ten months on
the feed lot the cows get fed corn and protein
supplements to fatten them up quickly but
many other things get mixed into their feed
many things you should be aware of many nasty
things like manure animal blood and the ground
up bodies of animals who didn't grow quickly
enough are the ones that died from disease
before they reach the slaughterhouse the
downed animals this is why mad cow disease and
other animal diseases like avian bird flu should
concern everyone who eats meat because it is still
perfectly legal and the standard operating
procedure of the meat industry to feed the
diseased ground up bodies of horses pigs chickens
and turkeys back to the cows the sheep and the
goats and vice versa anything to save a buck now
turkeys and ducks and sheep and other animals
they go through the same barbaric treatment too
like chickens turkeys have a portion of their
beak sliced off of the red hot blade while
ducks and geese have long steel poles shoved
down their throats to force feed them to fatten
up their livers to ten times their natural size
after killing them their liver is then turned
into a pate known as foie gras and sheep in the
wool industry when these gentle creatures can
no longer produce good quality wool any more
profitable to the clothing industry they're killed
too because bottom line when it's time to make a
profit off an animal or that animal's body is
no longer profitable the meat dairy egg and
clothing industries always always put a bullet
between the animal's eyes or slice their throat
now of the 18 billion marine animals that are
killed and eaten in america every year many
of them believe it or not were raised on fish
farms where they were genetically engineered
fish farm salmon they have fish farms nowadays
miracles of science the rest of these aquatic
animals are either hooked by the mouth or
they're netted in huge trawlers which are
basically just giant high-powered vacuum cleaners
and they'll suck up catch and kill anything and
everything that happens to be in its path now
to demonstrate to you folks why we believe that
fishing is cruel violent and unethical we've
come up with an analogy to help you empathize
now imagine for a moment that you're taking
a walk on a warm pretty bright sunny day
down a nice dirt country back
road and you spot an apple tree
fruit tree and you're hungry you've been walking
for a while so you reach up for a piece of fruit
but suddenly your hand is impaled by a large
metal hook that pulls you and drags you now
please keep in mind that's the whole entire weight
of your body pulling and dragging on your one hand
pulling and dragging you out of the air and
into an atmosphere in which you cannot breathe
see that is exactly what aquatic animals
experience when they're removed from their
watery habitats folks all we're really asking
of you of anyone that we ever do this lecture
for to actually do is just eat what comes from
the ground okay that's it and believe me it is
natural it is full of vitamins minerals nutrients
protein calcium iron potassium anything and
everything that the human body needs comes from
the ground really that's where it all comes from
fruits and vegetables nuts seeds grains legumes
tofu even though i know that's still a funny word
to a lot of people see these things cannot harm
you now when you eat what walks on the ground
that is unnatural it is full of death disease
and violence the human body does not get what
it needs from a meat-based diet diseases come
and have been proven to come time and time again
from meat and dairy and i'm still looking for the
first medical report in history that can indict
broccoli or bananas or carrots or apples as a
cause of illness i want to take a few moments
now and destroy this myth about human beings being
on top of the food chain because tools and weapons
power and intelligence have not magically
transformed our physiology and turned us into
carnivores or omnivores sharks lions tigers bears
wolves hyenas jackals even most dogs could easily
kill a human being in fact most herbivores like
rhinos elephants hippos horses bulls and gorillas
could easily kill a human being if provoked these
animals have always been ahead of us on the food
chain because killing during a one-on-one
confrontation without the use of weapons
and the ability to consume bloody raw flesh right
from the bone without the side effect of disease
have always been the only two true factors in
determining placement on the food chain this
is why most medical experts will attest to the
fact that human beings are completely herbivorous
creatures dr william roberts editor-in-chief of
the american journal of cardiology states quite
simply human beings are not natural carnivores
because when we kill animals to eat them
they end up killing us because their flesh was
never intended for human beings who are natural
herbivores the dairy industry has done a pretty
masterful job at convincing most people that cows
naturally give milk i really hope you don't
believe that i still come across children to this
day you know the age-old we've got to milk them
and they'll explode female cows are like any other
female mammal on this planet they only give milk
during and after pregnancy which is why every year
like clockwork they are artificially inseminated
it keeps their milk flow going and within a few
days of giving birth their babies are stolen from
them they are breaking up families now they steal
their babies from them at birth because from a
business standpoint you can't have a whole bunch
of little baby cows sucking up all the precious
milk they want to sell to us humans where do male
babies go on a dairy farm males obviously don't
give milk completely useless but unlike the male
baby chicks they've discovered a use for them they
are shipped off to the veal farm where they're put
in tiny little crates and kept in the dark to keep
them quiet ropes and chains around their necks to
keep keep them completely immobilized see that
is why veal is such a tender meat no movement is
ever allowed on behalf of these animals because
no muscle development is ever allowed they want
these animals to get to a large weight more meat
to sell but still retain their infant white flesh
but if you knew all of that about veal and you
don't eat it because you feel for little baby boy
cows and i mean really who wouldn't if you don't
eat veal but you do drink milk and eat cheese
eat veal you can eat veal to your heart's content
because it doesn't make a bit of difference the
veal industry is only in existence because of the
dairy industry and once again that's their words
not mine and we kind of talked about this already
but everyone in this room knows why a cow really
makes milk right a mother cow makes milk for her
babies so cow's milk is meant for a baby cow just
like human milk is meant for a baby human the
human body has no more need for cow's milk than
we do for dog milk giraffe milk rhinoceros milk
zebra milk i promise you there will come a day
when our grandchildren will ask us where were you
during the animal holocaust and what did you do
to stop these horrifying crimes will you be
able to say that you stood up against oppression
even when doing so was
considered radical or unpopular
so please please reevaluate your belief systems
ask yourself why is all this violence against
animals being permitted for what reasons we
hope you'll have the same revelation that we did
that non-violence through veganism
non-violence through animal liberation
is the only ethical and acceptable way to live
on this planet thank you very much for listening
i just recently read this story about this nazi
his name was ernst gerbel he and his men were
executing children one day but he didn't like the
way his guards were grabbing kids by their hair
before they shot him in the back of the head and
tossed him in a mass grave he actually ordered his
men to stop grabbing the kids by their hair
and i quote kill them in a more decent way
that story sickens me as much as the stories
that meat cheese milk and egg eaters love to
tell hey gary i only eat free range freedom eggs
hey gary i only eat animals who are raised and
killed humanely on a cage-free organic farm there
is no such thing as humane when it comes to meat
cheese milk and eggs humane slaughter humane rape
humane slavery humane holocaust do not exist and
if for some reason my aforesaid words and the
video we just watched aren't proof enough of
the terrorism claims that i am loving against the
meat dairy and egg industries and humanity itself
i don't know maybe the billions of dead
dismembered animal bodies could count
as proof peace begins at the dinner table with
what you put into your body on a daily basis good
people don't talk about kindness they practice it
they don't pray about love they actually give it
i know you have the capability of understanding
right from wrong because you all hate people
who harm children why not despise people who
harm animals it's hypocritical why protect one
and violate the other when neither one wants nor
deserves the abuse they just wish it would end
up
foreign
uh you will hear the translation in your
ear and when we talk to you we'll
translate simultaneously as best
foreign
one of the fears of the ministry of
education is the way that you choose to um to
provoke your agenda i think and in schools they
might they might think that it's inappropriate
what do you think first of all i'm here to speak
on behalf of the most oppressed most abused most
murdered group of beings that has ever existed the
animals i speak against speciesism in the same way
nelson mandela spoke against racism in the same
way dr martin luther king and malcolm x and rosa
parks spoke against the evils of racism and when
we teach children that the jewish holocaust was
evil but then we send animals to their death to
the slaughterhouses and the same extermination
trucks that sent jews to their death we're
committing a gross error we're teaching them that
it's okay to disregard animal life that human life
is more sacred than animals when every creature on
this planet values their life just like humans
value their life there's nothing wrong with it
because
do you want to call kids murderers or their
parents murderers in their faces in their schools
i call human beings murderers of animals that's
what we do that's the truth the truth is harsh
i understand it's tough for people to look
in the mirror and say my goodness i've been
doing something wrong for so long but there's
nothing wrong with admitting that you've been
doing something wrong and to make amends and move
forward but my question is kids that maybe choose
to be vegetarians from now on but will think
that their parents are murderers i mean you you
maybe you will destroy all the or the um you'll
destroy the family in a way to save the family
maybe the kids can teach their parents something
for a change because parents don't know everything
and i'm tired of everybody thinking mommy
and daddy know how the world works mommy and
daddy are just as clueless about the world as
everyone else but mommy and daddy are murderers
and if 60 billion land animals end up cut into
pieces what is it if it's not murder a party
yeah so gary you came here for three
weeks to give endless lectures in schools
now you don't have the lectures what you're going
to do now i do have lectures i have lectures in
colleges i have lectures at auditorium set up
and i'd like to know if you want to ask her
in hebrew what's the effect of lying to kids and
hiding the truth to kids we wonder why humans are
such a messed up species we can't get along with
each other we have wars we have discrimination
we have sexism heterosexism anti-semitism it's
because we don't teach that speciesism is evil
and it's the root of all hatred all the branches
of hatred racism and sexism stem from speciesism
what's wrong with teaching the truth the school
is supposed to be a place of learning of education
not deceit and propaganda which is what they do
they teach kids that it's okay to rape animals and
steal their babies and kill them and sell their
flesh and skin they tell kids that it's okay to
eat things that come out of a hen's ass they tell
kids it's okay to eat things that drip from animal
utters they tell kids it's okay to eat flesh
and blood and people are upset with me we'll try
is
foreign hello gary good afternoon welcome
to the show uh glad to have you here uh
quite an astonishing relationship with the israeli
community you are developing right absolutely
beautiful tell me about it i mean it's amazing
what's going on here people are listening to the
speech it's the most viewed speech in the history
of israel which is pretty amazing considering
what's been going on here for the last 50 60 70
years i find that people who have been oppressed
certainly understand oppression more
than others so i think that's why
israelis are really taking to
this message of animal liberation
and it's thrilling to know that people are paying
attention and making massive change try to compare
it to to what's happening in other places like in
the states or in europe can you compare it well
it's definitely more people are paying attention
here than in america america does have a lot of
vegan food a lot of vegan mock meats a lot of
vegan dairy products so there's more vegan food
there but more people seem to be interested in
veganism here more people are making that change
though i understand that you didn't get permission
to speak in front of high school students it's
kind of par for the course same thing back in
america it's really not different here but it is
it is sad that we can't talk to kids about the
truth about what's going on in the world that we
treat these teenagers like they're babies they're
not babies they need to understand what's going on
and when you hide the truth from people then you
have atrocities yeah maybe maybe but maybe the
right place is not in schools but you know after
afternoon lectures and evening lectures might be
so who is your audience in the states in
israel mainly in the states yes college
students for sure college students i only
give lectures to in colleges in america i
just finished doing 89 lectures in 12 states
okay i understand that just a few days ago
you had a very uh strong recollection of the last
time you've been to a slaughterhouse yeah can you
tell me about it in 2007 i actually went to an
auction house this is my first time i went to a
place where the auction off animals i had been
to dozens of slaughterhouses over the years but
i wanted to see this place it was open to the
public so i did not have to sneak around and
break it at three in the morning so i walked
right in i had a camera with me i went backstage
that day they were auctioning off sheep and cows
now first of all they had the males spray painted
on their back blue to mark them and the females
pink the same markings that we've done to humans
over the years with those atrocities which we can
talk about later what really was disturbing to me
and saddening to me was the first
time the animals didn't recognize
who i was and why i was there over the years
every time i went somewhere it was like they
knew i was there for them and i'm like i'm getting
footage i'm going to show people what's going on
and i'm going to share this with the world well
this was the day that they were just terrified
about what was going on and they turned their
backs to me and they were shaking and shivering
and as they looked back it was like they were
saying what are you doing to me now where are
you taking me now why are you stealing me away
from my family again leave me alone you two-legged
devil just leave me alone and here i am going
wait no i i'm gonna help i'm just showing people
what's going on and they didn't recognize me and
this is where my anger emanates from when people
don't want to listen to the message this is why
vegans get so militant because i don't want to be
a two-legged devil to the animals or to anybody
i don't want to be vicious and mean and callous
and vile but as a species we are so callous
towards the animals that's how they view us
and it brings to mind a quote that made me go
vegan way back in the day from a bishop from
england william ralph inge inge in
an 18th century sermon this man said
that we have treated our cousins in fur and
feathers so horribly that beyond a doubt
if they ever formed an organized religion
the devil would be depicted in human form
that broke my heart the day i read it and it still
breaks my heart today because again they must look
at us like we are devils we cut things off their
bodies their horns while they're fully conscious
off the cows we cut the beaks off of hens we rip
the testicles out of baby pigs when they're born
we torment them put them on concentration camp
trucks we send them to slaughterhouses they know
what's going on they're aware they're conscious
they smell death and fear and blood in the air
we cut them up into pieces this ad this this stuff
has to stop over and over again once and again uh
you um go to uh ways of of describing that we are
used to you to to to hear concerning the holocaust
it's uh pretty sensitive around here
but you you stand for it uh isn't it
over the top to uh to uh use the holocaust the
animal holocaust was happening long before the
jewish holocaust during the jewish holocaust and
it's still happening today i find it over the top
that the jewish holocaust is compared to the
animal holocaust because when you compare numbers
we're talking about six million jews and if you
add up the other six million gypsies and blacks
and catholics and mentally [ __ ] people we're
talking 12 million people were killed by the nazis
in one year alone on this planet 60 billion land
animals 90 billion marine animals are tortured
tormented and killed in the world's most massive
holocaust that's just in one year alone in america
today 30 million land animals will be tortured in
chicago in one day one day alone that is a massive
holocaust and jews don't own the term holocaust
i know jewish people like to think it's our term
like black people like to think that they own
slavery and i have to say i hate to admit that
the numbers are more than impressive but uh the
moral argument um is is quite uh difficult because
one of my colleagues here asked you were you
two uh to decide ilana dayan asked you that
and i listened to your answer and i want to go
back there she asked you if you had a three years
old baby and a three-year-old puppy that you have
to save one of them would you choose i think it's
a horrible question to be asking somebody and
when i asked her back would she save a black
baby or a white baby would you save a palestinian
suicide bomber or would you save a flea because
we act like human life is valuable and it's not
especially when you talk about mass murderers and
rapists and hitler and himmler and stalin and idi
amin and slobodan milosevic and muammar gaddafi
i mean is anybody going to save muammar qaddafi's
life how come people didn't come to his rescue
when they pulled him out of a sewer and took a
knife and shoved it in his anus nobody cares about
gaddafi osama bin laden this is so false we are
all speciesists we think that animal life isn't
valuable and we falsely believe that human life
is valuable if i can further explain how how how
unvaluable human life truly is do you know that
if you took humans off this planet the extinction
of humans would benefit everything that exists the
animals the forest the air the water the mountains
we are completely not special to this planet if
you removed ants this is how special ants are the
whole ecosystem would collapse without ants and
i know you've been following the news with bees
if the bees disappear everything falls apart this
is how special and valuable bees are to the world
where do we get off saying that we are valuable
when all we do is destroy and torment and think
that we're superior and we dominate others and
this is why you wished you said you wish that
people that work in slaughterhouses and get
slaughtered themselves or something very bad
happens to them listen i wish evil on evil people
all the time and any sane person would do the same
thing was anybody upset when the nazi hunters went
track down at all people like men and brought them
back here and killed people that work in some
party in the streets i like nazis sure to the to
their victims they are really doesn't matter what
i think to you to me yes but most importantly to
the victims the victims don't see the people that
killed jews any different than the people who kill
cows and people that were furs should be raped
i wish listen i certainly don't wish that they
hit the lottery i don't wish that bags of money
fall from the sky and boxes of lollipops land
in their laps i wish evil things happen to evil
people but i want to be clear about this i hope
rapists get raped i hope child molesters get raped
i hope all the evil people in the world have evil
done upon them so maybe they can for the first
time in their lives understand what it means
to be treated like nothing i don't understand
why my wishes are worse than people's actions
people that eat meat dairy and eggs
people that wear fur coats that support
vivisection that do vivisection i tell you why
it's important i tell you why it's important
because maybe someone hears you right now and
will take action which will be which will be
violent which will be a murder a killing okay
two things do you know when i made that statement
1997. okay it's been 16 years and not one
person has raped a woman in a fur coat because i
wished it all right okay so let's not get into
people taking my words that literally it was my
wish it was my fantasy and by the way i also
wrote three other lines about how rapists
should be used in experiments how rapists should
be tortured and killed how come people don't talk
about those things that i say nobody disagrees
with my position on violence they just only
disagree with who i propose to be violent
for see everybody thinks it's okay to kill
nazis on behalf of jews okay to kill a white slave
owner on behalf of a black slave but nobody thinks
it's okay to kill a chicken murderer on behalf
of a chicken so that's the issue at hand is why
do we devalue the life of a chicken and why do
we value human life so because nature is full of
species killing other species it's also full
of species not killing other species 75 of the
animals on this planet are herbivores of course
but why do we try to justify human behavior based
on lion behavior or shark behavior it's also
unfair because nobody else wants to do anything
else that lions do you notice that convenient
argument we just want to do what the lions do
when they eat antelope no the argument is it
might be quite natural to kill animals maybe you
should do it in the most humane way possible
and exaggerate what like a humane holocaust
we can't throw this word humane out there when
we're talking about rape torture and murder
you can't put the word humane next to it doesn't
work like that that's not how the world works
like if let's let's take for example some farmer
far away maybe far away in time in the past
grows an animal and the animal has a
wonderful life grazing and enjoying itself
and when the time crime comes he kills it the
animal in in the in a you know you know in a
nice way is the nicest possible this is not rape
this is not holocaust this is the way of life
okay so if i go and meet a woman at a bar i
buy her some drinks i bring her some flowers
i take her back and put on some soft music
some teddy pendergrass and we dance and we
look in each other's eyes and i slippery
date rape drug and rape her is that humane
why not she didn't feel a thing see because the
act of rape is evil okay the act of murder is evil
you can't do it in a nice way okay we have
to stop thinking that there's a nice we
in fact you know what the nice way to kill is
not to kill that's a nice way is it working
do you think do you think that the world is
progressing um in the direction you wanted to pre
to progress in a pace that's efficient
not quickly enough for the victims but
sadly as you know change is slow it took 400 years
to convince white people in america not to own
blacks you can see why this is taking so long we
can't even treat each other kindly you can see
why we have a difficult time treating chickens and
pigs and cows and mice and insects with kindness
but as i bring this up i want to let people know
that the the path to peace is through veganism
it is by we could we can find peace on this
planet by eradicating speciesism because
this is the first form of hatred humans are taught
racism sexism anti-semitism heterosexism these are
branches of hatred the root is speciesism because
that's the first form of hatred humans are taught
when you're a kid growing up you're taught
hey be nice to the dog be nice to the cat
but that cow that chicken yeah he doesn't count
just kill them screw them uh be nice to the horse
uh be upset when somebody poaches a rhino uh be
upset if somebody cuts the fins off of a shark
hey but that uh turkey kill em thanksgiving it's a
holiday so the kid is confused growing up so when
we get down to talking about discrimination and
why it's wrong where it comes from it all stems
from that somebody looks and acts differently
than you if you taught a child growing up that hey
just because that chicken looks differently than
you do that chicken has every right to live that
spider has every right to live just like you do
how is that child going to grow up and look at a
different person who's a different size shape and
color how is that kid going to look at that person
in hatred with violence speciesism by eradicating
that we can bring peace to this planet i want
to ask you gary but you're concentrating
on the moral argument might be that the
health or medical argument in not eating meat
may be more effective or the ecological argument
of the meat industry spoiling this planet
might be more effective but you make it a
point to concentrate on the moral argument almost
solely why because we claim to be moral beings
we claim to know right from wrong we
claim to be compassionate and as long
as humans make these claims i'm going to be in
everyone's face and say you can't do it halfway
you can't pick and choose who to be kind to and
when to be kind you're kind across the board or
you're not and i'm confused as to why we always
have to go back to the table of justice and beg
the majority of people to stop harming and killing
somebody else we do this over and over again can
we just cut to the chase and say that everyone
on this planet deserves fair and equal treatment
people who eat meat cheese milk and eggs are on
the wrong side of justice people who don't support
animal rights will not win this battle injustice
cannot live forever it never it lasts a long time
unfortunately for the victims but injustice
cannot live forever but if someone were to
to to convince you that the ecological argument or
the health the medical argument may be much more
effective why don't use it because the issue is
going to be ethics to me health issues are selfish
reasons i'm trying to make people unselfish the
reason why we're so mean animals because we think
we're so special that's selfish i'm trying
to make people unselfish i'm trying to make
people be altruistic as a boy back in michigan
in the states of a nice jewish family right
was it something that could have told me
that uh as a grown-up you'll be doing the
things that you do not a chance not a chance
there's no this is what's so bizarre about this
the meat eating temperament wise oh
well i always had an authority problem
surprise yeah i i always liked to buck
the system i was always kind of a rebel i
didn't like rules especially when the rules were
silly or unjust or they didn't make any sense so
were you one of these youths to get in trouble oh
every day at high school i was in the principal's
office every single day absolutely i'm not a funny
story too i was i was such a troublemaker too in
our high school growing up we had to sign up
for our classes but we were told over the four
years you have to make sure you do this amount
of math this amount of english well i despise
math so i never signed up for any math classes
i took extra english classes i'm a speaker i was
always fascinated with words so two weeks before
graduation miss jackson called me in and said gary
i was going over your your record you haven't
signed up for any math classes in four years
i can't let you graduate and i said you want to
keep me here for another year that's fine with me
no mind you i'm the troublemaker in the office
every day and she looks at me up and down
just get out of here side to side go get out of
here only i can get away with something like that
so and then eventually you find yourself
in jail as well yeah well you know after
when i first found out about the animal issues i
of course looked up other revolutions in history
i saw what gandhi did that he was going to jail
and getting arrested i saw martin luther king and
rosa parks and cesar chavez they were all getting
arrested for their cause doing civil disobedience
so i thought that was the path uh to help animals
become liberated so that's what i went out and did
too did you did you freeze some animals i freed
1542 mink from an animal concentration camp
that was one of the jail that was the first
major one that put me on the map uh things went
badly for me that night 540 mink did escape and
they were never going to be tortured again they
may have their necks broken by the way manually
on a fur farm uh i was apprehended that evening it
was easter sunday 1997 when i did this i thought
that was a good day to go help somebody out
uh i was charged with b e and i was sentenced to
six months in a maximum security detention center
and even those prisoners knew that it was crazy
that i was there because when they started asking
questions they saw me on the news and they said
what are you doing here with us you freed some
rats and you're here with us i said no no i also
caused 2.1 million dollars in damage that night
and put the put the make murder out of
business permanently and we don't tolerate
economic sabotage in our society because we
don't worship god i saw a stat that 96 of the
population believes in god i don't deny that
i just wish they worshiped god because people
worship the root of all evil people worship money
and that's why all this violence takes place too
it is the most profitable business on this planet
since the beginning of time animal slavery nothing
comes close not cars not gasoline not oil not
computers nothing compares to the amount of money
being made off the backs of animals literally do
you believe in god yes i do absolutely we'll talk
openly about god i don't believe in organized
religion but i absolutely believe in god
i believe in the garden of vegan oops the
garden of eden i believe and thou shall not
kill i believe genesis 1 29 god's first law
is i give you seed bearing plants for food i
believe that god created humans animals and the
earth therefore god is inside humans animals and
the earth therefore if you murder humans animals
and the earth you are murdering god i notice that
religious people love to worship things that
we created in god's name the bible the koran
stars of david and the cross but nobody worships
anything that god created animals kill them
kill them right now those horns and that
cow cut them off right now while that
cow was fully conscious that's the
water pollute it the air pollute it
every the force cut it down anything that god
made we destroy anything that we made in god's
name we worship so my condemnation isn't
about god it's about what religious people do
in god's name well i'm very glad you came to our
studio thank you for coming thanks for having me
do you think it's really necessary is it do
you really believe it's the same i think it's
killing people and killing animals yeah i think
it's worse when we talk about the holocaust we
have six million jews you can add the other six
million blacks gypsies mentally [ __ ] people in
america today 30 million innocent beings will be
murdered for a sandwich every year on this planet
60 billion land animals and 90 billion marine
animals are killed that's a holocaust of mine
these are cows and we're talking about people
but that's what the nazis said these are jews
they don't count i'm a nazi and i count and so you
really don't see a difference between animals and
people absolutely not especially when it comes to
pain and suffering we all suffer in the same way
we all feel pain in the same
way a knife in my throat
is just as painful and harmful as a knife
and a cow's throat in a chicken's throat
and the jew don't you get a strong reaction
for using the that comparison it's usually
positive i'm having nothing but success here
remember i don't do things to be a politician
i don't say things that people want me to
say i speak the truth and the truth is harsh
i know people don't want to hear that there's a
holocaust taking place that they're taking part in
but that's a fact i'm not being dramatic again if
you go back 60 70 years jewish women had babies in
their arms and the nazis ripped those babies away
in the dairy industry every cow not only has her
baby stolen she's raped to impregnate her and then
when the baby is born they steal the baby away
they tattoo jews we tattoo animals we brand them
as you see it we are all nothing to you well
not to me you have to think about the victims
the victims think you're a nazi remember isaac
bashevis singer great jewish humanitarian who
was vegan he's the one that said in relation to
animals all humans are nazis for the animals it
is an eternal treblinka so it's not so important
what i think it's what the animals are thinking
we're now seeing uh currently seeing uh uh short
uh that's shocking shocking it's
it's cruel and it's disgusting and uh
you want to prove what i want to show people
what's going on because if you watch the news
if you watch tv the advertisements are happy cows
right if they're never showing you slaughterhouses
think about this if a slaughterhouse wasn't such
an evil place how come mcdonald's and burger
ranch why don't they show you slaughterhouses
and say hey this is where your hamburger comes
from this is where your chicken nuggets come
from they intentionally lie to you i don't lie
i intentionally tell you the truth because i think
if you saw what was going on in the slaughterhouse
no logical person could choose to continue
to eat animal flesh and the things that come
out of animals so what is your final goal
to to kill the meat industry to kill the
farms i want to destroy all animal exploitative
industries they're unjust the animals are not
willing participants in this holocaust what about
the people that take place in those uh industries
i read this somewhere that you said that uh a
man that hurts an animal uh uh you could kill
him or should die or something like that there's
a justification for killing anybody who harms
a human or an animal intentionally again you have
to understand nobody's opposed to violence and
i've been asking the audience here every day raise
your hand if you're opposed to the allied forces
coming into auschwitz and birkenau and murdering
nazis to save jews and nobody raises their hands
the problem is nobody thinks animals are
important enough to kill for i think the
animals disagree i think the cows and the chickens
disagree so if i went into a slaughterhouse i'm
the peaceful person if i even if i had guns
drawn i don't know what's not about operator
i would say drop your weapons you're done killing
you're going to let these cows and these pigs and
these chickens go i'm the one that's justified i'm
stopping murder there's a justification there's
nobility in killing somebody who has no the allied
forces were noble do you think they weren't noble
do you think that they should have let nazis
kill jesus they did what they should have done
and that's what we need to do as human beings if
we claim to be compassionate claim to know right
from wrong we have to kill beings who kill evil
people but with that saying you give legitimacy to
people who murder other people you know every each
um every person could choose his own goal like uh
the person who killed our prime minister igalami
he said okay i did it to save the country to save
more people getting killed but you know why that
was unjust who was he killing the prime minister
no who was the prime minister killing nobody you
understand the difference between a murder for no
reason a psychotic murder a psychotic murder that
a fundamentalist jew a fundamentalist christian
the fundamentalist muslim takes part in and going
into a slaughterhouse and saying leave these cows
alone nobody chickens have harmed nobody we are
murdering innocent beings so if it ever came down
to that but that's not the issue that is not the
issue the issue is we just need to change the way
we view animals we have to realize humans aren't
the only beings on this planet and we're not
more important than animals so why are aren't
you allowed in some countries you can't enter
canada uh or the uk i think because we live on
a planet that murders animals a speciesistic
plant and understand like a racist who thinks that
their race is better than another race speciesists
think that the human species is superior to
animals and we have the right to harm and kill
any species we choose so why would countries
who murder animals want me to come in there
and open people's eyes and get people to change
were you surprised from your success in israel
i've always noticed that over the years if
i talk to people who have been oppressed
if i do a classroom full of jewish
people if i do a classroom full of women
full of hispanics black people people who have
been oppressed understand oppression so i'm
not surprised that israel is embracing veganism
right now and embracing me we've been oppressed
way back into egypt times and to this day still
depending on what part of the world you're in
so people who have been harmed understand why
it's wrong to harm somebody else so you really
think you have a chance i think there's a chance
i mean it kind of depends on which day you ask me
you ask me when i'm in israel for the last 10
days and people are embracing me i think yeah
i think israel could become the first nation
on this planet to abolish concentration camps
once and for all you ask me on a bad day when
people are screaming and yelling at me wanting
to fight i'll say no i don't think it's possible
but keep in mind no injustice can live forever
sadly injustice can live for hundreds or
even thousands of years but no lie can last
forever and people are becoming aware and i
think animals will obtain their freedom one
day and be treated equally and fairly well
thank you very much for coming you know uh
the jewish new year's day is uh in two
days hashanah hosh hashanah as you say
in america i would like to give you a rosh
hashanah gift it's a special organic seed
we bought it from an organization who helped
the disabled and happy new year to you thank you
hello and welcome back to this eye 24 news
evening edition i'm lucia outreach and this
is one on one joining me tonight is animal
liberation activist gary yourofsky who has
made a name for himself by becoming something of
a controversial figure in animal in the animal
rights arena apart from giving lectures mr
yarovsky is best known for his approaches
in which to get his point across such as
breaking into a fur farm in liberation 1500
soon to be murdered minx for reasons such as this
mr yurovsky has been arrested numerous of times
and has been banned from entering the united
kingdom and canada while mr yarovsky means of
putting an end to what he calls an animal
holocaust his message has reached millions of
people all around the world and has influenced
many in changing their perspective of the food
industry good evening and thank you very much for
coming to our studio thanks for having me so um
i will start like we said you affected millions
and millions of people around the world
why is it so effective here in israel
how come that it's catching in israel
i'm not clearly sure why but
the only thing that i can
figure out is that over the years as i've talked
to tens of thousands of people i've noticed that
people who have been oppressed jews hispanics
women blacks they always respond better to
this revolution that i'm involved in because
they understand oppression they've been through
it they know what it's like to be treated
like nothing like their lives don't matter
so that's what i think is going on here jews
have been an oppressed people for thousands of
years we understand oppression and we're supposed
to not support it so i'm just pointing this out
to everybody because people don't realize how much
they're harming animals in their daily lives so as
i point out the steak the hamburger the chicken
sandwich that you're eating the schnitzel okay
these these pieces of meat came off the bodies of
living animals who didn't want to be murdered who
didn't want to suffer and die who didn't want
to be tormented so once i pointed out to people
most people same people logical people make that
next step to veganism we like to use euphemisms
which is why these atrocities take place so we
always want to say leather when it's cow skin
and we want to say even even the term bacon
what's bacon you mean pig flesh so once you
start thinking about what we're wearing and what
we're eating again this is why i say sane people
will make a choice towards veganism it makes no
sense because if you let's put it this way i like
to explain how this is the biggest holocaust that
has ever existed people get upset at those terms
i have to tell you that i am upset about
hearing like holocaust comparing the holocaust
to like every single person that that heard your
lectures and to hear this holocaust comparing it
to animals it's a little bit limited and you know
what and i'm not even jewish okay but it's hurts
me well let me explain how how this this holocaust
is actually worse i'm offended that we compare
human holocaust to the animal holocaust which is
the biggest holocaust in the history of humankind
if you went to the nearest cow or chicken
slaughterhouse and remove the animals
and replace them with jews you have now
recreated auschwitz there's no difference
you have a building that exists to dismantle to
torment to torture and murder innocent beings
let's play a time game war a time warp game ghosts
go back 60 70 years you go back to auschwitz or
you go back to birkenau you remove the jews
and replace them with cows and chickens
you still have a holocaust taking place
this in fact we learn how to kill jews
in the hall like the nazis did because they
studied what the meat industry was doing
we've learned how to torture and kill each
other because we practiced on the animals first
but animals are eating animals some animals
75 of animals on this planet are herbivores
but the it's it's part of our circle of life now
this is the circle of torture and death when you
see uh a lion eating a zebra it's it's blue and
you're but i noticed you have clothes on and i
noticed that you have a cell phone and you have a
computer it is unfair to pick one thing that lions
do that you want to mimic when you don't want
to mimic anything else they do when lions walk
up and greet each other they sniff each other's
ass when i came in this room you did not kneel
down and sniff my ass okay lions sometimes kill
their young when their runts okay if a human being
killed their baby because they didn't want him we
arrest them and charge them with murder could you
go to a courtroom and say hey but your honor lions
kill their babies can't i it's a survivor it's
an unfair comparison you're not a lion and just
so you know lions are carnivores humans are not
we are herbivores one hundred percent up and
down you put a two-year-old child in a crib
with a bunny rabbit and an apple let me know
when the child eats the bunny rabbit and plays
with the apple we are purely herbivorous we have
no carnivorous or omnivorous instincts whatsoever
and physiologically if your jaw moves from side
to side in a grinding motion and you chew you're
100 herbivore if you were a meat-eater like a lion
your jaw would only go like this up and down rip
and swallow if you sweat through your pores to
cool yourself your herbivore what is your main
purpose because most of the world won't become
vegan it depends on which day you ask me the world
injustice can't live forever the world will become
vegan one day just like just like every woman on
this planet will one day have their equality with
men just like one day all oppression will fall
by the wayside injustice doesn't live forever and
it seems insurmountable don't get me wrong i mean
i'm in the trenches believe me it looks like it
seems like it can't happen but remember it took
400 years to convince white people in america
not to own black people you can see why this is
taking so long we can't even treat each other
with kindness let alone treat the chickens and
the pigs and the turkeys and the insects of the
world with kindness but i think we can treat each
other with kindness one day once we learn how
to treat the animals with kindness you know i'm
i'm i'm feeling a little bit uncomfortable
because i just had a steak for lunch and um
i and it's still i'm not convinced convinced 100
that i should stop eating meat for the rest of my
life it's not that i'm eating meat every day but
i do love my steak on the plate once a week so
you have now two minutes to try to convince me eat
meat once in once a month i don't want to convince
you to do it once a month i want to convince you
never to do it okay you have to put yourself in
the animal's position imagine that you were raped
to impregnate yourself okay somebody raped you to
impregnate you you gave birth to this baby this
baby was stolen from you at birth that baby was
fattened up with corn and soy and wheat and oats
that baby was put on a concentration camp truck
sent to a slaughterhouse hung upside down fully
conscious in front of all of her own species
screaming terrified in fear knife shoved into you
know her throat cut up into pieces where's the
justification for this and it's not your steak you
said my steak i'm very big on language that steak
was never yours okay that steak is a euphemism
by the way that's cow flesh that flesh belonged
to another living being where do humans get off
owning and controlling living beings where do
we get off thinking that we're the most special
thing that has ever existed on this planet when
in reality we're the most unspecial thing that has
ever existed on this planet are you aware that if
humans were removed from the planet the extinction
of humans would benefit everything that exists
are you also aware that if the bees died off
as we've been talking about this for about 10
years in the news the whole system collapses
if the ants were exterminated the whole system
would collapse this is how important and
special ants and bees are to the world
why do we think we're better than they are
when they serve a vital role and we serve no
vital role whatsoever we're tormentors we're
oppressors where do you think it's come it's
coming from the arrogance yeah i'm not sure i
don't know i don't know what has gotten into us
besides death and torture and murder i think
when you put violence in you get violence out
you consume discrimination and death you're
going to you know exude some people may say the
same things about you because some people may say
that he's arrogance he thinks that he knows better
he thinks that he's better than us and actually
we're all actually um we're all let's say
how can i put it i'm i'm the one to be charged and
you are the the judge who is judging me right now
yeah and well there's two people in this world
there's there's people that judge and people
that lie about judging we judge people every
day we judge child molesters we judge rapists
we judge nazis uh we judge murderers um and i
know this is a shock to the meat dairy and egg
eaters of the world but vegans are more ethical
than they are hands down and of course just like
a person that doesn't rape is more ethical than
a person who does rape a person who doesn't kill
cows pigs chickens and turkeys is better than
a person who does a vegetarian hitler was not a
vegetarian that's a complete lie a complete and
utter lie from gerbils his propaganda minister
hitler did have a lot of power didn't he if he had
all this power that he had why didn't he mandate
veganism if he were a vegan or a vegetarian do you
know that himmler the guy that constructed all the
gas chambers was a chicken he wanted to slaughter
jews this is why he had another idea a complete
other idea two of his biographers albert spear
and robert payne talked about hitler's love for
liver dumplings and pigeon which is known as squab
his main chef dion lucas wrote a book in 1964 the
gourmet school cooking book and she wrote his
favorite recipes which were all meat based recipes
this is the power of propaganda the
power of gerbils still alive and well
do you know why people think hitler was veg
gerbils wanted to make hitler seem as peaceful
as somebody else in the world at that time who was
loved and adored and his name was mohandas gandhi
and gandhi was vegetarian and gerbils will say
wait hitler's just like gandhi he loves animals
too and he's peaceful to the animals and he's a
vegetarian he's not and just so you know all the
concentration camps did have animal slaughter
houses there too and when the allied forces
came in to rescue the jews and the gypsies they
left the animals behind this is why i call this
the world's largest and longest-running holocaust
the animal holocaust was happening long before the
jewish holocaust during the jewish holocaust and
it's still happening today every second just so
you know of every minute of every hour of every
day female animals are raped to impregnate them
every second animals are being killed every
60 billion animals every year do you accept
or do you understand or the people are calling
you terrorists sure what else are they going to
call me and as we go back in time and look at all
the other people that we adore now collectively
we all agree gandhi and dr martin luther king
and all these people rosa parks and cesar chavez
do you know they were not loved during their time
they were despised they wanted to make change
massive change it's only later on that a society
looks back at revolutionary activists and says oh
man he was great he was just trying
to break bring peace and justice it's
amazing that i'm called a terrorist and if
i'm called a terrorist for saving animals
what do we call people that kill animals
and torture animals and eat animals
one last thing before we have 30-20 seconds what
did you have for lunch i had a vegan schnitzel and
a vegan burger from the vegan shawarma place in
town my favorite restaurant vegan schnitzel vegan
shawarma vegan schnitzel a vegan hamburger uh gary
thank you very much coming to our studio and thank
you our viewers for being with us tonight we
and we will be back on sunday at the same time