oh yeah looks like it's working okay i love you
what was that that came through all right we're
live i think all right looks like it's friday
yo these kids outside crazy
what was that that came through yo there's
a double up all right we're live i think
some doubling up on the audio
but we are now live i think
uh what's up everybody let me know in the comments
if the audio and the visual is okay with you
i've got a chat section on youtube that i'll
be maintaining and managing as best as i can
i'll just wait for people to join and for this
live to establish itself properly
and here people are joining the chat on youtube
what's up everybody what's up isaac sylvia
all right to be named good morning ariane laura
now i see you laura says yeah let me know how
the visual is and the audio i want to make sure
that the technology is on point for this one
um i also need you to tell me please
video and audio is clear thank you i am doing well
laura thank you i also need to tell i need you to
tell me if this microphone i'm about to plug
it in is going to make my audio better or not
now so i'm now plugged in with this mic
can you tell me if you can hear me okay
if it's better or worse than what it just was
we can't do icd because the uk went back into
lockdown we're in the same position here i feel
you we hello sylvia and hello tiff thank you
tiff appreciate that the audio is good great
great i'm going to keep this mic in
then it's better good thank you ariane
thank you guys appreciate the feedback
all right so now i'm going to move on
to the next thing great all right so yeah we're
in lockdown here in australia and currently uh
we can only assemble 10 people max in a
public area and so given that restriction
it's going to be really difficult for
any cubes to happen i'm going to be doing
a limited attendance cube in melbourne
tomorrow we'll see how we go with that but
yeah because of the restrictions around
the world we only have um 170 odd
uh almost up to 200 i think i haven't even checked
the figures over the last couple of days but
yeah i uh i had a look at the figures last
and was impressed that we have almost 200
events scheduled given the
restrictions that we have so
yeah last year we had 500 cubes scheduled
around the world and as you may or may not
know international cube day is the biggest day of
the year for us because it's our biggest campaign
and the essence of it in case you don't know is
to do as many cubes around the world as possible
so it's a fantastic time of the year for us
but given the restrictions it's a limited
campaign
all right what's up vegan king all right so
let's get into this we're gonna start off oh i
need to send out a quick story to everybody on
instagram telling them that we are now live so
just bear with me i've got no one moderating
this stream i'm going to be doing it myself
um if you have any questions
please try to save them until i do a q a but
if you can't wait until then drop them in the
chat and i'll do my best to respond to them
at some point happening now on youtube cool
all right
isaac you can moderate that would be a huge
help yeah i just it won't take much work
ah yeah cool no worries if someone wants to
moderate though it won't take much work i
just want to i just don't want to be dealing
with trolls and [ __ ] but it's no big deal
even if they do come up you know if they
want to come on and try to wreck my stream
they're welcome all right
so let's do this swipe up
cool all right about to get
into what we need to get into
so the first thing i'm going to be doing
is i'm going to play this live for you guys
and then what i'm going to do is review it for
you live and the first thing i need to do here
is since i haven't done this in a while i need to
i need to remember how to share the screen
correctly i remember how to do it but not
correctly so just give me a moment bear with me
and i'll have it ready you know what i think i
will take some questions to begin with let me
know if you have any and i'll kill some time
during that whilst i get this ready so if you
have any questions hit me up in the comments
damn
struggleville trying to get
this video to download properly please
do more of these streams paul it's good
to interact with you well i would
like to do more streams all right
why is it doing that yeah so again if you have
any questions let me know in the comments and
i'll go ahead and answer them for you now here's
a question what's your opinion on wild animal
suffering it's a topic i recently discovered
i don't know if you've heard of it or not
might have seen it in might have seen it from
humane hancock okay so i did respond to this
uh on my instagram so i forget what i
said exactly but i said something like
let's just focus i mean my answer to this question
is pretty straightforward let's just focus on the
human inflicted suffering on animals that we
are currently i mean it's the biggest issue
that we have to be accountable for so we need
to look in the mirror before we start trying
to intervene further in the animal kingdom
can we just stop murdering animals first can
we stop enslaving torturing and murdering them
that's what i would like to address this whole
thing and i think this is what i said in my
instagram post this whole thing is such an
odd discussion to me it's so strange and uh
it reminds me of how off-base it is for human
beings to explore and discover the universe and
space to the extent that humans do and yet we
still have 80 percent of the ocean 80 percent
completely undiscovered unobserved unexamined
you know this is just very typical of humans
i think that we don't address we don't look
into everything that's right here before us it
starts with us and then here on this planet we
want to try to find a home on mars and yet we
don't even know how to get things right here
it makes no sense so that's my answer
to that all right so next question um
um
all right so
long day yeah cool that sounds good laura
both three hour cubes you're doing
two for international cube day awesome
cool a question here about whether it has
started or not we are about to get started
i'm taking some questions just to get this started
and then we're going to get into the meat of this
uh much love sylvia thank you for the support
and thank you for representing us
how to talk to a parent or turn how to talk to
a parent to turn them vegan if he or she doesn't
want to hear about animal suffering anytime
i try to talk about he she walks out of the
room and hangs up the phone etc agatha aguita's
question regarding parents it's no different to
talking to anybody else you hold human beings
accountable for the evils they commit against
non-human animals whether they're family or
friends doesn't matter because they're guilty just
the same as anybody else the thing with family is
you obviously have more of an affinity with family
and that means that you should give them more
patience more effort more of an explanation more
not an explanation it's just more time more time
but at a certain point you have to say to yourself
i have done my best and they aren't open
and willing to end their human supremacy
and i know it's a hard road to walk but it's the
truth and i have dedicated myself to truth on this
planet i want my life to be dedicated to that and
nothing else so so that comes first i'm a human
being dedicated to truth before i am a human being
that belongs to a family does that make sense
um i also do think that family could be
one of the biggest downfalls of society
but i'm not going to get into that all
right so moving on another question here
about overpopulation i'm just going
to quickly answer this but this is
going to be the last question i answer
before we get started and i want to
thank you for your patience guys all
right so the next question here is
when we've solved the overpopulation of pet
animal issue do you think that we can still have
companion animals but create a solution when none
die in shelters yeah absolutely like sanctuaries
all of these shelters should be turned
into sanctuaries instead of a kill business
all right i'm going to get started
now guys thanks for your patience so
i'm going to share my screen i'm going to
need your feedback in the comments so please
light it up with feedback
about the video and the audio
okay down that's come on
uh okay
okay i'm gonna have to this is ten years ago
but the temperament of the times right now
from what i can see is that most people already
get sorry about that guys i didn't realize that
was playing uh okay so i'm gonna have to unplug
this mic when i'm playing and then plug it back
in when i need to make commentary technical
nonsense but it is what it is so let me just
yeah let me just get this going for you
guys okay
can you guys see that okay
i'm sharing my screen now
i'm sharing my screen right now so please let
me know in the comments if you can see that and
i'm gonna start playing right now okay thanks
my name is paul bashir i am my name my name
is paul bashir i am the co-founder and
director of anonymous for the voiceless
i became an animal rights activist in
june of 2015 and i started av with my
partner who i met basically just before we started
av asal and we started av in april of 2016.
since then we've become one of the most prominent
animal rights organizations in the world not
that it's a goal of ours necessarily at
the moment to have a billion chapters
that was our goal but we've changed that now to
wanting to have chapters who are working with us
working in alignment with what we're trying to
achieve and what we set out to achieve when we
started av this workshop is an attempt to do
that with regards to outreach as you all know
at the cube of truth we have protocols we have
rules and we have structure and we find that
really important because the more serious we take
our roles on the streets or in general the more
serious people take us and the message as you know
we have rules like wearing all black at the cubes
we wear the masks and only one kind of mask in the
cube we form a square cube structure there's the
outreach team in the cube team so we have these
kinds of structures another thing that we have
as a standardized structure is the outreach and
that's what i'm going to be talking to you about
today and the standard outreach approach that we
expect at the cubes is there to help you and help
everybody that does outreach to be effective
and the only thing i've found to be fulfilling
in this line of work is effective activism it's
the only thing that will help you to process the
frustration and the anger that you will naturally
have if you're paying attention as you may know
you've seen some outreach from me but it's from
the earlier stages and only recently did i start
putting outreach content up online last year there
was a gap where i wasn't putting outreach content
up online and that's because i was being patient
and i was applying different approaches and i
wanted to see what stuck what didn't i'm teaching
you nuts and bolts stuff here that i've observed
i've learned i've applied and i have observed
others apply and i can deem confidently now works
effectively for everybody this is also an approach
that is truly for everybody but i'm going to start
from the very top here with the definition
of veganism because in our movement right now
veganism is confused like everybody has a
different definition have you noticed this
does this bother you guys yeah don't you wish
we're on the same page about this wouldn't it be
easier i don't know why we're so confused about
it it seems pretty straightforward but i'll get
into the definition of veganism for you it's a way
of living that seeks to exclude any form of animal
exploitation as much as practicably possible
in the definition it doesn't include anything
to do with the environment it doesn't include
anything to do with human health it's purely about
animals and their rights and it really is that
simple another thing i'd like to tell you and
this has helped me to understand the function of
an activist is to be a medium of truth because
truth exists in this world but it doesn't act on
its own so we need to act and we need to speak the
truth we need to continually speak the truth
and we need to act on it as much as possible
so that's your role as an activist and it really
is that simple but if you ever get lost and you
are ever in doubt just remember you're
speaking for the animals in the same way you
would want to be spoken for if you're in their
position telling people the truth shouldn't be
perceived by you as something that will start
a fight because if you perceive it that way
maybe others will pick up on that but if you just
think that you're telling people the truth because
that's the loving thing to do then people will
pick up on that as well and they respect truth
people respect people who tell them the truth
have you ever heard the expression that you
don't lie to your friends you shouldn't
lie to your friends well if you extend that
to the public isn't that what being compassionate
is so people conflate veganism with compassionate
living a lot of the times as well i don't think
not stabbing animals to death is necessarily
compassionate i just think that's
the same and rational thing to do
but people also claim that this approach is not
compassionate that we're not being compassionate
to the abusers not giving them a chance but that's
nonsense because i'm a street activist that's all
i do is educate people i give people a chance to
wake up to this like i was i'm not forcing people
to go vegan that's physically impossible to do if
that was possible i'd probably be doing it right
now but you can't do that so you have to focus
on just talking to people and hoping they wake up
and that is the most compassionate thing
that you can do is offer people education
but again telling people the truth is
truly the most loving thing that you can do
i don't know why we think it's hateful
people say you're shaming people
we're not necessarily shaming people
we are making people feel guilty though
because how else are we going to make people go
vegan if they don't feel guilty isn't that why
you went vegan because you felt incredibly guilty
for what you were contributing to well why would
we avoid having others feel that why would we
try to avoid that why would we dance around the
topic and compromise on the message and panda
when that's the goal is for them to feel guilty
this is the real form of compassion that i see
that we need to bring into this movement more
is telling non-vegans the truth and one thing that
will happen when you're talking to non-vegans is
you're going to notice a lot of conscious and
some conscious distractions that come out so
whether they're consciously and maliciously doing
that or not you have to be aware of the fact that
they're going to distract away from what needs to
be discussed because their guilt is going to be
flaring when you're talking about something
that's obviously wrong everybody knows that
animal abuse is wrong that's the other thing
is that we think as vegans that people don't
already know about this people walk over to a cube
instantly know that we're vegan instantly know
that we're trying to promote an animal rights
message it may not have been the case 10 years ago
but the temperament of the times right now from
what i can see is that most people already get the
fact that we're talking about animal rights we're
talking about veganism and they need to go vegan
that's the crux of the conversation that they're
going to have with us so don't act like non-vegans
don't know this okay they already know we're a
lot more obvious about this than we think we are
when we have these very simple conversations with
people their guilt will flare up and they start
creating distractions that they don't even believe
in like plants have feelings they're trying to
distract from them taking accountability
from themselves taking accountability for
what they're doing it's your role again as a
medium of truth to anchor the conversation back
to make sure that that individual is in the
hot seat and it's not just something that they
can just palm off and the distractions that
they're creating you have to break through
them that's your job as an activist is to break
through them and not let the distractions become
real distractions for what needs to be
discussed you've all heard non-vegan
excuses i'm sure a lot of people think when i
do an outreach workshop i'm going to get into
how to deal with excuses how to deal with certain
arguments i'm not actually going to do that
if you have questions during the q a though i'll
answer them for you but i'm not going to do that
because i've come to know that they're all just
ridiculous excuses and there is no excuse under
the sun that should ever trump you plants have
feelings if people really believe that plants
have feelings how come we don't have a single
group out there that protest against lawn mowing
how come when the australian bushfires
occurred we didn't hear anything about the
plants burning to death we only heard about
the wildlife and when they said wild life
they were talking about animals every
single time even people like joe rogan
who's a [ __ ] avid hunter and loves to justify
not being vegan at every opportunity he gets
even he said he supported the wildlife in
australia and he was referring to the koalas
and the other animals people around the world have
only shown empathy or sympathy towards the animals
that were suffering in the wildfires right that
just goes to show that this is very obvious in
people's minds and that's why i'm saying this is
a lot more obvious than we think it is it really
is people already care about animal rights
and the reason i know that is because nobody
unless they're a psychopath would be comfortable
with the label of being an animal abuser
and that's what non-vegans are they're abusing
animals the only reason why they feel comfortable
is because the guilt is shared by everybody we've
broken out of that now we can see straight now
but it doesn't mean that it's not completely
obvious still for everybody else we've just
taken action on this none of these excuses are
ever going to trump you they should never have
you feeling flustered they should never have you
feeling like you don't know the answer because
the answer is always very simple and it's the fact
that they can't justify abusing animals needlessly
end of story whenever in doubt
just compare to any other
but it should injustice like a
delicacy and something that we eat
maybe once a week instead
of i don't think that the
the rate that we use it is natural we're
at the extreme end of this lifestyle now
would you say that with any
other injustice like sexism
child abuse no but i'm saying would
you take that position would you say
that it would be too extreme to avoid at
all that we should still do it sometimes
yeah that was good that was a good rebuttal we're
not vegan but we're vegetarian delivered chicken
yeah so we're fish chicken so would you take the
same position with any other injustice let's say
we're talking about sexism or racism would you
have the same view on that where are we going here
so let's say we're talking about racism yeah
would you be like i'm against racism i don't
want to be a racist but then maybe
like on sundays i make an exception
to be racist yeah so this is a form of
discrimination against another species
while you're still having a little bit of egg or
chicken whatever i'm not sure what you're having
you're still really supporting animal cruelty
and more exploitation we will do it slowly i
understand it might seem like a big jump would
you take that on any other issue for example
if somebody said i'm going to slowly stop
beating my child i'm going to slowly become
a non-racist no you wouldn't be uh that's we
got to do it right do you think that we should
contribute to this last or do you think that we
should say hey we should just stop hurting animals
stop stop right people will talk a good game about
reducing or making excuses for why they won't go
vegan just compare to any other injustice in that
moment we are an animal rights organization we've
never deemed ourselves to be an environmentalist
group a group of environmentalists trying to
change the world for the betterment of the
environment we've never claimed to be a
nutritionist organization a group of nutritionists
trying to change the world for the betterment of
human health we've only ever claimed to be an
animal rights organization but there's this myth
that exists in the vegan movement that when you
promote health and environment these things will
get people more interested in animal rights and
that's the reason why we've been talking about
these things is to try to get them hooked if
someone doesn't seemingly care about animals
well i guess i'll talk to them about health
because they have heart disease i guess i'll
talk to them about how they can reverse their
heart disease by eating a plant-based diet if they
don't seemingly care about the animals we think
we'll talk to them about the environment this
is destroying the rainforest this is destroying
our climate crisis the idea that this will lead
someone to animal rights and caring about animal
rights is a complete myth animal rights is obvious
nobody in their right mind would be comfortable
with the label of being an animal abuser so
it's not a matter of people not caring
about animal rights it's a matter of you
not promoting animal rights correctly it may
seem like a tough pill to swallow to hear that
but i'm only telling you this because it's the
truth and it's what i've learned to be true
people avoid animal rights and make you
think they don't care about animal rights
for a reason it's a distraction like i said
they create distractions they don't want to
face something that's obviously wrong and then you
buy into that by then pandering to environment and
health people don't care about animals because the
way that we advocate veganism to people doesn't
care about animals it seems like in this movement
the more i hear people advocating for veganism
the less i hear animal rights being tied into it
they quickly get mentioned and then we move on to
how this is really bad for the environment and
really bad for your health so that's why people
don't care about animal rights the vegan movement
hasn't been promoting animal rights i also just
want to say this those who say that what i'm doing
is aggressive that this isn't compassionate well
the irony the way i see it is the irony is that
when people aren't advocating for the animals
in the way that they communicate directly then
you're actually putting the compassion you want
to receive from the abuser before the compassion
you're supposed to be extending to the victim
i think that's hypocrisy right if we truly
are compassionate beings then we need to
extend compassion to the victims and when we're
talking to the abuser like i've already explained
it is actually the truest form of compassion to
offer the abuser education what do we usually
do with abusers we put them in prison don't we
right if these beings were any other species
other than a non-human so if they were human
these people would be put in prison wouldn't
they there would be no conversation
on the streets no trying to convince
people so this is compassion this is the most
compassionate thing we can possibly do is try to
wake people up with our words but if we pander
and we move away from animal rights when we're
talking to people then we're only doing more of
an injustice more of a disservice to the animals
it's not about how people feel about animals do
you have a dog at home do you have a cat at home
a lot of the times we as vegans try to lean on
the compassion that we think they already have
for animals for non-human animals we use dogs
as examples a lot in this movement we try to say
would you do this to your dog how would you
feel if your dog was eaten what about if a
dog was getting beaten up right in front of us
right now would you act on it that blows up in
our face a lot of the time replace all those
cows with dogs just for a moment in your mind
dogs don't produce milk yes they do yeah they do
but not like yeah it's hard to i don't i try just
morally i make that comment just for you to
consider it morally what is the difference between
puppies being raised all the female puppies to
get milk out of them instead of cows i don't feel
different you don't feel any different why do we
think we live in a society that cares about dogs
why do we think that i don't understand why our
movement thinks that we live in a society full
of dog lovers if we truly love dogs would we have
shelters that kill dogs by the thousand every day
around the world clearly if we lived in a
society of dog lovers just the same way that we
love human children then we'd have people
protesting at the front of shelters all the time
but that's not happening if you said that stuff
to me it wouldn't really work because i was never
really a dog lover growing up but my point is
to say that this isn't an animal conversation
this is an accountability conversation if you
were talking to me about the blood on my hands
if you're talking to me about the harm i'm
causing to beings who suffer like i suffer
it doesn't matter about how i feel about animals
it matters but how i feel about causing suffering
i also need to make this clear a lot of people
out there think that morality is subjective when
it comes to this morality is as objective as
it gets it's as black and white as my t-shirt
when it comes to animal rights people will love
for you to think that there's a great area that
there's something that you're not considering
you're not open-minded enough what about
if you're on a deserted island or those who don't
have you know access to they always try to bring
up great areas to this to see where the morality
can slip it doesn't ever slip you're never going
to wake up one day and think animal abuse is
justified are you you're not gonna go back
on your morals if you understand that this is
wrong you're not gonna go back on child abuse
you're not gonna wake up one day and think child
abuse is okay i think today i'm comfortable with
this idea i'm gonna do it today it's black and
white it's always wrong and it's never justified
another thing that vegans will focus way too
much on when advocating for animal rights
is being liked by the other person we think that
being likable vegans is going to get people to
take veganism seriously raise your hand if
you've fallen into this trap i know i have
thank you for being honest because we don't want
to be the preachy vegan we don't want to be the
pushy vegan we don't want to be the annoying
vegan we don't want to be the vegan that turns
people off veganism here's the thing non-vegans
have been trying to bully us psychologically
into this thinking and you need to realize that
and you know better this is just manipulation
people are trying to make you feel insecure about
this because they're shooting down the messenger
because they don't want to take the message
seriously and face it when we play into this
they win when i say they the abusers and the
animals lose it's a flaw to care about being liked
more than what you're saying and the rights
of these animals the rights of these beings
in no other situation do we actually use
this line of thinking so we're actually
being hypocrites here you probably noticed
that people actually like people who don't
really care what other people think of them when
you don't care what other people think of you
and to the contrary when you care so
much about what other people think of you
people actually don't like that they don't like
that about you because it comes off as a weakness
and i actually think that telling people the
truth is the best way to achieve this anyway
so it's counterproductive if you want to be liked
then do things that are deserving of being liked
and this shouldn't be your goal being life
shouldn't be your goal because if somebody
likes you and goes vegan for that reason
what happens when they don't like you anymore
which will happen
imagine civil rights activists
focusing on being liked by white people
in order for them to take black rights
seriously how weird would that be trying to be
accommodating in whichever way socially to have
them taking black rights seriously it would be
insane to even witness that happening and this is
also a tool that you should use in your advocacy
to make sure that you're in line with what you're
supposed to be doing here as an activist if you
ever feel like questioning what you're
doing compare it to any other injustice
would you be advocating this way in
any other case for any other injustice
if not don't do it here animals deserve
way better from us when we first started av
i noticed that the outreach that
we were doing on the streets
i noticed that there was a lot of
things that i learned in my previous
work experience in doing sales all
the sales training that i had received
there were things in that that i could carry
over into outreach that were applicable here
and so if you go on our website it says we use
a value-based sales approach i want to explain
what that means because i think there's been
a bit of a confusion about this i definitely
don't mean the kind of sales that we're
commonly used to and that we commonly know
i'm talking about certain aspects of sales that
are applicable here because at the end of the day
what we're doing is trying to convince somebody
of something they're not already convinced on
and that's what sales is really i'm trying to
convince you right now to apply this approach when
you're doing outreach and that's why i brought
this into this equation but i want to explain
that i really do not mean schmoozing people and
telling people what you think they want to hear
and using hooks like psychological hooks to trick
them into signing on the dotted line that's not
how this works at all activism is a different
ballpark to sales one of the traditional things
that occurs in sales is the three-step process for
any sale so i'll talk you through that right now
the three-step process is really simple
the first step is all right i'm gonna
okay i'm gonna pause right here because this
is the part where i find that there's the most
confusion and it's the whole sales message so yes
i'm going to break down this three-step process
but the only reason i'm doing that here is to
show you where sales tools and really they're
not sales tools they're communication tools but
where these communication tools are applicable
from the sales world into activism but again i
need to reiterate this i said this in the video
sales is not activism just because you
have x number of sales years of sales
experience doesn't mean you have x number of years
experience in activism that's not how this works
at all it just means that you've learned a
few things about communication that might
might be applicable here in activism i found
in fact when i go over all of the sales
things i've ever learned that most of it is
actually unapplicable unequivocally unapplicable
and that's because the the goal in sales is
usually to get someone to sign on the dotted
line and there's usually a financial incentive
here where and i named it the value-based sales
approach from the very beginning in 2016
when we started av for the purpose of
setting it apart from sales in general the common
view of sales this is a new i was trying to create
something new here where we can carry over what
is applicable and what i've found the deeper i've
gone into this is that a very minimal amount is
actually applicable from the sales world over here
so with that added commentary on this bit
i will now continue for you guys to get
somebody convicted in what it is that
you're trying to convince them of
we have all of the lodge process up to sales one
of the traditional things that occurs in sales is
the three-step process for any sale so i'll talk
you through that right now the three-step process
is really simple the first step is to get
somebody convicted in what it is that you're
trying to convince them of we have all the logic
all of the reason on our side and it's important
to use logic and reason i'm not saying don't use
that but if you don't get somebody emotionally
convicted in this issue because it's a justice
issue then don't expect a shift from anybody
that's why i don't like these philosophical
discussions that we have with people about
veganism we have these what seems to be like a bar
discussion just food for thought and that's a real
issue because that's not what this is supposed to
be about this is an accountability conversation
and that first step is best achieved when you
connect them to the sense of injustice and you
hold them accountable to that injustice
the second step is to make sure that they
understand that they as an individual are
responsible that they're in the hot seat
this isn't something they can just palm off to
the government or palm off to these industries and
say we need to focus on petitioning against these
industries this is about them as an individual and
you can't let them get out of that that's your job
meat doesn't just harm yourself it harms someone
else someone or something do you think an animal
is a thing oh okay i'll see where you're going
but like let's but that's the problem that's
going to be your that's going to be the club
the lack of compassion for non-human um you know
that's going to be your problem but what about
you because i'm talking to you right now do you
have a lack of compassion for non-human animals
so are you against animal exploitation yes i am
okay so what do you think you can do about it
yeah we're talking yeah i will share
this conversation with my family
what do you think you will do
though yeah i will start more
the third step once you have achieved that
second step through dealing with their objections
anchoring it back to accountability once they
concede you move on to the third step which is
tying in the benefits everybody loves to know
what's in it for them right because humans are
selfish right okay so the number one benefit
for you going vegan obviously for the animals
it's that they no longer have to be tortured
and abused by you but the benefit for you
is that you no longer have to abuse them
and therefore you're no longer a hypocrite
because you say that you're against animal
abuse in fact in that very conversation
they said that that they're against animal
abuse right that's the only reason we're
vegan today why you guys are sitting here right
now trying to learn about outreach is because
you hate the hypocrisy don't you you would never
want to live with that hypocrisy again would you
more importantly would never want to abuse animals
anymore would you i used to say if you do this
correctly you eat a whole foods plant-based diet
you will actually get the health benefits from
doing this as well and i used to say that it's
better for the environment if you do this as a
benefit you have a lower footprint it's a mistake
because i'm conflating animal rights with
environmentalism and with human health
i know that it's going to be tempting for you to
do this even after this workshop you're going to
be very tempted to go there still i i you only
know whether this is true if you apply this
but if i can save you some time it's a
mistake focus on why as opposed to how
way more focus on why how is so eat i
mean it's so easy to go vegan all right
so i just want to add some commentary there
to that piece that i just shared with you
guys and i'm not sure if i made this clear in
that last piece of commentary i offered but
that three-step process is not something you
necessarily need to follow at the cubes i'm just
breaking that down to explain the traditional
sales process and how it can be like how it's
applicable here and how we usually get people you
know what the process is to get them to that point
of taking veganism seriously but i'm going to
break down the process for you at the end of this
in in slides so i'm gonna break it down for you
even more um simpler and make it more clearer for
you guys so just stick around for that at the end
after this presentation is complete so i just want
to clarify i'm not asking you to do the three-step
process at the cubes that's not what we're asking
you to do we're just explaining the three-step
process and showing you how this one little thing
in sales is actually something that we can learn
from and apply some of that here in activism
in this day and age do we really think it's
difficult for people like we create our
way more focus on if you apply how is
so eat i mean it's so easy to go vegan
it's a mistake focus on why as opposed to
how way more focus on why how is so eat
i mean it's so easy to go vegan in this day and
age do we really think it's difficult for people
like we create all these programs and recipes and
we try to make sure people have all the support
in the world is it really that difficult though
aren't we babying people aren't we coddling people
because if you're convinced on why you need to
be vegan you just need to go and use google in
2020 we have the internet you can use google and
ask any question there is about any ingredients
about any recipe any product and you'll find out
pretty quickly if it's vegan or not and that's the
only compass you need to be vegan is this vegan
or is this not there's two types of people in
the world those who say being vegan is easy those
who say being vegan is hard those who say being
vegan is easier focus on the victims those who
say being vegan is hard to focus on themselves
so whenever they bring up that distraction
oh i don't know how i could do this
how whatever form of how that comes
up how is completely a distraction
if they're sold on why how is easy plus we
give them a card anyway so they get support
they get whatever they need at the end so
don't focus on how another good question
i just want to let you guys know also we
updated our resource page in our cards so when
you're so when you're at the end of the
interaction and you hand over a card
it it's now updated and it says will you stop
um what does it say will you stop being a human
supremacist this was just updated and it has
our website cubeoftruth.com and that link now
takes you to our resources page so it's a lot
more simple i'm really proud of this new update
and if you go over to our resources page we've
updated that as well to make that even simpler
specifically the video section we've now put up a
video that is the best of the best gary yourofsky
moments in speeches and other other content
he's put up mainly his speeches but we've
put the best of the best of gary yourofsky
all in one video and it's about three hours
so that's pretty cool because if they need
further convincing that's the video we're
still going to keep the georgia tech speech up
there the best speech you'll ever hear because
it has all of the translations available and i
think it covers like 30 languages or something so
that's important we need to keep that up there
for that reason but this other one that's up
there you can play using the caption feature on
youtube so it may still translate through that
i don't well yeah i don't know how that works in
other countries or if it just creates a caption
in in english um yeah i'm not sure how that works
but anyways we have that three-hour video for at
least the english-speaking people of the world and
uh that's pretty cool so let's get back into this
is it's we give them a card anyway so they get
support they get whatever they need at the end
so don't focus on health another good question
is when you're tying in the benefit at the end
of that three-step process to ask the question
do you think it's possible to be against this
to be against what you're saying you're against
while also supporting it and it's a good question
to just tie in hypocrisy again and also to tie
in the fact that there is no way around this
there's no alternative you're either an animal
abuser or you're not another thing i want to say
about this approach that i'm teaching you right
now is that this is way more satisfying to do
than all these other approaches that involve
pandering and compromising on the message
and focusing on being liked and all this stuff
this is way more satisfying i've noticed that
over the last four years there was a huge surge
in 2017 2018 for street outreach in our network
and then it sort of dropped and i feel like people
have lost interest in doing outreach they don't
really see the benefits and how successful
it is and they're not really convinced on how
effective it is anymore when you're doing this
approach you'll come to learn that all of your
interactions are successful even if the individual
doesn't say that they're going to go vegan
you've at least told them what they need to hear
which is probably the only time they're going to
hear it and when you have that perspective every
interaction is successful because again we're
mediums of truth we speak for the animals in the
same way that we would want to be spoken for if
we were in their position we have a rule that
we only talk to people who stop at the cube and
that's because we want to talk to people who are
open-minded and we also have an opening question
that we ask would you like to know why we're here
because we need a commitment from them so that
this is a two-way conversation so you shouldn't
be talking to people who are obviously unreachable
but at the end there they don't say they're going
vegan then there's no reason for you to think that
wasn't a successful interaction so many times
people don't even say anything affirmative to
the outreacher and they become vegan this happens
so often now we had someone at the melbourne
workshop who was sitting and learning who said
i don't think that the outreacher who got me to
go vegan at a cube a year ago in melbourne even
knows that i went vegan because i argued with the
outreacher and walked off that's another reason
why we've removed the tallies but i'll talk a
little bit about that at the end who here has not
heard about socratic questioning raise your hand
alright fair few of you this has been
blown out of proportion a little bit too
socratic questioning is a tool and it's a very
good tool but it is only a tool it should be
used within your interaction wherever you see fit
wherever it's supposed to be used because asking
questions is always a good idea it's always a
good way of gathering information from the person
to see where they're at psychologically when it
comes to this but don't just use it throughout
the whole interaction don't just ask question
after question after question there's gonna be
many times during the interaction where they give
you the flaw to speak and lecturing them in that
moment is actually the right way to go the reason
why socratic questioning is there is because
um so when i say giving you the like they're not
necessarily giving you the flaw it's just a part
in the a moment in the interaction where they're
not saying anything and it would be completely
appropriate for you to say something and to
make a statement at that point because and i'm
gonna break this down a little bit later when
i do the slides because at that point when you
make a statement or a closed-ended question or
you don't even ask a question at all at that point
what you're doing is pushing the conversation
forward and that's necessary sometimes i'll break
this down a little bit more detail like i said
but i just wanted to add that commentary let's get
back to it because we we wanna they give you the
flaw to speak and lecturing them in that moment
is actually the right way to go the reason why
socratic questioning is there is because we want
to ask questions instead of make statements but it
doesn't mean that making statements is a bad idea
so i know that after i teach you guys this
stuff it's just human nature that you will
take this approach you'll apply your
personality to it which i want you to do
but then what i don't want you to do is
butcher the approach itself and start
saying things differently to how i'm suggesting
that you say it so one little example is
we say we a lot when we're talking about
non-vegans and what they do to animals
we're not in that situation anymore so this is
pandering when we say the way we kill animals or
why do we do this to them you're not doing this to
them anymore so keep it accurate again apply apply
your personality by all means but just keep
it accurate and listen to what you're saying
you should make it very clear that the individual
you're speaking to needs to be held to account
not you i think i get why we've been focusing
on being liked more than promoting the message
at hand here and it's because the defensiveness
that we see coming from non-vegans i think is
more profound more astounding than perhaps any
of the defensiveness that we see in any other
group of culprits of perpetrators in the world
and i want to try to explain why i think that is
when it comes to eating it's the most intimate
connection we have with the outside world
this is why we see people getting a lot more
cognitively dissonant and defensive over the food
aspect of veganism as opposed to the clothing
aspects or the testing aspects of veganism
more people are willing to accept that wearing
fur is evil but when it comes to changing their
eating habits their defensiveness is truly
astounding this is what i experienced when i
was promoting a plant-based diet for almost two
years before i became an animal rights activist
so when you couple that with the fact that we
are addressing the largest and longest-standing
injustice with the most pressing issue of our
time and the fact that this is the most intimate
connection people have with the outside world
then you have to expect a nightmare i'm only going
to mention this one objection when people say i
only eat meat once in a while have you heard that
they only say this to vegans and this only happens
when they have a vegan in their environment
again this is just to prove to you how obvious
this is how obviously guilty people feel
it doesn't even take long for people
to say that to a vegan i don't eat meat
that much anyway i'm trying to eat less
and less meat to not participate today
i'm i ate a lot of meat before so i'm trying
to eat less it's hard to go really no meat for
me but i'm trying to do less and less so i'm
not participating in those games i lower my
i don't cook food anymore i don't cook meat
anymore but if i go to restaurants sometimes
i order meats okay yeah i'm not full vegan
myself but i try to at least five days a week
why are you saying that
you wouldn't say that to your non-vegan friends
and it's as black and white as that you know
you're only a little bit of an animal abuser
again they would never do this with any other
injustice they'd never be a little bit of a
child abuser the word speciesism the words
veganism and the word animal exploitation
and carnism as well carnist people
don't really understand these words
it doesn't really hit the way that we want them
to hit i'm not saying don't use these words
i say vegan all the time but i want you
to focus way more on what these words mean
and use words like human supremacism
because that clearly explains speciesism
and it clearly explains what being a non-vegan
is all about human supremacism and in terms of
exploitation i think people think of
sweatshop workers and i don't know they
think of exploitation the music industry in the
porn industry they don't really think of the
animals being hacked apart having the children
taken away from them the most torturous things
imaginable happening to these innocent beings
i don't really think of exploitation like that
so it is exploitation but the better word to
use here is animal abuse and human supremacism
statistics a lot of the times we feel the
need to bring up statistics you know 50 of
the world's crops are used to you know 3 trillion
animals are slaughtered every year by all means
do this but please keep this to an absolute
minimum because we're not supposed to be
highly educated and academic and it doesn't
need to be in order for people to take this
very simple issue seriously animal abuse is
wrong and there's no justification for it
we don't need statistics to prove that to people
necessarily if people want to talk about this to
you and they bring up statistics and they want
to debate statistics make sure that you're not
feeding into the distraction too much i
want to talk about vegetarianism real quick
i think vegetarianism is a cancer
to the animal rights movement
and we think that for some reason in this
movement we think that vegetarians are closer
to this message they're our allies again we would
never do this with i just wanna i just wanna take
a moment to call myself out this is the holding
non-vegans accountable 2.0 workshop but i'm going
to take a sweet moment to hold myself accountable
because i just said in this movement we think
that vegetarians are the same whatever i said i
don't think that anymore in fact i've probably
been the most vocal about this in the animal
rights movement but yeah i was just talking
about how we need to be accurate with our words so
i just want to pull myself up there and say that
i no longer talk like this about vegeta i never
really did ever so yeah any other injustice and
you and they bring up statistics animal abuse
is wrong and there's no justification for it
make sure that you're not feeding into the
distraction too much i want to talk about
vegetarianism real quick i think vegetarianism
is a cancer to the animal rights movement and
we think that for some reason in this movement we
think that vegetarians are closer to this message
they're our allies again we would never do this
with any other injustice and vegetarian is no
different to paleo i mean vegetarians will stop
eating meat then that's no different to what the
paleo crew are doing because they don't eat dairy
and it's been argued that the dairy industry could
be the cruelest industry in the world we should
really be calling the paleo crew our allies
not vegetarians but do you see how insane
that sounds me even saying that we would call
the paleo guys our allies just because meat is
obviously cruel to animals it doesn't mean dairy
isn't and eggs isn't and you all know that because
you're vegan and you already know this information
but when we even slightly give in to this
idea that vegetarians are on our side then
we perpetuate this myth even further we are the
ones who are spreading the wrong message here
so when someone says don't worry i'm
vegetarian you don't need to talk to me
your response should be you're actually our
target market and in fact you have more of a
responsibility to go harder on those individuals
because they already think they're doing enough
they feel entitled and how dare you tell them
they're doing any different is the attitude
they usually give you i appreciate all that
you're doing just once you know that i'm a
vegetarian that drinks almond milk okay that's
good local farm interesting i'm just saying like
you might want to just focus your food versus
somewhere else because i i totally am already
on board i got that so was animal cruelty
one of the reasons why you became vegetarian
since i was 19 i'm 45 okay that's about 27 years
of vegetarian one of the footage that we chose
here is also from local like free range like egg
farms let me ask you a question because you say
that you usually get your eggs from like local
like free range farms where did they get their
hands from like for example her father's chickens
that run around his yard so like they are i don't
know where he gets attention because um what sex
is important in the egg industry males are females
obviously the females so when people get hence
they get them from a breeder in hatcheries even
like for people that just want to get like
a egg laying hence males and females are
born a different color if you're born female
you're thrown to the left if you're a male
you're thrown to the right where do you think
the males go i get it directly into a blender
so i'm doing everything i can to
minimize my impact but i'm not good
would you consider animal cruelty to be an
injustice yes yeah would you take that same
stance with any other injustice because you do
recognize that there is cruelty and eggs right
sure so i found with the majority of vegetarians
actually they're harder to get through they're not
our allies they're not closest to this message
they're pompous sure there's vegetarians out
there who didn't know better and i've met many
of those too they just didn't know better once
you tell them they go vegan on the spot
that's the dream circumstance but i'm
saying most people are not like this if they're
vegetarian imagine if all vegetarians were vegan
the percentage of vegetarians is always way
larger than the percentage of vegans when
they do those statistics imagine if all the
vegetarians were outreached effectively and
they went vegan we would have way more vegans
on our side also when people at the end of your
outreach will say i'm gonna try to do better
i'll try i'm gonna try to go vegan please
do not use the word try and do not let people
use the word try would you try to be a non-racist
would you try not to be a child
abuser or would you just [ __ ] stop
once you realize that it's wrong again
don't let them off the hook let them
know that there is a moral imperative here
when someone says i'm gonna try what i say
in order to get them to rid themselves of this try
nonsense is to compare it to any other injustice
like i just compared it to child abuse and
racism etc would you say that you would try
or would you just stop and that usually
corrects that for people very quickly
um i'm going to get into this a little bit more
later but i want to add this piece in here and say
that we have had another update to this section
we're constantly seeking to improve here
guys we're constantly making software updates
and one of them is this one here when we
compare to other injustices we've actually found
see okay so my analysis on this is that
human beings only truly care about themselves
that's it so when we say child abuse racism
sexism feminism whatever it is we're relying
upon how much they care about those issues and
if they're not an activist when it comes to those
issues we shouldn't expect that they care
a great deal about those issues should we
so we've found that the most effective thing to do
in all situations is in fact hold them accountable
to themselves so in other words instead of
comparing it to an injustice that involves
other groups of humans how about you just ask them
about themselves how would you feel if someone
was torturing you enslaving you and was going to
murder you and the excuse your oppressors used was
i'm trying to do less of it i'm only going to cut
they say they're only going to cut your leg off
uh you're probably gonna die from a doe
so is that better than not killing i mean
you know it's essentially putting them in the
victim's position and saying what if someone was
to enslave torture and murder you less but
never ever liberate you from your oppression
how would you feel would you want to
be liberated if you were the victim
or would you want these nonsense baby
steps that don't really go anywhere
so when you're comparing to other groups of humans
it might be most effective for you to in fact
according to our latest update and my
analysis on this is that if you just
rely on the fact that human beings truly only care
about themselves uh more than more they at least
care more about themselves than than anything
else any other group of humans and i'm speaking
generally for most people here this is why i'm
trying to get deep into what is the most effective
because there is no perfect approach for every
single individual on the planet that doesn't exist
what i can only teach you is most effective
for most people and i'm going to continue
to expand that and improve on that as
much as possible let's get back into it
would you say that you would try or would you just
stop and that usually corrects that for people
very quickly i want to try to be better
there's no trying when it comes to justice
you can't try to be non-racist you're either
non-racist or you're a racist and i say that
comparison because you understand injustice
in that context but justice is justice
what's evil is evil you can't have it both ways
what's right is right what's wrong is wrong so
don't try you have to do it do you think
you'll go vegan um i can definitely try yeah
wow i love my family here but i can stop i can
spread it through my family make sure that they
eat less now i'm just going to leave you with
this to think about because you said try would
we say that with any other injustice would we try
to not be a child abuser or would we just do it
yeah so please don't compromise on this injustice
because the animals suffer as a result of that
you really just need to get out there and do
this and see how effective it is for yourself
that one guy he was talking to so anyone
can do this and i highly recommend it and
the tallies as you know we've removed our tallies
we used to try and measure how effective we are
and that was the reason why we had the tally
there we tried to have some kind of metric
that we wanted to use to show that these events
this form of street outreach is really effective
but the mistake that we made is that you can't
really tell if someone is going to go vegan or not
you just have to speak for the animals in
the way that you would want to be spoken for
if you're in their position say the correct
things and that's a successful conversation and
a lot of the times people say they're going to
go vegan and while that's still a good thing i'm
not saying that's not a good indication if someone
says they're going to go vegan they may very well
stick to that but i actually have examples of many
cases of people saying they're going vegan after
listening to me and they do not go vegan you don't
know what's going on in people's minds and what's
going on in their hearts and what they're going
to experience after they've talked to you you
don't know if they're going to continue arguing
with their friends about what you've talked to
them about and then that leading to them going
vegan because all of their friends made stupid
comments and one of their friend held them to
account again and that rang in their head and
they were thinking about it for a week and they
couldn't let it go and then finally they conceded
to the hypocrisy and they became vegan you
just don't know you don't know the process
another thing is that hypocrisy i just want to
go back to that real quick it's the reason why
each of us went vegan for sure there's a story
that i have on my youtube of gary yourofsky
i was in the car with him he was
telling this really awesome story that
all right okay guys i want you to pay attention
to this point i'm making here because i only
realized how powerful and significant this
point was when i watched this workshop back
what i have successfully pointed out here
is well you'll hear my point in a moment but
this is so tremendously profound and i really want
you to understand what i'm saying here but it's a
story about gary and i haven't even pointed this
out to gary yet but i'm going to do so soon but
one thing i learned from him is that he didn't go
vegan because of that elephant in the circus and
he didn't go vegan because of the pigs that he saw
being tortured and murdered at thorn apple valley
um pig pig slaughterhouse the pig sloth house
there so that's the story he's told the world
and i believe that that's what he felt was
the catalyst for a long time but when i was
chilling with him in detroit he told me a story
which i recorded and i put up on my youtube
and that story he tells a new story about how he
went vegan and what was really the catalyst to
change him and it's really powerful if you want
to understand what it takes to truly get people
to go vegan because if we can understand how
the best activists in the world have gone vegan
then that's a pretty good indicator because that's
what we're trying to shoot for here not just
people to go vegan but we need people to speak up
and to be effective when they speak up and let's
look at how activists went vegan that's a great
thing to observe and learn from so without further
ado please pay attention one of their friend held
them to account again and that rang in their head
and they were thinking about it for a week and
they couldn't let it go and then finally they
conceded to the hypocrisy and they became vegan
you just don't know you don't know the process
another thing is that hypocrisy i just want to
go back to that real quick it's the reason why
each of us went vegan for sure there's a story
that i have on my youtube of gary yourofsky
i was in the car with him he was telling this
really awesome story that i'd never heard before
about how a hockey team in detroit used to throw
octopuses onto the ice and he was an animal rights
guy at the time every time someone would score
a goal they would do this and he was an animal
rights guy at the time who was protesting this
and he called a radio station and he started
saying what's next are we going to have all these
other teams with sharks and lions and their names
also throwing those animals onto the ice every
time they score a goal and he was going nuts
and then the radio guy said whoa gary chill
chill what did you have for dinner last night
and then gary was like a salad
and it was that moment that he realized that no
other answer could have been acceptable and the
hypocrisy was what got gary yourofsky to go vegan
that night he said was the night that he went
vegan i heard stories about the elephant story
in michigan he talked about a circus incident and
then there was this other incident but it wasn't
that he was going to thorn apple valley pig farm
in in michigan and seeing pigs being slaughtered
every day he kept going and witnessing he couldn't
believe that this was going on he hadn't gone
vegan until that guy said you're a hypocrite
so please understand how powerful that is even the
best activists that we know of the most effective
this is what caused them to go vegan it's
the same thing for me it's the same exact
story for me when i realized from listening to
gary that i was a hypocrite if i wasn't vegan
and there's no way you can justify
even a little bit of animal consumption
that's when i became vegan but prior to that i
was bullshitting i was plant-based i would eat
salmon sometimes i'd wear leather i was
raw vegan while wearing leather jackets
i could take you through a typical interaction
if you'd like from start to end would you like
that yeah yep so we start the conversation
by would you like to know why we're here
they need to say something affirmative for the
conversation to go ahead they either say yes or
they try to guess and that's an affirmative answer
so you continue yes what we're doing here is we're
showing the standard practice footage of what
happens in the meat dairy in egg industries and
other industries that abuse animals and we're also
showing free-range grass-fed organic cage-free
humane certified hey guys would you like to know
why we're here i'm guessing against animal cruelty
that is a good guess what we're showing on
the screens is the animal industries meat
dairy and eggs and other industries also that
abuse animals for products would you like to
hear what we're doing here um sure cool yes what
we're doing is we're showing the behind the scenes
of industries that abuse animals so this is in
the meat industry dairy industry egg industry
we're showing is also the best of the best so
this is free range cage free humane certified
all right would you like to hear what we're doing
here yes what we're doing is we're showing the
behind the scenes of industries that abuse animals
like meat dairy eggs leather the next question you
have to ask them is how do you feel about animal
abuse usually they say well it's obviously wrong
100 against it that's what they usually say
people say okay so you think this is wrong
would you say this is evil this is me doubling
down to make sure i've owned them on this point
would you say this is evil would you say that
this is evil yes treating animals like our slaves
yeah would you say that stabbing animals to
death for a sandwich is wrong yeah yeah yeah
that's hard what are your initial thoughts how
does this kind of stuff make you guys feel guilty
yeah so it's safe to say that you guys are
against animal abuse yeah for sure i want you
all right i just want to clarify that again there
was an update here that we've made um i don't
think that closed-ended questions are actually as
effective as open-ended questions in this segment
of the interaction so instead of saying do you
think stabbing an animal to death for a sandwich
or torturing animals to death is evil
do you think that's evil do you think
that's wrong it's a closed-ended
question it's an obvious question
it's in fact more important for you to say how do
you feel about animal abuse and then when they say
i feel guilty i feel horrible it's terrible and
then the next thing you need to do to just confirm
their position on animal abuse is to say is it
safe to say that you are against animal abuse
and in in some circumstances i might even
triple down and say would you say it's evil
so you need to ask that open-ended question
first and then the closed-ended question
just to confirm and seal it off now
that will make sense why you need to
do that as i continue on with the approach
here showing you the step-by-step process
the footage how does it make you feel it makes
me cringe cringe why do you think it makes you
feel that way because i love the animals you love
animals interesting so safe to say you're against
animal abuse animal cruelty yeah absolutely most
people say yes absolutely now if they say no
they're either drunk or trolling and either
way you shouldn't be having a conversation
with those people they're not reachable
again this is so obviously wrong i mean
you're seeing animals being hacked apart on
the screens how could anybody say this is okay
so usually they say that then the next step would
be okay what do you think you can do about it as
an individual so we've gone from the first step
of the process within the three-step process of
emotional conviction really quickly moving to
the second step which is accountability what
do you think you can do about it and again most
of the time i actually get i think i could stop
eating them i could become vegan so what do
you think you can do about it as individuals
stop become vegan yes we can vegan it's very
simple isn't it yeah that's why i'm saying
this is so [ __ ] obvious to people it's not that
complex it's really not it's very obvious so the
interaction so then you say what do you think
you can do about this as an individual usually
they say well i can stop being vegan but if they
say something that a lot of the times they'll
actually try to distract and say well you can
protest the government protest these industries
again you deal with the objection bring it
back to accountability that's all you're doing
deal with the objection anchor it back to
accountability once you have the concede
after dealing with all of those back and
forth back and forth once you have them
concede then you bring in the benefits do you
know what the number one benefit is to be vegan
usually their ears perk up when you say
benefit and they look at you like what is it
i want to know and that's when you say
well obviously the benefit for them is
they're no longer tortured and abused
for you you're no longer the reason
that this happens to them but the benefit for you
is that you no longer have to be an animal abuser
right so a new update again and i'm gonna
break this down in the slides that i do later
but the update here is to
say for the first time um
you will have the opportunity to stop being a
hypocrite instead of saying you will no longer
be a hypocrite and i'm saying this because
many vegans are straight-up hypocrites
but when you become vegan it is the first
time in human life you can stop you have the
opportunity to stop being a hypocrite uh because
you address the biggest hypocrisy i think humans
are engaging in so i just want to clarify
that it doesn't automatically remove you
from hypocrisy when you become vegan but it does
give you an opportunity to truly end hypocrisy
and you no longer have to be hypocrite and abused
for you you're no longer the reason that this
happens to them but the benefit for you is that
you no longer have to be an animal abuser and you
no longer have to be a hypocrite because you say
that you're against animal abuse do you guys know
what the number one benefit is of not supporting
what's on the screen from being vegan any guesses
so the number one benefit obviously
for the animals once you're vegan
then they're no longer tortured and abused
because of you so they're relieved of that
and then the best benefit for you guys is that
because in the beginning of the conversation
you stated that you're against animal abuse
you're horrified by what's on the screens
when you're vegan for the first time
then you no longer have to be a hypocrite
never thought of it like that do you know the
number one benefit of going vegan the number
one benefit obviously for the animals once you're
vegan then they're no longer tortured because of
you so they're relieved of that and then the best
benefit for you is that because you said you're
against animal abuse when you're vegan for the
first time you no longer have to be a hypocrite
and do you know the number one benefit when
you stop supporting animals and be vegan the
number one benefit of that you're not part of a
crazy-ass society that's actually really close
it would first be for the animals would no
longer be abused by you but as an individual
this is really important on an individual
level since you've told me in this conversation
that you are against animal abuse and you're
clearly disturbed of what you see on the screen
when you become vegan for the first time
you no longer have to be a hypocrite
do you know the number one benefit of being vegan
like the number one benefit any guesses like
health health so health is conditional you can
absolutely receive some amazing health benefits
depending on how you coordinate your lifestyle but
the number one benefit would first of course be
for the animals they would no longer be abused
because of you but as individuals the number
one benefit would be if you say you're against
animal abuse and you look at these screens and
you're disgusted by it then you no longer have to
be a hypocrite it's really important that we don't
just say have a nice day after telling them the
benefit it's really important that you ask them
what they're going to do that's how you should
end the interaction so what do you think you'll do
and when people say i'll try to do better then you
tie in the fact that they shouldn't try they need
to do and the best way to end it is so what do
you think you'll do it's really important that
you close off strongly because then it's like
the whole interaction was for nothing if you
don't close it off properly without that close it
really like seals the whole conversation and they
really understand what the imperative is they're
after after seeing this footage after having
this conversation what do you think you'll
do moving forward regarding this suffering
i mean something had to be done but
so like just right there when hudson said what
do you think you'll do about this suffering
i'm just going to add this on and i'm
sure hudson will appreciate this because
he always appreciates these little updates but
he's absolutely killing it in these examples
um the suffering that you cause the suffering
that's happening because of you just a little
added update that i would make there and
i'll just go back this footage after having
this conversation what do you think you'll
do moving forward regarding this suffering
i mean something had to be done but i
don't know just keep in mind that until
the day comes that you're vegan animals
so i guess i spoke too soon there
because he ties in right here
um that further accountability that i was looking
to add into that comment he just made so let's
just retract that comment i made because
he really does double down at the end here
to make sure that this is happening because of
the individual so let's just continue our gonna
are gonna be victimized something had to be done
but i don't know just keep in mind that until
the day comes that you're vegan animals are
going to be victimized and abused because of you
so just think about what side of history you
want to stand on when it comes to stamping out
this particular injustice what do you think you
guys are going to do leaving here i feel like
i'll i'll think more about it i feel like the
next time i have me but whether they come vegan
i don't want to see that in my future to be honest
but i mean yeah just remember until the day that
you do align those actions with the words that
you said during this conversation that animals
will be abused because of you so just decide what
side of history you want to stand on what do you
guys think you're going to do after seeing this
footage i don't know i'm definitely going to try
to be more conscious about it i don't know if
i'm ready to fully be a vegan but i don't know
what i'll leave you guys with is that um
you agree that when you're taking baby steps
just keep in mind that for however long you are
taking baby steps animals are going to be tortured
for you guys so when you're ready to stop abusing
animals and stop being hypocrites then you guys
can be vegan so think about what side of history
you guys want to stand on all right what do
you think you're going to do leaving here we
rethink my [ __ ] process in terms of what i eat
for sure because i want to i want
to be a better person again is
just understand that until the day that
you do decide to align your actions
with the beliefs that you said
you've had during this conversation
the animals will be abused because of you so just
decide what side of history you want to stand on
when stamping out this particular injustice now
i know this seems confrontational you guys are
i just want to take a moment to give
a quick shout out to jacob and hudson
for those very fine examples they are killing it
right now and really adopting this approach whoops
i hope the audio was okay there but just want
to shout out to jacob and hudson they're doing
great work you're thinking [ __ ] i don't know if
i could just decide what side of history you want
to stand on when stamping out this particular
injustice now i know this seems confrontational
you guys are probably thinking [ __ ] i
don't know if i could say that to people but
i'm telling you this is the most satisfying
thing that you can say to somebody
because it's effective because that is the most
effective thing that you can say to somebody
and again this has been applied i mean we've got
a very keen student in the back here hudson do you
want to tell people what kind of reactions you've
had or if you've had any negative interactions
yes at first i was really worried about it about
this whole approach and paul was like no we gotta
try it you gotta try it and then i went up to
people who were twice my size hold up hold up
start from the start when you didn't want to do
this you thought that this was too aggressive
yeah i thought it was way too aggressive i got
brainwashed by the vegan movement and thought
that it's the wrong approach and anyway i recently
tried out this approach being direct and what i
found is people have so much more respect for me
because i don't come across as some politician
trying to sell them something and i found it's
worked so much better because people recognize
that we're not calling them hypocrites because
we don't like them we're doing it because we
don't like animal abuse and we're against the
torture of animals that's a big point unless
you have an ego issue this shouldn't be seen
as malicious by the person you're speaking to
unless you have an ego issue and you just want
to be right all the time and you're trying to own
people and that's the only reason why you're doing
activism then people may respond negatively to you
but what they pick up on is that your heart is in
the right place when you say this stuff you're not
saying this stuff for any other reason you
only know this to be true if you apply it
no matter what i say no matter what hudson just
said you need to apply this put aside everything
you've learned about outreach about everything
you've learned about animal rights activism and
just apply this not just today but for the
following cubes that occur after today keep
doing this and see what results you have because
again this is the reason why you went vegan
because you don't want to be a hypocrite you don't
want to be an animal abuser and someone called you
out on your hypocrisy if it wasn't someone else
it was yourself that made this distinction oh
i know it's crazy but apparently i need to
make this distinction for people when i say
holding non-vegans accountable i don't mean
forcing people to go vegan you can't hold
people accountable in the true sense of the word
because people have to hold themselves accountable
in the end it has to be a choice that comes from
them when i say holding people accountable it's
to the greatest extent that we can
possibly do so through verbal interaction
okay i didn't think i needed to clarify that but
i've been getting comments and dms from people
saying you can't force anyone to be vegan
this holding non-vegans accountable approach
is off base because people can
only hold themselves accountable
well this approach puts people in the best
position to hold themselves accountable
and that's the truth does this make sense to
everybody so thanks for the uh comments about
the audio there i'm doing my best here with the
technical end of things but let's just go back
doing this and see what results you have because
again this is the reason why you went vegan
because you don't want to be a hypocrite you don't
want to be an animal abuser and someone called
you out on your hypocrisy if it wasn't someone
else it was yourself that made this distinction
does this make sense to
everybody are you feeling this
all right now i'm going to take questions your
hand went up lightning fast i got to respect that
quickly what's your opinion on joaquin
phoenix's oscar speech on the long reaching
effectiveness of that i loved it but it's
i wouldn't have said exactly what he said
but i love the fact that he used his platform
to talk about what happens in the dairy industry
i didn't like how he conflated it with love and
compassion so much because i don't think you need
to love animals to not stab them to death you
don't need to love black people to know that
they deserve their rights you don't need to love
any being to know that they deserve their rights
it's not the perfect message but i still think
it was great that he did that i also want to
point out that joaquin phoenix said that meat and
dairy is the third leading cause of environmental
destruction or climate crisis but didn't we
hear in conspiracy that it was the leading cause
so why the [ __ ] are we even doing this why are
we even promoting environmentalism and trying to
use environmental facts when it keeps changing
on us when it comes to these things studies can
come back to us that may prove us wrong on the
environment tip in fact i've seen it proven that
you can be environmentally way more
better off as a non-vegan than a vegan
in many circumstances if you live in a rural area
you're a minimalist and you fish from your kayak
you're way more environmentally friendly than
a person who lives in new york procreates
eats processed foods so environmentally this is
not a surefire argument this really isn't and i
just want to say from the health point of view can
also be justified you can eat a piece of cheese or
you can eat a salmon once a week and justify that
from a health perspective because you just bounce
back very easily from a health point of view you
can feel better pretty quickly so there's no point
of even arguing the health and the environment for
those reasons next question even if that were true
reply like because i found that to be quite
good and when you say even if that were true
how do you justify this do you ever use that at
all i do i've been using that recently people
say i think there's bigger issues in the world
right human issues are more important well even
if there are bigger issues in the world which
we actually know that this is the biggest issue
with the health and environment the only reason
why we're talking about it is because animal
rights is such an issue that it's impacted our
environment it's become that big of an issue that
it impacts our environment and it impacts human
health to the extent that it does but we can give
them that still and say even if there are bigger
issues what justifies you doing this to them
any other questions yes i've found on the internet
so you put something up about veganism a lot of
people just put like you know means to take the
piss out of the veganism people sort of just go
straight to that and they won't listen to
you after that like so they take the piss
out of what you're trying to do and then you just
can't get through to them at all because they're
so fixated on taking the piss out of us how
would you get through take the piss out of them
roast them in return they're the ones that
are supposed to be roasted yeah but if they're
just trolling they're not reachable but my simple
response would be to roast them back but sometimes
it's just like people are more drawn to a picture
or something because the bulk amount of people
can just you know gang up on you like that and
it makes you feel like you know you should just
stop talking like it's sort of hard it feels
like you're trapped in that position where
you know like there's no actual response that's
worth and then it just makes you think oh you know
what i'm doing am i actually doing the right thing
is it worth me spending my time doing this you're
definitely doing the right thing when you speak
up for the animals it's always a good idea it's
always worth doing i think your question is is
it effective to be doing that is that what you're
asking yeah so i don't know like with regards to
the comments that coming in on your facebook or
instagram i don't know if those individuals are
going to go vegan but it may be more about who's
reading it you know what i'm saying the imprint
that you leave on those individuals it's important
that you only focus on what you're saying and how
you advocate for the animals so that if anybody
ever does stumble across the comment thread that
they read the right thing they hear what they're
supposed to hear from you know what i'm trying to
get at yeah yeah and that's the best you can do
whether you should be doing this with those
individuals i don't know because you'd have
to give me more specific examples about what
they're saying and how they're saying it
but if they're dropping memes about
eating meat and how tasty bacon is
i've actually found that roasting
those people can be pretty effective
don't waste too much energy on it you may want
to block them after a certain point once you've
made your point for people to read so you may
want to manage it that way on social media
but as long as you say the correct thing you're
in the right space yes um paul um i just wrote
down this thing that i was going to say when you
were talking about the blood on your hand on their
hands so i found it actually harder to speak to
people that i know personally that love animals
um also they love animals they actually i've
lost four people that i've known for a long
time because they they seem to think that my
message is hateful so people who have tried
to break down the barriers um around animals
in agriculture they reject any notion of even
so when my compassion for the animals involved
into more what you would call aggression and
like passionate speaking and ask why they can
ignore those animals quite um and can be hateful
how do we get people to abandon a lifetime
of adoption and views around farm animals
particularly as people seem to not acknowledge
their sentience or even have any regard for
them as if they're not relevant other
than as a commodity so i've found that
by trying to get people to engage their
compassion or even their sense of justice around
animals yeah and you're the only one who's
making them visible or attempting to at
this point yes like they know that that you know
advertising exists but they actually don't connect
they have to disconnect in order to sleep at night
and what you represent is a mirror you're a mirror
and when they call you hateful you are actually
hateful but not to them you're hateful to their
actions they're the abuse that's occurring to the
animals so don't again don't let people shame you
out of these things yes you are hateful own it
you are hateful you do hate what they're doing
to animals that's why you're speaking up and
that's why you're passionate you're not just
passionate this is an art we're talking about
you're not just passionate about this this is
an injustice and you are angry you hate the fact
that your friends people you love are so willing
to make excuses for something
so unbelievably unjustifiable
right that's what you hate the fact that they're
yeah but like even the people that you outreach to
like actually trying to make them feel something
though because it could be on their radar
what from what you've told me i actually think
that they do have it on their radar because
that's why they're trying to disconnect and call
you hateful things when they say things that are
inaccurate and irrational it's a sign that they
do have guilt and guilt is a sign of them caring
about the subject it's just so far buried down
there because that's where it needs to be for
them to sleep at do you understand these people
do care about this issue you're just living proof
of it being made into action and having your your
actions aligned with your morals and you represent
something to them that makes them feel
inadequate and they should [ __ ] feel that way
you do hate what they're doing
to the animals let them know that
that you don't respect what they're doing to
the animals and there's no way that they can
justify it keep asking them how do you justify
this even if you think that a cow doesn't feel
the same way as a dog or the same way more
importantly don't use a dog as an example use them
how would you feel if you're in a cow's position
what crime has a cow committed other than being
born non-human there's no way they can justify so
asking these basic questions usually will lead you
to having them face the facts and a vegan well
they may temporarily but if that's the reason i
don't talk to you anymore for someone who is a
concerned citizen speaking up against injustice
then they're not really your friend are they
friends don't abandon friends over something so
obviously righteous like that even if they're
the perpetrator again they can't justify it
a real friend would be like you know what i
respect the fact that you called me out and
there's nothing i can say like i am hypocrite
and i am an animal abuser or even if they don't
admit to that they would at least keep you in
their lives if they respected the fact that
you're speaking up against this and then it's
up to you how long you keep them in your lives
does that help yeah thanks a lot cool
stop share so there it is that was the holding
non-vegans accountable 2.0 from perth australia
that was the second stop on the australian leg
of the world tour that we
embarked on in february which got
put to an end due to the coronavirus
so i will take questions and i will also
start using this presentation with the
slides to break down this whole thing once over
just to reiterate all the points that were made
it is good to feel bad about
something that is bad simple
i love simplicity and effectiveness
the simpler the better
in terms of effectiveness it has
to have that effectiveness there
but the simplicity i just love that so much okay
so i'm gonna get these slides downloaded
but if you guys have any questions
lace me up in the comments
okay where is this
here we are
all right so i'm going to go
over everything once more just
to reiterate all these points and make
sure you guys fully understand them
there was a complaint about my speaking voice
how is the audio coming through let me know
oh
nope this isn't it
this is it um
um okay so question by carlo hi paul
once you understand that the person
you are talking to is not going to be interested
in the topic and continues justifying animal abuse
what do you say to them before going away all
these examples you saw and everything that we
said in the approach applies to these
individuals the only difference is that
at some i'm assuming that these people
probably at a cube of truth probably
won't even stop but if they do stop and
you're talking to them at some point
it could be really powerful for you to just end
the discussion with that that uh statement that
was made at the end of the interaction you saw
examples from hudson and jacob um just know that
for as long as you remain non-vegan these animals
will be tortured and abused because of you and
just decide what side of history so i'll
i'll leave this with you to think about but
you ultimately will need to decide which side of
history you want to stand on something powerful
like that a statement like that is all you can
really do with those individuals and i i just want
to say that it's important that you respect your
time as an activist and that you're not wasting
your breath on people so it's very powerful to
say to the individual that you would like to
carry on your work with those who are like you'd
like to move on you know so ending the discussion
and moving on after you make that statement is
super powerful and that's what you should do
audio is fine good thank you guys
i've got the slide ready i'm just
going to read through your comments
and see if there's any questions
david's saying i would only say i
wouldn't mind if an animal killed me
but i would say i would eat you would say
that you would eat a human okay david you uh
you sound a bit confused buddy i don't
think you would be okay with an animal
eating you if you had a choice and
you have a choice not to eat animals
so you're the oppressor and the power is in your
hands to end the suffering and abuse and torture
that you would inflict on these animals otherwise
if you choose to continue to be a non-vegan human
supremacist because that's what non-vegans are
human supremacists and you are subscribing to this
death cult you're subscribing to this
idea that animals should be reduced
to a sandwich through violent
beheadings and enslavement and torture
david says it's an excuse but i'm
addicted addiction isn't a justification
so let's hope that david gets the message
here and does actually connect his actions
to his words and ends his hypocrisy for real but
let's move on to your other questions here guys
can you say something about infighting between
vegans and outreach organizations i hate it and
how to stop this welcome to the animal rights
movement if you know how i can stop this i'd
like to know um vegans are the biggest threat
to the animal rights movement i've been saying
this for a while i learned this the hard way gary
told me told everyone and i didn't think it was
necessarily true either at first but i've come
to learn this very much so humans what can i say
it's terrible but one thing that gives me optimism
and hope is that there are plenty of us out there
who vibrate on this frequency and that's all
we need to do to continue moving forward is
us supporting us so when i read your comments
supporting av supporting me and asal and the
whole av team we appreciate it so much
because it means that we are working
together we do have unity between those who
vibrate on this frequency and that's important
where can you get the new outreach cards from
your organizer if there's no organizer in
your city go over to our website and go to the
join section and apply to become an organizer
so that you can launch a cube of truth a chapter
in your city where cuba truth events operate
lots of questions coming through
how do i respond to people that
say they can't go vegan because of
medical advice point them to
all of the medical advice that
that says otherwise we have empirical data
that shows that it's perfectly adequate for
all human beings to be on a plant-based diet
point them to the evidence there's only one
source of scientific data there's only
one database okay so michael greger is
a great person to look into because he breaks down
the data so nutritionfacts.com but the thing i
just want nutritionfacts.org is the website there
but i just want to say that this person saying
this most likely woody is using this as an excuse
to not go vegan if they're truly wanting to end
the abuse that they cause to animals the needless
suffering or in their case they think it's
required but if they really want to end it then
they'll look into it and they'll do their very
damnedest to make it happen to to end it
and so if you are talking to someone who's
truly trying to end it then just give them that
information that should be enough but usually
it comes back to accountability in those cases
usually people are just using that as an excuse
is it cruel to raise kids
non-vegan it's cruel to the animals
yeah and it is cruel to humans on some
level but it's not even comparable to
what we do to the animals so i'm not even
going to say it's cruel to the humans um so
what was the other part of that
question um saying this as a mother
it's cruel to the animals and you're robbing
children and you're robbing children over there
you're making them confused and you're robbing
them off i mean every vegan will say they wish
they were vegan since birth so you're robbing
them of that opportunity to do the right thing
when kids are just doing what their parents
tell them to do so when non-vegans say don't
force this on your children they're forcing
non-veganism on their children parenting is
forcing that's what parenting is they do what
their parents tell them to do up until they're 18.
so it's if you're gonna have to choose a diet for
them why wouldn't you choose the one that doesn't
involve bloodshed abuse torture suffering when
it's needless that's my answer to that question
much love jeanette appreciate your comment
um
how do you convince religious people or anyone
who is used to seeing animal abuse since young
to feel something for the animals that's two
different questions there religious people
it's no different this whole approach is no
different if people say i
believe god said it's okay
classic gary quote if god says this
is okay then what does the devil do
just you're not going to get through
to most religious people you just
need to ask them these really tough questions
and treat them no different to anyone else
with the approach that we're giving you
okay um and that second question
i think i've already answered
generally all right guys um there are other
questions here and if you're not going to stay
on this stream you can watch this back when this
video goes up and i will respond to your question
at some point but i'm now going to get into
the slides in the interest of time management
right i'm gonna share this
and i'm just gonna go through
each of the points that were raised
in that workshop for you guys
all right sharing my screen once again whoops
all right can you guys see that okay
i'm confident that you can but just to make sure
let me know in the comments if you can
see that slide i'm about to go through
i just need one of you guys to
confirm and then i'll continue
can you see the outreach workshop slides
okay
all good cool thanks guys all right so let's get
into it so this is our outreach workshop in slides
you might see organizers in your city or town and
if you are an organizer or you become an organizer
your organizer may run through a workshop with
you in your city and they'll use these slides
and these slides may be updated from time to
time but right now this is our most updated
outreach workshop in slide format so let's let's
go so we start with this important question
what even is veganism if you ask a
group of people what it means to be
vegan you most likely will get multiple
versions of what they believe it to be
veganism has nothing to do with our health the
environment human rights or affection towards
animals it is not about justice for non-human
animal rights vegan equals anti-animal abuse
now i'm not going to make any extra points
here unless they naturally come to me
but if you guys in the comments want to make any
points or any questions about this slide be as
quick as you can while this slides up i'm gonna
wait two minutes between each slide so that if
there's anything specifically that you would like
me to address regarding the points on each slide
i'll address them as we go so two minutes starting
now i'm going to start my stopwatch on my phone
you know we have to start with the definition
of veganism before we even talk about activism
so two minutes if anyone wants to
discuss anything here let me know
it's two minutes too long maybe
i should just do one minute
yeah common sense and self-explanatory
this slide all right well i'm i'm gonna
reduce that to one minute so we've got 30
seconds to go i think one minute is plenty
i don't have anything i'd like to add to
this it's very straightforward like you said
so 10 seconds i'm assuming
there's no questions here
i'm an admin of the malaysian vegan facebook
group one question we ask people who request
to join is what veganism means to them most
of them say it's kindness and great health
wow yeah that's just typical isn't it it's a
very common thing in the animal rights movement
and the other thing i want to point out is
you know when you ask what the benefit is
most people say health or the environment which
just goes to prove we don't need to talk about
health and the environment with people and talk
about them as benefits and act like that's what
animal rights is all about people already know
about those things what they really need to hear
is accountability for what they're
doing to the animals that's it moving on
all right so what is animal rights activism
activism is speaking up for the victims
in the same way that you would want to be
spoken up for if you were in their position
it is being a medium of truth and enacting change
by prioritizing the victims and not the oppressors
one minute starting now i don't
have anything to add to this either
this might even change to 30 seconds because i
don't want to drag this out for people watching
this back i want this to be as succinct as
possible but i just want to make sure i cover any
questions or points that might come up i just want
to be as thorough as possible in addressing this i
think i might reduce the time that i put aside for
you guys to 30 seconds in fact instead of a minute
all right let's move on yeah i'm going to
reduce this down to 30 seconds between slides
to allow you guys to jump in if you want
me to discuss anything more specifically
crystal clear says carlo great
don't try to be a communications guru
this goes back to the sales thing almost
um always remember that you will never have
100 success rate within animal rights outreach
there is no magic set of words to use during
outreach that will make someone go vegan
if they're ready they'll listen if they're not
ready they won't with the context provided your
function as an activist is to hold the individual
you're speaking with accountable for the animal
abuse they support and to make them aware of
the consequences of their choices 30 seconds
is too quick 30 seconds
if it's too quick uh how about we just
do a compromise make it 45 seconds
i just don't want it to get too
slow for those watching this back
you know
okay
cool all right so let's move
on we've done 45 seconds there
30 david's voting 30. all right let's
move on so your goal should not be to
plant seeds animal rights outreach is not
verbal leafleting i'm going to repeat that
standing in front of a non-vegan and spitting
all these little factoids out at them
is not activism and i heard someone say planting
seeds in the comments i mean i know planting seeds
is like a common term used in the animal rights
movement specifically but i guess we're doing that
but it's not in the same way that people think of
planting seeds that's not what we're doing here
animal rights outreach is not verbal leafleting
if the goal were to provide information we would
hand out leaflets and magazines and if that was
all that people needed to go out to go vegan then
the information is already out there so
it's not necessarily about the information
the function of outreach is to make
people understand the consequences of
their choices by holding them accountable
and centering the interaction on what they
can personally do about the animal
of the use on an individual level
45 seconds
is there anything here that you guys have any
questions about i don't apologize um you know
don't apologize this is a learning process i'm
taking you guys on i've learned this stuff and
i'm just teaching you guys what i've learned
and what we've learned together actually so
not verbal leafleting is the biggest
part of this slide no verbal leafleting
that's just cancer in the animal rights movement
i've seen it so many times i've done it myself
it gets you nowhere and it makes this message
seem even more of a like a mockery to people
like it's it takes it takes it down a notch to
then being taken less seriously so all right
that's 45 seconds moving on veganism is not
love or compassion veganism is about justice
your likability does not determine your rights so
out i'm going to repeat that just because someone
doesn't like you it doesn't mean they have
the right to take your rights away from you
so that's why we don't need to lean into how much
people like animals that's just the wrong way to
communicate this message outreach is not about
how you or anyone else feels about animals if
you don't go around beating children you aren't
instantly a compassionate individual refraining
from injustice does not make you compassionate by
default and we can see that because in the animal
rights movement vegans are some of the least
compassionate people that i have to deal with
veganism is a non-action it's not loving
it's merely the right thing to do 45
seconds
all right i'm reading your comments guys if
there's anything you want me
to expand on now's your time
you know what i'm going to reduce this back down
to 30 seconds uh and if you guys like need more
time to write your comment just start off with
a comment that you can just send out real quick
that says i have a comment or i have something
i want to add and then i will wait for you to
write your longer question if this is too quick
so i'm going to reduce this back to 30 seconds
and that's what you can do if you have any
questions but there are questions coming in now
so i will answer them what does leaf litting mean
leafleting means handing out pieces of information
to people and then it's just like all these little
factoids about like how old chickens are when
they're murdered and all these things and you know
the the irony of how counterproductive this is is
obvious to me because so many non-vegans already
know about how much of a shocker the meat dairy
and egg industries are they already know that they
treat animals horribly they already know about how
young the animals are when they're murdered and
all these crazy statistics and it's very easy
to find out but it doesn't make people go vegan
because knowing all these factoids is one thing
and yes that might cause some people to go
vegan i take that back i know some of you
thinking well i went vegan when i looked
into the dairy industry but at some point
there was accountability for your actions and
wanting to be accountable for yourself for what
you're doing to them and yeah that's what it
comes down to these factoids don't really push
people towards it it just puts them in a position
where they just feel like they need to continue
arguing the points and all this stuff and it's
just it's not it's not very effective at all so
let's see if there's any other comments here
ariane huge comment very well said people
will forget about the facts anyways
what they will remember is the
guilty feeling when they hear
that they are animal abusers so just to expand
on ariane's point here and point out how
how true that is there's a really great quote that
everyone knows and it's just so true people don't
remember what you said they remember how they felt
when you said it and that's what this is all about
yeah veganism is about justice we
can't point that out enough seemingly
so we cannot point it out enough all right moving
on guys thanks for your comments i appreciate it
i just want to make sure that i
cover everything for you guys and
i appreciate you guys being a part of
this live stream all right moving on
this approach is pure honesty telling someone the
truth is the most respectful thing you can do for
them when you agree with every statement said by
the bystander they will often lose respect for you
and you will lose respect so you will lose control
of the conversation they see that your desire to
be validated by them is stronger than your desire
to end animal cruelty thereby making a mockery of
animal rights this one needs to be repeated
they see that your desire to be validated by
them is stronger than your desire to end animal
cruelty thereby making a mockery of animal rights
you imagine if the primary goal of human rights
activists was to be liked by the oppressors
30 seconds
all right that's 30 seconds i'm liking
the 30 seconds it feels like the right
amount of time here moving on
whenever you are afraid to speak up for animals
directly or if bystanders call you too extreme
place yourself in the victim's position and
analyze your approach from their perspective would
you consider a respectful yet direct conversation
too extreme if you were locked in a slaughterhouse
and that's the thing you know we are being
respectful here it's the most respect you'll
ever show someone because you're telling
the truth and giving them a true opportunity
to end their hypocrisy and to stop
abusing innocent beings like a psychopath
like a cold-blooded monster
that's what these people
are especially once they know about what is
going on and they continue to do it right
um i forgot to press start on the 30 seconds
so let's just say we're up to 15 seconds now
yes honesty is the highest form of intimacy this
might be irritating to some but it may not stop us
from telling the truth that's beautiful
yeah that's so true honesty is the
highest form of intimacy word all right
moving on guys all right so next slide
don't talk about health and environment
why do we think people care about either
most people in the streets do not care
about their health nor the environment
so rooting your outreach in these topics will
marginalize the animals even further health and
environment may become have become exacerbated
because people do not take animal abuse seriously
um again i need to repeat this
point because this is really
powerful to know and understand that these
crisis that we're facing that we're facing
that we're facing with our
environment and our health
is just an indication merely a a sign that's all
it is of how bad animal abuse is on this planet
again i was supposed to press start there
um oh no i haven't finished this all right
um the last point trying to hook people with
an approach that revolves around what benefits
them does not let me start again trying to hook
people with an approach that revolves around what
that revolves around what benefits
them does a disservice to the animals
focus on the root cause of
the issue the animal abuse
i kind of stumbled through that one but you
get the point you can see it i'm going to
start this 30 seconds if you guys have anything
you'd like me to expand on here let me know
people say this is fake that it's not
true what to say just point at the screens
what part of this is fake challenge them to go
into a farm for themselves and see what happens
in a slaughterhouse specifically say because
that's where all the animals end up right
uh i
i feel that i don't want to be friends with
people after giving information anymore
who won't go vegan well that's
the right position i think
you wouldn't again when you compare this
to any other injustice you wouldn't stick
around and be friends with people who continue to
enslave torture and murder once they know better
if we were the victims we would not want our
advocates to prioritize the environment or our
oppressor's health no and it would it would be a
huge spit in your face to do that that's the whole
point of clarifying this for you guys because
the victims deserve so much better from us to
be advocating directly for them and they they do
deserve a direct message that's dedicated to them
yes yes okay um what are some variable ways
to start the conversation other than have
you seen this type of footage before we don't
actually ask that anymore have you seen this
type of footage before we do sometimes
but in this approach with this update
you don't need to ask that in fact what we do
is we say would you like to know why we're here
um so vegan mark i'm not sure if you're just
joining the stream but we did cover this you
might want to watch this video back and it will
be available for everyone to watch back once i'm
done and we did cover that raping is bad for
your health yeah that's what it sounds like
never met a 100 zero waste and whole food
vegan so why expect non-vegans to care
exactly summer it's so obvious isn't it i always
say health and environment are just consequences
of animal abuse and our mentality towards animals
and if we want to solve a problem we have to pull
the root of evil out very well said david if
you said that to me when i wasn't vegan that
would punch me in the stomach in the best way you
can see you can say would you like to know why
we're here today yes thank you jaz you've been
paying attention all right cool let's move on
why don't people care about ethics let's explore
that because vegans don't advocate for animals
correctly they focus on things like plant-based
recipes restaurants weight loss or deforestation
another reason is they lead with
phrases like friends not food
or animal lovers don't eat animals this
is not a conversation about sympathy
this is a conversation about accountability
don't plead with bystanders make them understand
the consequences of their choices by
placing them in the victim's position
30 seconds i don't have anything else to add
to this unless you guys want me to expand on it
um check out the majority of vegans online
rather not just on instagram vegan king
they don't even talk about animals yeah
it seems like in this movement that the
animals barely get a mention they barely get a
shout out and we quickly move on to humans and
humans humans humans how does this
affect humans let's talk about that
when humans are the oppressors it's just
backwards
all right cool you guys don't have anything uh you
want me to expand on here so i'm going to move on
all right next slide morality is black and white
when it comes to this issue specifically i'm
talking about guys okay i'm not talking about
these fringe gray area examples that could be
brought up with very insignificant choices
you could say this is very significant and
it's involving in it's involving oppression so
when you're talking about an issue of oppression
where there are victims involved morality is black
and white when it comes to that if bystanders tell
you that you aren't considering the other side
to this or you aren't open-minded enough that is
a distraction there is no other side to needless
animal abuse you either support it or you don't
don't get lost in these distractions compare
animal abuse to a comparable injustice to get
you back on track and like i was saying earlier
on in this video the best injustice to compare to
is the one that involves the individual you're
speaking to as the victim so if they imagine
themselves as the victim of the injustice that
you're speaking about when you compare it that's
going to be the best way for them to feel what
it is they need to feel in that moment 30 seconds
good night daniel thank you
for being a part of this man
uh i don't know who epa is david
all right we've done 30 seconds i
don't see anything you guys want me to
expand on here so we're going to move on
all right moving on so the next
slide where we got to the 12th slide
okay which injustices to compare to so i
actually break this last point i just made
even further down in this slide it is most
effective to compare to injustices such as
child abuse or human trafficking child abuse and
human trafficking are the most comparable human
injustices that we've found to compare to the
most effective comparison to make is to place
the bystander in the victim's position i just
explained that but that's there for you again to
absorb i really want you to take that
into consideration and really absorb that
avoid dog comparisons this goes
back to not leading with compassion
it's not about the love people feel towards
animals it's about the hate they feel towards
injustice and i would say injustice in their name
or because of them not in their name but because
of their actions right in their name is kind of an
ego thing it doesn't come down to whether you can
imagine your dog in a slaughterhouse it comes
down to whether you can imagine yourself in a
slaughterhouse right i'm going to repeat that it
doesn't come down to whether you can imagine your
dog in a slaughterhouse it comes down to whether
you can imagine yourself in a slaughterhouse
that's the truth that's what makes
you really wake up to this 30 seconds
yeah so carlo about the moralities
black and white you have to
clarify that specifically we're talking
about injustices that involve victims
oppression these things are black and white
if it's needless and this is it needs to stop
it's really simple you don't need to
necessarily say morality is black and white
i'm just pointing this out in this in
this workshop for you guys that you need
to understand morality is black and white and the
way that you communicate this to other people but
you don't necessarily need to say morality
is black and white in those words but yeah
if people want to get into a philosophical
discussion you know just put an end to that
america's environmental protection agency is
the epa which is a broken government system
uh yeah i wouldn't i don't have any interest
um okay yeah people just say they don't mind
eating dogs as well it happens so often yeah
what about dogs yeah well if i had to eat a dog
i would it just immediately blows up in our face
um and i'm talking about most of the time here dog
comparisons seemingly work niraj they seemingly
work because your indicator of an effective
conversation might be someone doing this uh-huh
yes i agree yes uh-huh that's not necessarily
effective it's very easy to agree with things like
um like if they had a dog with them and they
obviously care about their dog like they're
walking with the dog and then they're showing
you know like empathy for their dog in some way
and you say well what if that dog was stabbed to
death yeah it's an easy thing to agree with yep
but what happens when that dog dies in the family
how long will they take to grieve that dog's life
compared to a human compared to how sad
they would feel about their own death and
if they were going to be
murdered you see what i'm saying
all right i'm going to move on i don't
see any comments here wanting me to
expand on this particular slide i think i've
covered as much as i can so let's move on
statistics keep them minimal outside of what is
asked of you state minimal information during
outreach conversations we are not on the streets
to verbally leaflet again let the footage provide
the context to the conversation you aren't at a
cube of truth to be a statistician you're there
to have a concise conversation that holds people
to account for their unjustified animal abuse a
conversation will go on for longer than necessary
if it turns into an argument over statistic
over statistics this is another reason why you
should bring up health and environment talking
points why you shouldn't pardon me this is another
reason why you shouldn't bring up health and
environment talking points because that usually
leads into a never-ending debate about nothingness
seconds if you guys have any points
you want me to expand on let me know
yeah this is a good point
here if the conversation went
to logic i usually believe the person won't
go vegan try to keep it about the abuse and
here it says best of a logic person is to
go plant-based veganisms from your heart
you do need to hit people in the chest people
talk part of me you're talking about how
you know it's how you make people feel
that's what people are going to remember
moving on
yeah it's not a debate club on the streets very
good point street activism is not a debate club
moving on guys reachability and conversation
length not everybody on the streets is worth
talking to part of your role is to assess
who is reachable and who is not many people
are not reachable if they want to have a short
conversation with you keep it short with them
don't entertain bystanders who want to engage
in long argumentative debates we just covered
that do not underestimate the cunningness
of non-vegan guilt and the ability that non
vegans many non-vegans will have to waste
your vital time at work for the animals
that's a huge point that last one 30
seconds
yeah part of the game here
is assessing who is reachable
you get better at this with practice by the way
yeah well jezebel you're right it's also logical
the point here is to not get lost in the logic
you have to also have what
hits people in the chest too
cunningness what is cunningness you
mean the actual definition of the word
let's look it up the actual definition of
the word according to miriam webster is
skill in achieving one's ends through
indirect subtle or underhanded means
and here's an example it took a certain amount of
cunningness on the photographer's part to obtain
such revealing portraits of his rich and famous
subjects anyhow the way it applies here in this
context is that non-vegans are very cunning in the
way that they address these arguments with vegans
and the way that they try to make vegans think
that plants have feelings for example like they
really get deep into it and they're like yeah
like they feel stuff and like yeah they're like
they act like they really believe it but it's
just their cunningness is a lie it's really
their guilt trying to double down you know so um
are there any questions here i'm not even going
to do the 30 seconds thing because i've given
you guys plenty of time while i've been talking
yes it does stay online afterwards malia
this will be available online once i'm done
you can tell by their body language when they're
not even looking at the footage because they're
only there to waste our time yeah if they don't
want to be there just get them to go just go
indirect distractions and so on yes exactly
indirect distractions that's what it is
all right moving on guys it doesn't seem like
you guys want me to expand on much here so i
might even just keep this moving at a quicker
pace activism is not sales sales training does
not equal good activism using slick talk to trick
people into veganism doesn't work your job is to
hold the bystander accountable it's up to them
which actions they take initially av made too
strong of a connection between sales and activism
tools taught in sales training only go so far
any questions about this or anything you
want me to expand on it 30 seconds but
[ __ ] i might even reduce this
down even further 10 seconds
now i'll keep it at 30 seconds but uh
let me let me know guys if you want me to break
anything down further for you five seconds
moving on so the next slide activism is not
sales we're still continuing on this thing
a successful conversation is not one
where the bystander says i'm going vegan
that's not necessarily the thing that you should
be looking for it's where you say the right things
most people become vegan after they hear the truth
from us how long it takes is up to the individual
30 seconds
okay so uh there's a question here i'm you're
still confused about the sales thing could you
give me an example or more could you be more
specific about what you're confused about
good question summer do you still promote feel
felt found i never really understood what that
means again that was just a communication tool i
thought it would be helpful i don't use it anymore
and it's not in this outreach workshop for a
reason that you have pointed out and i appreciate
that we've removed it because again we make too
strong of a connection to sales and i don't want
people to think that these communication tools are
the approach like this is that's not an approach
that's just a tool a little tiny little tool
that can help with your communication but feel
fat found no you don't really need to use
that and we've removed it it's unnecessary
what you said about giving fair warning
before asking a question or commenting
is a good way to proceed awesome like
how do we know if we've made an impact
on their perception apart from their
guilt you don't uh you well you don't
there are certain indicators but like we say here
most people become vegan after they hear the truth
from us how long it takes is up to the individual
and that's why i say i want you to connect to this
approach in in i want you to connect to
understanding that if you say the right things
on behalf of the victims then you have succeeded
in your outreach because that's the best you can
do the next step is physically forcing people
to become vegan which we can't do does that help
sales is too much practical veganism
is more from the from our internals
not sure what you mean there soilless magician
is it good to start with the socratic method
to get to know where the individual is
at well socratic questioning is
something that we touch on in this
so jazz just stick around and i'll get into
that further all right guys i'm gonna move on
okay that does help good let's move on
the socratic the very next slide there it is jazz
maybe we sensed the line of questions that
might come from you guys and that's why we
put this slide next all right so socratic
the socratic method socratic questioning
is a communication tool that we use within our
approach it is not an approach in and of itself
and neither is the sales thing where we ask
questions to lead the bystander to their own
conclusions so yes jazz you're right and i'll
read that again okay so credit questioning is
a communication tool that we use within our
approach it is not an approach in and of itself
where we ask questions to lead the
bystander to their own conclusions
use open-ended questions such as why are you sorry
let me start again use open-ended questions such
as why are you against animal abuse instead of
a closed statement such as animal abuse is wrong
open-ended questions are
generally prefer preferred
i've got a problem with speaking today open-ended
questions are generally preferred to anchor
and progress the conversation you should use
closed-ended questions and statements 30 seconds
would it be possible to ask the non-vegan to give
us feedback on the conversation they had well
we kind of do at the end we say what do you
think you'll do that gives you the answer
and danya if i'm saying
you're not your name correctly
dania could you also point out the tip about
open-ended questions are generally preferred
to anchor and progress the conversation you
should you should use closed-ended questions and
statements so we're not saying use open-ended
questions all the time that's just ridiculous
but generally they are preferred i'm
going to move on now to the next slide
you versus we we don't torture animals and kill
animals for products non-vegans do using we
undermines individual accountability when you tell
non-vegans that we as a society are responsible
for animal cruelty in farms it takes away the
imperative for the individual accountability it
makes them think of lobbying government programs
etc instead of personal responsibilities people
need to feel guilty to change they'll only change
once they understand that there is a difference
between you the vegan and them the non-vegan
and that difference needs to be very clear
30 seconds
i can add and say that guilt is the only way
in my opinion to get people to go vegan not
plant-based but transform them into a vegan
activist that's gonna change the [ __ ] world
amen
um can we mean i was in the same boat as
the non-vegan well that's the thing it's
being used that way but when you say we you no
longer do it so it's just completely inaccurate
you're making an inaccurate statement
in an effort to seem more humble
which is really just trying to be liked
which is really focusing on getting
compassion from the abusers as opposed to
focusing your compassion on the victims
does that help
all right moving on thank you for your comments
guys but um i'm going to move on so on to the next
people already know how to go
vegan this is the why versus how
people already know how to go vegan with the
constant availability of google and the internet
people are literally glued to their phones in
2020. anybody can figure out how to become vegan
instantly in order for people to feel the need to
become vegan they need to be held accountable for
why they said for why they should do it my vision
is going blurry at this point i'll read that again
in order for people to feel the need to become
vegan they need to be held accountable for
why they should do it with any other injustice you
would never focus on the how by talking about how
to not participate in the violence so i'm
reading this incorrectly let me start again
with any other injustice you would never
focus on the how by talking about how
to not participate in the violence focusing on the
how in the context of any other injustice would be
an insult to the victims and the entire movement
fighting to end their oppression 30 seconds
how do you convince intersectionals to
be vegan intersectionals to be vegan
i'm assuming they're not vegan then usually i
find intersectionals are vegan but if they're
if they're not even vegan you i would just
say to talk to them like you talk to anybody
else
yes moving on guys thank you on to the next
slide vegetarianism is cancer to animal rights
vegetarians are non-vegans and should be
outreached in the same manner as anyone else
and in most cases even harder because vegetarians
act so pompous vegetarians are our target market
they're no different to paleo eaters
why should we treat them any differently
they are not allies don't let other non-vegans
and vegans manipulate you into thinking that
they are 30 seconds i don't have
anything to add to these points if
if i'm just moving straight into looking at
the comments and it doesn't look like you guys
want me to expand on this
it's pretty straightforward
all right five seconds vegetarians
are proper carnists yeah well said
they should get tenfold harsher
activism especially if they're pompous
especially if they're pompous all right
moving on typical outreach structure ask
them if they would like to know why
you're here this was asked earlier
ask them if they would like to know why you're
here and with the context of the footage playing
tell them what the cube of truth sets out to
do what we are doing is showing the reality of
what happens to animals and the meat dairy
egg and other industries everything you see
here is standard practice here and around the
world asking the following open-ended question
what are your feelings on animal abuse
then confirm their stance to form moral
consistency with something like so it's safe to
say that you are against animal abuse 30 seconds
hmm
moving on
we're nearly nearly finished
with these slides also guys
typical outreach structure ask them do
they think it's possible to be against
animal abuse while demanding
products like meat dairy and eggs
i don't think we covered this in the uh
presentation but this is a powerful point
i'm going to read it again ask them do you
think it's possible to be against animal
abuse while demanding products like meat dairy
and eggs ask them what is stopping them from
not abusing animals and being vegan what
do you feel like would be stopping you from
not abusing animals and being vegan this
will lead to their objections 30 seconds
how to respond if they
don't consider those footage
wow let me read this question out um how to
respond if people don't consider the footage
to be animal abuse you have no conversation to be
having with that person move on to the next person
if blood flying everywhere and heads being cut
off is not animal abuse if baby male chicks if
baby chicks are being grinded alive in a big
blender and they don't think that's animal abuse
you're not talking to a rational person so i would
say you need to move on to the next person jezebel
if they say they don't care about animal
abuse is it best just to end the conversation
i would say what if you were the one being
abused would you care then or it's easy to
say when you're the abuser what if you were the
one being abused that's the upgrade there for you
and then move on if it goes
downhill from there because
this is not a rational open and
willing person you're speaking to
carlo recently you said in a video
we have to avoid the word vegan i'm
a little confused about it now so you suggest
to openly say we are promoting veganism or not
i never said to not use the word vegan in
fact i say i said that i used the word vegan
it's just what i'm saying carlo is that
it's far more effective for us to explain
what the meaning like to say
human supremacy or animal abuse
you know to detail what it really means to be
vegan like if in this point um if i mean at
this point in the conversation you're saying if
we are saying that we're promoting veganism um
this is it depends this is something that i would
say if someone says you're promoting vegetarianism
i would correct that and say we're not promoting
vegetarianism because that doesn't address the
issue at all we're promoting veganism so i would
not shy away from saying the word vegan however
it's usually best for you to talk about what that
word actually means than to just use the word
why because the word has a lot of confusion
around it within the animal rights movement
you can see how there's so
many definitions flying around
and that's why we started this with
the definition of veganism itself
even if they are killed quickly it is
still animal abuse of course because again
if you were the victim it is still abuse to take
your life even if it's done quickly of course
you would see it as abuse in that circumstance you
know the jews who were killed in the concentration
camps if they were gassed and killed quickly
that doesn't make the injustice any less worse
cool um moving on next slide objection handling
whenever a bystander brings up an objection
place them in the victim's position
and allow them to analyze the objection
from that perspective every single time
this happens the objection will fall apart
most objections are easy and quick to respond
to some are more nuanced and require a deeper
explanation but they should still be quick to
respond to your response should always anchor
back to individual accountability this can't be
more simple this is so simple again 30 seconds
all right moving on
bring it back to the individual if they try to
create excuses that try to remove accountability
for example pointing to rural communities lions
low income families etc don't get lost in lengthy
explanations bring it back to the individual
by placing themselves in the victims position
and asking how that excuse justifies their
personal contribution to animal abuse
i don't know if contribution is the right word
i might update that but you
guys know what this is saying
uh yeah 30 seconds i'm gonna
shave five seconds off that so 25
seconds
objections are good they can
be good yes they can be good
all right moving on next slide
um tying the benefit tying the benefit only
once they concede by saying if they're against
animal abuse then it's not possible to be
against animal abuse while supporting it
the number one benefit of going vegan for the
animals the benefit is that they no longer have
to be tortured and abused because of you for
you if you say you are against animal abuse
and what you see on the screens then when you're
vegan you no longer have to be a hypocrite
and so we're going to update this part like i said
to say when you're vegan you have the opportunity
for the first time in your life to not be
a hypocrite so that's the update there when
you're vegan you now have the opportunity
to no longer be a hypocrite this drives home
the accountability and makes them understand
the consequence of their actions 30 seconds
wow this has gone on for ages i saw it like five
hours ago govi well jen you know i'm trying to
make sure that this workshop is as thorough
as possible but we're almost about to wrap up
do people only care about being
hypocrites yeah because it affects
people care about themselves
and the image of themselves and
if you want to hit people and and mess up
their ego about themselves that's how you
do it you you call them out on things like
this and this is unfortunately how people
work i mean i wish that it was just as
easy as saying guys we have 50 less than
50 years left on this planet animal abuse is
the biggest pressing issue of our time we have
no right to be abusing animals please stop
if that was it was just as easy as that
i would i would that's what i would be telling
you to do in this outreach workshop but it's not
moving on
26 all right close the conversation
always end outreach conversations
by asking what the individual will personally
do to take action ask them open and ask
the open-ended question after our conversation
what are you going to do about this injustice
after a long conversation they may still
say that they'll only reduce or do nothing
if they can if you can sense that the
interaction will keep going in circles
end the conversation with the statement 30 seconds
from a outsider point of view this vegan
approach is genius david velas is in the comments
and seems effective and david is not vegan joining
us and giving his feedback on this approach
i appreciate it david i appreciate your
feedback but you know that this is going to be
a huge thing for you that you have to
face because this whole conversation
if you're telling us it's effective what we
really want to know is how effective is it for you
all right let's move on
so this is the last slide guys
closing the conversation an effective statement
in this situation can be so keep in mind that for
however long that you're not vegan animals
will be abused and tortured because of you
so when you're ready to stop abusing animals
and align your actions with your words
you know what to do so think about what side
of history you want to stand on and that closed
um that closes the conversation but this is also
the question that we have for you david this
question is for you what are you going to do
your question david i'm not sure on
uh how would i respond to someone
saying that they would hire animals
it's i don't i've never heard that before but
hiring i'm not sure if you've used the wrong word
there but hiring animals is still exploitation
that's just another word for enslaving animals
but i'm not quite sure i
understand your question there
and this is the end of this live stream
and this workshop so i want to thank you
each of you for being a part of this it's
been really energizing for me to do this
leading into international cube day which
is tomorrow and this is something that i've
been wanting to roll out for a few months
now so thank you for being a part of this
and if you have any questions that you want to
send me directly on social media about anything
we've discussed here feel free to do so you can
follow me on instagram paul bashir underscore av
um i also have a youtube channel paul bashir
and uh yeah connect with me on social media
after this if you need any further support thank
you for the support you've shown us and if you're
going to be at a cube tomorrow have a good one i'm
going to be out in melbourne with a very limited
number of people and we're gonna do what we can
to make it happen and i will go live at some point
so i'll see you there see you on the
streets hopefully at some point too
much love everybody i'm gonna
stop this share and stop