oh yeah looks like it's working okay
i love you
what was that
that came through
all right, we're live i think
looks like it's friday
yo these kids outside crazy
what was that that came through yo
there's a double up all right we're live
i think
some doubling up on the audio but
we are now live i think
uh what's up everybody
let me know in the comments if the audio
and the visual
is okay with you
i've got a chat section on youtube that
i'll be
maintaining and managing as best as i can
i'll just wait for people to join
and for this
live to establish itself properly
and here people are joining the chat
on youtube what's up everybody what's up
isaac sylvia
all right to be named good morning
ariane laura
now i see you laura says yeah let me
know how the visual
is and the audio i want to make sure
that the
technology is on point for this one
um i also need you to tell me please
video and audio is clear thank you
i am doing well laura thank you
i also need you to tell me
if this microphone
i'm about to plug it in is going to make
my audio better or not
now
so i'm now plugged in with this mic can
you tell me if you can hear me okay
if it's better or worse than what it
just was
we can't do icd because the uk went back
into lockdown
we're in the same position here
i feel you
we hello sylvia and hello tiff
thank you tiff appreciate that
the audio is good great
great i'm going to keep this mic in then
it's better good thank you ariane
thank you guys appreciate the feedback
all right so now i'm going to move on
to the next thing great all right so
yeah we're in lockdown here in australia
and currently
we can only assemble 10 people max
in a public area and so given that
restriction
it's going to be really difficult for
any cubes to happen i'm going to be
doing
a limited attendance cube in melbourne
tomorrow
we'll see how we go with that but
yeah because of the restrictions around
the world we only have
170 odd
almost up to 200 i think i haven't
even checked the figures
over the last couple of days but
yeah i had a look at the figures
last
and was impressed that we have almost
events scheduled given the restrictions
that we have so
yeah last year we had 500 cubes
scheduled around the world and as you
may or may not know international cube
day is the biggest day of the year for
us
because it's our biggest campaign and
the essence of it in case you don't know
is to do as many cubes around the world
as possible
so it's a fantastic time of the year for
us but given the restrictions
it's a limited
campaign
all right what's up vegan king all right
so let's get into this we're gonna
start off oh i need to send out a quick
story to everybody on instagram telling
them that we are now live so just bear
with me
i've got no one moderating this stream
i'm going to be doing it myself
if you have any questions
please try to save them until i do a Q and A
but if you can't wait until then
drop them in the
chat and i'll do my best to respond to
them at some point
happening now on youtube
cool
all right
isaac you can moderate that would be a
huge help
yeah it won't take much work
ah yeah cool no worries if someone wants
to moderate though it won't take much
work i just want to
i just don't want to be dealing with
trolls and shit but it's no big deal
even if they do come up
you know if they want to come on and try
to wreck my stream
they're welcome all right so let's do this
swipe up
cool all right about to get into what we
need to get into
so the first thing i'm going to be doing
is
i'm going to
play this live for you guys
and then what i'm going to do
is review it for you live
and the first thing i need to do here
is since i haven't done this in a while
i need to
i need to remember how to share
the screen correctly i remember how to
do it but not correctly
so just give me a moment bear with me
and i'll have it ready
you know what i think i will take some questions to
begin with
let me know if you have any and
i'll kill some time during that whilst i
get this ready so if you have any
questions hit me up
in the comments
damn
struggleville
trying to get
this video to download properly
"please do more of these streams paul
it's good to interact with you"
well i would like to do more streams
all right
why is it doing that
yeah so again if you have any questions
let me know in the comments and i'll go
ahead and answer them for you
now here's a question what's your
opinion on wild animal suffering it's a
topic i recently discovered i don't know
if you've heard of it or not
might have seen it
from
humane hancock okay so i did respond to
this
uh on my instagram so i forget what i
said exactly
but i said something like
let's just focus i mean my answer to
this question is pretty straightforward
let's just focus on the human inflicted
suffering on animals that we
are currently i mean it's the biggest
issue
that we have to be accountable for so
we need to look in the mirror before we
start trying to intervene further
in the animal kingdom
can we just stop murdering animals first can we stop
enslaving torturing and murdering them
that's what i would like to address
this whole thing and i think this is what
i said in my instagram post
this whole thing is such an
odd discussion to me it's so strange
and it reminds me of how
off-base it is for human beings to
explore and discover
the universe and space
to the extent that humans do and yet we
still have 80 percent of the ocean
80 percent completely
undiscovered unobserved unexamined
you know this is just very typical of
humans i think
that we don't address we don't look into
everything that's right here before us
it starts with us
and then here on this planet
we want to try to find a home on mars and yet
we don't even know how to get things right
here
it makes no sense
so that's my answer to that
all right so next question
all right so
long day yeah cool that sounds good
laura
both three hour cubes you're doing two
for international cube day
awesome
cool a question here about whether
it has started or not
we are about to get started
i'm taking some questions
just to get this started and then we're
going to
get into the meat of this
uh much love silvia thank you for the support
and thank you for representing us
how to talk to a parent
how to talk to a parent to turn them
vegan if he or she
doesn't want to hear about animal suffering
anytime i try to talk about
he/she walks
out of the room and hangs up the phone
etc
agatha's question regarding parents
it's no different to
talking to anybody else
you hold human beings accountable for
the evils they commit against
non-human animals whether they're family
or friends
doesn't matter because they're guilty
just the same as anybody else
the thing with family is
you obviously have more of an affinity with family
and that means that
you should give them more patience
more effort
more of an explanation more not an
explanation it's just
more time
more time but at a certain point
you have to say to yourself
i have done my best
and they aren't open and willing to end
their human supremacy
and i know it's a hard road to walk
but it's the truth and i have dedicated
myself to truth on this
planet i want my life to be dedicated to
that and nothing else so
so that comes first i'm a human being
dedicated to truth before i am
a human being that belongs to a family
does that make sense?
i also do think that family could be
one of the biggest downfalls of society
but i'm not going to get into that
all right so moving on another question here
about overpopulation
i'm just going to quickly answer this
but this is going to be the last
question i answer before we get started
and i want to
thank you for your patience guys
all right so the next question here is
when we've solved the overpopulation of
pet animal issue
do you think that we can still
have companion animals but create a
solution
when none die in shelters yeah
absolutely like sanctuaries
all of these shelters should be turned
into sanctuaries
instead of a kill business
all right i'm going to get started now
guys thanks for your patience so
i'm going to share my screen
i'm going to need your feedback in the comments so
please
light it up with feedback about the
video and the audio
okay down that's come on
okay i'm gonna have to this "is ten years
ago but the temperament of the times
right now
from what i can see is that most people
already get" sorry about that guys
i didn't realize
that was playing
okay so i'm gonna have to unplug this
mic when i'm playing
and then plug it back in when i need to
make commentary
technical nonsense but it is what it is
so let me just
yeah let me just get this going for you guys
okay
can you guys see that okay?
i'm sharing my screen now
i'm sharing my screen right now
so please let me know
in the comments if you can see that and
i'm gonna start playing right now
okay thanks, my name is paul bashir
i am the co-founder and director of
anonymous for the voiceless
i became an animal rights activist in
june of 2015 and i started av with my
partner who i met basically just before
we started av
asal and we started av in april of 2016.
since then we've become one of the most
prominent animal rights organizations
in the world not that it's a goal of
ours necessarily at the moment to have a
billion chapters
that was our goal but we've changed that
now to
wanting to have chapters who are working
with us
working in alignment with what we're
trying to achieve and what we
set out to achieve when we started av
this workshop is an attempt to do that
with regards to
outreach as you all know at the cube of
truth we have protocols we have rules
and we have structure and we find that
really important because the more
serious we take our roles on the streets
or in general the more serious people
take us and the message
as you know we have rules like wearing
all black at the cubes
we wear the masks and only one kind of
mask in the cube we form a
square cube structure
there's the outreach team and the cube team
so we have these kinds of structures
another thing that we have as a
standardized structure is the outreach
and that's what i'm going to be talking
to you about today
and the standard outreach approach that
we expect at the cubes
is there to help you and help everybody
that does outreach
to be effective and the only thing i've
found to be fulfilling in this line of
work
is effective activism
it's the only thing that will help you
to process the frustration and the anger
that you will naturally have if you're
paying attention
as you may know you've seen some
outreach from me
but it's from the earlier stages and
only recently did i start putting
outreach content up online last year
there was a gap where i wasn't putting
outreach content up online and that's
because i was
being patient and i was applying
different approaches
and i wanted to see what stuck what didn't
i'm teaching you nuts and bolts
stuff here that i've observed i've
learned i've applied and i
have observed others apply and i can
deem
confidently now works effectively for
everybody this is also
an approach that is truly for everybody
but i'm going to start from the very top here
with the definition of veganism because
in our movement right now
veganism is confused like everybody has
a different definition, have you noticed this?
does this bother you guys? yeah
don't you wish we're on the same page about this?
wouldn't it be easier? i don't know why
we're so confused about it it seems
pretty straightforward but i'll get into
the definition of veganism for you
it's a way of living that seeks to
exclude
any form of animal exploitation as much
as practicably possible
in the definition it doesn't include
anything to do with the environment
it doesn't include
anything to do with human health
it's purely about
animals and their rights and it really
is that simple
another thing i'd like to tell you and
this has helped me to understand
the function of an activist is to be a
medium
of truth because truth exists in this world
but it doesn't act on its own so we need
to act
and we need to speak the truth we need
to continually
speak the truth and we need to act on it
as much as possible
so that's your role as an activist and
it really is that simple
but if you ever get lost and you
are ever in doubt just remember you're
speaking for the animals in the same way
you would want to be spoken for if
you're in their position
telling people the truth shouldn't be
perceived by you as something that will
start a fight
because if you perceive it that way
maybe others will pick up on that
but if you just think that you're
telling people the truth because that's
the loving thing to do
then people will pick up on that as well
and they respect truth
people respect people who tell them the truth
have you ever heard the expression
that you don't lie to your friends?
you shouldn't lie to your friends
well if you extend that
to the public isn't that what being
compassionate is
so people conflate veganism
with compassionate living a lot of the
times as well
i don't think not stabbing animals to
death is necessarily
compassionate, i just think that's the
same and rational thing to do
but people also claim that this approach
is not compassionate that we're not
being compassionate to the abusers
not giving them a chance
but that's nonsense because i'm a street activist
that's all i do is educate people i give
people a chance to wake up to this like i was
i'm not forcing people to go vegan
that's physically impossible to do
if that was possible i'd probably
be doing it right now but you can't do that
so you have to focus on just talking to
people and hoping they wake up
and that is the most compassionate thing
that you can do is offer people
education
but again telling people the truth is
truly the most loving thing that you can do
i don't know why we think it's hateful
people say "you're shaming people"
we're not necessarily shaming people
we are making people feel guilty though
because how else are we going to make
people go vegan if they don't feel guilty?
isn't that why you went vegan?
because you felt incredibly guilty for what you were contributing to?
well why would we avoid
having others feel that?
why would we try to avoid that?
why would we dance around the topic and
compromise on the message and panda
when that's the goal is for them to feel guilty?
this is the real form of compassion that
i see that we need to bring into this
movement more
is telling non-vegans the truth
and one thing that
will happen when you're talking to
non-vegans is you're going to notice a
lot of conscious and some unconscious
distractions that come out so whether
they're consciously and maliciously
doing that or not
you have to be aware of the fact that
they're going to distract
away from what needs to be discussed
because
their guilt is going to be flaring when
you're talking about something that's
obviously wrong. everybody knows that
animal abuse is wrong
that's the other thing is that we think
as vegans that people don't already know
about this
people walk over to a cube instantly
know that we're vegan instantly know
that we're trying to promote an animal
rights message. it may not have been the
case 10 years ago but the temperament of
the times right now
from what i can see is that most people
already get the fact
that we're talking about animal rights,
we're talking about veganism, and they
need to go vegan. that's the crux of the
conversation that they're going to have with us
so don't act like non-vegans don't know this
okay? they already know, we're a lot more
obvious about this than we think we are.
when we have these very simple
conversations with people
their guilt will flare up and they start
creating distractions that they don't
even believe in.
like plants have feelings. they're trying to
distract from them taking accountability
from themselves, taking accountability
for what they're doing.
it's your role again as a medium of
truth to anchor the conversation back,
to make sure that that individual is in
the hot seat.
and it's not just something that they
can just palm off
and the distractions that they're
creating you have to
break through them, that's your job as an
activist is to break through them and
not let the distractions become
real distractions for what needs to be discussed
you've all heard non-vegan excuses, i'm sure.
a lot of people think when i do an
outreach workshop i'm going to get into
how to deal with excuses, how to deal
with certain arguments; i'm not actually
going to do that.
if you have questions during the Q and A though
i'll answer them for you.
but i'm not going to do that because
i've come to know that
they're all just ridiculous excuses
and there is no excuse under the sun
that should ever trump you
plants have feelings if people really
believe that plants have feelings.
how come we don't have a single group out there
that protest against lawn mowing?
how come when the australian bushfires
occurred, we didn't hear anything about
the plants burning to death?
we only heard about the wildlife and
when they said wild life
they were talking about animals every
single time
even people like joe rogan who's a
fucking avid hunter and loves to justify
not being vegan at every opportunity he gets,
even he said he supported the wildlife
in australia and he was referring
to the koalas and the other animals.
people around the world have only shown
empathy or sympathy
towards the animals that were suffering
in the wildfires, right?
that just goes to show that this is very
obvious in people's minds,
and that's why i'm saying this is a lot
more obvious than we think it is.
it really is people already care about
animal rights,
and the reason i know that is because
nobody
unless they're a psychopath would be
comfortable
with the label of being an animal abuser.
and that's what non-vegans are.
they're abusing animals.
the only reason why they feel
comfortable is because the guilt is
shared by everybody.
we've broken out of that now, we can see
straight now,
but it doesn't mean that it's not
completely obvious still for everybody
else, we've just taken action
on this. none of these excuses
are ever going to trump you, they should
never have you feeling flustered,
they should never have you feeling like
you don't know the answer, because the
answer is always very simple and it's
the fact that they can't justify abusing
animals needlessly.
end of story. whenever in doubt just
compare to any other injustice.
but it should injustice like a delicacy
and something that we eat
maybe once a week instead of i don't
think that the
the rate that we use is natural
we're at the extreme end of
this lifestyle now.
Would you say that with any other
injustice? like sexism?
child abuse? no, but i'm saying, would you
take that position? would you say
that it would be too extreme to avoid at
all? that we should still
do it sometimes?
yeah that was good, that was a good rebuttal!
we're not vegan, but we're vegetarian
with lil chicken
yeah so we're fish-chicken vegetarian. so, would you
take the same position with any other
injustice? let's say
we're talking about sexism or racism.
would you have the same
view on that? where are we going here?
so let's say we're talking about racism.
would you be like "i'm against racism,
i don't want to be a racist,
but then maybe like on sundays i make an exception."
to be racist? yeah! so this is a form of
discrimination against another species.
while you're still having a little bit
of egg or chicken,
whatever i'm not sure what you're having,
you're still really supporting animal
cruelty and more exploitation.
we will do it slowly. i understand it
might seem like a big
jump; would you take that on any other
issue? for example if somebody said "i'm
going to slowly
stop beating my child", "i'm going to
slowly become
a non-racist". no. you wouldn't be uh?
that's we got to do it right?
do you think that we should
contribute this to last or do you think
that we should say: "hey we should just
stop hurting animals"?
stop. stop, right? people will
talk a good game about reducing or
making excuses for why they won't go
vegan
just compare to any other injustice in
that moment we are an animal rights
organization, we've never deemed
ourselves to be an
environmentalist group, a group of
environmentalists
trying to change the world for the
betterment of the environment. we've
never claimed to be
a nutritionist organization, a group of
nutritionists trying to change the world
for the betterment of human health.
We've only ever claimed to be an animal
rights organization.
But there's this myth that exists in the
vegan movement; that when you promote
health and environment these things will
get people more interested in animal rights.
And that's the reason why we've been
talking about these things: is to try to
get them hooked.
If someone doesn't seemingly care about animals,
well i guess i'll talk to them about
health, because they have heart disease. i
guess i'll talk to them about how they
can reverse their heart disease by
eating a plant-based diet.
If they don't seemingly care about the animals,
we think we'll talk to them
about the environment. this is destroying
the rainforest, this is destroying it,
climate crisis ... the idea that this
will lead someone to animal rights
and caring about animal rights is a
complete myth. animal rights is obvious.
Nobody in their right mind would be
comfortable with the label of being an
animal abuser.
So it's not a matter of people not caring
about animal rights,
it's a matter of you not promoting
animal rights correctly.
It may seem like a tough pill to swallow
to hear that,
but i'm only telling you this because
it's the truth.
And it's what i've learned to be true.
People avoid animal rights and make you
think they don't care about animal rights
for a reason. It's a distraction, like i
said: they create distractions
they don't want to face something that's
obviously wrong.
And then you bind into that by then
pandering to environment and health.
People don't seemingly care about animals because
the way that we advocate
veganism, to people, doesn't care about
animals.
It seems like in this movement the more
i hear people advocating for veganism,
the less i hear animal rights being tied
into it.
They quickly get mentioned and then we
move on to
how this is really bad for the
environment and really bad for your
health.
So that's why people don't care about
animal rights.
The vegan movement hasn't been promoting
I also just want to say this: those who
say that what i'm doing is aggressive;
that this isn't compassionate. Well, the
irony the way i see it is the irony
is that: when people aren't advocating
for the animals,
in the way that they communicate directly,
then you're actually putting the compassion
you want to receive from the abuser
before the compassion you're supposed to
be extending to the victim.
I think that's hypocrisy, right?
If we truly are compassionate beings,
then we need to extend compassion to the
victims, and when we're talking to the abuser
like i've already explained, it is
actually the truest form of compassion
to offer the abuser education.
What do we usually do with abusers?
We put them in prison, don't we? right
If these beings
were any other species
other than a non-human (so if they were human),
these people would be put in prison,
wouldn't they? There would be no
conversation on the streets,
no trying to convince people, so this is compassion.
This is the most compassionate thing we
can possibly do; is try to
wake people up with our words. But if we
pander and we move away from animal
rights when we're talking to people,
then we're only doing more of an
injustice, more of a disservice to the animals.
It's not about how people feel about
animals: do you have a dog at home?
do you have a cat at home?
A lot of the times we, as vegans, try to lean
on the compassion that we think they
already have for animals, for non-human animals.
We use dogs as examples a lot in this movement,
we try to say:
would you do this to your dog?
how would you feel if your dog was eaten?
what about if a dog was getting beaten
up right in front of us right now,
would you act on it?
That blows up in our face a lot of the time
Replace all those cows with dogs
just for a moment in your mind
dogs don't produce milk?
yes they do, yeah, they do but
not like ahh ...  it's hard to ..
i don't ... i try
just morally, i make that
comment just for you to consider it morally
What is the difference between puppies
being raised, all the female puppies
to get milk out of them, instead of cows?
I don't feel difference.
You don't feel any difference?
Why do we think we live in a society
that cares about dogs?
Why do we think that? I don't understand
why our movement thinks
that we live in a society full of dog lovers.
If we truly love dogs, would we have shelters?
that kill dogs by the thousand? every day?
around the world? Clearly if we lived in
a society of dog lovers just the same
way that we
love human children then we'd have
people protesting at the front of
shelters all the time.
But that's not happening. If you said
that stuff to me, it wouldn't really work
(because i was never really a dog lover growing up).
But my point is to say
that this isn't an animal conversation,
this is an accountability conversation.
If you were talking to me about the
blood on my hands, if you're talking to
me about the harm i'm causing to beings
who suffer like i suffer,
it doesn't matter about how i feel about animals,
it matters, but how i feel about
causing suffering. I also need to make
this clear: a lot of people out there
think that morality is
subjective. When it comes to this,
morality is
as objective as it gets: it's as black
and white as my t-shirt.
When it comes to animal rights people
will love for you to think that there's
a great area, that there's something that
you're not considering, you're not
open-minded enough. What about
if you're on a deserted island? Or those
who don't have,
you know, access to ... they always try to
bring up grey areas to this, to see
where the morality can slip.
It doesn't ever slip. You're never going
to wake up one day and think animal abuse
is justified, are you? You're not gonna go
back on your morals,
if you understand that this is wrong.
You're not gonna go back on child abuse.
You're not gonna wake up one day and
think child abuse is okay. i think today
i'm comfortable with this idea i'm gonna
do it today. it's black and white,
it's always wrong and it's never justified.
Another thing that vegans will focus way
too much on, when advocating for animal rights,
is being liked by the other person.
We think that being likable vegans
is going to get people to take veganism seriously.
Raise your hand if you've fallen into
this trap, i know i have.
Thank you for being honest,
because we don't want to be the preachy vegan,
we don't want to be the pushy vegan,
we don't want to be the annoying vegan,
we don't want to be the vegan that turns people off.
Veganism, here's the thing: non-vegans
have been trying to bully us
psychologically into this thinking,
and you need to realize that and you know better.
This is just manipulation
People are trying to make you
feel insecure about this,
because they're shooting down the messenger.
Because they don't want to take the message seriously
and face it. When we play into this,
they win. When i say they, the abusers.
And the animals lose.
It's a flaw
to care about being liked,
more than what you're saying and the
rights of these animals, the rights of these beings.
In no other situation do we actually use
this line of thinking,
so we're actually being hypocrites here.
You probably noticed that people
actually like people who don't really care
what other people think of them.
When you don't care what other people think of you.
And to the contrary when you care
so much about what other people think of you,
people actually don't like that.
They don't like that about you,
because it comes off as a weakness
and i actually think that telling people
the truth is the best way to achieve this anyway.
So it's counterproductive: if you want to be liked
then do things that are deserving of being liked.
And this shouldn't be your goal,
being liked shouldn't be your goal because
if somebody likes you and goes vegan for that reason
what happens when they don't like you anymore?
Which will happen!
Imagine civil rights activists focusing
on being liked by white people
in order for them to take black rights seriously.
How weird would that be? Trying to be
accommodating in whichever way socially
to have them taking
black rights seriously: it would be
insane to even witness that happening.
And this is also a tool that you should
use in your advocacy
to make sure that you're in line with
what you're supposed to be doing here as
an activist. If you ever feel like
questioning what you're doing, compare it
to any other injustice.
Would you be advocating this way in any
other case for any other injustice?
If not, don't do it here! Animals deserve
way better from us.
When we first started AV
i noticed that the outreach that we were
doing on the streets ..
i noticed that there was a lot of things
that i learned in my previous
work experience in doing sales ..
all the sales training that i had received ..
there were things in that that i could
carry over into outreach, that were applicable here.
And so if you go on our website it says
we use a value-based sales approach.
I want to explain what that means because
i think there's been
a bit of a confusion about this.
I definitely don't mean the kind of sales that
we're commonly used to
and that we commonly know.
I'm talking about certain aspects of
sales that are applicable here because
at the end of the day what we're doing
is trying to convince somebody of
something they're not already convinced on.
And that's what sales is really.
I'm trying to convince you right now
to apply this approach when you're doing outreach,
and that's why i brought this into this equation.
But i want to explain that i really do not mean
schmoozing people, and telling people
what you think they want to hear,
and using hooks like psychological hooks
to trick them into
signing on the dotted line.
That's not how this works at all.
Activism is a different ballpark to sales.
One of the traditional things that occurs in sales
is the three-step process,
for any sale, so i'll talk you through that right now.
The three-step process is really simple
the first step is ... all right
okay i'm gonna pause right here because
this is the part where i find
that there's the most confusion and
it's the whole sales message.
So yes i'm going to break down this
three-step process,
but the only reason i'm doing that here
is to show you
where sales tools (and really they're not
sales tools, they're communication tools)
but where these communication tools are
applicable from the sales world
into activism. But again i need to
reiterate this, i said this in the video:
sales is not activism. Just because you
have x number of sales,
years of sales experience, doesn't mean
you have x number
of years experience in activism.
That's not how this works at all:
it just means that you've learned
a few things about communication that might,
might, be applicable here in activism.
I found in fact when i go over all of the
sales things i've ever learned, that most of it
is actually unapplicable, unequivocally unapplicable.
And that's because the goal in sales
is usually to get someone to sign on the
dotted line, and there's usually a
financial incentive.
Here i named it the
value-based sales approach from the very
beginning in 2016, when we started AV, for
the purpose of
setting it apart from sales.
In general, the common view of sales.
this is a new
i was trying to create something new
here, where we can
carry over what is applicable. And what
i've found the deeper i've gone into
this is, that a very minimal amount
is actually applicable from the sales
world, over here.
So with that added commentary on this bit,
i will now continue for you guys ... to get
somebody convicted in what it is that
you're trying to convince them of.
we have all of the lodge process up to sales
One of the traditional things that
occurs in sales is the three-step
process, for any sale.
So i'll talk you through that right now.
The three-step process
is really simple: the first step is to get
somebody convicted in what it is that
you're trying to convince them of.
We have all the logic, all of the reason
on our side, and it's important to use
logic and reason (i'm not saying don't use that),
but if you don't get somebody
emotionally convicted in this
issue, because it's a justice issue,
then don't expect a shift from anybody.
That's why i don't like these
philosophical discussions that we have
with people about veganism. We have these
what seems to be like a bar discussion,
just food for thought,
and that's a real issue
because that's not what this is supposed
to be about. This is an accountability conversation
and that first step is best achieved
when you connect them to the sense of injustice
and you hold them accountable to that injustice.
The second step is to make sure that
they understand that they,
as an individual, are responsible.
That they're in the hot seat
This isn't something they can just palm
off to the government, or palm off to
these industries and say "we need to
focus on petitioning against these industries".
This is about them as an individual and
you can't let them get out of that,
that's your job.
Meat doesn't just harm yourself,
it harms someone else.
Someone or something?
Do you think an animal is a thing?
Oh okay, i'll see where you're going but
like let's ..
but that's the problem, that's going to
be your that's going to be the club
the lack of compassion for non-human um
you know, that's going to be your problem
But what about you? because i'm talking
to you right now.
Do you have a lack of compassion for
non-human animals? No I don't
So are you against animal exploitation?
Yes I am okay. So what do you think you
can do about it?
Yeah we're talking .. yeah i will share
this conversation with my family.
What do you think you will do though?
yeah i will start
more
The third step, once you have achieved
that second step
(through dealing with their objections,
anchoring it back to accountability ..
once they concede you move on to the
third step) is tying in the benefits.
Everybody loves to know what's in it for
them, right? Because humans are selfish,
right? okay so
the number one benefit for you going
vegan: obviously for the animals it's
that they no longer have to be tortured
and abused by you. But the benefit for you
is that you no longer have to abuse them,
and therefore you're no longer a hypocrite.
Because you say that you're against
animal abuse, in fact in that very conversation
they said that, that they're against animal abuse.
Right? that's the only reason we're vegan
today. Why you guys are sitting here
right now, trying to learn about outreach?
It's because you hate the hypocrisy, don't you?
You would never want to live with that
hypocrisy again, would you?
more importantly would never want to abuse animals anymore
would you? I used to say "if you
do this correctly you eat a whole foods
plant-based diet, you will actually get
the health benefits from doing this" as well
and i used to say that "it's better for
the environment if you do this:
as a benefit, you have a lower footprint".
It's a mistake
because i'm conflating animal rights
with environmentalism
and with human health.
I know that it's going to be tempting
for you to do this, even after this workshop.
You're going to be very tempted to go there still
You only know whether this is true
if you apply this,
but if i can save you some time it's a mistake.
Focus on why, as opposed to how. Way more
focus on why.
how is so .. i mean it's so easy to go vegan ..
All right
so i just want to add some commentary there
to that piece that i just shared with you guys
and i'm not sure if i made this clear in
that last piece of commentary i offered but,
that three-step process is not something
you necessarily need to follow at the cubes.
I'm just breaking that down to explain
the traditional sales process
and how it can be ... like how it's
applicable here and how we usually get people ...
you know what the process is to get them
to that point of taking veganism seriously
but i'm going to break down the process
for you at the end of this
in slides so i'm gonna break it down for you
even more simpler and make it more clearer
for you guys so
just stick around for that
at the end after this presentation is
complete. So i just want to clarify i'm
not asking you to do the three-step
process at the cubes,
that's not what we're asking you to do;
we're just explaining the three-step process
and showing you how this one little thing
in sales is actually something that we
can learn from
and apply some of that here, in activism.
...
how is so .. i mean, it's so easy to go vegan
in this day and age. Do we really think it's
difficult for people?
like we create all these programs and
recipes and we try to
make sure people have all the support in
the world. is it really that difficult though?
aren't we babying people?
aren't we coddling people?
because if you're convinced on why
you need to be vegan, you just need to go and
use google.
in 2020 we have the internet, you can use
google and ask any question there is
about any ingredients,
about any recipe, any product and you'll
find out pretty quickly if it's vegan or not
and that's the only compass you need to
be vegan: is this vegan or is this not?
there's two types of people in the world:
those who say being vegan is easy,
those who say being vegan is hard.
those who say being vegan is easier
focus on the victims;
those who say being vegan is hard to
focus on themselves.
so whenever they bring up that
distraction "oh i don't know how i could do this"
how, whatever form of how that comes up,
how is completely a distraction.
if they're sold on why, how is easy
plus we give them a card anyway
so they get support
they get whatever they need at the end
so don't focus on how.
another good question ...
i just want to let you guys know also we
updated our resource page in our cards.
so when you're at the end of the
interaction and you hand over a card,
it's now updated and it says:
will you stop being a human supremacist?
this was just updated and
it has our website cubeoftruth.com
and that link now takes you to our resources page.
so it's a lot more simple, i'm really
proud of this new update
and if you go over to our resources page
we've updated that as well to make that
even simpler.
specifically the video section
we've now put up
a video that is the best of the best
gary yourofsky moments in speeches
and other content he's put up
mainly his speeches but we've put the
best of the best of gary yourofsky
all in one video and it's about three hours
so that's pretty cool because if
they need further convincing
that's the video. we're still going to
keep the georgia tech speech up there
the best speech you'll ever hear because
it has all of the translations available
and i think
it covers like 30 languages or something
so that's important, we need to keep that up there
for that reason
but this other one that's up there
you can play using the caption feature on youtube,
so it may still translate through that
i don't ... well, yeah i don't know how that
works in other countries
or if it just creates a caption in english
um yeah i'm not sure how that works but
anyways we have that three-hour video
for at least the english-speaking people
of the world
and that's pretty cool
so let's get back into this
... we give them a card anyway
so they get support
they get whatever they need at the end,
so don't focus on health.
another good question is,
when you're tying in the benefit at the
end of that three-step process,
to ask the question: do you think it's
possible to be against this?
to be against what you're saying you're
against while also supporting it?
and it's a good question to just tie in
hypocrisy again and also to tie in the
fact that there is no way around this.
there's no alternative: you're either an animal abuser
or you're not. another thing i want to
say about this approach that i'm
teaching you right now is that this is
way more satisfying to do
than all these other approaches that
involve pandering and
compromising on the message and focusing
on being liked and all this stuff.
this is way more satisfying. i've noticed that
over the last four years
there was a huge surge in 2017/2018
for street outreach in our network,
and then it sort of dropped and i feel
like people have lost
interest in doing outreach.
they don't really see the benefits and
how successful it is and they're not really
convinced on how effective it is anymore.
when you're doing this approach
you'll come to learn that
all of your interactions are successful.
even if the individual doesn't say that
they're going to go vegan,
you've at least told them what they need
to hear, which is probably the only time
they're going to hear it. and when you
have that perspective
every interaction is successful because,
again, we're mediums of truth;
we speak for the animals in the same way
that we would want to be spoken for,
if we were in their position.
we have a rule that we only talk to
people who stop at the cube
and that's because we want to talk to
people who are open-minded. and we also
have an opening question that we ask
"would you like to know why we're here?"
because we need a commitment from them,
so that this is a two-way conversation.
so you shouldn't be talking to people
who are obviously unreachable
but at the end there they don't say
they're going vegan
then there's no reason for you to think
that wasn't a successful interaction.
so many times people don't even say
anything affirmative to the outreacher
and they become vegan.
this happens so often now: we had someone
at the melbourne workshop who was
sitting and learning who said
"i don't think that the outreacher who
got me to go vegan at a cube a year ago in melbourne
even knows that i went vegan, because
i argued with the outreacher and walked off".
that's another reason why we've removed
the tallies, but i'll talk a little bit
about that at the end.
who here has
not heard about socratic questioning?
raise your hand
alright fair few of you. this has been
blown out of proportion a little bit too.
socratic questioning is a tool,
and it's a very good tool,
but it is only a tool. it should be used
within your interaction wherever you see fit,
wherever it's supposed to be used,
because asking questions is always a good idea,
it's always a good way of
gathering information from the person to
see where they're at psychologically
when it comes to this.
but don't just use it throughout the
whole interaction
don't just ask question after question after question
there's gonna be many times
during the interaction where
they give you the flow to speak
and lecturing them in that moment
is actually the right way to go.
the reason why socratic questioning is
there is because ...
um so when i say giving you the ... like
they're not necessarily giving you the flow,
it's just a part/a moment in the
interaction where they're not saying anything
and it would be completely appropriate
for you to say something
and to make a statement at that point
because (and i'm gonna break this down a
little bit later when i do the slides)
at that point when
you make a statement or a closed-ended question
or you don't even ask a
question at all,
at that point what you're doing is
pushing the conversation forward
and that's necessary sometimes.
i'll break this down a little bit more detail,
like i said, but i just wanted to add that
commentary. let's get back to it.
... they give you the flow to speak
and lecturing them in that moment
is actually the right way to go.
the reason why socratic questioning is there is because
we want to ask questions instead of make statements,
but it doesn't mean that making
statements is a bad idea.
so i know that after i teach you guys this stuff
it's just human nature that you will
take this approach
you'll apply your personality to it,
which i want you to do,
but then what i don't want you to do is
butcher the approach itself and start
saying things differently to how
i'm suggesting that you say it.
one little example is [when]
we say "we" a lot when we're talking about
non-vegans and what they do to animals:
we're not in that situation anymore,
so this is pandering when we say
"the way we kill animals" or
"why do we do this to them?"
you're not doing this to them anymore so
keep it accurate.
again apply your personality by all means
but just keep it accurate and
listen to what you're saying.
you should make it very clear that
the individual you're speaking to needs
to be held to account, not you.
i think i get why we've been focusing on
being liked more than
promoting the message at hand here, and
it's because the defensiveness that we see,
coming from non-vegans, i think is
more profound more astounding than
perhaps any of the defensiveness
that we see in any other group of
culprits, of perpetrators, in the world.
and i want to try to explain why i think that is.
when it comes to eating, it's the most
intimate connection we have with the
outside world.
this is why we see people getting a lot
more cognitively dissonant and defensive
over the food aspect of veganism,
as opposed to the clothing aspects,
or the testing aspects of veganism.
more people are willing to accept that
wearing fur is evil, but when it comes to
changing their eating habits
their defensiveness is truly astounding.
this is what i experienced when i was
promoting a plant-based diet for almost
two years before i became an animal
rights activist.
so when you couple that with the fact
that we are addressing the largest and
longest-standing injustice
with the most pressing issue of our time
and the fact that this is the most
intimate connection people have with the
outside world,
then you have to expect a nightmare.
i'm only going to mention this one
objection when people say "i only eat meat
once in a while", have you heard that?
they only say this to vegans and this
only happens when they have a vegan in
their environment.
again this is just to prove to you
how obvious this is,
how obviously guilty people feel.
it doesn't even take long for people to
say that to a vegan "i don't eat meat
that much anyway" .. i'm trying to eat less
and less meat
to not participate to this killing.
i ate a lot of meat before,
so i'm trying to eat less. it's hard to go
really no meat for me, but i'm trying to do
less and less so i'm not participating
in those games.
i lower my ...
i don't cook food anymore,
i don't cook meat anymore
but if i go to restaurants sometimes
i order meats. okay
yeah, i'm not full vegan
myself but i try to
at least five days a week.
why are you saying that?
you wouldn't say that to your
non-vegan friends
and it's as black and white as that.
you know you're only a little bit of an
animal abuser
again they would never do this with any
other injustice they'd never be a little
bit of a child abuser.
the word speciesism, the words veganism,
and the word animal exploitation
and carnism as well, carnist people don't
really understand these words.
it doesn't really hit the way that we
want them to hit. i'm not saying don't
use these words,
i say vegan all the time, but i want you
to focus
way more on what these words mean
and use words like human supremacism,
because that clearly explains speciesism,
and it clearly explains what being a
non-vegan
is all about: human supremacism.
and in terms of
exploitation i think people think of
sweatshop workers
and i don't know they think of
exploitation the music industry, in the
porn industry they don't really think
of the animals being
hacked apart having the children taken
away from them
the most torturous things imaginable
happening to these innocent beings i
don't really think of exploitation like that.
so it is exploitation but the better
word to use here is animal abuse
and human supremacism.
statistics: a lot of the times we
feel the need to bring up statistics.
you know 50 of the world's crops are used to..
you know 3 trillion animals are slaughtered every year..
by all means:
do this but please keep this to an
absolute minimum,
because we're not supposed to be highly
educated and academic and it doesn't
need to be
in order for people to take this very
simple issue seriously.
animal abuse is wrong and there's no
justification for it.
we don't need statistics to prove that
to people necessarily.
if people want to talk about this to you
and they bring up statistics
and they want to debate statistics,
make sure that you're not
feeding into the distraction too much.
i want to talk about vegetarianism real quick.
i think vegetarianism is a cancer
to the animal rights movement
and we think that for some reason
in this movement we think that vegetarians
are closer to this message,
they're our allies. again we would never
do this with ...
i just wanna take a moment
to call myself out.
this is the holding non-vegans
accountable 2.0 workshop,
but i'm going to take a sweet moment to
hold myself accountable
because i just said in this movement we think
that vegetarians are the same .. whatever i said.
i don't think that anymore in fact i've
probably been the most vocal about this
in the animal rights movement but
yeah i was just talking about how
we need to be accurate with our words,
so i just want to pull myself up there
and say that i no longer talk like this
about vegetarian. i never really did ever so
yeah ...
...
i want to talk about vegetarianism real quick
i think vegetarianism is a cancer
to the animal rights movement
and we think that for some reason in this
movement we think that vegetarians are
closer to this message,
they're our allies. again we would never
do this with any other injustice
and vegetarian is no different to paleo.
i mean vegetarians will stop eating meat
then that's no different to what the
paleo crew are doing,
because they don't eat dairy,
and it's been argued
that the dairy industry could be the
cruelest industry in the world.
we should really be calling the paleo
crew our allies,
not vegetarians, but do you see how
insane that sounds?
me even saying that we would call the
paleo guys our allies?
just because meat is obviously cruel to animals
it doesn't mean dairy isn't and eggs isn't
and you all know that because
you're vegan and you already know this information
but when we even slightly
give in to this idea that vegetarians
are on our side, then we perpetuate
this myth even further.
we are the ones who are spreading
wrong message here.
so when someone says "don't worry i'm
vegetarian, you don't need to talk to me",
your response should be "you're actually
our target market"
and in fact you have more of a
responsibility to go harder on those individuals
because they already think they're doing enough.
they feel entitled and how dare you tell them
they're doing any different is the
attitude they usually give you..
i appreciate all that you're doing just
wanted you to know that i'm a vegetarian that
drinks almond milk. okay,
that's good.. local farm .. interesting ..
i'm just saying like you might want to
just focus your resource on someone else
because i totally am already on board.
i got that.
was animal cruelty one of the reasons
why you became vegetarian?
yes, have been vegetarian since i was 19 i'm 45
that's about 27 years of vegetarian.
one of the footage that we chose here is
also from local like
free range like egg farms. let me ask you
a question, because you say
that you usually get your eggs from like
local like free range farms.
where did they get their hens from?
like for example
her father's chickens that run around
his yard
so ..like.. they are .. i don't know where he
gets his hens from..
because what sex is important in the
egg industry? males or females?
obviously the females. so when people get
hens they get them from a breeder in
hatcheries, even like
for people that just want to get like a
egg laying hens.
males and females are born a different color:
if you're born female you're thrown to the left,
if you're a male you're thrown to the right.
where do you think the males go?
i get it ... directly into a blender.
I'm never gonna be a vegan,
so i'm doing everything i can to
minimize my impact, but i'm not going to be a vegan.
would you consider animal cruelty to be an injustice?
yes, I would. would you take that same stance
with any other injustice? because you do
recognize that there is cruelty in eggs, right?
sure
so i found with the majority of vegetarians
actually they're harder to get through,
they're not our allies,
they're not closest to this message,
they're pompous. sure, there's vegetarians
out there who didn't know better and
i've met many of those too
they just didn't know better
once you tell them they go vegan on the spot.
that's the dream circumstance but
i'm saying most people are not like this
if they're vegetarian.
imagine if all vegetarians were vegan
the percentage of vegetarians is always
way larger than the percentage of vegans
when they do those statistics.
imagine if all the vegetarians were
outreached effectively and they went vegan:
we would have way more vegans on our side.
also when people at the end of your
outreach will say "i'm gonna try to do better",
"i'll try, i'm gonna try to go vegan",
please
do not use the word "try" and do not let people
use the word "try". would you try to be a
non-racist?
would you try not to be a child abuser?
or would you just fucking stop,
once you realize that it's wrong?
again, don't let them off the hook: let them
know that there is a moral imperative here.
when someone says "i'm gonna try", what i say
in order to get them to rid themselves
of this "try" nonsense,
is to compare it to any other injustice,
like i just compared it to child abuse
and racism etc.
would you say that you would try?
or would you just stop?
and that usually corrects that for people,
very quickly ...
i'm going to get into this a little
bit more later,
but i want to add this piece in here and say
that we have had another update to this section.
we're constantly seeking to improve here guys,
we're constantly making software updates
and one of them is this one here: when we
compare to other injustices we've actually found
... see ... okay so ... my analysis on this
is that human beings only truly care
about themselves, that's it.
so when we say child abuse, racism, sexism,
feminism, whatever it is, we're relying
upon how much they care about those issues
and if they're not an activist, when it comes to those
issues, we shouldn't expect that they care
a great deal about those issues, should we?
so we've found that the most effective thing to do
in all situations is in fact hold them
accountable to themselves.
so in other words, instead of comparing
it to an injustice that involves
other groups of humans how about you just
ask them about themselves? how would you feel
if someone was torturing you, enslaving you
and was going to murder you?
and the excuse your oppressors used
was "i'm trying to do less of it",
"i'm only going to cut"
they say they're only going to cut your leg off
uh you're probably gonna die from a doe
so is that better than not
killing i mean, you know it's essentially
putting them
in the victim's position and saying
"what if someone was
to enslave torture and murder you less,
but never ever liberate you from your oppression?"
how would you feel? would you want to be
liberated if you were the victim?
or would you want these nonsense baby
steps that don't really go anywhere?
so, when you're comparing to other groups
of humans it might be most effective for
you to in fact,
according to our latest update and my analysis on this,
rely on the fact that human beings truly
only care about themselves.
they at least care
more about themselves
than anything else, any other group of humans
and i'm speaking generally for most
people here; this is why
i'm trying to get deep into what is the most effective,
because there is no perfect approach
for every single individual on
the planet, that doesn't exist.
what i can only teach you is most
effective for most people
and i'm going to continue to expand that
and improve on that as much as possible.
let's get back into it.
would you say that you would try?
or would you just stop?
and that usually corrects that for people,
very quickly ... i want to try to
be better ... there's no trying when it
comes to justice,
you can't try to be non-racist,
you're either non-racist
or you're a racist, and i say that
comparison because you understand injustice
in that context, but justice is justice.
what's evil is evil you can't have it
both ways.
what's right is right what's wrong is wrong, so
don't try, you have to do it. do you think
you'll go vegan?
um i can definitely try yeah
wow i love my family here but i can stop
i can spread it through my family make
sure that they eat less..
now i'm just going to leave you with
this to think about because you said try:
would we say that with any other
injustice would we try to not be a child abuser?
or would we just do it?
yeah so please don't compromise on this
injustice because the animals suffer as
a result of that.
you really just need to get out there
and do this and see
how effective it is for yourself
that one guy he was talking to
so anyone can do this and i highly
recommend it and
the tallies, as you know we've removed
our tallies, we used to
try and measure how effective we are and
that was the reason why we had the tally there
we tried to have some kind of metric
that we wanted to use to show that these events,
this form of street outreach is really
effective, but the mistake that we made
is that you can't really tell if someone
is going to go vegan or not.
you just have to speak for the animals
in the way that you would want to be spoken for
if you're in their position.
say the correct things and that's
a successful conversation.
a lot of the times people say they're
going to go vegan and while that's still
a good thing (i'm not saying that's not
a good indication if someone says
they're going to go vegan, they may very
well stick to that)
but i actually have examples of many
cases of people saying they're going vegan after
listening to me and they do not go vegan.
you don't know what's going on in
people's minds and what's going on in
their hearts and what they're going to
experience after they've talked to you.
you don't know if they're going to
continue arguing with their friends
about what you've talked to them about
and then that leading to them going
vegan because all of their friends
made stupid comments and one of their
friend held them to account again
and that rang in their head and they
were thinking about it for a week
and they couldn't let it go and then
finally they conceded
to the hypocrisy and they became vegan.
you just don't know, you don't know the process.
another thing is that hypocrisy: i just
want to go back to that real quick.
it's the reason why each of us went vegan for sure.
there's a story that i have on my
youtube of Gary Yourofsky:
i was in the car with him, he was telling
this really awesome story that ...
all right, okay guys i want you to pay attention
to this point i'm making here because
i only realized how powerful and significant
this point was when i watched this workshop back.
what i have successfully pointed out here
is, well you'll hear my point in a moment but
this is so tremendously profound and
i really want you to understand what i'm
saying here
but it's a story about Gary and
i haven't even pointed this out to Gary yet
but i'm going to do so soon
but one thing i learned from him is that
he didn't go vegan because of that elephant
in the circus and he didn't go vegan
because of the pigs that he saw being tortured
and murdered at thorn apple valley pig slaughterhouse.
that's the story he's told the world
and i believe that that's
what he felt was the catalyst for a long time,
but when i was chilling with him in Detroit,
he told me a story
which i recorded and i put up on my YouTube
and that story he tells
a new story about how he went vegan and
what was really the catalyst to
change him and it's really powerful
if you want to understand
what it takes to truly get people to go vegan
because if we can understand
how the best activists in the world have gone vegan
then that's a pretty good indicator
because that's what we're trying to
shoot for here not just people to go vegan
but we need people to speak up and
to be effective when they speak up.
let's look at how activists went vegan: that's a great
thing to observe and learn from so,
without further ado, please pay attention...
one of their friend held them to account again
and that rang in their head
and they were thinking about it for
a week and they couldn't let it go
and then finally they conceded to the
hypocrisy and they became vegan.
you just don't know, you don't know the process.
another thing is that hypocrisy:
i just want to go back to that real quick.
it's the reason why each of us went vegan for sure.
there's a story that i have on my
youtube of Gary Yourofsky;
i was in the car with him, he was telling
this really awesome story that i'd never
heard before
about how a hockey team in Detroit
used to throw octopuses onto the ice
and he was an animal rights guy at the time
every time someone would score a
goal they would do this
and he was an animal rights guy at the
time who was protesting this
and he called a radio station
and he started saying "what's next?
are we going to have all these other
teams with sharks and lions on their
names also throwing those animals onto
the ice every time they score a goal?"
and he was going nuts and then
the radio guy said "whoa
Gary, chill chill what did you have for
dinner last night?"
and then Gary was like "a salad"
and it was that moment that he realized
that no other answer could have been acceptable
and the hypocrisy was what got
Gary Yourofsky to go vegan.
that night he said was the night that
he went vegan.
i heard stories about the elephant story
in Michigan he talked about a circus incident
and then there was this other incident
but it wasn't that
he was going to thorn apple valley pig farm  in michigan
and seeing pigs being slaughtered
every day he kept going and witnessing
he couldn't believe that this was going on
he hadn't gone vegan until that guy
said "you're a hypocrite"
so please understand how powerful that is
even the best activists that we know of
the most effective
this is what caused them to go vegan
it's the same thing for me
it's the same exact story for me
when i realized
from listening to Gary that i was a
hypocrite if i wasn't vegan
and there's no way you can justify
even a little bit
of animal consumption
that's when i became vegan
but prior to that i was bullshitting
i was plant-based i would eat salmon sometimes
i'd wear leather
i was raw vegan while wearing leather jackets.
i could take you through a typical
interaction if you'd like,
from start to end, would you like that?
yeah yep
so we start the conversation by
"would you like to know why we're here?"
they need to say something affirmative
for the conversation to go ahead
they either say yes or they try to guess
and that's an affirmative answer.
so you continue "yes what we're doing
here is we're showing the standard practice footage
of what happens in the meat, dairy and egg industries
and other industries that abuse animals
and we're also showing
free-range grass-fed organic cage-free
humane certified...
hey guys would you like to know why we're here?
i'm guessing against animal cruelty
that is a good guess what we're showing
on the screens is the
animal industries meat dairy and eggs
and other industries also
that abuse animals for products.
would you like to hear what we're doing here?
sure! cool, yes what we're doing is we're
showing the behind the scenes
of industries that abuse animals
so this is in the meat industry
dairy industry egg industry
we're showing is also the best of the best
so this is free range, cage free, humane certified.
all right. would you like to hear what
we're doing here? sure. yes what we're doing is
we're showing the behind the scenes
of industries that abuse animals
like meat dairy eggs leather..
the next question you have
to ask them is
"how do you feel about animal abuse?"
usually they say
well it's obviously wrong 100% against it
that's what they usually say, people say.
"okay so do you think this is wrong?"
"would you say this is evil?" this is me doubling
down to make sure i've owned them on
this point "would you say this is evil?"..
would you say that this is evil?
yes. treating animals like our slaves?
yeah. would you say that stabbing animals
to death for a sandwich is wrong?
yeah yeah yeah that's orrible. what are your
initial thoughts? how does this kind of
stuff make you guys feel?
guilty
yeah so it's safe to say that you guys
are against animal abuse?
yeah for sure. i want you ...
all right, i just want to clarify
that, again, there was an update here that
we've made. i don't think that
closed-ended questions
are actually as effective as open-ended
questions in this segment of the interaction,
so instead of saying "do you think stabbing
an animal to death for a sandwich
or torturing animals to death is evil?",
"do you think that's evil?" / "do you think
that's wrong?" it's a closed-ended
question, it's an obvious question
it's in fact more important for you to say
"how do you feel about animal abuse?" and
then when they say
"i feel guilty, i feel horrible, it's terrible.."
and then
the next thing you need to do to just confirm
their position on animal abuse is to say
"is it safe to say that you are against animal abuse?"
and in some circumstances i might even
triple down and say "would you say it's evil?".
so you need to ask that open-ended question first
and then the closed-ended question just to
confirm and seal it off.
now, that will make sense why you need to do
that as i continue on with the approach here
showing you the step-by-step process...
the footage, how does it make you feel?
it makes me cringe
cringe? why do you think it makes you
feel that way?
because i love the animals. you love
animals,
interesting, so safe to say you're
against animal abuse?
animal cruelty? absolutely... yeah absolutely,
most people say "yes absolutely". now,
if they say no
they're either drunk or
trolling and either way you shouldn't be
having a conversation with those people,
they're not reachable.
again this is so obviously wrong, i mean
you're seeing animals being hacked apart
on the screens, how could anybody say
this is okay?
so usually they say that. then the next
step would be "okay what do you think
you can do about it as an individual?"
so we've gone from the first step of the
process within the three-step process of
emotional conviction, really quickly
moving to the second step which is
accountability "what do you think you can
do about it?" and
again most of the time i actually get
"i think i could stop
eating them", "i could become vegan" ...
so what do you think you can do about it as individuals?
stop, become vegan, yes become vegan
it's very simple isn't it? yeah.
that's why i'm saying this is so fucking
obvious to people,
it's not that complex, it's really not,
it's very obvious.
so, the interaction, so then you say
"what do you think you can do about this as an individual?"
usually they say "well i can
stop being vegan" but if they say something
that a lot of the times they'll actually
try to distract and say well
you can protest the government protest these industries
again you deal with the objection
bring it back to accountability that's all you're doing
deal with the objection anchor it back to accountability
once you have the concede after dealing
with all of those back and forth back and forth
once you have them concede,
then you bring in the benefits
"do you know what the number one benefit
is to be vegan?"
usually their ears perk up when you say benefit
and they look at you like "what is it?
i want to know" and that's when you say
"well obviously the benefit for them is
they're no longer tortured and abused
for you, you're no longer the reason
that this happens to them, but the
benefit for you
is that you no longer have to be an
animal abuser."
right so a new update again and
i'm gonna break this down in the slides that i'll do later
but the update here is to say
"for the first time
you will have the opportunity to stop
being a hypocrite"
instead of saying "you will no longer be a hypocrite"
and i'm saying this because many
vegans are straight-up hypocrites
but when you become vegan
it is the first time in human life
you can stop you have the opportunity to stop
being a hypocrite because you address
the biggest hypocrisy i think humans
are engaging in. so i just want to
clarify that it doesn't automatically
remove you from hypocrisy when you
become vegan, but it does give you an
opportunity to truly end hypocrisy.
..and you no longer have to be hypocrite
... you're no longer the
reason that this happens to them but the
benefit for you
is that you no longer have to be an
animal abuser and you no longer have to
be a hypocrite because you say that
you're against animal abuse..
do you guys know what the number one benefit is
of not supporting what's on the screen?
from being vegan?
any guesses?
so the number one benefit obviously for
the animals
once you're vegan then they're no longer
tortured and abused because of you
so they're relieved of that
and then the best benefit for you guys
is that because in the beginning of the conversation
you stated that you're against animal
abuse you're horrified by what's on the screens
when you're vegan for the first time
then you no longer have to be a hypocrite
never thought of it like that
do you know the number one benefit
of going vegan?
the number one benefit obviously for the
animals once you're vegan then they're no longer
tortured because of you, so they're
relieved of that
and then the best benefit for you is
that because you said you're against animal abuse
when you're vegan for the first time
you no longer have to be a hypocrite
and do you know the number one benefit
when you stop supporting animals and be
vegan? the number one benefit of that?
you're not part of a crazy-ass society
that's actually really close
it would first be for the animals would no longer
be abused by you but as an individual
this is really important on
an individual level since you've told me
in this conversation that you are against
animal abuse
and you're clearly disturbed of what you
see on the screen.
when you become vegan for the first time
you no longer have to be a hypocrite.
do you know the number one benefit
of being vegan?
like the number one benefit, any guesses?
like health?
health. so health is conditional
you can absolutely receive some amazing
health benefits
depending on how you coordinate your lifestyle
but the number one benefit would first
of course be for the animals
they would no longer be abused because of you
but as individuals
the number one benefit would be
if you say you're against animal abuse
and you look at these screens
and you're disgusted by it
then you no longer have to be a hypocrite
it's really important that
we don't just say have a nice day
after telling them the benefit
it's really important that you ask them
what they're going to do
that's how you should end the
interaction "so what do you think you'll do?"
and when people say i'll try to do better
then you tie in the fact that
they shouldn't try they need to do
and the best way to end it is
"so what do you think you'll do?"
it's really important that you close off strongly
because then it's like
the whole interaction was for nothing
if you don't close it off properly
without that close it really like seals
the whole conversation and
they really understand what the imperative is
they're after. after seeing this footage
after having this conversation
what do you think you'll do moving
forward regarding this suffering?
[Music]
i mean something had to be done but..
so like just right there when hudson
said "what do you think you'll do about
this suffering?"
i'm just going to add this on and
i'm sure hudson will appreciate this because
he always appreciates these little
updates but he's absolutely killing it
in these examples
the suffering that you cause
the suffering that's happening because of you
just a little
added update that i would make there
and i'll just go back..
after seeing this footage, after having this
conversation what do you think you'll do
moving forward regarding this
suffering?
[Music]
i mean something had to be done but
i don't know
just keep in mind that until
the day comes that you're vegan, animals..
[Music]
so i guess i spoke too soon there
because he ties in right here
that further accountability that
i was looking to add into
that comment he just made so let's just retract
that comment i made because he really
does double down at the end here
to make sure that this is happening
because of the individual
so let's just continue ..
something had to be done but
i don't know
just keep in mind that until
the day comes that you're vegan
animals are going to be
victimized and abused because of you
so just think about what side of history
you want to stand on when it comes to
stamping out
this particular injustice. what do you
think you guys are going to do
leaving here? i feel like
i'll i'll think more about it i feel
like the next time i have me but whether
they come vegan
i don't want to see that in my future to
be honest but
i mean yeah.. just remember until the day
that you do align those actions
with the words that you said during
this conversation that animals will be abused
because of you
so just decide what side of history
you want to stand on
what do you guys think you're going to
do after seeing this footage?
i don't know i'm definitely going to try
to be more conscious about it, i don't
know if i'm ready to fully be a vegan but
i don't know
what i'll leave you guys with is that
you agree that when you're taking baby steps
just keep in mind that for however long
you are taking baby steps
animals are going to be tortured for you guys so
when you're ready to stop abusing animals and
stop being hypocrites then you guys
can be vegan so think about what side of
history you guys want to stand on.
all right what do you think you're going
to do leaving here?
we rethink my fucking process in terms
of what i eat
for sure because i want to i want to be
a better person.  that's crazy
just understand that until the day that
you do decide to align your actions
with the beliefs that you said you've had
during this conversation
the animals will be abused because of you
so just decide what side of history you
want to stand on
when stamping out this particular injustice
now i know this seems confrontational
you guys are ..
i just want to take a moment to give a
quick shout out to jacob and hudson
for those very fine examples they are
killing it right now
and really adopting this approach whoops
i hope the audio was okay there but just
want to shout out to jacob and hudson
they're doing great work
you're thinking [ __ ] i don't know if i
could just decide what side of history
you want to stand on
when stamping out this particular
injustice
now i know this seems confrontational
you guys are probably thinking [ __ ] i
don't know if i could say that to people
but
i'm telling you this is the most
satisfying thing that you can say to
somebody
because it's effective because that is
the most effective thing that you can
say to somebody
and again this has been applied i mean
we've got a very keen student in the
back here hudson do you want to tell
people what kind of reactions you've had
or if you've had any negative
interactions
yes at first i was really worried about
it about this whole approach
and paul was like no we gotta try it you
gotta try it
and then i went up to people who were
twice my size hold up hold up
start from the start when you didn't
want to do this you thought that this
was too aggressive
yeah i thought it was way too aggressive
i got brainwashed by the vegan movement
and thought
that it's the wrong approach and anyway
i
recently tried out this approach being
direct
and what i found is people have so much
more
respect for me because i don't come
across as some politician
trying to sell them something and i
found it's worked
so much better because people recognize
that we're not calling them hypocrites
because we don't like them
we're doing it because we don't like
animal abuse and we're against the
torture of animals
that's a big point unless you have an
ego issue
this shouldn't be seen as malicious by
the person you're speaking to
unless you have an ego issue and you
just want to be right all the time and
you're trying to own people and
that's the only reason why you're doing
activism then people may respond
negatively to you
but what they pick up on is that your
heart is in the right place when you say
this stuff you're not saying this stuff
for any other reason
you only know this to be true if you
apply it
no matter what i say no matter what
hudson just said you need to apply this
put aside everything you've learned
about outreach about everything you've
learned about
animal rights activism and just apply
this
not just today but for the following
cubes that occur
after today keep doing this and see what
results you have
because again this is the reason why you
went vegan
because you don't want to be a hypocrite
you don't want to be an animal abuser
and someone called you out on your
hypocrisy
if it wasn't someone else it was
yourself that made this distinction
oh
i know it's crazy but apparently i need
to make
this distinction for people when i say
holding non-vegans accountable
i don't mean forcing people to go vegan
you can't hold people accountable in the
true sense of the word
because people have to hold themselves
accountable in the end
it has to be a choice that comes from
them
when i say holding people accountable
it's
to the greatest extent that we can
possibly do so
through verbal interaction
okay i didn't think i needed to clarify
that but i've been getting comments and
dms from people
saying you can't force anyone to be
vegan this holding non-vegans
accountable approach
is off base because people can only hold
themselves accountable
well this approach puts people in the
best
position to hold themselves accountable
and that's the truth does this make
sense to everybody
so thanks for the uh comments about the
audio there
i'm doing my best here with the
technical end of things
but let's just go back doing this
and see what results you have because
again this is the reason why you went
vegan because you don't want to be a
hypocrite you don't want to be an animal
abuser
and someone called you out on your
hypocrisy if it wasn't someone else it
was yourself
that made this distinction
does this make sense to everybody are
you feeling this
all right now i'm going to take
questions your hand went up lightning
fast i got to respect that
quickly what's your opinion on joaquin
phoenix's oscar speech on the long
reaching effectiveness of that
i loved it but it's i wouldn't have said
exactly what he said
but i love the fact that he used his
platform to talk about what happens in
the dairy industry
i didn't like how he conflated it with
love and compassion so much because i
don't think you need to love animals to
not stab them to death you don't need to
love black people to know that they
deserve their rights
you don't need to love any being to know
that they deserve their rights
it's not the perfect message but i still
think it was great that he did that i
also want to point out
that joaquin phoenix said that meat and
dairy is the third leading
cause of environmental destruction or
climate crisis
but didn't we hear in conspiracy that it
was the leading cause
so why the [ __ ] are we even doing this
why are we even promoting
environmentalism and trying to use
environmental facts when it keeps
changing on us
when it comes to these things studies
can come back
to us that may prove us wrong on the
environment tip
in fact i've seen it proven that
you can be environmentally way more
better off as a non-vegan
than a vegan in many circumstances if
you live in a rural area
you're a minimalist and you fish from
your kayak
you're way more environmentally friendly
than a person who lives in new york
procreates
eats processed foods so environmentally
this is not a surefire argument
this really isn't and i just want to say
from the health point of view can also
be justified
you can eat a piece of cheese or you can
eat a
salmon once a week and justify that from
a health perspective because you just
bounce back
very easily from a health point of view
you can feel better pretty quickly
so there's no point of even arguing the
health and the environment for those
reasons
next question even if that were true
reply like because i found that to be
quite good and when you say
even if that were true how do you
justify this do you ever use that at all
i do i've been using that recently
people say i think there's bigger issues
in the world
right human issues are more important
well even if there are bigger issues in
the world which we actually know that
this is the biggest issue
with the health and environment the only
reason why we're talking about it is
because animal
rights is such an issue that it's
impacted our environment
it's become that big of an issue that it
impacts our environment
and it impacts human health to the
extent that it does
but we can give them that still and say
even if there are bigger issues what
justifies you doing this to them
any other questions yes i've found on
the internet
so you put something up about veganism a
lot of people just put like you know
means to take the piss out of the
veganism people sort of just go
straight to that and they won't listen
to you after that like
so they take the piss out of what you're
trying to do and then you just can't get
through to them at all because they're
so fixated on taking the piss out of us
how would you get through take the piss
out of them
roast them in return they're the ones
that are supposed to be roasted
yeah but if they're just trolling
they're not reachable but
my simple response would be to roast
them back but sometimes
it's just like people are more drawn to
a picture or something because the
bulk amount of people can just you know
gang up on you like that and
it makes you feel like you know you
should just stop talking like it's sort
of hard
it feels like you're trapped in that
position where
you know like there's no actual response
that's
worth and then it just makes you think
oh you know what i'm doing
am i actually doing the right thing is
it worth me spending my time doing this
you're definitely doing the right thing
when you speak up for the animals it's
always a good idea it's always
worth doing i think your question is is
it effective to be doing that
is that what you're asking yeah so i
don't know
like with regards to the comments that
coming in on your facebook or instagram
i don't know if those individuals are
going to go vegan but it may be more
about who's reading it
you know what i'm saying the imprint
that you leave on those individuals
it's important that you only focus on
what you're saying
and how you advocate for the animals so
that if anybody ever does stumble across
the comment thread
that they read the right thing they hear
what they're supposed to hear from
you know what i'm trying to get at yeah
yeah and that's the best you can do
whether you should be doing this with
those individuals i don't know because
you'd have to give me more specific
examples about what they're saying and
how they're saying it
but if they're dropping memes about
eating meat and how tasty bacon is
i've actually found that roasting those
people can be pretty effective
don't waste too much energy on it you
may want to block them after a certain
point once you've made your point
for people to read so you may want to
manage it that way on social media
but as long as you say the correct thing
you're in the right
space yes um paul
um i just wrote down this thing that i
was going to say when you were talking
about the blood on your hand
on their hands so i found it actually
harder to speak to people that i know
personally that love animals
um also they love animals they actually
i've lost four people that i've known
for a long time because they
they seem to think that my message is
hateful so people who have tried to
break down the barriers
um around animals in agriculture they
reject any notion
of even
so when my compassion for the animals
involved
into more what you would call aggression
and like passionate speaking
and ask why they can ignore those
animals quite um and can be hateful
how do we get people to abandon a
lifetime of adoption and
views around farm animals particularly
as people seem to not acknowledge their
sentience or even have any regard for
them as if
they're not relevant other than as a
commodity so i've found that
by trying to get people to engage their
compassion or
even their sense of justice around
animals
yeah and you're the only one who's
making them visible
or attempting to at this point yes like
they
know that that you know advertising
exists but they actually don't
connect
they have to disconnect in order to
sleep at night
and what you represent is a mirror
you're a mirror
and when they call you hateful you are
actually hateful but not to them you're
hateful to their actions they're
the abuse that's occurring to the
animals so don't again don't let people
shame you out of these things
yes you are hateful own it you are
hateful
you do hate what they're doing to
animals that's why you're speaking up
and that's why you're passionate
you're not just passionate this is an
art we're talking about you're not just
passionate about this
this is an injustice and you are angry
you hate the fact that
your friends people you love are so
willing
to make excuses for something so
unbelievably unjustifiable
right that's what you hate the fact that
they're
yeah but like even the people that you
outreach to like actually
trying to make them feel something
though because it could be on their
radar
what from what you've told me i actually
think that they do have it on their
radar because that's why they're trying
to disconnect and call you hateful
things when they say things that are
inaccurate and irrational it's a sign
that they do have
guilt and guilt is a sign of them caring
about the subject
it's just so far buried down there
because that's where it needs to be for
them to sleep at
do you understand these people do care
about this issue
you're just living proof of it being
made into action and having your
your actions aligned with your morals
and you represent
something to them that makes them feel
inadequate and they should [ __ ] feel
that way
you do hate what they're doing to the
animals let them know that
that you don't respect what they're
doing to the animals and there's no way
that they can justify it keep asking
them how do you justify this
even if you think that a cow doesn't
feel the same way as a dog
or the same way more importantly don't
use a dog as an example use them
how would you feel if you're in a cow's
position what crime has a cow committed
other than being born non-human there's
no way they can justify so asking these
basic questions usually will lead you
to having them face the facts and
a vegan well they may temporarily but if
that's the reason i don't talk to you
anymore
for someone who is a concerned citizen
speaking up against injustice
then they're not really your friend are
they
friends don't abandon friends over
something so
obviously righteous like that even if
they're the perpetrator again they can't
justify it
a real friend would be like you know
what i respect the fact that you called
me out and there's nothing i can say
like i am hypocrite and i am an animal
abuser
or even if they don't admit to that they
would at least keep you in their lives
if they respected the fact that you're
speaking up against this
and then it's up to you how long you
keep them in your lives
does that help yeah thanks a lot cool
[Music]
stop share so there it is
that was the holding non-vegans
accountable 2.0 from perth australia
that was the second stop on the
australian leg
of the world tour that we embarked on
in february which got
put to an end due to the coronavirus
so i will take questions and i will also
start using this presentation with the
slides to break down this whole thing
once over
just to reiterate all the points that
were made
it is good to feel bad about something
that is bad simple
i love simplicity and effectiveness
the simpler the better
in terms of effectiveness it has to have
that effectiveness there but the
simplicity i just love that so much
okay
so i'm gonna get these slides downloaded
but if you guys have any questions lace
me up in the comments
okay where is this
here we are
all right so i'm going to go over
everything once more just to reiterate
all these points and make sure you guys
fully understand them
there was a complaint about my speaking
voice
how is the audio coming through let me
know
oh
nope this isn't it
this is it um
um okay so question by carlo hi paul
once you understand that the person
you are talking to is not going to be
interested in the topic and continues
justifying animal abuse
what do you say to them before going
away all these examples you saw
and everything that we said in the
approach applies to these individuals
the only difference is that
at some i'm assuming that these people
probably at a cube of truth probably
won't even stop but if they do stop
and you're talking to them at some point
it could be really powerful for you to
just end the discussion
with that that uh statement that was
made at the end of the interaction you
saw examples from hudson and jacob
um just know that for as long as you
remain non-vegan these animals will be
tortured and abused
because of you and
just decide what side of history
so i'll i'll leave this with you to
think about but
you ultimately will need to decide which
side of history
you want to stand on something powerful
like that a statement like that is all
you can really do
with those individuals and i i just want
to say that it's important that you
respect your time
as an activist and that you're not
wasting your breath on people so
it's very powerful to say to the
individual
that you would like to carry on your
work with those who are
like you'd like to move on you know so
ending the discussion and moving on
after you make that statement
is super powerful and that's what you
should do
audio is fine good thank you guys
i've got the slide ready i'm just going
to read through your comments and see if
there's any questions
david's saying i would only say i
wouldn't mind if an animal killed me
but i would say i would eat you would
say that you would eat a human
okay david you uh
you sound a bit confused buddy i don't
think you would be okay with an animal
eating you if you had a choice
and you have a choice not to eat animals
so you're the oppressor and the power is
in your hands
to end the suffering and abuse and
torture
that you would inflict on these animals
otherwise if you choose
to continue to be a non-vegan human
supremacist
because that's what non-vegans are human
supremacists
and you are subscribing to this
death cult you're subscribing to this
idea that animals should be reduced
to a sandwich through violent
beheadings and enslavement and torture
david says it's an excuse but i'm
addicted
addiction isn't a justification
so let's hope that david gets the
message here and does actually connect
his actions to his words and ends his
hypocrisy for real
but let's move on to your other
questions here guys
can you say something about infighting
between vegans
and outreach organizations i hate it and
how to stop this
welcome to the animal rights movement if
you know how i can stop this i'd like to
know
um vegans are the biggest threat to the
animal rights movement
i've been saying this for a while i
learned this the hard way
gary told me told everyone
and i didn't think it was necessarily
true either at first but i've come to
learn this
very much so humans
what can i say it's terrible
but one thing that gives me optimism and
hope
is that there are plenty of us out there
who vibrate on this frequency and that's
all we need to do to continue moving
forward is
us supporting us so when i read your
comments
supporting av supporting me and asal and
the whole av
team we appreciate it so much because it
means that
we are working together we do have unity
between those who vibrate on this
frequency and that's important
where can you get the new outreach cards
from your organizer
if there's no organizer in your city go
over to our
website and go to the join section and
apply to become an organizer
so that you can launch a cube of truth a
chapter in your city where cuba truth
events operate
lots of questions coming through
how do i respond to people that say they
can't go vegan because of
medical advice point them to all of the
medical advice that
that says otherwise we have empirical
data that shows
that it's perfectly adequate for all
human beings to be on a plant-based
diet point them to the
evidence there's only one
source of scientific data there's only
one database
okay so michael greger is
a great person to look into because he
breaks down the data
so nutritionfacts.com but the thing i
just want nutritionfacts.org is the
website there
but i just want to say that this person
saying this most likely woody
is using this as an excuse to not go
vegan
if they're truly wanting to end
the abuse that they cause to animals the
needless suffering or in their case they
think it's
required but if they really want to end
it then they'll look into it
and they'll do their very damnedest to
make it happen to to end it
and so if you are talking to someone
who's truly trying to end it
then just give them that information
that should be enough but usually it
comes back to accountability
in those cases usually people are just
using that as an excuse
is it cruel to raise kids non-vegan it's
cruel to the animals
yeah and it is cruel to humans on some
level but it's
not even comparable to what we do to the
animals so i'm not even going to say
it's cruel to the humans
um so
what was the other part of that question
um saying this as a mother
it's cruel to the animals and you're
robbing
children and you're robbing children
over there you're making them confused
and you're robbing them off
i mean every vegan will say they wish
they were vegan since birth so
you're robbing them of that opportunity
to do the right thing
when kids are just doing what their
parents tell them to do so
when non-vegans say don't force this on
your children they're forcing
non-veganism on their children
parenting is forcing that's what
parenting is
they do what their parents tell them to
do up until they're 18.
so it's if you're gonna have to choose a
diet for them
why wouldn't you choose the one that
doesn't involve bloodshed
abuse torture suffering when it's
needless
that's my answer to that question
much love jeanette appreciate your
comment
um
how do you convince religious people or
anyone who is used to seeing animal
abuse
since young to feel something for the
animals that's two different questions
there
religious people
it's no different this whole approach is
no different if people say i believe god
said it's okay
classic gary quote if god says this is
okay then what does the devil do
just you're not going to get through to
most religious people you just need to
ask them these really tough questions
and treat them no different to anyone
else with the approach that we're giving
you
okay um and that second question i think
i've already answered
generally all right guys um
there are other questions here and if
you're not going to stay on this stream
you can watch this back when this video
goes up and i will respond to your
question at some point but i'm now going
to get into the slides
in the interest of time management
right i'm gonna share this and i'm just
gonna go through
each of the points that were raised in
that workshop for you guys
all right
sharing my screen once again
whoops
all right can you guys see that okay
i'm confident that you can but just to
make sure
let me know in the comments if you can
see that slide
i'm about to go through
i just need one of you guys to confirm
and then i'll continue
can you see the outreach workshop slides
[Music]
okay
all good cool thanks guys all right so
let's get into it so
this is our outreach workshop in slides
you might see
organizers in your city or town and if
you are an organizer or you become an
organizer
your organizer may run through a
workshop with you in your city
and they'll use these slides and these
slides may be updated from time to time
but right now this is our most updated
outreach workshop in slide format so
let's
let's go so we start with this important
question
what even is veganism if you ask a group
of people what it means to be vegan you
most likely will get multiple versions
of what they believe it to be
veganism has nothing to do with our
health the environment human rights or
affection towards animals
it is not about justice for non-human
animal rights
vegan equals anti-animal abuse
now i'm not going to make any extra
points here unless they naturally come
to me
but if you guys in the comments want to
make any points
or any questions about this slide be as
quick as you can
while this slides up i'm gonna wait two
minutes
between each slide so that if there's
anything specifically
that you would like me to address
regarding the points on each slide
i'll address them as we go so two
minutes starting now i'm going to start
my stopwatch on my phone
you know we have to start with the
definition of veganism before we even
talk about activism
so two minutes if anyone wants to
discuss anything here let me know
it's two minutes too long maybe i should
just do one minute
yeah common sense and self-explanatory
this slide all right
well i'm i'm gonna reduce that to one
minute so we've got 30 seconds
to go i think one minute is plenty
i don't have anything i'd like to add to
this
it's very straightforward like you said
so 10 seconds i'm assuming there's no
questions here
i'm an admin of the malaysian vegan
facebook group one question we ask
people who request to join is what
veganism means to them most of them say
it's kindness
and great health
wow yeah that's just typical isn't it
it's a very common thing in the animal
rights movement
and the other thing i want to point out
is you know when you ask what the
benefit is
most people say health or the
environment
which just goes to prove we don't need
to talk about health and the environment
with people and
talk about them as benefits and act like
that's what animal rights is all about
people already know about those things
what they really need to hear
is accountability for what they're doing
to the animals that's it
moving on
all right so what is animal rights
activism activism is speaking up for the
victims in the same way that you would
want to be spoken up for if you were in
their position
it is being a medium of truth and
enacting change by prioritizing the
victims and not the oppressors
one minute starting now
i don't have anything to add to this
either
this might even change to 30 seconds
because i don't want to drag this out
for people watching this back i want
this to be
as succinct as possible but i just want
to make sure i cover any
questions or points that might come up i
just want to be as
thorough as possible in addressing this
i think i might reduce
the time that i put aside for you guys
to 30 seconds in fact
instead of a minute
all right let's move on yeah i'm going
to reduce this down to 30 seconds
between slides to allow you guys to jump
in if you want
me to discuss anything more specifically
crystal clear says carlo great
don't try to be a communications guru
this goes back to the sales thing almost
um always remember that you will never
have 100
success rate within animal rights
outreach
there is no magic set of words to use
during outreach that will make someone
go vegan
if they're ready they'll listen if
they're not ready they won't
with the context provided your function
as an activist is to hold the individual
you're speaking with
accountable for the animal abuse they
support and to make them aware of the
consequences
of their choices 30 seconds
is too quick 30 seconds
if it's too quick uh
how about we just do a compromise make
it 45 seconds
i just don't want it to get too slow for
those watching this back
you know
okay
cool all right so let's move on we've
done 45 seconds there
30 david's voting 30.
all right let's move on so your goal
should not be to plant seeds animal
rights
outreach is not verbal leafleting i'm
going to repeat that
standing in front of a non-vegan and
spitting all these little factoids out
at them
is not activism and i heard someone say
planting seeds in the comments i mean i
know planting seeds is like a common
term used in the animal rights movement
specifically
but i guess we're doing that but it's
not
in the same way that people think of
planting seeds that's not what we're
doing here
animal rights outreach is not verbal
leafleting
if the goal were to provide information
we would hand out
leaflets and magazines and if that was
all that people needed to go out to go
vegan then
the information is already out there so
it's not necessarily about the
information
the function of outreach is to make
people understand the consequences of
their choices by holding them
accountable
and centering the interaction on what
they can personally do about the animal
of the use
on an individual level
45 seconds
is there anything here that you guys
have any questions about i don't
apologize
um you know don't apologize this is
a learning process i'm taking you guys
on i've learned this stuff and i'm just
teaching you guys what i've learned and
what we've learned together actually
so
not verbal leafleting is the biggest
part of this slide
no verbal leafleting
that's just cancer in the animal rights
movement i've seen it so many times i've
done it myself it gets you nowhere and
it makes this message
seem even more of a like a mockery to
people
like it's it takes it takes it down a
notch to then being taken less seriously
so all right that's 45 seconds moving on
veganism is not love or compassion
veganism is about justice your
likability does not determine your
rights
so out i'm going to repeat that just
because someone doesn't like you it
doesn't mean they have the right to take
your rights away from you
so that's why we don't need to lean into
how much people like animals
that's just the wrong way to communicate
this message
outreach is not about how you or anyone
else
feels about animals if you don't go
around beating children you aren't
instantly a compassionate individual
refraining from injustice does not make
you compassionate by default
and we can see that because in the
animal rights movement vegans are some
of the
least compassionate people that i have
to deal with
veganism is a non-action it's not loving
it's merely the right thing to do 45
seconds
all right i'm reading your comments guys
if there's anything you want me to
expand on
now's your time
you know what i'm going to reduce this
back down to 30 seconds
uh and if you guys like need more time
to write your comment
just start off with a comment
that you can just send out real quick
that says i have a comment or i have
something i want to add
and then i will wait for you to write
your longer question
if this is too quick so i'm going to
reduce this back to 30 seconds
and that's what you can do if you have
any questions but there are questions
coming in now
so i will answer them what does leaf
litting mean leafleting means
handing out pieces of information to
people and then
it's just like all these little factoids
about like
how old chickens are when they're
murdered and all these things and you
know
the the irony of how counterproductive
this is is obvious to me because so many
non-vegans
already know about how much of a
shocker the meat dairy and egg
industries are
they already know that they treat
animals horribly they already know about
how
young the animals are when they're
murdered and all these crazy statistics
and it's very easy to find out but it
doesn't make people go vegan
because knowing all these factoids is
one thing
and yes that might cause some people to
go vegan i take that back i know some of
you
thinking well i went vegan when i looked
into the dairy industry but at some
point there was accountability for your
actions and wanting to be
accountable for yourself for what you're
doing to them and yeah
that's what it comes down to these
factoids don't really push people
towards it it just puts them in a
position where they just feel like they
need to continue
arguing the points and all this stuff
and it's just
it's not it's not very effective at all
so
let's see if there's any other comments
here
ariane huge comment
very well said people will forget about
the facts anyways
what they will remember is the guilty
feeling when they hear
that they are animal abusers so just to
expand on
ariane's point here and point out how
how true that is there's a really great
quote that
everyone knows and it's just so true
people don't remember what you said
they remember how they felt when you
said it
and that's what this is all about
yeah veganism is about justice we can't
point that out enough seemingly
so we cannot point it out enough
all right moving on guys thanks for your
comments i appreciate it
i just want to make sure that i cover
everything for you guys and i appreciate
you guys being a part of this live
stream
all right moving on
this approach is pure honesty telling
someone the truth is the most respectful
thing you can do for them
when you agree with every statement said
by the bystander
they will often lose respect for you and
you will lose respect
so you will lose control of the
conversation
they see that your desire to be
validated by them is stronger than your
desire to end
animal cruelty thereby making a mockery
of
animal rights this one needs to be
repeated
they see that your desire to be
validated by them is stronger than your
desire to end animal cruelty
thereby making a mockery of animal
rights
you imagine if the primary goal of human
rights activists was to be liked by the
oppressors
30 seconds
all right that's 30 seconds i'm liking
the 30 seconds it feels like the right
amount of time here moving on
whenever you are afraid to speak up for
animals directly or if bystanders call
you too extreme
place yourself in the victim's position
and
analyze your approach from their
perspective
would you consider a respectful yet
direct conversation too extreme
if you were locked in a slaughterhouse
and that's the thing you know we are
being respectful here
it's the most respect you'll ever show
someone because you're telling
the truth and giving them a true
opportunity
to end their hypocrisy and to stop
abusing innocent beings
like a psychopath
like a cold-blooded monster that's what
these people
are especially once they know about what
is going on and they continue to do it
right
um i forgot to press start on the 30
seconds so let's just say we're up to 15
seconds now
yes
honesty is the highest form of intimacy
this might be irritating to some but it
may not stop us
from telling the truth that's beautiful
yeah that's so true honesty is the
highest form of intimacy
word all right moving on guys
all right so next slide
don't talk about health and environment
why do we think people care about either
most people in the streets do not care
about their health nor the environment
so rooting your outreach in these topics
will marginalize the animals
even further health and environment may
become have become
exacerbated because people do not take
animal abuse seriously
um again i need to repeat this point
because this is really
powerful to know and understand that
these
crisis that we're facing that we're
facing
that we're facing with our environment
and our health
is just an indication merely a a sign
that's all it is of how bad animal abuse
is on this planet
again i was supposed to press start
there
um oh no i haven't finished this all
right
um the last point trying to hook people
with an approach
that revolves around what benefits them
does not
let me start again trying to hook people
with an approach that revolves around
what
that revolves around what benefits them
does a disservice to the animals
focus on the root cause of the issue the
animal abuse
i kind of stumbled through that one but
you get the point you can see it
i'm going to start this 30 seconds if
you guys have anything you'd like me to
expand
on here let me know
people say this is fake that it's not
true what to say just point at the
screens
what part of this is fake challenge them
to go into a farm for themselves and see
what happens
in a slaughterhouse specifically say
because that's where all the animals end
up
right
uh i
i feel that i don't want to be friends
with people after giving information
anymore
who won't go vegan well that's the right
position i think
you wouldn't again when you compare this
to any other injustice you wouldn't
stick around and be friends with people
who
continue to enslave torture and murder
once they know better
if we were the victims we would not want
our advocates to prioritize the
environment or
our oppressor's health no and it would
it would be a huge
spit in your face to do that that's the
whole point of
clarifying this for you guys because the
victims
deserve so much better from us to be
advocating directly for them and they
they do deserve
a direct message that's dedicated to
them
yes yes okay
um what are some variable ways to start
the conversation other than have you
seen this type of footage before we
don't actually ask that anymore have you
seen this type of footage before
we do sometimes but in this approach
with this update
you don't need to ask that in fact what
we do is we say would you like to know
why we're here
um so vegan mark i'm not sure if you're
just joining the stream but we did cover
this you might want to watch this video
back and it will be
available for everyone to watch back
once i'm done and we did cover that
raping is bad for your health
yeah that's what it sounds like
never met a 100 zero waste and whole
food vegan so why expect non-vegans to
care
exactly summer it's so obvious isn't it
i always say health and environment are
just consequences of animal abuse
and our mentality towards animals and if
we want to solve
a problem we have to pull the root of
evil
out very well said david if you said
that to me when i wasn't vegan that
would punch me in the stomach in the
best way
you can see you can say would you like
to know why we're here today yes thank
you jaz you've been paying attention
all right cool let's move on
why don't people care about ethics let's
explore that
because vegans don't advocate for
animals correctly
they focus on things like plant-based
recipes
restaurants weight loss or deforestation
another reason is they lead with phrases
like friends not food
or animal lovers don't eat animals
this is not a conversation about
sympathy
this is a conversation about
accountability
don't plead with bystanders make them
understand the consequences of their
choices by placing them in the victim's
position
30 seconds i don't have anything else to
add to this
unless you guys want me to expand on it
um
check out the majority of vegans online
rather not just on instagram vegan king
they don't even talk about animals yeah
it seems like in this movement that the
animals barely get a mention
they barely get a shout out and we
quickly move on to humans and
humans humans humans how does this
affect humans let's talk about that
when humans are the oppressors it's just
backwards
all right cool you guys don't have
anything uh you want me to expand on
here so i'm going to move on
all right next slide morality is black
and white when it comes to this
issue specifically i'm talking about
guys okay i'm not talking about
these fringe gray area examples that
could be brought up
with very insignificant choices you
could say
this is very significant and it's
involving
in it's involving oppression so when
you're talking about an issue of
oppression
where there are victims involved
morality is black and white when it
comes to that if
bystanders tell you that you aren't
considering the other side to this
or you aren't open-minded enough that is
a distraction
there is no other side to needless
animal abuse
you either support it or you don't don't
get lost in these distractions
compare animal abuse to a comparable
injustice to get you back on track
and like i was saying earlier on in this
video the best injustice to compare to
is the one that involves the individual
you're speaking
to as the victim so if they
imagine themselves as the victim of the
injustice that you're speaking about
when you compare it
that's going to be the best way for them
to feel what it is they need to feel in
that moment
30 seconds
good night daniel thank you for being a
part of this man
uh i don't know who epa is david
all right we've done 30 seconds i don't
see anything you guys want me to
expand on here so we're going to move on
all right moving on so the next slide
where we got to the 12th slide
okay which injustices to compare to
so i actually break this
last point i just made even further down
in this slide it is most effective to
compare to injustices such as
child abuse or human trafficking child
abuse
and human trafficking are the most
comparable human injustices that we've
found
to compare to the most effective
comparison to make
is to place the bystander in the
victim's position
i just explained that but that's there
for you again to
absorb i really want you to take that
into consideration and really absorb
that
avoid dog comparisons this goes back to
not leading with compassion
it's not about the love people feel
towards animals it's about
the hate they feel towards injustice
and i would say injustice in their name
or because of them not in their name but
because of their actions right in their
name is kind of an ego thing
it doesn't come down to whether you can
imagine your dog in a slaughterhouse
it comes down to whether you can imagine
yourself in a slaughterhouse
right i'm going to repeat that it
doesn't come down to whether you can
imagine your dog in a slaughterhouse
it comes down to whether you can imagine
yourself in a slaughterhouse
that's the truth that's what makes you
really wake up to this
30 seconds
yeah so carlo about the moralities black
and white you have to
clarify that specifically we're talking
about
injustices that involve victims
oppression these things are black and
white
if it's needless and this is it needs to
stop
it's really simple you don't need to
necessarily say morality is black and
white
i'm just pointing this out in this in
this workshop for you guys
that you need to understand morality is
black and white and
the way that you communicate this to
other people but you don't necessarily
need to say morality is black and white
in those words
but yeah if people want to get into a
philosophical discussion you know just
put an end to that
america's environmental protection
agency is the epa which is a broken
government system
uh yeah i wouldn't i don't have any
interest
um okay
yeah people just say they don't mind
eating dogs as well it
happens so often yeah what about dogs
yeah well if i had to eat a dog i would
it just immediately blows up in our face
um and i'm talking about most of the
time here dog comparisons
seemingly work niraj
they seemingly work because your
indicator of an effective conversation
might be
someone doing this uh-huh yes
i agree yes uh-huh that's not
necessarily
effective it's very easy to agree with
things like
um like if they had a dog with them and
they obviously care about their dog
like they're walking with the dog and
then they're showing you know
like empathy for their dog in some way
and you say well what if that dog was
stabbed to death
yeah it's an easy thing to agree with
yep
but what happens when that dog dies in
the family how long will they take to
grieve that dog's life
compared to a human
compared to how sad they would feel
about their own death and
if they were going to be murdered you
see what i'm saying
all right i'm going to move on i don't
see any comments here
wanting me to expand on this particular
slide i think i've covered as much as i
can so let's move on
statistics keep them minimal outside of
what is asked of you
state minimal information during
outreach conversations
we are not on the streets to verbally
leaflet again
let the footage provide the context to
the conversation
you aren't at a cube of truth to be a
statistician
you're there to have a concise
conversation that holds people to
account
for their unjustified animal abuse
a conversation will go on for longer
than necessary if it turns into an
argument over statistic
over statistics this is another reason
why you should bring up health and
environment talking points why you
shouldn't
pardon me this is another reason why you
shouldn't bring up
health and environment talking points
because that usually leads into
a never-ending debate about nothingness
seconds if you guys have any points you
want me to expand on
let me know
yeah this is a good point here if the
conversation went
to logic i usually believe the person
won't go vegan
try to keep it about the abuse and here
it says
best of a logic person is to go
plant-based veganisms from your heart
you do need to hit people in the chest
people talk part of me you're talking
about how
you know it's how you make people feel
that's what people are going to remember
moving on
yeah it's not a debate club on the
streets very good point street activism
is not a debate club
moving on guys reachability and
conversation length not everybody on the
streets is worth talking to part of your
role is to assess
who is reachable and who is not many
people are not reachable
if they want to have a short
conversation with you keep it short with
them
don't entertain bystanders who want to
engage in long
argumentative debates we just covered
that do not underestimate the
cunningness of non-vegan guilt
and the ability that non vegans many
non-vegans will have to waste your vital
time at work for the animals
that's a huge point that last one 30
seconds
yeah part of the game here is assessing
who is reachable
you get better at this with practice by
the way
yeah well jezebel you're right it's also
logical
the point here is to not get lost in the
logic
you have to also have what hits people
in the chest too
cunningness what is cunningness
you mean the actual definition of the
word
let's look it up the actual definition
of the word
according to miriam webster is
skill in achieving one's ends through
indirect
subtle or underhanded means
and here's an example it took a certain
amount of cunningness on the
photographer's part to obtain such
revealing portraits
of his rich and famous subjects
anyhow the way it applies here in this
context
is that non-vegans are very
cunning in the way that they address
these arguments with vegans and the way
that they
try to make vegans think that plants
have feelings for example like they
really get deep into it and they're like
yeah like they feel stuff and like yeah
they're like they act like they really
believe it
but it's just
their cunningness is a lie
it's really their guilt trying to double
down
you know so um are there any questions
here i'm not even going to do the 30
seconds thing because i've given you
guys plenty of time while i've been
talking
yes it does stay online afterwards malia
this will be available online once i'm
done
you can tell by their body language when
they're not even looking at the footage
because they're
only there to waste our time yeah
if they don't want to be there just get
them to go just go
indirect distractions and so on yes
exactly
indirect distractions that's what it is
all right moving on guys it doesn't seem
like you guys want me to expand on much
here so i might even just keep this
moving
at a quicker pace activism is not sales
sales training does not equal good
activism using slick talk
to trick people into veganism doesn't
work
your job is to hold the bystander
accountable it's
up to them which actions they take
initially av made too strong of a
connection between sales and activism
tools taught in sales training only go
so far
any questions about this or anything you
want me to expand on it
30 seconds but
[ __ ] i might even reduce this down even
further
10 seconds
now i'll keep it at 30 seconds but uh
let me let me know guys if you want me
to break anything down further for you
five seconds
moving on so the next slide
activism is not sales we're still
continuing on this thing
a successful conversation is not one
where the bystander says i'm going vegan
that's not necessarily the thing that
you should be looking for
it's where you say the right things most
people become vegan after they hear the
truth from us
how long it takes is up to the
individual
30 seconds
okay so uh there's a question here
i'm you're still confused about the
sales thing could you give me an example
or more could you be more specific about
what you're confused about
good question summer do you still
promote feel felt found i never really
understood what that means
again that was just a communication tool
i thought it would be helpful
i don't use it anymore and it's not in
this outreach
workshop for a reason that you have
pointed out and i appreciate that
we've removed it because again we make
too strong of a connection
to sales and i don't want people to
think that these communication tools
are the approach like this is that's not
an approach
that's just a tool a little tiny little
tool that can help
with your communication but feel fat
found
no you don't really need to use that and
we've removed it
it's unnecessary
what you said about giving fair warning
before asking a question or commenting
is a good way to proceed
awesome like how do we know
if we've made an impact on their
perception apart from their guilt
you don't uh you well you don't
there are certain indicators but like we
say here most people become vegan after
they hear the truth from us
how long it takes is up to the
individual and that's why i say i want
you to connect
to this
approach in in i want you to connect to
understanding that
if you say the right things on behalf of
the victims then you have succeeded in
your outreach
because that's the best you can do the
next step is physically forcing people
to become vegan which we can't do
does that help
sales is too much practical
veganism is more from the from our
internals
not sure what you mean there soilless
magician
is it good to start with the socratic
method to get to know where the
individual is
at well socratic questioning is
something that we touch on in this
so jazz just stick around and i'll get
into that
further all right guys i'm gonna move on
okay that does help good let's move on
the socratic the very next slide there
it is jazz
maybe we sensed the line of questions
that might come from you guys and that's
why we put this slide next all right so
socratic the socratic method
socratic questioning is a communication
tool that we use within our approach
it is not an approach in and of itself
and neither is the sales thing where we
ask questions
to lead the bystander to their own
conclusions so yes
jazz you're right and i'll read that
again okay
so credit questioning is a communication
tool that we use within our approach it
is not an approach in and of itself
where we ask questions to lead the
bystander to their own conclusions
use open-ended questions such as
why are you sorry let me start again use
open-ended questions such as
why are you against animal abuse instead
of a closed statement such as animal
abuse is wrong
open-ended questions are generally
prefer preferred
i've got a problem with speaking today
open-ended questions are generally
preferred
to anchor and progress the conversation
you should use closed-ended questions
and statements
30 seconds
would it be possible to ask the
non-vegan to give us
feedback on the conversation they had
well
we kind of do at the end we say what do
you think you'll do that
gives you the answer
and danya if i'm saying you're not your
name correctly
dania could you also point out the tip
about
open-ended questions are generally
preferred
to anchor and progress the conversation
you should you should use
closed-ended questions and statements so
we're not saying use open-ended
questions all the time that's just
ridiculous
but generally they are preferred i'm
going to move on now
to the next slide
you versus we we don't torture animals
and kill
animals for products non-vegans do using
we
undermines individual accountability
when you tell non-vegans that we as a
society are responsible for animal
cruelty in farms it takes away the
imperative for the individual
accountability
it makes them think of lobbying
government programs
etc instead of personal responsibilities
people need to feel guilty to change
they'll only change once they understand
that there is a difference between you
the vegan and them the non-vegan and
that difference needs to be very
clear
30 seconds
i can add and say that guilt is the only
way
in my opinion to get people to go vegan
not plant-based but transform them into
a vegan activist that's gonna change the
[ __ ] world
amen
um can we mean i was in the same boat as
the non-vegan well that's the thing it's
being used that way
but when you say we you no longer do it
so it's just completely inaccurate
you're making an inaccurate statement in
an effort to seem more humble
which is really just trying to be liked
which is really focusing on getting
compassion from the abusers
as opposed to focusing your compassion
on the victims
does that help
all right moving on thank you for your
comments guys but um
i'm going to move on so on to the next
people already know how to go vegan this
is the why versus how
people already know how to go vegan with
the constant availability of
google and the internet people are
literally glued to their phones
in 2020. anybody can figure out how to
become vegan instantly
in order for people to feel the need to
become vegan
they need to be held accountable for why
they said for why they should do it
my vision is going blurry at this point
i'll read that again
in order for people to feel the need to
become vegan they need to be held
accountable for
why they should do it with any other
injustice you would never focus on
the how by talking about how
to not participate in the violence
so i'm reading this incorrectly let me
start again
with any other injustice you would never
focus on the how by talking about how
to not participate in the violence
focusing on the how in the context of
any other injustice
would be an insult to the victims and
the entire movement fighting to end
their oppression 30 seconds
how do you convince intersectionals to
be vegan
intersectionals to be vegan i'm assuming
they're not vegan then
usually i find intersectionals are vegan
but if they're if they're not even vegan
you i would just say
to talk to them like you talk to anybody
else
yes moving on guys thank you on to the
next slide
vegetarianism is cancer to animal rights
vegetarians are non-vegans and should be
outreached in the same manner as anyone
else
and in most cases even harder because
vegetarians act so pompous
vegetarians are our target market
they're no different to paleo eaters why
should we treat them any differently
they are not allies don't let other
non-vegans
and vegans manipulate you into thinking
that they are
30 seconds i don't have anything to add
to these
points if
if i'm just moving straight into
looking at the comments and it doesn't
look like you guys
want me to expand on this it's pretty
straightforward
all right five seconds
vegetarians are proper carnists yeah
well said
they should get tenfold harsher activism
especially if they're pompous
especially if they're pompous all right
moving on
typical outreach structure ask them if
they would like to know why you're here
this was asked earlier
ask them if they would like to know why
you're here and with the context of the
footage playing
tell them what the cube of truth sets
out to do
what we are doing is showing the reality
of what happens to animals and the meat
dairy egg and other industries
everything you see here is standard
practice here
and around the world asking the
following open-ended question
what are your feelings on animal abuse
then confirm their stance
to form moral consistency with something
like so it's safe to say that you are
against animal abuse
30 seconds
hmm
moving on
we're nearly nearly finished with these
slides also guys
typical outreach structure ask them do
they think it's possible to be against
animal abuse while demanding products
like meat dairy and eggs
i don't think we covered this in the uh
presentation but this is a powerful
point i'm going to read it again
ask them do you think it's possible to
be against animal abuse while demanding
products like meat dairy and eggs
ask them what is stopping them from not
abusing animals and being vegan
what do you feel like would be stopping
you from not abusing animals
and being vegan this will lead to their
objections
30 seconds
how to respond if they don't consider
those footage
wow let me read this question out um how
to respond if
people don't consider the footage to be
animal abuse
you have no conversation to be having
with that person move on to the next
person
if blood flying everywhere and heads
being
cut off is not animal abuse
if baby male chicks if baby chicks
are being grinded alive
in a big blender and they don't think
that's animal abuse
you're not talking to a rational person
so i would say you need to move on to
the next person jezebel
if they say they don't care about animal
abuse is it best just to end the
conversation
i would say what if you were the one
being abused
would you care then or it's easy to say
when you're the abuser
what if you were the one being abused
that's the upgrade there for you
and then move on if it goes downhill
from there because
this is not a rational open and willing
person you're speaking to
carlo recently you said in a video
we have to avoid the word vegan i'm a
little confused about it now
so you suggest to openly say we are
promoting veganism or not
i never said to not use the word vegan
in fact i say i said that i used the
word vegan
it's just what i'm saying carlo is that
it's
far more effective for us to explain
what the meaning like to say human
supremacy or animal abuse
you know to detail what it really means
to be vegan
like if in this point
um if i mean at this point in the
conversation you're saying if we are
saying that we're promoting veganism um
this is it depends this is something
that i would say if someone says
you're promoting vegetarianism i would
correct that and say we're not promoting
vegetarianism because that doesn't
address the issue at all
we're promoting veganism so i would
not shy away from saying the word vegan
however it's usually
best for you to talk about what that
word actually means than to just use the
word
why because the word has a lot of
confusion around it within the animal
rights movement
you can see how there's so many
definitions flying around
and that's why we started this with the
definition of veganism itself
even if they are killed quickly it is
still animal abuse of course because
again
if you were the victim it is still abuse
to take your life even if it's done
quickly of course you would see it as
abuse
in that circumstance
you know the jews who were killed in the
concentration camps if they were gassed
and killed quickly
that doesn't make the injustice any less
worse
cool um moving on
next slide objection handling whenever a
bystander brings up an objection
place them in the victim's position and
allow them to analyze the objection
from that perspective every single time
this happens the objection will fall
apart
most objections are easy and quick to
respond to
some are more nuanced and require a
deeper explanation
but they should still be quick to
respond to your response should always
anchor back to individual accountability
this
can't be more simple this is so simple
again 30 seconds
all right moving on
bring it back to the individual if they
try to create excuses that try to remove
accountability for example pointing to
rural communities
lions low income families etc
don't get lost in lengthy explanations
bring it back to the individual by
placing themselves in the victims
position
and asking how that excuse justifies
their personal contribution
to animal abuse
i don't know if contribution is the
right word i might update that but you
guys know what this is saying
uh yeah 30 seconds i'm gonna
shave five seconds off that so 25
seconds
objections are good they can be good yes
they can be good
all right moving on next slide
um tying the benefit tying the benefit
only once they concede by saying if
they're against animal abuse then it's
not possible to be against animal abuse
while supporting it
the number one benefit of going vegan
for the animals
the benefit is that they no longer have
to be tortured and abused because of you
for you if you say you are against
animal abuse
and what you see on the screens then
when you're vegan
you no longer have to be a hypocrite
and so we're going to update this part
like i said
to say when you're vegan you have the
opportunity
for the first time in your life to not
be a hypocrite
so that's the update there when you're
vegan
you now have the opportunity to no
longer be a hypocrite
this drives home the accountability and
makes them understand the consequence of
their actions
30 seconds
wow this has gone on for ages i saw it
like five hours ago govi
well jen you know i'm trying to make
sure that this workshop is
as thorough as possible but we're almost
about to wrap up
do people only care about being
hypocrites yeah because it affects
people care about themselves and the
image of themselves and
if you want to hit people and and mess
up their ego about themselves that's how
you do it you you call them out on
things like this and this is
unfortunately how people
work i mean i wish that it was just as
easy as saying
guys we have 50 less than 50 years left
on this planet
animal abuse is the biggest pressing
issue of our time we have
no right to be abusing animals please
stop
if that was it was just as easy as that
i would i would that's what i would be
telling you to do in this outreach
workshop but it's not
moving on
26 all right close the conversation
always end outreach conversations
by asking what the individual will
personally do
to take action ask them open and ask
the open-ended question after our
conversation
what are you going to do about this
injustice
after a long conversation they may still
say that they'll
only reduce or do nothing
if they can if you can sense that the
interaction will
keep going in circles end the
conversation with the statement
30 seconds
from a outsider point of view this vegan
approach is genius
david velas is in the comments
and seems effective and david is not
vegan
joining us and giving his feedback on
this approach
i appreciate it david i appreciate your
feedback
but you know that this is going to be
a huge thing for you that you have to
face because this whole conversation
if you're telling us it's effective what
we really want to know is how effective
is it
for you
all right let's move on
so this is the last slide guys
closing the conversation an effective
statement in this situation can be so
keep in mind that for however long that
you're not vegan
animals will be abused and tortured
because of you
so when you're ready to stop abusing
animals and align your actions with your
words
you know what to do so think about what
side of history
you want to stand on and that closed
um that closes the conversation but this
is also
the question that we have for you david
this question is for you what are you
going to do
your question david i'm not sure on
uh how would i respond to someone saying
that they would hire animals
it's i don't i've never heard that
before but hiring i'm not sure if you've
used the wrong word there but hiring
animals is still exploitation
that's just another word for enslaving
animals
but i'm not quite sure i understand your
question there
and this is the end of this live stream
and this workshop so i want to thank you
each of you for being a part of this
it's been
really energizing for me to do this
leading into international cube day
which is tomorrow
and this is something that i've been
wanting to roll out for
a few months now so thank you for being
a part of this
and if you have any questions that you
want to send me directly on social media
about anything we've discussed
here feel free to do so you can follow
me on instagram paul bashir underscore
av
um i also have a youtube channel paul
bashir
and uh yeah connect with me on social
media
after this if you need any further
support thank you for the support you've
shown
us and if you're going to be at a cube
tomorrow
have a good one i'm going to be out in
melbourne with a very limited number of
people
and we're gonna do what we can to make
it happen and i will go live at some
point
so i'll see you there see you on the
streets hopefully at some point too
much love everybody i'm gonna stop this
share
and stop